<searchresult><anarcho_capitalism /><document><title>Bugger the bankers!</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WSIUf2hD6Io</url><snippet /></document><document><title>My Trouble with Nations</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ty--HHErH4Q</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Why not just make teachers millionaires?</title><url>http://www.marketplace.org/topics/economy/education/can-money-buy-good-teachers</url><snippet>  Several teachers at my high school made six figures, all the administrators too, yet if I remember right the overall test scores were below what they were 'supposed' to be. Of course, the teachers making $100,000+ were because of seniority/automatic pay raises through the union and not actual market determination of your worth, so this isn't a particularly even comparison.  Same here. I think we all know Chicago teachers are well compensated and due to union agreements you can't fire bad ones and mediocre ones can make 6 figures easily with nothing more than time in. T/a's OTH are paid a 1/3 of that. I actually didn't go to high school in Chicago, I was out in Aurora/Naperville at the time. But it seems to largely be a statewide problem of overpaying because of the unions here.  Yeah, our looming pension crisis is heartwarming. Btw, are you still going to law school? Yep, over half done, on the internship hunt now.   The catch:

&amp;gt;But for TEP founder Zeke Vanderhoek, there&#8217;s no time to wait. Teachers must bring their A-game on day one, or else.

&amp;gt;&#8220;**We give our master teachers *one year* to prove themselves**,&#8221; Vanderhoek says. 

&amp;gt;Teachers are judged on classroom management and student test scores. They're also evaluated by other teachers. Vanderhoek says **about a quarter of them don't make it to the second year.**

The other catch:

&amp;gt;In Kristen VanOllefen&#8217;s music class, there are also lessons in vocabulary and math. And Van Ollefen's job doesn't stop at the classroom. Last year, she also administered state achievement tests. This year, she has a different additional job. And that&#8217;s part of the secret to TEP's high pay: **Most teachers are doing the work of, well, two teachers.**

**Edit:** In other words, this school is paying more money, but they're not buying the sames goods/services.  With that caveat it makes sense that the pay scale is different. I don't know if it's really a catch. Perform or be fired. It's the same way in any other highly paid, competitive field (e.g. business consulting). As for the "two jobs" thing, I'm not biting. From observing teachers and administrators back when I was in high school, I think it's reasonable to double-up.  </snippet></document><document><title>Any history book recommendations on the rise of soviet communism (or italian fascism)?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17yep4/any_history_book_recommendations_on_the_rise_of/</url><snippet>  Antony C. Sutton has two books purtaining to both.  "Wallstreet and the Bolshievik Revolution" and "Wallstreet and the rise of hiter".  These are not comprehensive studies, but focus on one paticular aspect, namely the role of american capital in subsidizing these movements.  </snippet></document><document><title>CT resident Corey Soulier mentions NAP at Gun Violence Prevention Public Hearing</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?NR=1&amp;amp;v=qGqOc4h1tpQ&amp;amp;feature=endscreen</url><snippet>  This should be cross posted to every (respectable) gun subreddit. and /r/libertarian, and many others. [deleted] [deleted] Some could argue the same about this subreddit, or most other subreddits.  Most definitely /r/anarchy. [deleted] This should be cross posted to every (respectable) gun subreddit. and /r/libertarian, and many others.  We need more guys like this to get the spotlight. The media always focuses on the crazy people or those who don't bother to fully explain their position in a logical reasonable manner.    </snippet></document><document><title>Want to avoid the TSA altogether?  Enter Blackjet.</title><url>http://www.coolhunting.com/travel/blackjet.php/</url><snippet>  Blatant advertisement, but pretty cool. I'm really torn between the extreme convenience of flying in small aircraft (We have flying cars. It's just the rich are the only ones who can afford them), and the fact that small aircraft are the only way rich people die. A little more dangerous per mile than motorcycles.   As always the cost of governments idiocy falls on the poor and middle class. Even the moderately wealthy can usually escape the worst. From the TSA to drugs the vast majority of victims are below the upper middle class.  Get everybody to stop flying. See how quickly those TSA agents disappear and ticket prices plummet. 

AC/DC said it best: Money Talks.  Get everybody to stop flying. See how quickly those TSA agents disappear and ticket prices plummet. 

AC/DC said it best: Money Talks.   yikes. bit of a pricetag. aren't there cheaper flight alternatives out there? &amp;gt;300 miles / 400 passengers

vs

&amp;gt;300 miles / 5 passengers

Costs a bit more. :) It's a very quality plane. Did you see the interior, so sexy. It makes you feel like you're a millionaire. 

Edited: Don't forget to bring your top hat! 

&#9484;&#9472;&#9488;

&#9524;&#9472;&#9524;

&#3232;&#8255;&#3248;&#3267; It's like the difference between a sky-bus and sky-limo &amp;gt;300 miles / 400 passengers

vs

&amp;gt;300 miles / 5 passengers

Costs a bit more. :) </snippet></document><document><title>What about the motha fuckin roads!?! : YouTube</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hK9cIRDWVlA</url><snippet>  Everyone on this subreddit should be subscribed to this guy. If you're not you'd be missing out. Agreed. I watch a few of his videos a day. Lots to catch up on. Doesn't help my progress that I often watch videos 3 or 4 times over. What about him so complelling in your opinion? So far I have only seen his Molyneux video and some of this one, which were good. He's very well read, and so he brings content to his videos that you don't typically hear brought up that much, he's extremely articulate in putting forth his ideas and he doesn't mind elaboration, almost to a fault. Cool thanks. Why kind of stuff does he seem to read? Your standard liberty jerk stuff, economics, psych, fiction? cough  http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PjW_xZWkse4
plug  http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIQVfk1C_8g Cool thanks. Why kind of stuff does he seem to read? Your standard liberty jerk stuff, economics, psych, fiction? Economics, History, Philosophy. Kinda shit we all do, he just reads lots of it and a good mix. Check out his videos on Libertarian books for an idea. I've found a lot of awesome reading material through those. Nice, have you thought about trying to find a time (that works for you) that you could have him on for an interview/roundtable discussion on libertarian relevant literature?? :-)     If you want to it would force me to research /watch up on him properly which is totally fine. He would be a great guest if you could all work out a time. Nice, have you thought about trying to find a time (that works for you) that you could have him on for an interview/roundtable discussion on libertarian relevant literature?? :-)     If you want to it would force me to research /watch up on him properly which is totally fine. I had thought about it yeah. I figured I should get the Book Club podcast off the ground a bit before asking him to come on. I talk to him quite a lot on Skype, so asking him to come on would be easy-peasy. Fuck yeah, that could be the pilot episode! Or we could just make it another episode and we can direct content a la your knowledge and preference. Anyway, just ideas  Dashrath Manjhi. That's some fucked up shit.

Was there some law prohibiting or otherwise making unprofitable the building of a more efficient transportation channel?  Dude always looks like he *just* woke up from or [just got finished with](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3rN2LCKVnyk) wild crazy gay sex.

I love him all the same.

Is this guy a Chem or MechE or something? Sadly I am a virgin, and so have never woken up or finished wild crazy gay sex prior to making a video.  Though I promise should I ever have wild gay sex I will do a vid in the immidiate aftermath to document its effect.     Dude always looks like he *just* woke up from or [just got finished with](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3rN2LCKVnyk) wild crazy gay sex.

I love him all the same.

Is this guy a Chem or MechE or something?</snippet></document><document><title>Reading the constitution again... Not as impressed as I used to be.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17wtd3/reading_the_constitution_again_not_as_impressed/</url><snippet> I love that some of the first written acts that these guys make is giving congress permission to take individual's funds in order to make war. Furthermore they go on to say its acceptable for congress to enslave the nation it is "serving" under whatever debt congress deems appropriate. 


Re-reading this document is making that Larken Rose video a while back about the insanity of being held accountable to someone's rules they simply write down on paper really hit home for me right now.


I don't think ive ever felt so foolish as right now and ive been around here for a while...   Man, I used to be a Marxist and AnComm. Your embarrassment is not even in the same ballpark =P Yeah, I ignored politics for a while because of how much it upset me, then ows came along.... Yeah... Thank god some of the people here were hanging out in that arena.  Man, I used to be a Marxist and AnComm. Your embarrassment is not even in the same ballpark =P Actually, I find that to be a far less embarrassing transition.  Ha, well that's encouraging. How so? Ha, well that's encouraging. How so? The only real difference between ancom and ancap is the underlying view on property rights. It's still a big difference, obviously, but I think it's ideologically much closer than statism. Man, I used to be a Marxist and AnComm. Your embarrassment is not even in the same ballpark =P If you don't mind being asked (for probably the umpteenth time), what was the idea or argument that most affected your thinking? Like, moved me from AnComm to AnCap? It seems silly, but I just realised that actual voluntary Communism would be indistinguishable from a private property system where everybody simply chose to share the results of their labour. And that if you were disallowed the choice of not sharing your labour, you were effectively a slave.

It's hard to say what exactly brought me the necessary ideas to understand that. I hadn't read any AnCap literature, or been exposed to much propertarian thought at all. It is still kinda a mystery really. Max Stirner definitely played a part in my dismissal of Communism though, through his writings and ideas I formulated my own incomplete conception of Subjective Value Theory and in doing so rejected Labour Theories of Value, which had never managed to convince me anyway. LTV makes sense once you realize it's not a descriptive but prescriptive theory of value. It describes how *they* wish the world to behave. 

Leftism runs on envy -- they can't stand the idea that someone else might be better than them and get paid more. LTV makes sense once you realize it's not a descriptive but prescriptive theory of value. It describes how *they* wish the world to behave. 

Leftism runs on envy -- they can't stand the idea that someone else might be better than them and get paid more. If you don't mind being asked (for probably the umpteenth time), what was the idea or argument that most affected your thinking? Man, I used to be a Marxist and AnComm. Your embarrassment is not even in the same ballpark =P How did you escape that prison of the mind? Man, I used to be a Marxist and AnComm. Your embarrassment is not even in the same ballpark =P How could someone be a Marxist and an AnComm ? How Marxist were you ? No like, sequentially, not simultaneously. Why did you stop being a Marxist ? Because I believed it inevitable that a State will breed a parasitic ruling class. This wouldn't refute all Marxism. Marxism is a lot more than a political theory. What do you think about materialism ? How do you see history ? Heh, which one (which historical materialism)?  Amen to this. I have a lot of friends who are Ron Paul libertarians too since  I honed a lot of my beliefs there and eventually found this subreddit which completely changed me. They constantly quote the Constitution and I have started challenging them to come to the core basis of what some of the Constitution represents. Also, that any group that feels they need to document your rights will just as easily erase or alter that document as they see fit. If a right is inherent then you don't actually need to document it. Just recently I challenged a semi-libertarian *"is slavery wrong because of the constitution, or because it's immoral or harmful."*  I was sad to hear him say *"the constitution"* but evidently (heard though someone else) I challenged him to think more on that subject. Wasn't slavery supported by the Constitution, until it was amended in the 1860s? Amen to this. I have a lot of friends who are Ron Paul libertarians too since  I honed a lot of my beliefs there and eventually found this subreddit which completely changed me. They constantly quote the Constitution and I have started challenging them to come to the core basis of what some of the Constitution represents. Also, that any group that feels they need to document your rights will just as easily erase or alter that document as they see fit. If a right is inherent then you don't actually need to document it. Of course it needs to be documented.  It's not exclusive either.  Just because a right isn't listed doesn't mean that you don't have it.  If rights weren't documented then everything would be an argument.  The constitution is the basis of law in the US, to be built on.  

Your argument that 'if they write it, they can take it (erase/alter)' doesn't hold up.  Just because the rights are enumerated doesn't mean that they can take it or erase it.  It's still an inherent right, like you said.  I agree with you, it IS self-evident.  

I forgot, I'm in the anarchy sub.  Let me guess, you don't like signing leases for rentals either. Amen to this. I have a lot of friends who are Ron Paul libertarians too since  I honed a lot of my beliefs there and eventually found this subreddit which completely changed me. They constantly quote the Constitution and I have started challenging them to come to the core basis of what some of the Constitution represents. Also, that any group that feels they need to document your rights will just as easily erase or alter that document as they see fit. If a right is inherent then you don't actually need to document it. I only support 'going back to the constitution' because that would be better then what we have now. I believe that you will never see a real revolution that ends up with positive improvement over what we have now. All improvements are going to be incremental. 

One thing to point out to the pro-constitution folks is how did many signers of the constitution justify the alien and sedation of acts in 1798. These acts made it illegal to criticize the then-current political party (Federalists) that was in charge of Congress and the Presidency. (It was still legal to criticize the Vice President since he was from a different political party). They used these laws to imprison many news paper editors and deport people.  They considered this perfectly and 100% legal under the constitution... people had the freedom to say what they wanted, but that doesn't mean that you can't later on put them in jail for it.

Even Thomas Jefferson thought the case for the first amendment against the alien and sedation acts was a weak one and thought that the the amendment with the best chance of defeating the acts was the 10th... which basically meant that the states should simply refuse to carry out the orders of the Federal government. 


The successful 1775 war of cessation from the British Empire was a huge step forward in liberty and freedom for this country. The constitution, not so much. :/

But, regardless, I support using whatever possible to limit and reduce the size of government.. including constitution. Once we get 'back' to limited government then it will be much easier to argue that it should be limited further... or even eliminated. The problem is that political systems don't go backwards - they ratchet up or fall apart. That's mostly correct, but I will take what I can get.     &amp;gt;implying that you can get it  Lysander Spooner had it right.  

The Declaration of Independence is the more important document from the standpoint of personal liberty.  It's very clear in what they were expecting and the violations the colonial government was visiting on them, and it applies just as much to us today as it did to them.  Larken Rose is the shit. His videos drive right at the heart of the psychological delusion of the state. Larken Rose is the shit. His videos drive right at the heart of the psychological delusion of the state. I found out he lives in my county based from a video he did about when it's OK to shoot a cop. It is now my mission to find him so I can buy him some wings. My eyes are always open. Do you have a bitcoin address? You can buy him a beer on me. You were probably kidding, but here it is.

19B3qgDYj7q1mC62L4ANcRqG65Ax5zsMdG

I'm brand new to bitcoin. Reading some of your posts on it over the months is one of the reasons I made the plunge. Well, at least it is what made me take a closer look. I still think Nielso and some of the Austrians have a good point and it might be a pseudo-ponzi scheme. Not a conscious one perhaps, but it could end the same way.

Either way, the potential to really punish the state is there. At the moment, the barriers seem a little high for it to take off. From what I can gather, and I am by no means an expert on it at all, there is only one easy way for me to add funds that don't link directly back to my bank account. I have to email a guy up the street and give him cash. There is only one guy in my area, at least on the websites I looked at so far, who is willing to do those kinds of trades. I doubt I could sell my friends on this type of transaction let alone a large percent of the populace.

Got any good bitcoin resources on how to add funds anonymously? I'd be interested in some comprehensive resources as well. The vids on youtube seem to be outdated and /r/bitcoin has so much information on it, I have a hard time finding a precise yet comprehensive breakdown of how to get the most out of bitcoin. I am just starting to use coinbase. I don't mind the connection to my bank account right now. As far as privacy is concerned, I don't think the community is mature enough to sustain a truly pseudonymous network yet. And once it does, to the extent that I can get paid in, and pay my bills with bitcoin, it should be easy to transfer my existing funds to more anonymous accounts. I'm more worried about fraud than about anonymity right now, and coinbase seems to satisfy what I want.

The [bitcoin wiki](https://en.bitcoin.it) has pretty good information. The [Getting Started](https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Getting_started) page should be helpful.

&amp;gt;Not a conscious one perhaps, but it could end the same way.

I just don't see this ever happening, unless some clearly superior cryptocurrency pushes bitcoin out of the market. The value of the general concept of cryptocurrency is just too damn valuable for it to be supplanted by gold or silver (or fiat). There will always be people who wish to route around the state's monetary institutions, and until there is a better way to do that than with bitcoin, it's here to stay. [Here's](http://mises.org/Community/forums/t/31743.aspx) an excellent description of (and an amusing ensuing debate about) how bitcoin is unlike anything we've previously called "money". It really doesn't make sense to apply traditional monetary theory, which was conceived in a world where only meatspace tokens could be used as money, to what isn't money at all, but a value ledger instead.
___
I'm waiting on a pending transaction, but once that's done I'll send you a bit-quarter to buy a drink for Larken! I am just starting to use coinbase. I don't mind the connection to my bank account right now. As far as privacy is concerned, I don't think the community is mature enough to sustain a truly pseudonymous network yet. And once it does, to the extent that I can get paid in, and pay my bills with bitcoin, it should be easy to transfer my existing funds to more anonymous accounts. I'm more worried about fraud than about anonymity right now, and coinbase seems to satisfy what I want.

The [bitcoin wiki](https://en.bitcoin.it) has pretty good information. The [Getting Started](https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Getting_started) page should be helpful.

&amp;gt;Not a conscious one perhaps, but it could end the same way.

I just don't see this ever happening, unless some clearly superior cryptocurrency pushes bitcoin out of the market. The value of the general concept of cryptocurrency is just too damn valuable for it to be supplanted by gold or silver (or fiat). There will always be people who wish to route around the state's monetary institutions, and until there is a better way to do that than with bitcoin, it's here to stay. [Here's](http://mises.org/Community/forums/t/31743.aspx) an excellent description of (and an amusing ensuing debate about) how bitcoin is unlike anything we've previously called "money". It really doesn't make sense to apply traditional monetary theory, which was conceived in a world where only meatspace tokens could be used as money, to what isn't money at all, but a value ledger instead.
___
I'm waiting on a pending transaction, but once that's done I'll send you a bit-quarter to buy a drink for Larken!  My signature is not on it, so i am not bound by it...... just dont tell the government that or i could be in trouble.   Which Larken Rose video do you refer to? Which Larken Rose video do you refer to?  [After watching this, I agree.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rrC5lRY4Kr8)  It's so frustrating when statist libertarians constantly refer back to the constitution to try to justify what the government is doing. I always hear "If we just go back to the constitution then all these problems will be fixed." The problem is that the constitution is where we started and it led us directly into this hole. Either the constitution allowed such a government we have today to exist, or it was powerless to stop it. 

Next time someone brings out the constitution to justify 'smaller government' ask them why they think government would stay small this time. It was pretty small back when they started it and it just steadily grew in scope and power up until today.

Also when they bring up states rights as a subset of the constitution as a panacea. Like there's any meaningful difference between the federal government and a state government.  Are you referring to the power to tax and borrow money on the credit of the US Government? Hypothetically, if Britain tried to invade the US again wouldn't these powers be necessary for the new government? Yes we won the revolutionary war but you cannot always rely on citizen militias.  Are you referring to the power to tax and borrow money on the credit of the US Government? Hypothetically, if Britain tried to invade the US again wouldn't these powers be necessary for the new government? Yes we won the revolutionary war but you cannot always rely on citizen militias.  </snippet></document><document><title>Public Property and Illegitimate Power Accumulation Dilemma in a Post-Statist Society.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17xtjd/public_property_and_illegitimate_power/</url><snippet>If a hypothetical anarchist society were to spring up tomorrow, what would happen to the many functions of government existing in the physical form that do not require abolishment, i.e. publicly-owned railroads, bureaucratic offices, publicly owned sewage systems etc. Stuff that due to its origin in the theft and oppression of peaceful people should not be left to for the states directors or managers to retain control over. Forgive me my cynicism but I trust neither the formerly governmental owners of the organization nor any single private interest to auction it off in a manner that would be fair in accordance with anarcho-capitalist theory.

In fact, this is merely a minor quandary of a far larger problem. The immediate aftermath of any transition to a voluntaryist society would leave huge imbalances of power due to the wealth accumulated  illegitimately by agents of the state. Do we "confiscate" and "redistribute" this wealth in the way of the communist or left anarchist? Or do we let it fade over time, trusting in market forces and the aversion of people to the idea of trading with their former oppressors (for comparison see the way in which many are loath to trade with criminals today) to bankrupt those that thrived off of institutional violence? A similar problem arises when we look at companies such as GM, who have survived only by the grace of the state in funneling them stolen money: do we dismantle these in a similar manner to how we would dismantle the Post Office or any other arm of the state? How much state assistance becomes a qualifier for illegitimacy in a business or institution?     Any kind of institutional change creats disorder in the long run. Even relativly slow gradual change does that.

If we would jump from what we have now to AnCap world, it would be the biggest institutional change since feudalism. When you say disorder what exactly do you mean? Any kind of institutional change creats disorder in the long run. Even relativly slow gradual change does that.

If we would jump from what we have now to AnCap world, it would be the biggest institutional change since feudalism.   </snippet></document><document><title>Why does Australia have a really high minimum wage but really low unemployment?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17wu4m/why_does_australia_have_a_really_high_minimum/</url><snippet>  Our Youth Unemployment is pretty high, which is what you'd expect with high minimum wages. Also underemployment is an issue here.

http://www.aph.gov.au/About_Parliament/Parliamentary_Departments/Parliamentary_Library/pubs/MSB/15

http://www.abs.gov.au/AUSSTATS/abs@.nsf/Lookup/4102.0Main+Features60Jun+2010

http://www.abs.gov.au/ausstats/abs@.nsf/Latestproducts/6265.0Main%20Features4Sep%202011?opendocument&amp;amp;tabname=Summary&amp;amp;prodno=6265.0&amp;amp;issue=Sep%202011&amp;amp;num=&amp;amp;view= We need more libertarian Australians.  Go make babies. I'll get to it eventually. [Female Aussie accents](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NLOPfmcfTOU&amp;amp;t=34s) are pretty sexy, actually (not the [sexiest](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQr58kYNJJY) though; dear God, that shy, timid voice makes me melt!!). Watch the movie "Before Sunrise".  You can thank me later. We need more libertarian Australians.  Go make babies. Too few libertarian Aussies. Adopt Asian babies and teach them Hayek. Steal* Why you only learn Austrian economics??  Why you not learn A+ustrian economics? Our Youth Unemployment is pretty high, which is what you'd expect with high minimum wages. Also underemployment is an issue here.

http://www.aph.gov.au/About_Parliament/Parliamentary_Departments/Parliamentary_Library/pubs/MSB/15

http://www.abs.gov.au/AUSSTATS/abs@.nsf/Lookup/4102.0Main+Features60Jun+2010

http://www.abs.gov.au/ausstats/abs@.nsf/Latestproducts/6265.0Main%20Features4Sep%202011?opendocument&amp;amp;tabname=Summary&amp;amp;prodno=6265.0&amp;amp;issue=Sep%202011&amp;amp;num=&amp;amp;view= I always thought you were a kiwi Haha, why'd you think that? I watch a lot of flight of the conchords, and thought I could tell the difference between accents. Guess not!  Easy: because there are enough jobs worth the minimum wage to employ that many people. This is true, my first job during college in AUS was paying $18 an hour which is comfortably above minimum wage. Even fast food jobs often pay above minimum.  They have a very good economy going to base it on, all the mining they are doing is a great help. If they removed the minimum wage, I don't think you'd see much of a change in wage rates. The market has already determined where wages should be, the minimum wage simply reflects that. They also aren't spending ~5% of their GDP on defense, etc. 5%? I think your numbers are off, if you were refering to America. 5%? I think your numbers are off, if you were refering to America. You're probably thinking of government spending. No defense is roughly 25% of our federal government budget. Here is a good graphic representation / breakdown. http://www.usgovernmentspending.com/fed_spending_2013USrn  1. Their minimum wage [scales with age](http://www.fairwork.gov.au/pay/national-minimum-wage/pages/default.aspx). Generally, minimum wage laws hit youths the hardest, but Australia alleviates that by reducing the minimum wage for younger people.

2. Australia has a high Purchasing Power Parity ratio. PPP is a way to attempt to normalize the fact that the cost of living can vary place to place. Australia's ratio is [166](http://stats.oecd.org/Index.aspx?DataSetCode=CPL). This means $166AUD will only get you as far as $100USD. Thus wages should be adjusted down by a factor of 1.66 to get figures that make sense in the US. The top wage would have the purchasing power of $9.39USD, and the lowest mininum wage $3.54USD. 

3. Youth unemployment is still pretty high.[See](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17wu4m/why_does_australia_have_a_really_high_minimum/c89jjog)           </snippet></document><document><title>What if one is "forced" to commit a crime against their will?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17y3jq/what_if_one_is_forced_to_commit_a_crime_against/</url><snippet>What would happen if someone was forced to commit a crime? For instance, someone's family is held hostage, and this someone has to rob someone else in order to save his family. The robbing part is clearly against the NAP, as an innocent person (the robbed) is aggressed against.

Basically, he has to choose between letting his family die or robbing the person.

Is the person who committed the  crime against his will still guilty?  The initial criminal is responsible and must be held accountable for those additional crimes.  What if the hostage was merely the man's favorite recliner, and the crime he is "forced" to commit murder? Is the initial criminal still solely responsible? Or is the man? Or is there some kind of shared responsibility? The initial criminal is responsible and must be held accountable for those additional crimes.    &amp;gt; Is the person who committed the crime against his will still guilty?

No. Why? Quite clearly he has broken against the NAP.

What if he does a crime that would be worse than the killing of his family, say the killing of 30 innocents? He would choose this over killing his own family because of emotional attachment. &amp;gt; Why? Quite clearly he has broken against the NAP.

No, he was forced to by someone else, thus absolving him of any wrongdoing. The extent to his involvement may have to be determined in court, especially his actions at the time and if he acted appropriately. For example, he may still be found to be responsible for not contacting a security firm, or something similar. 

&amp;gt; What if he does a crime that would be worse than the killing of his family, say the killing of 30 innocents? He would choose this over killing his own family because of emotional attachment.

Let's stick with the original scenario. These discussions tend to get quite out of hand when people just keep changing the scenario.

In the original scenario, there are two likely outcomes:

* the guy commits the cool crime of robbery, and his family is returned to him safely. Then the guy calls his security firm, tells them what happened, what the suspect looks like, etc., and he's arrested. I'd imagine the stolen property would then be turned back over to its rightful owner.

* The guy doesn't rob the bank, the robber kills the guys family (and maybe him too) and then the robber get's apprehended, and likely sentenced to live in a jail. 

Seemingly, the criminal would be better off just doing the crime himself, thus taking out any confounding variables that could screw up his plan. Rather than involving another man and his entire family, he has a much better chance of just doing it himself. This is why you rarely hear about criminals forcing other people to commit crimes; it just doesn't work. &amp;gt; No, he was forced to by someone else, thus absolving him of any wrongdoing.

But I've never seen a description of the NAP that contains the exception "unless you're committing aggression to avoid some personal disutility."  This reminds me of the [Trolley Problem](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trolley_problem).   </snippet></document><document><title>Ron Paul tweets about Iraqi war veteran Chris Kyle's death: "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword."  Thoughts?</title><url>https://twitter.com/RonPaul/status/298477312876355585</url><snippet>  For what it's worth, Chris Kyle was a very violent guy. 

[His first kill was a woman who cradled a toddler with one hand and held a grenade in the other. 
"I had to do it to protect the Marines," Kyle told Time magazine a year ago. "You want to lose your own guys, or would you rather take one of them out?"](http://www.cnn.com/2013/02/03/us/texas-sniper-killed-kyle-profile/index.html)

I''m struggling to articulate my thought, and I'm not into grave-dancing, but it is pretty strange how unapologetic the guy was about violence and then this is what happens to him.
 while I definitely don't support United States military action, or Kyle who avidly supported that action and participated in it, in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade. I would probably say the same words.

a grenade tossed by a woman hurts just as much as one tossed by a man. &amp;gt;in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade

Is it a defensive situation if a group of guys all fly half-way around the world, gather a bunch of big weapons, and invade a person's neighborhood and that person offers resistance? I totally agree with you. But realistically, what should he have done in that situation?  Let her kill him?  

She was justified in defending herself, and he was unjustified in invading her country.  But what else can you do if you only realize your crime once you're in the situation?  If you rob someone's house, but grow a conscience in the middle of the act, how should you react when the homeowner aims a shotgun at your head?   I totally agree with you. But realistically, what should he have done in that situation?  Let her kill him?  

She was justified in defending herself, and he was unjustified in invading her country.  But what else can you do if you only realize your crime once you're in the situation?  If you rob someone's house, but grow a conscience in the middle of the act, how should you react when the homeowner aims a shotgun at your head?   &amp;gt;in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade

Is it a defensive situation if a group of guys all fly half-way around the world, gather a bunch of big weapons, and invade a person's neighborhood and that person offers resistance? &amp;gt;in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade

Is it a defensive situation if a group of guys all fly half-way around the world, gather a bunch of big weapons, and invade a person's neighborhood and that person offers resistance? &amp;gt;in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade

Is it a defensive situation if a group of guys all fly half-way around the world, gather a bunch of big weapons, and invade a person's neighborhood and that person offers resistance? I see what you're trying to say, but there are a lot of folks in the military that joined for rational reasons that didn't have to do with invading other places, and through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive. To that end, yes it is a defensive move to shoot the woman with a grenade. It's not like these kids have much of an option when they discover their government is sending them into a war that shouldn't be fought, especially if they have family financially depending on them. Fast forward to the moment when the service member takes a hard look through his glass and sees mother, baby, and grenade, and it is suddenly very obvious it is a lose-lose scenario for everyone involved.  &amp;gt;through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive

What?  You are saying people sign up for the military and then "through no fault of their own" go to war?  There is no "noble intent" anymore.  WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario.  Every US war in our lifetimes has been fought with imperial conquest in mind. &amp;gt; WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario. 

Tell that to the burnt civilian corpses in Dresden or Hiroshima. &amp;gt;through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive

What?  You are saying people sign up for the military and then "through no fault of their own" go to war?  There is no "noble intent" anymore.  WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario.  Every US war in our lifetimes has been fought with imperial conquest in mind. &amp;gt; WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario.

who the hell was "good" in WWII? Finland? Bulgaria. &amp;gt; WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario.

who the hell was "good" in WWII? Finland? Yep.  Finland.  But I guess getting attacked at Pearl Harbor for no reason was a good enough excuse to call the Japanese "evil" and hell, the Germans were practically reaping souls with their extermination tactics.  I know all civilizations do this, but that doesn't mean they have to continue doing so. "No reason" is being rather generous I think.  We enacted trade sanctions on Japan first, taking sides and injecting ourselves into the conflict.  Was their response proportional?  Perhaps not, but it wasn't unprovoked. "No reason" is being rather generous I think.  We enacted trade sanctions on Japan first, taking sides and injecting ourselves into the conflict.  Was their response proportional?  Perhaps not, but it wasn't unprovoked. Yep.  Finland.  But I guess getting attacked at Pearl Harbor for no reason was a good enough excuse to call the Japanese "evil" and hell, the Germans were practically reaping souls with their extermination tactics.  I know all civilizations do this, but that doesn't mean they have to continue doing so. &amp;gt; attacked at Pearl Harbor for no reason

You might want to reconsider this line of thinking.  Just because the US had not officially entered the war does not mean they were not in the war. &amp;gt;through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive

What?  You are saying people sign up for the military and then "through no fault of their own" go to war?  There is no "noble intent" anymore.  WW2 was the last time it was a "Good vs. Evil" scenario.  Every US war in our lifetimes has been fought with imperial conquest in mind. Many people still believe that a standing military is a good thing for purposes of defense. I'm not arguing your point about our wars not being defensive (although I think there's room for discussion about the invasion of Afghanistan). They also join to learn a trade, for college money, or to just get out of a bad home life. Are they perfect decisions? No, but don't forget most people are rational actors, and they're going to make decisions based on their self-interest. When the currency is debased, jobs are being killed, the price of college is skyrocketing, and the family is disincentivized, it is almost a guarantee that you'll get a line if candidates in front of a recruiters office.  Many people still believe that a standing military is a good thing for purposes of defense. I'm not arguing your point about our wars not being defensive (although I think there's room for discussion about the invasion of Afghanistan). They also join to learn a trade, for college money, or to just get out of a bad home life. Are they perfect decisions? No, but don't forget most people are rational actors, and they're going to make decisions based on their self-interest. When the currency is debased, jobs are being killed, the price of college is skyrocketing, and the family is disincentivized, it is almost a guarantee that you'll get a line if candidates in front of a recruiters office.  &amp;gt;Many people still believe that a standing military is a good thing for purposes of defense.

So what? Many people still think rape is an appropriate tool in war; that doesn't make it an appropriate tool in war. See the thread, you're taking that out of context. My point is people can join the military with noble reasons, and it doesn't occur to them they'll be participating in unjust wars. (Even AnCaps and other libertarians debate which wars in our history, if any, were defensive.) There are many that don't see our point of view until they're thrust into the situation, or sometimes after when they return home and have time to process what in the hell just happened.


Edit: Getting back to the original point... if a service member finds themselves looking through a scope and sees someone about to kill his/her teammates, I don't expect that person to say to themselves, "Well, we did invadade their country, so it's okay if I let that person kill them." In my view it was a defensive move for the sniper to shoot the mother with the grenade and save his teammates' lives.  So when the robber sees the security guard about to shoot his wheelman, killing the security guard is self-defense? See the thread, you're taking that out of context. My point is people can join the military with noble reasons, and it doesn't occur to them they'll be participating in unjust wars. (Even AnCaps and other libertarians debate which wars in our history, if any, were defensive.) There are many that don't see our point of view until they're thrust into the situation, or sometimes after when they return home and have time to process what in the hell just happened.


Edit: Getting back to the original point... if a service member finds themselves looking through a scope and sees someone about to kill his/her teammates, I don't expect that person to say to themselves, "Well, we did invadade their country, so it's okay if I let that person kill them." In my view it was a defensive move for the sniper to shoot the mother with the grenade and save his teammates' lives.  I see what you're trying to say, but there are a lot of folks in the military that joined for rational reasons that didn't have to do with invading other places, and through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive. To that end, yes it is a defensive move to shoot the woman with a grenade. It's not like these kids have much of an option when they discover their government is sending them into a war that shouldn't be fought, especially if they have family financially depending on them. Fast forward to the moment when the service member takes a hard look through his glass and sees mother, baby, and grenade, and it is suddenly very obvious it is a lose-lose scenario for everyone involved.  &amp;gt;To that end, yes it is a defensive move to shoot the woman with a grenade

No, it wasn't. You don't bust down someone's door, kill the occupant who is trying to resist, and call your actions defensive (and thus justified) by any means. See the thread above. We are talking about the actions of a sniper saving his teammates. Should he just let her kill them? I don't think so.  I see what you're trying to say, but there are a lot of folks in the military that joined for rational reasons that didn't have to do with invading other places, and through no fault of their own (other than joining the service with noble intent) find themselves in a war in a foreign place and just want to make it home alive. To that end, yes it is a defensive move to shoot the woman with a grenade. It's not like these kids have much of an option when they discover their government is sending them into a war that shouldn't be fought, especially if they have family financially depending on them. Fast forward to the moment when the service member takes a hard look through his glass and sees mother, baby, and grenade, and it is suddenly very obvious it is a lose-lose scenario for everyone involved.  &amp;gt;It's not like these kids have much of an option when they discover their government is sending them into a war that shouldn't be fought

They could do this:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lV6wRLaRsiM while I definitely don't support United States military action, or Kyle who avidly supported that action and participated in it, in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade. I would probably say the same words.

a grenade tossed by a woman hurts just as much as one tossed by a man. I'm admittedly a male chauvinist, but I think the breakdown in social differences between men and women is part of the problem with society nowadays. If a women is holding her child and a grenade, it should be giving people pause as to something not being right.

A parallel might be when children are killing children in schools, something is wrong. The problem isn't guns, it's what leads someone to that point in their life. Blaming guns is a scapegoat intended to ignore the underlying problem.

Therefore if a woman is holding a grenade, everyone should stop what they're doing for a second and think that something is very wrong. The sniper in question should have recognized that he was the hand of oppression and tyranny. I'm admittedly a male chauvinist, but I think the breakdown in social differences between men and women is part of the problem with society nowadays. If a women is holding her child and a grenade, it should be giving people pause as to something not being right.

A parallel might be when children are killing children in schools, something is wrong. The problem isn't guns, it's what leads someone to that point in their life. Blaming guns is a scapegoat intended to ignore the underlying problem.

Therefore if a woman is holding a grenade, everyone should stop what they're doing for a second and think that something is very wrong. The sniper in question should have recognized that he was the hand of oppression and tyranny. &amp;gt;Therefore if a woman is holding a grenade, everyone should stop what they're doing for a second and think that something is very wrong. 

This is kind of my thought as well. But I would add that a woman holding a *child* and a grenade is even more compelling. She's not invading space with a grenade and a child. She's in an utterly (the most?) defensive position. while I definitely don't support United States military action, or Kyle who avidly supported that action and participated in it, in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade. I would probably say the same words.

a grenade tossed by a woman hurts just as much as one tossed by a man. while I definitely don't support United States military action, or Kyle who avidly supported that action and participated in it, in a hypothetically defensive scenario, I see nothing wrong with shooting a woman with a grenade. I would probably say the same words.

a grenade tossed by a woman hurts just as much as one tossed by a man. I see something wrong with joining a military you know is in the business of empire, which creates the very enemies which justifies its existence, and then winding up in a position where you're shooting at a woman with a grenade, who would not have thought to lob such a thing at Americans were it not for endless occupation of their lands.

I get your point -- a woman with a grenade is not a "sacred cow."  Within the logic of war what you say makes sense and I am in agreement.  At the same time, I find it hard to consider these ideas in a clean room, given the fact of our all-volunteer military, which is, in terms of empire and adventurism abroad, the equivalent of flour in a cake.

When a person joins the military, they make empire possible.  They know they are joining in service of the state, and that by joining, they will strengthen the ability of the state of make illegitimate war abroad.  

Therefore, I hold them responsible.  The concept of a paid military gig which has little to do with defending a nation's borders, along with all of its benefits as "service" is absurd. For what it's worth, Chris Kyle was a very violent guy. 

[His first kill was a woman who cradled a toddler with one hand and held a grenade in the other. 
"I had to do it to protect the Marines," Kyle told Time magazine a year ago. "You want to lose your own guys, or would you rather take one of them out?"](http://www.cnn.com/2013/02/03/us/texas-sniper-killed-kyle-profile/index.html)

I''m struggling to articulate my thought, and I'm not into grave-dancing, but it is pretty strange how unapologetic the guy was about violence and then this is what happens to him.
 For what it's worth, Chris Kyle was a very violent guy. 

[His first kill was a woman who cradled a toddler with one hand and held a grenade in the other. 
"I had to do it to protect the Marines," Kyle told Time magazine a year ago. "You want to lose your own guys, or would you rather take one of them out?"](http://www.cnn.com/2013/02/03/us/texas-sniper-killed-kyle-profile/index.html)

I''m struggling to articulate my thought, and I'm not into grave-dancing, but it is pretty strange how unapologetic the guy was about violence and then this is what happens to him.
  I was a little taken aback by that tweet when I read it earlier. It seems out of character for Dr. Paul to say something like that about a fellow veteran and Texan, though I can't say for sure if he's done so in the past. On the other hand he's a straight talker and now that he's out of office maybe he feels he has more leeway to speak his mind.  I get the impression he was talking about the shooter, not the victim. I think he was saying that the guy deserves capital punishment. I was a little taken aback by that tweet when I read it earlier. It seems out of character for Dr. Paul to say something like that about a fellow veteran and Texan, though I can't say for sure if he's done so in the past. On the other hand he's a straight talker and now that he's out of office maybe he feels he has more leeway to speak his mind.  I'd be more irritated with Ron Paul right now if his tweet weren't so cryptic.  What does he mean by "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword?"  Is he suggesting there was some other foul play involved or is he just being a dumbass? It's a quote attributed to Jesus in the Bible telling his disciples to be nonviolent. In the garden of Gethsemane Judas comes to betray Jesus with a host of Roman soldiers. Peter draws his sword and starts swinging, but Jesus quickly tells him put it away 'he who lives by the sword dies by the sword.' 

Which in a nutshell is if you're going to be violent, don't  be surprised if someone gets you back. I understand the figure of speech.  I'm confused because Paul is usually pretty measured in his statements but is making little sense in this particular tweet.  That's why I considered the possibility of Paul alluding to something else.

This simply isn't a case of "live by the sword die by the sword."  If Kyle got killed during a mission in Afghanistan, I guess it would warrant the use of that expression.  However, Kyle's alleged homicide by his friend simply wasn't a case of "dying by the sword." Kyle's violent death at the hands of someone suffering from a disorder caused directly by the kind of violence that Kyle caused in Afghanistan is not "dying by the sword?" That case of "dying by the sword" is incongruous with the "living by the sword" that you just described. I don't see how that's so. The two are the result of the same policy (sword). It's a quote attributed to Jesus in the Bible telling his disciples to be nonviolent. In the garden of Gethsemane Judas comes to betray Jesus with a host of Roman soldiers. Peter draws his sword and starts swinging, but Jesus quickly tells him put it away 'he who lives by the sword dies by the sword.' 

Which in a nutshell is if you're going to be violent, don't  be surprised if someone gets you back. I'd be more irritated with Ron Paul right now if his tweet weren't so cryptic.  What does he mean by "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword?"  Is he suggesting there was some other foul play involved or is he just being a dumbass? I'd be more irritated with Ron Paul right now if his tweet weren't so cryptic.  What does he mean by "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword?"  Is he suggesting there was some other foul play involved or is he just being a dumbass? I'd be more irritated with Ron Paul right now if his tweet weren't so cryptic.  What does he mean by "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword?"  Is he suggesting there was some other foul play involved or is he just being a dumbass? Very strange indeed, and why I'm unsure what to think about it. Although I really seems like more foul play involved with the tweet than the shooting itself, like someone posted on his behalf or something. Using that particular quote makes it seem like Kyle had it coming somehow, and I just don't think that's in line with Dr. Paul's philosophy.   I'd be more irritated with Ron Paul right now if his tweet weren't so cryptic.  What does he mean by "he who lives by the sword dies by the sword?"  Is he suggesting there was some other foul play involved or is he just being a dumbass?  He's right, but that kind of talk isn't going to bring many more people to the light of libertarianism. He's right, but that kind of talk isn't going to bring many more people to the light of libertarianism. He's right, but that kind of talk isn't going to bring many more people to the light of libertarianism.   Since Kyle was killed by an apparently malicious third party, I don't think his PTSD or the fact he was at a gun range has anything to do with his death.

More likely, the fact that he is a mass killer who was glorified by the media is the reason he was targeted. As someone who had never heard of Chris Kyle before, was he the one who had PTSD or was it the guy who killed him?

EDIT: I just looked it up, and Kyle didn't have PTSD.  His killer did. Since Kyle was killed by an apparently malicious third party, I don't think his PTSD or the fact he was at a gun range has anything to do with his death.

More likely, the fact that he is a mass killer who was glorified by the media is the reason he was targeted.  UPDATE:

[As a veteran, I certainly recognize that this weekend's violence and killing of Chris Kyle were a tragic and sad event. My condolences and prayers go out to Mr. Kyle&#8217;s family. Unconstitutional and unnecessary wars have endless unintended consequences. A policy of non-violence, as Christ preached, would have prevented this and similar tragedies. -REP](https://www.facebook.com/ronpaul/posts/10152285499876686)    Who honestly believes that Ron Paul uses twitter, the man is 77 years old.

Some associate of his runs the account, and used a terrible choice of words. It's not uncommon for old politicians to learn to use twitter. Neither is it uncommon for PR representatives to manage social media for politicians, ie. the Obama &amp;amp; Romney presidential campaigns.   Whether or not it's true. The actions of Chris Kyle are not ones I can endorse. I've noticed Right-wingers like O'Reilly seem to engage in the whole hero-worship thing. He even had Kyle on his show. Personally, this further cements my contempt for the political Right. To me, they're no more Libertarian than the Left are. In some ways, they're even worse.  Was this actually written by him or a staffer?

Either way, I don't personally have a problem with it, but it would seem out of character. A staffer? He doesn't hold office and I don't think he's going to run for office. I think he can pretty much say what he wants at this point.     I took it as "if all you have is a hammer, every problem lookslike a nail. "


My first thought in hearing of the deaths was "WTH would they take someone with PTSD to a shooting range??"   Turns out the familiarity and concentration required is very therapeutic. Unfortunately it didn't work this time.  It might be therapeutic, but it is still stupid.  "Here, I know you are mentally unstable right now, but have a weapon that could be used to kill someone!  What could go wrong?"    If by 'dies by the sword' he means Kyle ... he's wrong.

Could have been anybody who got in the guy's way.

At this time, that it happened at a gun range just seems to be a weird coincidence.

Also: this bum gives everyone who comes back from the military a bad name.  Most of us come home, settle down, and after our hair grows back and we loose the urge to 'Sir' everyone you can't really tell a veteren from anyone else. Then there are the guys who are 60 and still act like they're active duty even though they served just 3 years and got out when they were 22.          &amp;gt; Thoughts? 

Ron Paul made a follow up statement, hiding behind his own veteran status. I'm not an A-C, but I don't see the appeal of this guy in these parts.

For a bunch of anti-statists, there sure are a lot of people here apologizing for a career politician like Paul. &amp;gt; a career politician 

Do you happen to know anything about his record other than the fact that he has won re-election a bunch of times? &amp;gt; Do you happen to know anything about his record other than the fact that he has won re-election a bunch of times?

Yes. I do. Ron Paul has almost no record. He has introduced over 600 bills in his career and only one has passed. He missed over 90% of his votes last year, the most in Congress. I certainly wish I could get paid to work 10% of the time.</snippet></document><document><title>EXCLUSIVE: Justice Department memo reveals legal case for drone strikes on Americans</title><url>http://openchannel.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/02/04/16843014-exclusive-justice-department-memo-reveals-legal-case-for-drone-strikes-on-americans?lite</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>How should corporations be broken up?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17x9rk/how_should_corporations_be_broken_up/</url><snippet>If corporations are inventions of government, but property can only legitimately be owned by individuals, how should property currently "owned" by corporations be turned over to individuals?  Simply cease to recognise limited liability. Problem solved. Simply cease to recognize mandated limited liability, but acknowledge that the exact same function would exist in a free market is a more exact answer. Wouldn't it basically be equivalent to moving from implied to explicit contracts? You're free to contract in a manner identical to the current state of things, it's just that there's no longer a single mandatory (well, a few possible options, technically) way these contracts have to be structured. And no one would ever be bound by terms they didn't explicitly agree to. Right? For ease of conversation, yes, though Kinsella points out that dealing with a company named "XYZ, Inc." or "XYZ Corp." could put you on constructive notice of limited liability. Simply cease to recognize mandated limited liability, but acknowledge that the exact same function would exist in a free market is a more exact answer. In that case, wouldn't limited liability only be recognised by those who were part of that contract?  Simply cease to recognise limited liability. Problem solved. Why should stockholders accountable for the actions of management? Should someone that bought BP stock receive a subpoena for $5,000 because of a disaster that they had nothing to do with? Of course, in a free market, managers are able to market shares of their company while assuming the liabilities of their actions.

We should leave corporations as they are, and just end all government-mandated regulations and subsidies. Why should we use force against corporations like Google, Microsoft, IBM and Smith and Wesson just because they have been the recipients of government funds at some point in their financial history? Let the market decide whether or not they should continue to exist.  The only sense in which corporations are created by government is that individual owners are protected against tort claims against the company. The only difference in the end would be that they would be individually liable for tort claims.   I never understood what was wrong with corporations.  They are legal entities that only exist because of government. I don't see why a state is necessary for a corporation to exist, the structure seems to use mechanisms consistent with normal contracts.  The state isn't necessary for a *business* to exist (i.e. a person or group of people willingly united toward some commercial goal), but the purpose of the word "corporation" is to refer to the additional features a state provides to a business (like limited liability, "personhood," etc.). The state isn't necessary for a *business* to exist (i.e. a person or group of people willingly united toward some commercial goal), but the purpose of the word "corporation" is to refer to the additional features a state provides to a business (like limited liability, "personhood," etc.). Why can't stateless law provide for limited liability and personhood? Shareholders are protected via contract, so that instead the corporation can acquire debt. This debt can then be paid off via bonds. To me it looks like a legitimate contract system. 

And keep in mind, those in the company who make criminal decisions can be held personally accountable.  What happens in a situation where the corporation cannot get finance for it's liability? Why should the people whom the corporation owes be stuck with the debt? They were not party to the limited liability contract. That's part of the risk of buying a corporation's bonds. If the corporation goes bankrupt you lose your money and the stock holders are not liable.

As long as it's all done under a free and fair contract, what's the problem? There is no need for government regulation. What is the justification for limited liability in a dispute between the corporation and an individual or group who did not agree to recognise limited liability? Why is it ok for a third party to be forced to abide by a contract they were not part of? Why can't stateless law provide for limited liability and personhood? Shareholders are protected via contract, so that instead the corporation can acquire debt. This debt can then be paid off via bonds. To me it looks like a legitimate contract system. 

And keep in mind, those in the company who make criminal decisions can be held personally accountable.  It certainly is feasible with a contract system. I was merely referring to when government does it. Government doesn't really "do it", though. Individuals incorporate into limited liability corporations, and the government only (through its monopoly on legal systems) prevents individuals from going after shareholders of a corporation.

The only difference is that the courts would be provided privately under anarcho-capitalism. Why can't stateless law provide for limited liability and personhood? Shareholders are protected via contract, so that instead the corporation can acquire debt. This debt can then be paid off via bonds. To me it looks like a legitimate contract system. 

And keep in mind, those in the company who make criminal decisions can be held personally accountable.  I don't see why a state is necessary for a corporation to exist, the structure seems to use mechanisms consistent with normal contracts.  Joe and Beth want to start a corporation.  Joe goes into the bank and tries to open an account in the corporation's name.  The bank asks whose name the account will be in.  Joe says "the corporation".  The bank says "bzzt, property can only be owned by individuals". Ever heard of Tenancy in Common/Joint Tenants/Tenants by the Entirety? More than one person can own something under basic common law legal theory. The same would be true for companies.  That's funny because I've been told repeatedly that only individuals can own property.

If you guys want to switch over to arguing for collective property (which is exactly what Tenancy by the Entirety is), okay, then you're not capitalists anymore.

To answer my own question: The property of corporations could be put directly in the hands of the workers.  If that happened, sure, let's have "anarcho"-capitalism... or rather in that case it would be anarcho-"capitalism" since there wouldn't be a hell of a lot of capitalism to speak of. That's funny because I've been told repeatedly that only individuals can own property.

If you guys want to switch over to arguing for collective property (which is exactly what Tenancy by the Entirety is), okay, then you're not capitalists anymore.

To answer my own question: The property of corporations could be put directly in the hands of the workers.  If that happened, sure, let's have "anarcho"-capitalism... or rather in that case it would be anarcho-"capitalism" since there wouldn't be a hell of a lot of capitalism to speak of. That's a strawman. You can of course have common property arrangements in a free market, you just have to establish it with contract.

Anarcho-capitalism doesn't mean that every and all human interaction is based on capitalism. It is simply a distinguishment from other anarchist schools that are explicitly against private property.

Further, if workers created a certain productive facility and limited the use of said facility to worker-members only, then the facility would simply be jointly owned private property. The "strong" capitalist anarcho-capitalist would argue that the workers would eventually divide labor and create some sort of membership/ownership hierarchy. "Weak" capitalist anarcho-capitalists would argue that in many cases they would have to divide labor between capital managers and wage workers, but in some cases they would not. I fall more on the weak side because I can imagine some scales, types, and phases of production where worker-managed capital could be feasible. I'm not willing to entirely rule out the feasibility of worker coops. Whether they are feasible or not, no ancap would claim they do not have a right to organize how they please. Here's the thing about you guys: If you would focus on the collective and communitarian possibilities, instead of saying shit like "Well yeah if you really want to I guess," then you'd have 95% of the population on your side, because that's what people want.  Instead you're always going on about DROs and contracts and insurance, which are *precisely* the things practically every other person in the world hates *most* about the current society.

And these organizations that supposedly would organize boycotts and disseminate information in order for the threat of economic and social consequences for environmental destruction and breaking contracts to have teeth- they would have to be *more powerful* than the corporations and neo-bourgeoisie they're to regulate, or else the cost of hiring PR flunkies to counter the truth-tellers would simply be just another cost of doing business (as it is today).

Those groups have to be organized by someone.  An economy based on solidarity has to be built.  If YOU people would work on these things, instead of trying to push this idea that after we get rid of the state it'll be everyone for themselves, we could have it within a matter of decades.  And do you know what you would be if you got your heads out of your asses and helped create those groups and economic systems?  *Fucking Anarchists.* Anarchists do very little to create their utopias. Mostly they protest against the branches rather than the roots, chant slogans, push radical feminism/cultural marxism, and apologize for totalitarian states. A few will incite union action or flaccidly engage in gift economies and petty-bourgeois coops.

Anarcho-capitalists reject the idea that economies are organized or planned. Central planning runs counter to the free market, which is based on adaptation and spontaneous order. The market is inherently decentralized, the actors responding to individual values, not ideological concerns.

Anarcho-capitalists tend to be productive compared to the leftists. Many are business owners, investors, economists, and entrepreneurs. The Sea-Steading  Institute is doing well, Bitcoin is doing well, Cody Wilson's Defense Distributed has some gained mainstream attention, free market charter cities are being proposed (the most infamous unfortunately being Glenn Beck's proposed libertarian enclave, but there are others, less ironic), the Free State project has gained mainstream attention and seems to be doing well, Libertarians are making in-roads into mainstream American politics, and Austrian Economics is becoming more widely discussed partly thanks to Ron Paul.

All in all, anarcho-capitalists are a far more productive and entrepreneurial group than radical leftists. The radical left has ditched economics in favor of cultural Marxism and prophetic whining.  That's funny because I've been told repeatedly that only individuals can own property.

If you guys want to switch over to arguing for collective property (which is exactly what Tenancy by the Entirety is), okay, then you're not capitalists anymore.

To answer my own question: The property of corporations could be put directly in the hands of the workers.  If that happened, sure, let's have "anarcho"-capitalism... or rather in that case it would be anarcho-"capitalism" since there wouldn't be a hell of a lot of capitalism to speak of. I never understood what was wrong with corporations.  * The state has ~~provide~~ provided limited liability for corporations with regards to 3rd parties.
* The state uses corporations to play tax games.
 &amp;gt;The state uses corporations to play tax games.

No, people use corporations to play tax games. I can hardly fault someone for trying to keep their wealth, especially if they can shirk the robber by using the robber's own tools.  I never understood what was wrong with corporations.  &amp;gt; I never understood what was wrong with corporations.

People choose to incorporate their businesses for 2 major reasons:

1. It's a special tax bracket for business income. That way you can earn money for your business and not have it taxed as individual income.

2. It reduces liability. As a corporation, unless you do something very criminal, your liabilities are limited by what you have in the business. So if a accident happens and a customer sues you they can't go after your house or child's college fund or anything like that. 

People who actually know how businesses work tend to object to #2.   They think that individuals should be liable for their actions whether or not they performed those actions as part of a business or not. 
    &amp;gt; property currently "owned" by corporations

Pardon my ignorance but the corporations in turn are owned by individuals.  Trying to divest property from people is theft.

Granted, with a behemoth like IBM that is many, many, people but the principals are the same.  And a whole lot of incorporated companies are small businesses like the shop my wife used to own.

The same process you are talking about - taking away a building from IBM - is no different than coming into my wife's store and liberating her stock 'for the people'.

How can you legitimately deprive people of property? Suppose there's a factory which employs 200 workers and is owned by 12,000 stockholders through a publicly-traded corporation.  Which one of those individuals owns the factory? The stockholders. Which one? Which one? Life is short: make your point or wiki the subject.  That's my point.  That you guys have no clue how to get there from here. There is no "there". The company would continue to be owned by 12,000 stockholders, or one would be appointed to be the "owner" but she would be contractually obligated to follow the wishes of the rest, those wishes determined by certain rules and procedures just like they are now.

There is a feeling that in a more anarcho-capitalist society smaller companies would naturally have an advantage in that they would face fewer organizational challenges and would be more able to adapt to changing consumer preferences. Thus larger companies would naturally break themselves up into whatever logical chunks they deem fit in order to stay profitable. But this is mostly speculation based on tendencies in the real world.

Are you perhaps confusing Anarcho-Capitalism with Anarcho-Communism? I think the AnComs want to forcibly remove people's property. Check out [this sub](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarchism), maybe ask this question over there -- I actually would be genuinely interested in their answers.

* Edit: fixed link. Thanks JordanTheBrobot! There is no "there". The company would continue to be owned by 12,000 stockholders, or one would be appointed to be the "owner" but she would be contractually obligated to follow the wishes of the rest, those wishes determined by certain rules and procedures just like they are now.

There is a feeling that in a more anarcho-capitalist society smaller companies would naturally have an advantage in that they would face fewer organizational challenges and would be more able to adapt to changing consumer preferences. Thus larger companies would naturally break themselves up into whatever logical chunks they deem fit in order to stay profitable. But this is mostly speculation based on tendencies in the real world.

Are you perhaps confusing Anarcho-Capitalism with Anarcho-Communism? I think the AnComs want to forcibly remove people's property. Check out [this sub](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarchism), maybe ask this question over there -- I actually would be genuinely interested in their answers.

* Edit: fixed link. Thanks JordanTheBrobot! &amp;gt;or one would be appointed to be the "owner"

Which one?

You guys are pulling this out of your ass, just because you want so badly to keep the current power structures in place, even though they are founded on fraud. &amp;gt;or one would be appointed to be the "owner"

Which one?

You guys are pulling this out of your ass, just because you want so badly to keep the current power structures in place, even though they are founded on fraud. &amp;gt;or one would be appointed to be the "owner"

Which one?

You guys are pulling this out of your ass, just because you want so badly to keep the current power structures in place, even though they are founded on fraud. What are you even talking about? A corporation isn't an invention of government unless it's protected by government. Corporations have been around forever, why would they suddenly disappear in an an-cap society?  What are you even talking about? A corporation isn't an invention of government unless it's protected by government. Corporations have been around forever, why would they suddenly disappear in an an-cap society?  That's my point.  That you guys have no clue how to get there from here. How do you go from my question 

&amp;gt; How can you legitimately deprive people of property?

To concluding

&amp;gt; That you guys have no clue how to get there from here.

 How can you possibly determine who the property of a corporation, since as I've been told repeatedly in other threads that only individuals can own property, if you have potentially tens of thousands of people currently owning that property?  If they own it "together" that means it's not owned by an individual. &amp;gt;since as I've been told repeatedly in other threads that only individuals can own property

I don't believe this is true. Allow me to explain:

Property is a tool used to mediate conflict between two parties. When party A and party B disagree on how an object is used, a property right may be negotiated that grants ownership to one of those parties, and settles the conflict. What's important here is that saying "both A and B own the object" fails to resolve the conflict between them. Property must differentiate between parties to a conflict for it to be effective at resolving that conflict.

So while I don't think "only individuals can own property" is precisely correct, it's a decent approximate argument in response to a collectivist argument that claims taxation is legitimate because all the people in the country own the country. In such a case, the conflict is between the tax payer and the tax collector, so it doesn't do any good to claim that both the tax payer and the tax collector own the property in question. In this case, property needs to be defined at a more granular level to resolve the conflict, and sometimes that means going as far down as the individual level.

However, when multiple people can agree on how some property should be managed, there's nothing wrong with them coming together and collectively owning it. Their conflicts are with people outside the collective, so their ownership only needs to differentiate people in the collective from people out of the collective. How can you possibly determine who the property of a corporation, since as I've been told repeatedly in other threads that only individuals can own property, if you have potentially tens of thousands of people currently owning that property?  If they own it "together" that means it's not owned by an individual. &amp;gt; property currently "owned" by corporations

Pardon my ignorance but the corporations in turn are owned by individuals.  Trying to divest property from people is theft.

Granted, with a behemoth like IBM that is many, many, people but the principals are the same.  And a whole lot of incorporated companies are small businesses like the shop my wife used to own.

The same process you are talking about - taking away a building from IBM - is no different than coming into my wife's store and liberating her stock 'for the people'.

How can you legitimately deprive people of property? IBM hardly dominates IT markets compared to other IT companies. I am old and can almost remember when IBM and 'IT' were synonymous.

Feel free to substitute the IT bogeyman of your choice.

The question remains. I did not know that IBM has greater market share than Apple or Samsung.     &amp;gt;If corporations are inventions of government,

They're not. Corporations at their core are a pooling of assets to create a "legal fiction" where debtors are to only go after the value of the coporation. Tort liability is also, correctly I would add, not extended to shareholders who are not the tortfeasor.  &amp;gt;"legal fiction"

AKA an invention of the government No. Let's say I open a business, a sole proprietorship, and call it "Steenalized Industries." Just a hint, Steenalized is not my real name. The existence of 'Steenalized Industries' is equally a legal fiction, it is just a holding name, a business name, not a creation of the government.  That's not a corporation.  That's a sole proprietorship. &amp;gt;No. Let's say I open a business, **a sole proprietorship,** and call it "Steenalized Industries." 

I acknowledged that. It's also a legal fiction, just like if I made it a corporation. In either case, I am the entire company. In AnCapistan, I'd likely try to persuade my creditors to limit my liability to the company assets, even if I just had a sole proprietorship with no piece of paper declaring me a corporation. Of course, I'd likely be able to get more investments or lower rates if I let them hold me personally liable on the debts. In both instances, as I am the only actor, I am liable personally for tort actions.  &amp;gt;I acknowledged that. It's also a legal fiction, just like if I made it a corporation.

You're completely missing the problem.  How do you handle the property of CURRENTLY-EXISTING corporations in the transition to Stateless capitalism? There is no problem, that's my point.  The ones that currently exist are owned by many people, not by any one particular individual.  The limit on liability is the construction of government. Owning property with other people is perfectly fine. Remove the limited liability and most or all of the largest corporations will either voluntarily break up or they will be sued into the ground.  &amp;gt;Owning property with other people is perfectly fine.

I've been told repeatedly that only individuals can own property. &amp;gt;Owning property with other people is perfectly fine.

I've been told repeatedly that only individuals can own property.  Corporations are still businesses, so without State support they'll tank or survive subject to the consumer and competition. If you just say "OK, stateless capitalism starting... Now!" with these huge mountains of unjustly accumulated capital sitting in the hands of a few, they *will* use that power to entrench themselves.  I know, I know, it's impossible for "anarcho"-capitalism to develop States.  Totally impossible. What do you mean by "entrench"?  Umm, corporations already have rules for how the shareholders make their will regarding the use of the common property known. All that abolishing government oversight of the process would do would open up new possibilities for contract structures to arise. People could keep using more or less the same model (ultimately I'll have to defer to others with more corporate law experience, but I've heard Kinsella express this opinion before). You'd just need explicit contracts instead of deferring to the few ones the government currently allows. &amp;gt;common property

So, not capitalism You clearly misunderstand how the term is used around here. I'd feel bad, but since it's been explained literally dozens of times in this thread, it's pretty clear you're not interested in understanding. Your definition of capitalism is absurd.  It comes out to "Any time anyone other than a State does anything economically productive". No, it's that anyone may claim unowned resources and then do whatever he desires with them unless it involves interfering with resources someone else has already claimed. What precisely constitutes a claim may be open for debate, but what one does with that property is up to his discretion. He's free to maintain exclusive control and not let anyone else benefit, or he's free to pool his property with other people and agree to whatever contractual terms they all settle upon. This is a corporation. It's not fundamentally different from someone pooling his labor with others according to whatever mutually-agreed-upon rules they create. Thus a commune or coop is viable within a capitalist framework so long as all members who are staking the claim agree to such terms. They just can't force other groups outside of theirs to abide by the same terms. In the same way, a Homeowner's association could have a contractual obligation applied to all who buy into the area it represents (which is thus all claimed land, not unclaimed) as a condition of purchasing that property. Anyone who entered the contract but didn't fulfill the terms would be guilty of aggression. &amp;gt;No, it's that anyone may claim unowned resources and then do whatever he desires with them unless it involves interfering with resources someone else has already claimed.

Hunter-gathering: Capitalism! You're certainly dedicated, I'll give you that. And, by definition, each time I've responded I've been the beneficiary of a mutually beneficial exchange, so I can't fault you on those grounds. Still, it would seem like you could find much more profitable uses of your time than engaging in such a poor attempt at trolling. It's certainly your choice, and I'd never dream of coercing you, but seriously, think about it. Hurtling abuse at the handmaidens of fascism is always a good time.  Dude, I'm having trouble determining if you're outright trolling/trying to convert or looking for a real answer, but I'm glad you posted either way.  =)

I consider myself voluntaryist and this is a question I've struggled with.  This question is part of why I'm uncomfortable identifying as an ancap without caveat and arguing "self-government through contract"; I think all concentrated power, public or private, should be treated with suspicion.

There are ideas like Coase theorem that assert that initial allocation of property rights does not affect the market's ability to reach an efficient solution, but that's focused narrowly on externalities.  There are also statistics about accumulated wealth in families and how it dissipates after a few generations.  Taken broadly, those could be reassuring for the distant future.

Neither of those address the problem of corporations who have benefited largely from government granted privilege in the short term, however, which is what I believe you're concerned with.

I do kinda think your line of questioning about flipping a switch might be unintentionally disingenuous?  As far as I'm aware, ancaps subscribe to NAP, so the only way we'd "switch" to an ancap society is if the vast majority of people woke up one morning and also rejected initiation of force.  

Were that the case, and coercion was generally unacceptable, doesn't it stand to reason that if a company can't find a way to provide market value absent government, they'd have to adjust quickly or fail?  People would reject a company that tried to become a state or rule based on stifling contracts; people would certainly reject a corporation that spend all it's money to claim a territory against the will of residents.  Right?

I'm not 100% sure I know the conventional ancap answer, but I know where I'd land.

Anyway, absent a magical switch, I consider pursuit of NAP and educating people to be our best path to freedom.  That's a slow progression.  In the short term, I'm concerned with the biggest concentration of power in the world today and how my children and grandchildren can break free of them.  In the long term, I don't see how a company that provides no value and uses contracts as a weapon could succeed in an "ancap" society, but I don't actually care too much whether freedom looks like a commune or a giant corporate glass tower, as long as society isn't based around force. "Non-aggression principle" is already insanely fanciful on its face, but when taken with the idea that a person's 'right' to let 'their' food rot trumps the right of starving people to take that food, it's clear what it really means.  "Non-aggression principle" is a good reason why the proper name for "anarcho"-capitalists is really "Propertarian" since you think property 'rights' trump human rights.  That is a profound endorsement of mass violence.

&amp;gt;There are also statistics about accumulated wealth in families and how it dissipates after a few generations

Sure, like how the French aristocracy dissipated suddenly in 1789.   How should the cotton be picked without slaves? It doesn't matter.

It seems like all of these posts about "how will _____ be done without violence?" are disrupting the cause by diverting the conversation away from the first principles and towards a burying in the minutiae. </snippet></document><document><title>Opened a discussion about Anarcho Capitalism in /r/politicaldiscussion. Feel free to stop by and help present our point. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/PoliticalDiscussion/comments/17vpie/whats_your_opinion_on_anarcho_capitalism_serious/</url><snippet>  In the future if you're going to open up a discussion like this, please be around to argue it yourself. What you've done is you've opened this up to them. If we don't go there and argue, they're going to circlejerk about how "bad" anarcho-capitalism is, and the cause of liberty will be marginally hurt by that. In an effort to break up the circlejerk, a bunch of us are now going to have to do damage control for you.

tl;dr - If you're not going to defend the point, don't bring it up for discussion. Fortunately mindless repetition of market principles is one of my favorite hobbies! In the future if you're going to open up a discussion like this, please be around to argue it yourself. What you've done is you've opened this up to them. If we don't go there and argue, they're going to circlejerk about how "bad" anarcho-capitalism is, and the cause of liberty will be marginally hurt by that. In an effort to break up the circlejerk, a bunch of us are now going to have to do damage control for you.

tl;dr - If you're not going to defend the point, don't bring it up for discussion. In the future if you're going to open up a discussion like this, please be around to argue it yourself. What you've done is you've opened this up to them. If we don't go there and argue, they're going to circlejerk about how "bad" anarcho-capitalism is, and the cause of liberty will be marginally hurt by that. In an effort to break up the circlejerk, a bunch of us are now going to have to do damage control for you.

tl;dr - If you're not going to defend the point, don't bring it up for discussion.  For those who are going to /r/politicaldiscussion to participate in the debate, a plea from a /r/politicaldiscussion moderator: 

Please do not vote based on ideology. While many people on reddit (including many subscribers to /r/politicaldiscussion) use the downvote arrow as some sort of "weapon," the problem is always worse when directly-linked from a partisan subreddit. /r/politicaldiscussion is intended to be a ground for people of all sides to discuss issues. I think the voting in that thread at the moment is *relatively* representative of this idea, as mostly well-articulated comments are higher up - but also some relatively well-articulated anti-ancap comments are being voted down. It's a discussion, not a battleground. 

Also, a plug for /r/libertariandebates if you like this sort of thing. 

Thank you. For those who are going to /r/politicaldiscussion to participate in the debate, a plea from a /r/politicaldiscussion moderator: 

Please do not vote based on ideology. While many people on reddit (including many subscribers to /r/politicaldiscussion) use the downvote arrow as some sort of "weapon," the problem is always worse when directly-linked from a partisan subreddit. /r/politicaldiscussion is intended to be a ground for people of all sides to discuss issues. I think the voting in that thread at the moment is *relatively* representative of this idea, as mostly well-articulated comments are higher up - but also some relatively well-articulated anti-ancap comments are being voted down. It's a discussion, not a battleground. 

Also, a plug for /r/libertariandebates if you like this sort of thing. 

Thank you. &amp;gt; Please do not vote based on ideology

What? I remember always getting that level of respect when I go there! I unsubbed months ago The golden rule. I practice it, I endorse it, I hope the AnCaps do to.. I'm just saying I've had mostly bad experiences in that subreddit, regardless of how polite I am and how many citations I use. For those who are going to /r/politicaldiscussion to participate in the debate, a plea from a /r/politicaldiscussion moderator: 

Please do not vote based on ideology. While many people on reddit (including many subscribers to /r/politicaldiscussion) use the downvote arrow as some sort of "weapon," the problem is always worse when directly-linked from a partisan subreddit. /r/politicaldiscussion is intended to be a ground for people of all sides to discuss issues. I think the voting in that thread at the moment is *relatively* representative of this idea, as mostly well-articulated comments are higher up - but also some relatively well-articulated anti-ancap comments are being voted down. It's a discussion, not a battleground. 

Also, a plug for /r/libertariandebates if you like this sort of thing. 

Thank you.   I think the important thing from these kind of discussions is to see what concerns most people.  The things that concern people are the things we should get good at explaining in a way that addresses their concerns.

Concerns I noticed so far:

Monopoly

the rich will rule

Can&#8217;t have property rights without a state.

environment

the poor will be worse off

The free market can&#8217;t solve every problem

the system will inherently come to a violent end

Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind. I think the important thing from these kind of discussions is to see what concerns most people.  The things that concern people are the things we should get good at explaining in a way that addresses their concerns.

Concerns I noticed so far:

Monopoly

the rich will rule

Can&#8217;t have property rights without a state.

environment

the poor will be worse off

The free market can&#8217;t solve every problem

the system will inherently come to a violent end

Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind. Very good observation. Don't forget aesthetics: "Justice is not a commodity!" I think the important thing from these kind of discussions is to see what concerns most people.  The things that concern people are the things we should get good at explaining in a way that addresses their concerns.

Concerns I noticed so far:

Monopoly

the rich will rule

Can&#8217;t have property rights without a state.

environment

the poor will be worse off

The free market can&#8217;t solve every problem

the system will inherently come to a violent end

Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind. &amp;gt; Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind.

I think of this the other way around. I argued with somebody and he said humans are basiclly all assholes. I said right, thats why you should have the system where assholes can do the least amount of harm.

This argument is very old, David Hume talkes about this when he talkes about parlaments. &amp;gt; Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind.

I think of this the other way around. I argued with somebody and he said humans are basiclly all assholes. I said right, thats why you should have the system where assholes can do the least amount of harm.

This argument is very old, David Hume talkes about this when he talkes about parlaments. I think the important thing from these kind of discussions is to see what concerns most people.  The things that concern people are the things we should get good at explaining in a way that addresses their concerns.

Concerns I noticed so far:

Monopoly

the rich will rule

Can&#8217;t have property rights without a state.

environment

the poor will be worse off

The free market can&#8217;t solve every problem

the system will inherently come to a violent end

Anarcho-capitalism ignores the fundamental flaws of mankind. We need a better Q&amp;amp;A    Just received this gem out of that thread:

&amp;gt;"Anarcho"-capitalism is a complete crock of unworkable shit dreamed up by middle-class American white men, the most privileged motherfuckers that have ever existed, who wonder why everyone isn't as successful as them and conclude it's because the poor are all just a bunch of lazy moochers. The ideology (which is basically a religion) perfectly meshes with their corporatist and bureaucratic worldview, which works perfectly for them because being able to fill out every form (it's almost like they were written specifically for them!) or pay for any service has never been a problem, and they will never understand what it's like for the overwhelming majority of the world for whom this is not the case. "Anarcho"-capitalists are funded by corporations whose agenda is to destroy what little governmental environmental protections exist (but not government protections for corporations, naturally) so there's nothing to stop them from pillaging what little is unspoiled in pursuit of short-term profit, and to the good name of Anarchism to keep those who would stop them disorganized. "Anarcho"-capitalists are the worst people in the world and the only justice would be for a bridge to fall on them. &amp;gt; "Anarcho"-capitalists are funded by corporations

That's strange, I haven't received my check from our beloved corporate sponsors. Anyone else with the same problem? &amp;gt; "Anarcho"-capitalists are funded by corporations

That's strange, I haven't received my check from our beloved corporate sponsors. Anyone else with the same problem? Just received this gem out of that thread:

&amp;gt;"Anarcho"-capitalism is a complete crock of unworkable shit dreamed up by middle-class American white men, the most privileged motherfuckers that have ever existed, who wonder why everyone isn't as successful as them and conclude it's because the poor are all just a bunch of lazy moochers. The ideology (which is basically a religion) perfectly meshes with their corporatist and bureaucratic worldview, which works perfectly for them because being able to fill out every form (it's almost like they were written specifically for them!) or pay for any service has never been a problem, and they will never understand what it's like for the overwhelming majority of the world for whom this is not the case. "Anarcho"-capitalists are funded by corporations whose agenda is to destroy what little governmental environmental protections exist (but not government protections for corporations, naturally) so there's nothing to stop them from pillaging what little is unspoiled in pursuit of short-term profit, and to the good name of Anarchism to keep those who would stop them disorganized. "Anarcho"-capitalists are the worst people in the world and the only justice would be for a bridge to fall on them. Just received this gem out of that thread:

&amp;gt;"Anarcho"-capitalism is a complete crock of unworkable shit dreamed up by middle-class American white men, the most privileged motherfuckers that have ever existed, who wonder why everyone isn't as successful as them and conclude it's because the poor are all just a bunch of lazy moochers. The ideology (which is basically a religion) perfectly meshes with their corporatist and bureaucratic worldview, which works perfectly for them because being able to fill out every form (it's almost like they were written specifically for them!) or pay for any service has never been a problem, and they will never understand what it's like for the overwhelming majority of the world for whom this is not the case. "Anarcho"-capitalists are funded by corporations whose agenda is to destroy what little governmental environmental protections exist (but not government protections for corporations, naturally) so there's nothing to stop them from pillaging what little is unspoiled in pursuit of short-term profit, and to the good name of Anarchism to keep those who would stop them disorganized. "Anarcho"-capitalists are the worst people in the world and the only justice would be for a bridge to fall on them.   I've never been to r/politicaldiscussion before, but I'm assuming it's full of statists with little calm in dealing with out of the box thinking. They're better than many, but not great. I've never been to r/politicaldiscussion before, but I'm assuming it's full of statists with little calm in dealing with out of the box thinking.    </snippet></document><document><title>Argentina freezes prices to break inflation spiral - New York News</title><url>http://www.myfoxny.com/story/20958959/argentina-freezes-prices-to-break-inflation-spiral</url><snippet>     Talk about a biased headline, huh? What evidence is there that price freezes break 'inflation spirals?' Banning exchanges above certain prices always gives way to hoarding, hiding, and black market exchange, while creating incentives for importers to stop doing business. Maybe "Argentina freezes prices **in an attempt** to break inflation spiral" would be more correct but I don't think the headline as written is necessarily biased. 

I could write a headline like "Man wears socks on ears to increase garden yield" without espousing the belief that what he is doing is going to have the intended effect. 

Coincidentally Argentinians have about as much chance of stopping inflation by wearing socks on their ears as they do by simply implementing price freezes.  I prefer "Argentina freezes prices **in a *futile* attempt** to break inflation spiral." Now *that* would be biased No, it would be factual.  I agree with that too. Now I'm pondering the real meaning of "bias."
   I remember reading that people were buying brand new cars as a hedge against inflation. The value of the car increasing faster than it can depreciate from age. Money not spent on something quickly turning into dust.

Quoting from Wikipedia:
&amp;gt;Argentina went through steady inflation from 1975 to 1991. At the beginning of 1975, the highest denomination was 1,000 pesos. In late 1976, the highest denomination was 5,000 pesos. In early 1979, the highest denomination was 10,000 pesos. By the end of 1981, the highest denomination was 1,000,000 pesos. In the 1983 currency reform, 1 peso argentino was exchanged for 10,000 pesos. In the 1985 currency reform, 1 austral was exchanged for 1,000 pesos argentinos. In the 1992 currency reform, 1 new peso was exchanged for 10,000 australes. The overall impact of hyperinflation: 1 (1992) peso = 100,000,000,000 pre-1983 pesos.   According to Doug Casey [Argentina is the best place in the world to weather the economic crisis.](http://www.caseyresearch.com/cwc/doug-casey-his-favorite-place-world)

Is he off his rocker? He assumes you are a wealthy foreigner, diversified internationally, and wont have to rely on Argentina's currency or banking sector. The dollar will be quite strong in Argentina for the short/medium term. He assumes you are a wealthy foreigner, diversified internationally, and wont have to rely on Argentina's currency or banking sector. The dollar will be quite strong in Argentina for the short/medium term. Yes, he says specifically that Argentina is horrible for business and he would never do business or invest there. Yes, he says specifically that Argentina is horrible for business and he would never do business or invest there. According to Doug Casey [Argentina is the best place in the world to weather the economic crisis.](http://www.caseyresearch.com/cwc/doug-casey-his-favorite-place-world)

Is he off his rocker? His rationale is that the state is so inefficient there that you can basically ignore the rules and bribe the officials you come into contact with.  Which is true to some extent, but there are plenty of other countries where this is the case.  Personally, I would have chosen Chile or Peru, where there is a much, much stronger free market popular base.

At the end of the day, it may have been a somewhat emotional decision which he would have post-rationalised later into a "common sense business decision".

     </snippet></document><document><title>Justice Department memo reveals legal case for drone strikes on Americans</title><url>http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/i/msnbc/sections/news/020413_DOJ_White_Paper.pdf</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Gabe Newell Presentation at LBJ - Part 2 (Includes thoughts on corporations vis a vis the internet)</title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=jhgOqyZHBIU#t=1096s</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Aren't all current property titles, having been acquired under the State, illegitimate?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17wwsc/arent_all_current_property_titles_having_been/</url><snippet>Doesn't that imply that all property should be redistributed as a precondition for establishing a truly just Stateless-capitalist society?  No. Just because the State allows you to rightfully homestead a piece of land does not make your homesteading illegitimate for the State having allowed it.

Eminent domain is another matter. So you'll have no problem awarding all currently-held titles in the US and Canada to the Native American tribes who originally owned them, right? If they can demonstrate homesteading of the particular land in question by themselves or an ancestor then of course the land is rightfully theirs. They have to prove that particular bit of earth was homesteaded by their particular ancestors and taken by force however.

I love when people like you make threads like this and come back with that response. It's so cute how you think you've managed to "catch me out" so to speak. That's funny, because ArchonAlarion just said "The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago, the victims and aggressors long dead, and the facts of the cases obscured by time." And? At least one of you doesn't know what he's talking about (my guess: both). ArchonAlarion is just saying a similar thing to what I am saying, just with less grace and clarity. He probably disagrees with me to a certain extent though, his statements sound more utilitarian than mine in flavour.

Do you have an argument for your "guess", or can we consider this discussion over? We can easily show which land was owned by whom.  Assuming you live in North America, when will you be handing over your keys? And how do we do that? That's funny, because ArchonAlarion just said "The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago, the victims and aggressors long dead, and the facts of the cases obscured by time." So you'll have no problem awarding all currently-held titles in the US and Canada to the Native American tribes who originally owned them, right?  Aren't all current marriages, having been acquired under the state, illegitimate?

I would say no. If the state had not forced them to get a marriage license, wouldn't they still have gotten married? If the state did not lay some nebulous claim to all property within an arbitrary geographical area, wouldn't property still be changing hands for the benefit of both parties?

**Edit:** Hey guys, let's not downvote for disagreement. I'm sure most of you aren't but there are a few who clearly are. His response to this post is a perfectly legitimate one, let's not be petty (you know who you are). That's not the argument.  If the government robs people via taxes, and gives some of that money to a business because they made the most campaign contributions, and that business then buys a factory, if the State ceased to exist the next day should they keep the factory?  How is it not stolen property? [deleted] &amp;gt;if not the state, then who?

Maybe the same entity as the answer to this (begged-)question:

&amp;gt;If you can make a case that you have a superior claim to ownership [deleted] That no such entity exists, therefore legitimizing the primitive Statist theft and making a possible "anarcho"-capitalist system fatally flawed from the start? [deleted] That's my point.  There isn't anyone.  And all of you are working hard to justify keeping the current illegitimate titles maintained at all costs.  Making "anarcho"-capitalism either impossible, or exposed as nothing but a way for today's wealthy and their sycophants to solidify their hold on privilege. In an ancap or even more mincap society, even in our mixed society, wealth and property move around a lot. Given this situation even now, a purely ancap society would deviate towards more people having a rightful ownership via capital accumulation. A 1/2 acre lot with a really nice house or a 30 acre lot with a larger house, would all require effort, but no longer require the same effort as now, and certain inefficiencies would dry up as well.

tl;dr - don't think too hard about things as they are and confuse them with how they could be That's not the argument.  If the government robs people via taxes, and gives some of that money to a business because they made the most campaign contributions, and that business then buys a factory, if the State ceased to exist the next day should they keep the factory?  How is it not stolen property? Look up the concept called yeush, conscious abandonment. It's from Jewish Law, but it's a natural law concept.

If you throw something into garbage, you abandon it (return it to "nature"). My taking it from there is not stealing. But if you see something fall into the sea, you also abandon it, since you abandon hope to ever recover it. If I find your wallet, with your license, washed up by the sea, I can legitimately keep it: it's no longer yours. (Although it might be nice to return it. But that's going above and beyond the basic legal/moral requirement.)

When government takes something from a person, he abandons hope to get it back (unless there is a possibility of litigation, etc.). That us why whoever takes it from the government can keep it. Look up the concept called yeush, conscious abandonment. It's from Jewish Law, but it's a natural law concept.

If you throw something into garbage, you abandon it (return it to "nature"). My taking it from there is not stealing. But if you see something fall into the sea, you also abandon it, since you abandon hope to ever recover it. If I find your wallet, with your license, washed up by the sea, I can legitimately keep it: it's no longer yours. (Although it might be nice to return it. But that's going above and beyond the basic legal/moral requirement.)

When government takes something from a person, he abandons hope to get it back (unless there is a possibility of litigation, etc.). That us why whoever takes it from the government can keep it. Look up the concept called yeush, conscious abandonment. It's from Jewish Law, but it's a natural law concept.

If you throw something into garbage, you abandon it (return it to "nature"). My taking it from there is not stealing. But if you see something fall into the sea, you also abandon it, since you abandon hope to ever recover it. If I find your wallet, with your license, washed up by the sea, I can legitimately keep it: it's no longer yours. (Although it might be nice to return it. But that's going above and beyond the basic legal/moral requirement.)

When government takes something from a person, he abandons hope to get it back (unless there is a possibility of litigation, etc.). That us why whoever takes it from the government can keep it. That's not the argument.  If the government robs people via taxes, and gives some of that money to a business because they made the most campaign contributions, and that business then buys a factory, if the State ceased to exist the next day should they keep the factory?  How is it not stolen property? &amp;gt; If the government robs people via taxes, and gives some of that money to a business because they made the most campaign contributions, and that business then buys a factory, if the State ceased to exist the next day should they keep the factory?

Probably. I think that it's a bit murky if we were to come away from a centuries old, established system that promoted such underhanded dealings.

If you're expecting the corporate version of the French Revolution, you'd probably be disappointed. 

**However**, it would be up to consumers, other corporations, employees, and watchdog groups to ascertain if certain companies should be boycotted and peacefully abolished through voluntary means (like not working for/with them or buying from them). &amp;gt;I think that it's a bit murky

Here's the thing.  You guys have no answer for the most fundamental question of the act of establishing what you espouse. &amp;gt;I think that it's a bit murky

Here's the thing.  You guys have no answer for the most fundamental question of the act of establishing what you espouse. I see lots of answers. Perhaps they just aren't ones you like? I've seen a lot of dodges and moving of goalposts, but no one squarely answering the question.  It's true RanDomino5 that most properties in the world have been acquired unjustly at some point.

The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago, the victims and aggressors long dead, and the facts of the cases obscured by time.

I am not for redistribution/restitution unless the victims can prove their case and that the acquisition happened relatively recently. If you are suggesting that *all* property should be redistributed (to whom?) as a pre-condition to establishing a stateless society, then I disagree. It is not a necessary precondition to improving an imperfect world. &amp;gt;The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago

Why isn't *every* acquisition that occurs while the State stands fundamentally unjust?  Even if the money and title exchanges hands 'voluntarily' it still occurs in an environment based, at some level, on coercion. Yeah, sucks dude. At some point you have to make due and at least try to change the system marginally for the better.

The enemy of good is perfect. The environment can never be perfect, but that's no reason to dump the whole system of property and capitalism. One can only cut the gold from the shit and work on making the shit go away. Hey, if you guys want to have property and capitalism, that's your thing.  But just don't try to claim it would be consensual, fair, or just without hitting the reset button on property first.  Shall we start the game of Monopoly with a few having $10,000, some having $1000, and the rest having $50? Past injustices don't echo throughout eternity. Eventually, things even out or the (dis)advantage might become obsolete.

The monopoly analogy is weak in two ways. The first is that monopoly is a zero-sum game. You can never really gain without someone else losing. Markets and trade occur due to the mutual benefits of exchange. The second is that there are no generations in monopoly. Say if you were to play an infinite number of games, where the players would pass their end cash to another randomly chosen player at the beginning of the next game. Further, players could choose what tiles they occupy, purchase additional boards and players, and produce their own currencies. Any inequities in wealth at the beginning of the first game (the preconditions) would eventually disappear or become obsolete. Hey, if you guys want to have property and capitalism, that's your thing.  But just don't try to claim it would be consensual, fair, or just without hitting the reset button on property first.  Shall we start the game of Monopoly with a few having $10,000, some having $1000, and the rest having $50? [deleted] [deleted] &amp;gt;statists like you

lololololololooloololololol [deleted] The "peace" of starving because you can't afford food even though there's so much of it that it will be thrown away- just because there's no profit in letting you have it for free; the "peace" of dying of exposure even though there are countless empty buildings, just because you can't pay rent; the "peace" of a private 'court' sending thugs to take your land, because you couldn't afford to pay as big of a bribe.  There's your "peace". [deleted] The "peace" of starving because you can't afford food even though there's so much of it that it will be thrown away- just because there's no profit in letting you have it for free; the "peace" of dying of exposure even though there are countless empty buildings, just because you can't pay rent; the "peace" of a private 'court' sending thugs to take your land, because you couldn't afford to pay as big of a bribe.  There's your "peace". That's just going overboard. The USA is the most charitable nation in the history of the world and it happens to have been the most capitalist for the longest time. Those bad things don't happen when help is looked and asked for.  Hey, if you guys want to have property and capitalism, that's your thing.  But just don't try to claim it would be consensual, fair, or just without hitting the reset button on property first.  Shall we start the game of Monopoly with a few having $10,000, some having $1000, and the rest having $50? I've met people that are not native to the USA, are poor as dirt, and somehow are better off with their tiny little patch of dirt then their parents, their kids will most likely be even better off when they grow up with the opportunities and living standards found here. 

Now imagine if we had no taxes? Imagine if even 1/10 the tax money currently gathered went to charities/investment/education/research/healthcare.

People in all walks of life would be better off. &amp;gt;The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago

Why isn't *every* acquisition that occurs while the State stands fundamentally unjust?  Even if the money and title exchanges hands 'voluntarily' it still occurs in an environment based, at some level, on coercion. &amp;gt;The problem is that much of the unjust acquisitions happened many years ago

Why isn't *every* acquisition that occurs while the State stands fundamentally unjust?  Even if the money and title exchanges hands 'voluntarily' it still occurs in an environment based, at some level, on coercion. Because not every acquisition requires the state to steal. I don't "need" the state to buy a house, it just happens to still exist and get in my way. However, if you are attempting to use the state to take the house (tax liens or unjust eviction/takeover) then it is truly unjust.    If those titles are the only justification you have for the claim to your land, probably. Do you think that bit of paper is the only thing that gives you a legitimate claim? That's a strong contender for "the definition of capitalism". Paper justification for possession of land? I prefer calling it "title-based property ownership".  Usually referred to as "private property" but I think that's too ambiguous. Why does private property require issuance of a title by a government? I don't think most libertarian style capitalists would agree that issuing a government title is what creates private property. On the contrary, i think they would look at such action as an attempt by government to meddle in things that are none of its concern.  Then in order to make the switch to a Stateless capitalist system, all current property ownership has to be thrown out the window, since it's based on nothing. Libertarians typically base it on an act of creation, so its not based on "nothing." There are certainly conflicting claims out there, many hard to provide evidence for. As a matter of conscience, any libertarian that is presented with a viable claim ought to be willing to negotiate with the claimant towards an equitable solution. I would.  How can anyone make a competing claim when the criteria for claims is based on the illegitimate remnants of the illegitimate system? That's not the basis I, or most libertarians, would use. The basis I would use is basically "Was this land taken forcefully or fraudulently from your ancestors while they were using it?"  I prefer calling it "title-based property ownership".  Usually referred to as "private property" but I think that's too ambiguous. Private property is the product of your time, energy, and talents/skills. I also like to include resources in that list, which are presumably a product of the first three. Then that makes selling impossible, because the new owner would have invested no time, energy, or skills into their new acquisition. Then that makes selling impossible, because the new owner would have invested no time, energy, or skills into their new acquisition. But they would have invested some of their resources, which are the product of their time, energy, and/or talents. I presume you mean money.  So what's the statute of limitations on that?  If someone decides to homestead some property that *seems* abandoned, but then the person who previously invested some of their resources comes back and wants it, who wins? Money, or currency, is an abstract concept that represents value. 

And in the example you cite, no doubt there would be some arbitration service that would adjudicate disputes such as this. They might also settle the dispute amongst themselves. It's also a very complicated situation, the details of which would likely define the statute of limitations.    Why do you think they are all illegitimate?  They were acquired under a corrupt, unjust system.  Therefore they have no ethical basis.   I'm torn. I like to upvote the threads on here that generate hearty discussion, but most of the time that results in me upvoting troll threads. *sigh*.  [Rothbard to the rescue!](http://mises.org/rothbard/ethics/ten.asp) &amp;gt;It is of course possible that the previously owned land has been abandoned; but the newcomer must not assume blithely that land which has obviously been transformed by man is no longer owned by anyone. He must take steps to find out if his new title to the land is clear, as we have seen is in fact done in the title-search business.

So if a slice of property has ever been owned by anyone, it can never be homesteaded?  And without taxes to set a condition for ownership or eminent domain to seize it for public good... Yep, if you're not already rich, you're fucked.

&amp;gt;Just as the original Jones was a continuing aggressor against the original Smith, so the modern peasants are being aggressed against by the modern holder of the Jones-derived land title. In this case of what we might call &#8220;feudalism&#8221; or &#8220;land monopoly,&#8221; the feudal or monopolist landlords have no legitimate claim to the property. The current &#8220;tenants,&#8221; or peasants, should be the absolute owners of their property, and, as in the case of slavery, the land titles should be transferred to the peasants, without compensation to the monopoly landlords.

Sounds good to me.  Practically all current property ownership is the result of a great crime- whether because an ancestor was tricked by a bank, intimidated by hired thugs, robbed through taxation, or deprived of opportunities by manipulation of the market by the State.

In fact, if feudalism was illegitimate, and I should think mercantilism for a similar reason (for example the State-forced driving of the English peasants from the villages and into the factory slums, or the mass robbery of the imperialist era), and if we have the right to take the fruits of that crime, then essentially *all* modern wealth and property rightly belongs to the descendants of the people who were disenfranchised; namely, the global proletariat.

Thanks, Rothbard!  I never knew you were a revolutionary anarcho-syndicalist! &amp;gt;And without taxes to set a condition for ownership or eminent domain to seize it for public good... Yep, if you're not already rich, you're fucked.

You think eminent domain is used against the rich *and* for the public good?

&amp;gt;Yep, if you're not already rich, you're fucked.

Cause that's the way markets work.

&amp;gt;...then essentially all modern wealth and property rightly belongs to the descendants of the people who were disenfranchised; namely, the global proletariat.

"The global proletariat" is not a person. Like all crimes, you need specific victims and specific violators.

Also, somethings telling me you came here to start a fight rather than try and find out what others opinions are on things or to seek clarity... &amp;gt;You think eminent domain is used against the rich and for the public good?

Hey, at least it would be a theoretical solution.  As it is, you guys would apparently have no problem with an intractable landed aristocracy.

&amp;gt;Cause that's the way markets work.

Yes, I think that's basically my argument.

&amp;gt;"The global proletariat" is not a person. Like all crimes, you need specific victims and specific violators.

Of course, because that ensures that restitution is impossible: Your true goal. &amp;gt;Hey, at least it would be a theoretical solution.

So basically no then.

&amp;gt;Yes, I think that's basically my argument.

Ha, good answer! Wrong, but clever.

&amp;gt;Of course, because that ensures that restitution is impossible: Your true goal.

If it was anything other than what I described, it wouldn't be restitution. With restitution, the transgressor restores to the victim. The transgressor is the capitalist class.  The victim is the proletariat.  I don't see what's complicated about this.  As I said in my OP, all wealth and property is tainted by theft.  Therefore the only just solution is some kind of redistribution.  I mean, if you guys are serious about "anarcho"-capitalism.</snippet></document><document><title>NDAA Alert for Arizona, Legislation introduced to prohibit and arrest Feds for NDAA</title><url>http://livingnotsurviving.com/2013/02/04/ndaa-nullification-alert-for-arizona/</url><snippet>  you can't vote away tyranny. Threatening to arrest them and throw them in jail is a decent start. I'm suspecting you were being sarcastic, but in case you weren't, thats just turning the tables. The solution to the problem is a separation from them, not a tyrannical system with us at the top. &amp;gt;is a separation from them, not a tyrranical system with us at the top

That doesn't put us at the top.  It's a wholly decentralizing act. I don't understand. Objectively speaking, what is the difference between them putting us in jail and us putting them in jail? Such an equivocation could only occur through muddled reasoning; one is in pursuit of self-defense, the other in pursuit of assault.

The punishments need not also be equal, too; what matters is merely neutralizing outside aggression in the most efficient manner. I think you're conflating self-defense with retribution. Punishing politicians for acts they performed in the past is retribution and technically not self-defense. Threatening to arrest them and throw them in jail is a decent start. Threatening to arrest them and throw them in jail is a decent start.   Isn't this very similar to FEMA and REX 84? </snippet></document><document><title>Giving Away Money Costs More Than You Think - The Folly of Rent Seeking</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XwBP_pqkGJA</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Why isn't their mediation ala Anarcho-capitalistic dogma in black markets?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17vij1/why_isnt_their_mediation_ala_anarchocapitalistic/</url><snippet>It seems like a voluntary and self organizing system of dispute resolution would occur in instances where one couldn't use current legal channels. Instead what we see, in the case of drug trafficking, is violence to resolve disputes, theft, etc.

Is this an information flow problem (as individuals have to stay hidden) or a flaw in ancap train of thought. 

I personally was leaning towards it being an information problem but was also considering the fact that so much relies on reputation in black market transactions. So I am at a loss.  The Silk Road,  a website that sells illicit drugs, uses mediation very successfully. And yes, it is anarchist in nature (but I'm not sure which flavor of anarchism). The Silk Road's success probably is owed to the establishment of a pseudonymous reputation system. Sellers can build their reputation within the context of that particular market without having to link that reputation to their meatspace identity. The Silk Road,  a website that sells illicit drugs, uses mediation very successfully. And yes, it is anarchist in nature (but I'm not sure which flavor of anarchism).  I think you are right. Voluntary dispute resolution is very dependent on reputation.  Reputation is dependent on being widely know (at least to your customer base).  The black market has be very secretive to avoid the authorities so I suspect this hampers dispute resolution.  Also, the black market often attracts people that are, willing to take risks, and more readily use violence. Most people in the black market know eachother and have relationships (either negative or positive).  That is why violence appears in the first place.  Also, why can't the ancap market attract violent, power hungry leaders like the black market does?  Because the state actively blocks any form of peaceful mediation from occurring and then comes in to "save the day" from the "violent gangsters". how specifically? Usually with a gun barrel and a series of cages. dont forget the costumes. and the rape and the slavery. Sounds like a good weekend. how specifically? how specifically?  One of the services of the Mafia is brokering deals, *for a favor* (laundering money, etc), or a fee of some kind, flat or percentage.

So if I was a grocer who didn't want to pay taxes on the produce that I stock on my shelves, I could approach the leader of the local mafia clan, and they would know a farmer who was likewise looking to avoid paying taxes on the produce they sell. No one cheats, i.e. the farmer exchanges only his most rotten or low grade fruit, because no one cheats someone protected by the mafia. Everyone benefits.

It should come as no great surprise that brokering such an exchange is also very illegal. Sometimes I wish I had a local mafia instead of a local government. You do.  That's what government is.   The mafia at least has the reputation it deserves. One of the rules of the mafia is to never appropriate funds that do not belong to you. The Don isn't the Don for very long, especially if they would leave their successor with unpaid debts. And never steal from the family, or anyone in general, because it's bad business. That's how you lose turf, and gain stoolies.

It's disrespectful to compare the mafia with a government. "or anyone in general"

Um, pretty sure the mafia is responsible for all kinds of thefts. "or anyone in general"

Um, pretty sure the mafia is responsible for all kinds of thefts.   Can you imagine how nice it would be for cops to sit outside there waiting for the criminals?      Mediation requires a desire on the part of both parties to settle the matter peacefully. The black market is filled with people who are already willing to break the law and may have no qualms with using violence to solve disputes. Peaceful people are unlikely to become sellers in the black market to begin with. Also, like someone else mentioned, it's hard for a reputation-based system to work in an underground market where vendors are trying to remain as anonymous as possible.        **SHORT VIDEOS -- Black Markets, Prohibition and Crime**

______________________________________________


[First 15 Minutes: Why the Government Does Not Own You](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-EIBCXwQ6QE#t=04m06s)

[Robert Murphy: Black Markets/Mafia vs. Government](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XSeYEz67Se4#t=57m20s)

[Robert Murphy on Voluntary Associations vs. Coercive Monopolies](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XSeYEz67Se4#t=33m35s)

**ESSENTIAL articles on private courts and defense - Osterfeld and Long**

[LINK](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/108yif/two_mindblowing_essential_articles_on_private/)

________________________________________
[Learn Liberty:What You Should Know About Drug Prohibition](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kSXKHLkK4jI)

[Stefan Molyneux: Organized Crime vs. Government](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ztzv_MyKB24#t=19m20s)
________________________________________
[Top 10 Reasons Why the Mafia is Better than the State](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IErlI34-0so)
_____________________________________________

[Thread: What would happen to criminal organizations in an AnCap society?](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/vqmxq/what_would_happen_to_criminal_organizations_in_an/)

Drug wars are a result of.. well, the War on Some Drugs. Competitors in the drug market cannot resort to any kind of legal means to solve disputes over property, so they must resort to secret violence and fraud.

People only tolerate the violence of drug gangs because the State makes it impossible for a peaceful free market alternative to exist.

Drug wars exist now because of the immense profits to be made in drug trafficking. Those profits are ONLY possible because drugs are illegal and the large legitimate producers of pharmaceuticals aren't allowed to come up with incredibly cheap versions of those drugs and market them. The supply is artificially reduced, and the supply that is available is far more dangerous to produce. It creates a situation where only criminals are producing and are making very large % profits. Those large profits make it valuable for them to use force to eliminate competition, etc. Alcohol is a perfect example of this principle. 

During prohibition, large criminal organizations formed around the supply and distribution of alcohol. It was perfect. Alcohol is quite addictive, the market for it is huge, and when it was made illegal its supply was artificially contracted to drive up the price and profits of those still willing to sell it, ie the criminals. Now look at today, there are no criminal gangs involved in the sale of alcohol. Why? 

Because like every other commodity the price and profits seek a level where violence is too expensive to employ, both in the resources used and in the reputation hit such a company would take. No one would buy more expensive stuff from the criminals when there's a legitimate dealer right around the corner.</snippet></document><document><title>Hurricane Sandy and Black Markets: Peter C. Earle Interviewed by Jeffrey Tucker</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=USG7j8bP_l4</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>A new poll finds that, for the first time ever, most Americans (53%) see government as a threat to their rights. (x-post r/politics)</title><url>http://www.politico.com/story/2013/01/poll-government-threatens-rights-86997.html#.UQ9nzU7JgJg.reddit</url><snippet>  I wonder how many of those people see the welfare state as part of their "rights"? </snippet></document><document><title>Drug Dealers Admit Berkeley PD Have Asked Them To Assault Cop-watchers</title><url>http://www.indybay.org/newsitems/2013/02/03/18731288.php</url><snippet>   This is why we need competing security officers. If one group won't protect you, another will.  free-market law enforcement. isn't that what we have now? just with one big monopolistic agency that now seems to outsource their beatings to local drug dealers.
bootstraps, people.
   Silver lining: If the cops aren't there to defend the cop watchers while the dealers beat/kill them, then they're also not there to enforce the gun laws preventing these fine folks from defending themselves against said drug dealers. Silver lining: If the cops aren't there to defend the cop watchers while the dealers beat/kill them, then they're also not there to enforce the gun laws preventing these fine folks from defending themselves against said drug dealers.</snippet></document><document><title>Economic forecasts no better than a random walk</title><url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2013-02-04/economic-forecasts-no-better-than-a-random-walk/4499098</url><snippet>  Humans and the future, unpredictable? No I don't think so, we obviously just need to refine our formulas.... We just need more assumptions, that's all. We should make them more abstract too. Our focus on the real world is holding us back.  What will the price of oil be in 5 minutes? If you can't answer this question, you can't tell me what will happen to the entire economy in 6 months. Same price as it currently is, give or take a few cents per litre.  so is it the give, or the take that will win out?  But we should totally base govt policy on their predictions. Policy isn't based on prediction, it's based on macro and micro economic theory. Campaigning, advertising, and fear mongering is based on prediction. Policy is based on which group gives the politicians more money or votes.</snippet></document><document><title>
No Way Out: Crime, Punishment &amp;amp; the Capitalization of Power -- by Jonathan Nitzan
</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJ_4QqdHPtY</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Alertness Against Leviathan - Criticize by Creating</title><url>http://www.fee.org/the_freeman/detail/alertness-against-leviathan#axzz2Jw3dn1dX</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>We need to get these weapons of war off our streets!! Fear mongering sells.</title><url>https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;ved=0CDgQqQIwAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.usatoday.com%2Fvideos%2Fnews%2Fnation%2F2013%2F02%2F04%2Fobama-weapons-of-war-have-no-place-on-our-streets%2F1891313%2F&amp;amp;ei=VSkQUZCvK8b-2QXE9IDIAg&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNE6TTY9zamn1zp5G9KL-O-OAh5mqQ&amp;amp;sig2=mZ36eO_YQaVOdHqVl2AKFw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.41867550,d.b2I</url><snippet>   The proper place for weapons of war are *other* people's streets.    Please dont post link where you have to click the ''back'' button 50 times to get back... I hate being trap like that. </snippet></document><document><title>Can Seasteads really escape the jurisdiction of the American court system? A neat little series about how to minimize the influence of American politicians and judges on future seasteads.  </title><url>http://www.seasteading.org/2012/05/can-seasteads-ever-truly-escape-the-american-court-syste/</url><snippet>  Nowhere on earth are you safe from the US government. [deleted]   I honestly think any successful seastead will need a nuclear deterrent. </snippet></document><document><title>So Krugman saw Hoppe's video and in fact he did have no response about printing money. </title><url>http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/02/03/despicable-me/</url><snippet>   To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run. I think Hoppe's point can be used thusly.

*Curious onlooker*: "How does fiat make society wealthier? If fiat qua fiat was a source of wealth, why isn't the entire globe covered in people who live with the top living standards?"

*Kruggy*: "Stimulating V leads to increased aggregate spending. That means total income increases and then so does the incentive for people to produce and social wealth follows. Y = C + I + G + NX"

*Onlooker*: "What of the effects of an increased supply of fiat?"

*Kruggy*: "Inflation combats the paradox of thrift."

*Onlooker*: "Savings are a problem? Don't prices reflect subjective consensuses necessary to clear a given stock of goods?"

*Kruggy*: *Coughing into his hand, struggling to remember basic subjectivist economics.* "Aha! Yes, but Y = C + I + G + NX. Investment increases wealth. Savings do not."

*Onlooker*: "Savings are reserve holdings and are a basic necessity for any complex economic transactions whatever simply because not all transactions can be based on credit. It is true that they do not increase wealth, but a 10% reserve demand for money means that purchasing power increases by a commensurate amount. How is this a problem?"

*Kruggy*: "We measure wealth via the proxy of aggregate income. The only way to elevate aggregate income is by stimulating aggregate demand because exports and investment are too complex to affect with simple policies (I don't know if he would say this - but if he would, he would strike at a kernel of truth!). We then realize the best way to achieve that is to increase government spending by combined tax increases and an increase in the monetary base."

*Onlooker*: "So the problem is in how wealth is measured by the proxy of GDP? Basically, you're using monetary values to attempt to determine real wealth. Savings decrease the absolute number of monetary units rotating through exchange, but preserve the relative value. Inflation then distorts individual behavior by increasing time preference. The temporal dislocation of purchasing power means that real interest rates are higher than the nominal rates. And of course, the only way to increase growth is to lengthen production structures, which require low time preference."

The only response Kruggy could make is, "Welp, look at this GDP growth function with respect to time." Basically, that's self-referencing shit. If we've shown that GDP is flawed precisely because monetary manipulation can game the stat, then we've shown that any "empirical study" which relies solely upon that as a determinant or indicator of production is at best tenuous. GDP is only a very rough measure of economic output. If I recall correctly, business investment is below its 2008 peak while consumption spending and government spending are both above that 2008 level. I'm not saying that GDP is useless - far from it. If you can offset this monetary confusion somewhat, then you can derive a more accurate picture. Pretty interesting that the information I've seen indicates that median US income has declined below 2004 levels, adjusted for inflation. (Comparisons of 2011 and 2004 median income adjusted for CPI show no real growth whatsoever. Since the CPI chronically understates inflation, clearly there has been a real decline.) I think Hoppe's point can be used thusly.

*Curious onlooker*: "How does fiat make society wealthier? If fiat qua fiat was a source of wealth, why isn't the entire globe covered in people who live with the top living standards?"

*Kruggy*: "Stimulating V leads to increased aggregate spending. That means total income increases and then so does the incentive for people to produce and social wealth follows. Y = C + I + G + NX"

*Onlooker*: "What of the effects of an increased supply of fiat?"

*Kruggy*: "Inflation combats the paradox of thrift."

*Onlooker*: "Savings are a problem? Don't prices reflect subjective consensuses necessary to clear a given stock of goods?"

*Kruggy*: *Coughing into his hand, struggling to remember basic subjectivist economics.* "Aha! Yes, but Y = C + I + G + NX. Investment increases wealth. Savings do not."

*Onlooker*: "Savings are reserve holdings and are a basic necessity for any complex economic transactions whatever simply because not all transactions can be based on credit. It is true that they do not increase wealth, but a 10% reserve demand for money means that purchasing power increases by a commensurate amount. How is this a problem?"

*Kruggy*: "We measure wealth via the proxy of aggregate income. The only way to elevate aggregate income is by stimulating aggregate demand because exports and investment are too complex to affect with simple policies (I don't know if he would say this - but if he would, he would strike at a kernel of truth!). We then realize the best way to achieve that is to increase government spending by combined tax increases and an increase in the monetary base."

*Onlooker*: "So the problem is in how wealth is measured by the proxy of GDP? Basically, you're using monetary values to attempt to determine real wealth. Savings decrease the absolute number of monetary units rotating through exchange, but preserve the relative value. Inflation then distorts individual behavior by increasing time preference. The temporal dislocation of purchasing power means that real interest rates are higher than the nominal rates. And of course, the only way to increase growth is to lengthen production structures, which require low time preference."

The only response Kruggy could make is, "Welp, look at this GDP growth function with respect to time." Basically, that's self-referencing shit. If we've shown that GDP is flawed precisely because monetary manipulation can game the stat, then we've shown that any "empirical study" which relies solely upon that as a determinant or indicator of production is at best tenuous. GDP is only a very rough measure of economic output. If I recall correctly, business investment is below its 2008 peak while consumption spending and government spending are both above that 2008 level. I'm not saying that GDP is useless - far from it. If you can offset this monetary confusion somewhat, then you can derive a more accurate picture. Pretty interesting that the information I've seen indicates that median US income has declined below 2004 levels, adjusted for inflation. (Comparisons of 2011 and 2004 median income adjusted for CPI show no real growth whatsoever. Since the CPI chronically understates inflation, clearly there has been a real decline.) GDP = GDI and GDI includes savings, which are the supply curve for desired investment (not including inventory investment) and government borrowing (which is the deficit). So even according to mainstream economics stimulating spending at the expense of savings is at best a zero-sum game. Yes, but a 20% reserve demand as compared with 10% reserve demand lowers the nominal velocity of all money. Those reserve holdings circulate at a fraction of the mean velocity, hence the total mean lowers. I didn't make up the paradox of thrift - Keynesians did - so I'm not misrepresenting them unless they seriously altered their stances since last I checked. &amp;gt;at a fraction of the mean velocity

As someone formally trained in physics, the physics-envy is mindblowing. I think most economists wanted to be physics majors or engineers, but weren't quite smart enough to actually get the mathematics and the concepts. &amp;gt;at a fraction of the mean velocity

As someone formally trained in physics, the physics-envy is mindblowing. Yes, but a 20% reserve demand as compared with 10% reserve demand lowers the nominal velocity of all money. Those reserve holdings circulate at a fraction of the mean velocity, hence the total mean lowers. I didn't make up the paradox of thrift - Keynesians did - so I'm not misrepresenting them unless they seriously altered their stances since last I checked. To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run. &amp;gt; idle resources 

If certain resources aren't being worked/used, necessarily some other resources *are.* "Stimulating" these resources into use is merely a forced reallocation of efforts from where actors individually would choose to direct them. &amp;gt; idle resources 

If certain resources aren't being worked/used, necessarily some other resources *are.* "Stimulating" these resources into use is merely a forced reallocation of efforts from where actors individually would choose to direct them. Wait, no, that doesn't make sense. If markets are not in equilibrium, it is actually possible to have suboptimal employment of resources. Thus, bringing markets towards equilibrium in such a condition could lead to expansion of the use of resources without having to redirect them from other places necessarily. &amp;gt;  If markets are not in equilibrium, it is actually possible to have suboptimal employment of resources.

Markets are never in equilibrium in the real world. If left unregulated and unhampered, they will employ the resources better than any other means. Commanding the market to behave in a certain way *because you believe you know better than the market what it should be doing* is gross incompetence. To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run. I agree about the Hoppe point, yet Krugman doesn't even make the defense that you do. He literally just misdirects.  I agree about the Hoppe point, yet Krugman doesn't even make the defense that you do. He literally just misdirects.  To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run. Well how does printing money "stimulate idle resources back into productivity"?

This is obviously just a managerial metaphor made to make it *sound* good. ::Enter Keynes' investment and savings "conundrums.":: I know some of the arguments. But Hoppe's point is that Keynesians can't answer these basic fundamental questions. Are some of these what Hoppe asked, why mere printing of money makes a country wealthier?

That was answered as not their position and I've never run into a Keynesian who believed printing money was a path to wealth itself.

What they would say is printing of money, if done 'correctly', may be coincidental to economic growth, but only as a means of stimulating production.

Are there other basic questions you would ask them?

The main problem with debating Keynesians as an Austrian is that Austrians are much more philosophically rich and their points require decent knowledge of epistemology, something hypermathematized schools entirely skip.

Their reasoning is literally: "Hey, the natural sciences use a lot of math.  We want to be a science; thus, it follows we need use a lot of math." &amp;gt;I've never run into a Keynesian who believed printing money was a path to wealth itself.

I've never seen an economic issue come up where the Krugman-ite solution was not to "print money".  Nor has the Fed, headed alternatively by Keynesians or the "free market Keynesians" of the Chicago school, ever decided that the best thing to do in a circumstance was to stop printing money for a while. But, do you not see that they would argue credit expansion is merely coincidental with their goal, a means to that end, not the end in itself? Are some of these what Hoppe asked, why mere printing of money makes a country wealthier?

That was answered as not their position and I've never run into a Keynesian who believed printing money was a path to wealth itself.

What they would say is printing of money, if done 'correctly', may be coincidental to economic growth, but only as a means of stimulating production.

Are there other basic questions you would ask them?

The main problem with debating Keynesians as an Austrian is that Austrians are much more philosophically rich and their points require decent knowledge of epistemology, something hypermathematized schools entirely skip.

Their reasoning is literally: "Hey, the natural sciences use a lot of math.  We want to be a science; thus, it follows we need use a lot of math." &amp;gt; What they would say is printing of money, if done 'correctly', may be coincidental to economic growth, but only as a means of stimulating production.

You're saying here that they believe that printing money CAN (in certain circumstances) make a society richer. By "stimulating production".

Yes, Hoppe was imprecise by implying that Keynesians believe that you can just print money to solve world poverty. But if you watch the whole video he is expanding on a point just made by Joe Salerno, who said that you need to take the Keynesian ideas, like that you can just print money to "jump start" an economy, and explain them in simple language to expose them. Hazlitt style. Check it out.

Agree with the different approaches. This total disrespect to epistemology is just awkward. It definitely works in our favor ultimately, in "lay" debates. Well how does printing money "stimulate idle resources back into productivity"?

This is obviously just a managerial metaphor made to make it *sound* good. To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run. &amp;gt;So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run.

This sounds good in theory, but have you ever had success using that argument against a Keynesian? It feels like talking to a brick wall for all the good it does.

They have an "answer" to everything. Insufficient demand for some mysterious reasons. Paradox of thrift. Market failure. It's like fencing a fart -- you think you scored a hit, but there's nothing but air. To be fair, I didn't think Hoppe had too great of an argument.

I don't know any Keynesians who believe mere printing of money for its own sake makes a society wealthier; I always took their argument that credit expansion stimulated idle resources back into productivity.

So, they can still agree that production is what makes a society wealthier, but that production needs injected demand during certain "self-imposed" market dilemmas.

So, the way to debate them is to show why that's not necessary, why what the market is doing as an aggregation of individual choices is exactly what the solution is, both in the short-run and long-run.  So, Professor Krugman, how does expanding the money supply increase prosperity? Keynesians take the credit for moving forward by withholding the carrot from the horse, just out of reach. The horse is always ignored.  I ventured into the /r/politics thread for this article... I made a huge mistake.  That Hoppe video was just dumb, and a good example of how not to argue. Anyone with basic knowledge about keynesian economics know that monetary expansion doesn't just magically create wealth according to the theory. Is this guy really a professor? That's embarrassing. No Keynesian claims it does 100% of the time, but that is literally what they claim in regards to *some* of the time. Nope. You need to read up on theory. I've read General Theory.

Would you like to explain *why* I am mistaken? That Hoppe video was just dumb, and a good example of how not to argue. Anyone with basic knowledge about keynesian economics know that monetary expansion doesn't just magically create wealth according to the theory. Is this guy really a professor? That's embarrassing. If it doesn't create wealth, what is it a theory for? Not economics, for sure.    You don't need to talk about money printing and imaginary capital creation to refute Krugman, his beard refutes his views, he needs to shave that bitch. His beard is his one redeeming feature. It always reminded me of a lob-sided cat.  Krugman also looks like he could be George Clooneys evil, clever, devious brother.</snippet></document><document><title>Does a Free Market prevent concentration of media ownership?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17vwjr/does_a_free_market_prevent_concentration_of_media/</url><snippet>Right now our media is dominated by oligopolies. Can a free market reduce the power oligopolies have on the media? Has the state helped to support entities like News Corp and CBS?  &amp;gt;Can a free market reduce the power oligopolies have on the media? 

Isn't it already? (the internet) </snippet></document><document><title>/r/AnCap, I wrote you a poem :)</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17tfgi/rancap_i_wrote_you_a_poem/</url><snippet>*Krugman and Bernanke were having dinner one night;*

*Their discussion concerned the unemployed, and their plight.*


*Krugman shouted, &#8220;We aren&#8217;t spending enough, consumption is key!&#8221;*

*Bernanke nodded, but where to get the money? Ah, of course, QE3.*


*Off to the printing press, to print billions more;*

*The FED would buy bonds; GDP would soar.*


*However, months later, things weren&#8217;t going as expected;*

*GDP was up, but confidence down, and the unemployed were basically unaffected.*


*It was times like these, in the dead of night, lying in bed,*

*That the strangest of thoughts crept into Bernanke&#8217;s head.* 


*What if printing was nothing more than a temporary fix?*

*In a single stroke hard earned savings would be utterly nixed.*


*What if buying bonds just made the outlook bleaker?*

*Or worse, created a bubble, whose membrane was getting weaker and weaker&#8230;*


*Bernanke shot up, drenched in a cold sweat.*

*His heart was racing, his underpants wet.*


*In times like these only one thing could calm him, put him at ease;*

*He looked out the window, put on his coat, grabbed his keys...* 


*His neighbors often report the strangest of sights;*

*A panicked old man unlocking his shed in the dead of night.*


*What&#8217;s in the shed no one&#8217;s quite sure, but many rumors have been told.*

*Most witnesses swear to seeing a man fondling bars of pure gold.*
         reading this with the Cat In The Hat's voice (I have 3 little kids..) didn't quite fit, but I couldn't help it....   This is awesome:

next step: make a rap video and start a an-cap band     You are a faggot, OP. You are a faggot, OP.</snippet></document><document><title>This terrifies me to no end</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IHgYPDvQFU8&amp;amp;feature=related</url><snippet>   It must be no interesting to work for an intelligence agency. Probably there's a risk of ending up "knowing too much", but oh boy would it be nice to work with people who see reality for what it is and have access to all the dirt files. It must be no interesting to work for an intelligence agency. Probably there's a risk of ending up "knowing too much", but oh boy would it be nice to work with people who see reality for what it is and have access to all the dirt files. Do you think there is communist propaganda lying around on the internet indoctrinating people without them even knowing it?   Well, assuming that this is true, it only proves that propaganda works, or rather that a small group of people, if motivated and persistent, can, in due time, change the political discourse in their favor. Of course, the KGB was a formidable force, but it was still much, much smaller (if more focused) than the liberty movement is today. What I'm trying to say is that this can go in "our" favor as well. It may take 20 years, but if we keep pushing the discourse to non-violence, self-ownership and personal liberty, things WILL start to change for the better. Well, assuming that this is true, it only proves that propaganda works, or rather that a small group of people, if motivated and persistent, can, in due time, change the political discourse in their favor. Of course, the KGB was a formidable force, but it was still much, much smaller (if more focused) than the liberty movement is today. What I'm trying to say is that this can go in "our" favor as well. It may take 20 years, but if we keep pushing the discourse to non-violence, self-ownership and personal liberty, things WILL start to change for the better.  [This video](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dE38dLxapVo) should cure a couple of leftists  </snippet></document><document><title>The disconnect between the "Right to choose" and self-ownership. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17vnx8/the_disconnect_between_the_right_to_choose_and/</url><snippet>The main argument in favor of abortion is that a woman has a right to make decisions about her body. For those who agree with that premise, why can't or don't they then extend that reasoning to other choices, such as drugs, helmet laws, and gambling? And for us, should making that connection be a compelling segue into discussing AnCap philosophy? As a rhetorical strategy I mean?

(This post is **NOT** about the arguments for or against abortion. Please let's not go there).     Pure speculation here, but I think part of it has to do with the load on the state. They're for safety laws because if the state has to pay for your healthcare (such as a single payer system), they have a large incentive to keep your from hurting yourself. Also, the less unwanted children that come about, the less stress on the welfare system.    I always thought you could make a business selling aborted cow fetuses as a humane source of meat since they aren't real animals yet just collections of cells. Plus the probably taste better than veal.</snippet></document><document><title>Suggestions for a reading list</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17vkjy/suggestions_for_a_reading_list/</url><snippet>I've seen a couple of threads asking people for their recommendations for a reading list so that they could further their understanding of anarcho-capitalism. This is pretty much the same except I would like a reading list that the other side would use. Preferably nothing too dense or difficult for someone who is just starting to read this sort of material.

tl;dr-What are some statism 101 and an-com 101 books to read?  There is a subreddit dedicated to this:
[r/AnCapVexationClub](http://www.reddit.com/r/AnCapVexationClub/)  Joke response:

History and government textbooks used in public schools.      </snippet></document><document><title>Gonna get downvoted, but genuinely want to see where I'm wrong.  I don't understand the most basic justifications of capitalism, and wiki doesn't help.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17tiz4/gonna_get_downvoted_but_genuinely_want_to_see/</url><snippet>OK, help me out here.  I want to understand capitalism from base principals.  ~~By what natural right does one claim property?~~  We own things by having the most justifiable claim to them, by reshaping them and working on them, and it is, I think, objectionable to work or change something someone else has already made theirs, unless they abandon it.  ~~Right now, I know, it's because we pay for it and have presumably done some service that justifies it, but the system is already in place.  The companies already have billions, the property deeds have already been doled out, and ownership is entrenched.~~  I want to understand this from the very basics.  So:

Suppose that tomorrow, out of nowhere, we can travel to other planets and bring arbitrarily large amounts of hardware with us to mine/build upon/exploit these planets.  ~~I know this is unrealistic but my question is who, and by what natural right, do they lay claim to anything out there?~~  Not to sound petty, but first come, first serve.  In an ideal, prosperous civilization, people would work to be granted someone else's property, or else make use of abandoned property, or else go and find their own.  ~~With property in the United States, the government claimed right to it first~~, by no right except the permissiveness of the people ... mistakes were made, but we've never been perfect ~~then sold it, then protected what they sold.  Obviously, the US government cannot control space.  So what if I claim a whole planet?  What if I claim just the area my factory sits on?  What if my competitor takes over the resources I claimed out of the blue?  Why can I not claim the whole universe apart from the Earth as mine right now?~~  They can't, everyone would laugh at this just as they would today, and make use of these resources as they were able.

~~The whole concept of "property" seems very flimsy to me.~~  *It seems very difficult to enforce, because on one hand, I am being answered that the state and its powerful courts could not exist, and on the other, that people would not give up their lives for companies under an anacap civilization, putting an absolute ceiling on retribution or ability to stop someone else from simply taking a resource out from under you as best they could and two parties basically resigned to calling each other assholes and trying to get public opinion on their side.*   It ~~ironically, despite your protests~~, virtually REQUIRES government enforcement *for maximum efficiency*, otherwise larger companies with greater resources could destroy their competition however they liked, *though not resorting to murder, destruction*.  ~~They could collude into price fixing~~. If any non-monopoly remains, though, they can profit massively by undercutting the status quo.  *I do still worry that hyper-powerful companies without oversight and regulation could abuse the general population once they have the money to afford "armies" and "protection" not beholden to any law but the promise of wealth.

~~I agree with you right now that the government is the greater evil, as they act with whole righteous authority to take what they want, arrest who they want, kill who they wants, war with who they want, grant monopolies to the businesses they want, subsidize them (whether they're good "investments" or not).  Businesses do not have this kind of power, but in an anacap system they would have even more power, being the only means of production of goods and able to afford violence, coercion, protection, etc.~~  The snarky answer was on the money, here:  if we can break our government of its terrible holds on us, we shouldn't be subservient to companies that emulate it, either.

So work me through the first principles, the right to claim anything as solely your own.

***Edited: Anything I haven't struck through is updated opinion on the matter.  Thanks guys!  Learning a lot.***  Also I think I've made this post mostly unreadable but hopefully anybody just clicking will see the strikeouts and comments and put 2 and 2 together.  You're talking about two different things 

1. Moral justification for property ownership. 
2. The ramifications of market anarchy. 

Many here would argue that the justification for property ownership comes from self-ownership. Noone else has a better claim to my body than I do, it's not morally right for you to take my liver. When I eat something it becomes a part of me. When I produce something I have the greatest claim to the thing that I produced. When I mix my labor with land, as per the Lockean theory of property, I have the greatest claim to that land. 

I respect this view, but for me and many other an-caps natural rights simply do not exist. There are no such thing as rights, positive or negative other than what society will allow. 

quoting me. 

&amp;gt; "The law" the guiding force in society is illusory. We think of society's laws as being homogeneous because we live in under the watchful eye of the monolith, the state. In truth laws and rights are a temporal, geographical, social phenomenon, property is not a natural right and neither is a living wage. It's up to society and the individuals within that society to choose which rights laws they will support and which they won't.
&amp;gt;To my mind the law that resolves disputes, in the absence of the state, would reflect the changing social norms of the populace that it served. If the social norm was that property is a valid construct then the law and local method of legal enforcement would reflect that. In some regions people would say that one has the strongest right to the things that they own by way of production and trade and would support a dispute resolution system that upheld that right. In others people would say that property is theft and the people would socially own the means of production. Stateless peoples would be able to move and define their regional dispute resolution system as they wished. In this manner these systems would optimize and self-improve. Free peoples observing productive systems in which the people living within them were happy would support dispute resolution among their peers modeled after or improving upon those systems.

Therefore, as an an-cap, I think property should be valid, I support a certain set of guide lines surrounding the validity of property, I support a dispute resolution system that follows those guidelines. If the an-coms are happier, I change my mind and go live with them. 

In terms of the ramifications of market anarchy the things you described are functinons of the state. If society were able to cast off the hegemonic force of the state it would continue to do so with corporations acting as states.  &amp;gt; If the an-coms are happier, I change my mind and go live with them.

What do you mean by "happier"? What if they are raping babies every night but they look really happy doing so? Or do you take the misery of the babies into account as well and come up with some sort of grisly calculus?

Either way, I'm no utilitarian. I would prefer a just system over a "happy" system. &amp;gt; If the an-coms are happier, I change my mind and go live with them.

What do you mean by "happier"? What if they are raping babies every night but they look really happy doing so? Or do you take the misery of the babies into account as well and come up with some sort of grisly calculus?

Either way, I'm no utilitarian. I would prefer a just system over a "happy" system. You're talking about two different things 

1. Moral justification for property ownership. 
2. The ramifications of market anarchy. 

Many here would argue that the justification for property ownership comes from self-ownership. Noone else has a better claim to my body than I do, it's not morally right for you to take my liver. When I eat something it becomes a part of me. When I produce something I have the greatest claim to the thing that I produced. When I mix my labor with land, as per the Lockean theory of property, I have the greatest claim to that land. 

I respect this view, but for me and many other an-caps natural rights simply do not exist. There are no such thing as rights, positive or negative other than what society will allow. 

quoting me. 

&amp;gt; "The law" the guiding force in society is illusory. We think of society's laws as being homogeneous because we live in under the watchful eye of the monolith, the state. In truth laws and rights are a temporal, geographical, social phenomenon, property is not a natural right and neither is a living wage. It's up to society and the individuals within that society to choose which rights laws they will support and which they won't.
&amp;gt;To my mind the law that resolves disputes, in the absence of the state, would reflect the changing social norms of the populace that it served. If the social norm was that property is a valid construct then the law and local method of legal enforcement would reflect that. In some regions people would say that one has the strongest right to the things that they own by way of production and trade and would support a dispute resolution system that upheld that right. In others people would say that property is theft and the people would socially own the means of production. Stateless peoples would be able to move and define their regional dispute resolution system as they wished. In this manner these systems would optimize and self-improve. Free peoples observing productive systems in which the people living within them were happy would support dispute resolution among their peers modeled after or improving upon those systems.

Therefore, as an an-cap, I think property should be valid, I support a certain set of guide lines surrounding the validity of property, I support a dispute resolution system that follows those guidelines. If the an-coms are happier, I change my mind and go live with them. 

In terms of the ramifications of market anarchy the things you described are functinons of the state. If society were able to cast off the hegemonic force of the state it would continue to do so with corporations acting as states.  I don't think the social norms regarding dispute resolution are "designed" by some territorial community. I think it's making the same mistake as saying that laws must be homogeneous in an area.

I'd expect it to be emergent from precisely the resolution to people's disagreements as to what should be lawful and what not. The best compromises win and become the norm.   "gonna get downvoted"

who do you think we are? One can conclude that Anarcho-Capitalism is correct simply by observing the difference between us and /r/anarchism.  "gonna get downvoted"

who do you think we are?   Well done for thinking about the justification for property explicitly. I guess you have reached the point where some initial anarchocapitalists realized they were actually mutualists.

I am a proponent of Lockean homesteading, that is: mixing your labour with the land gives a right to property.  But, influenced by Proudhon (and common law), not *nudo animo*, by intent alone, in infinity; If you leave it useless for decades after your initial investment, don't be surprised if someone is squatting on 'your' property.

&amp;gt; So what if I claim a whole planet? Why can I not claim the whole universe apart from the Earth as mine right now?

Because in these cases, it'd be very hard to show in court that you are using the whole planet or the universe in a beneficial way (assuming you're not actually plowing, or building on, the whole planet)

&amp;gt; What if I claim just the area my factory sits on? What if my competitor takes over the resources I claimed out of the blue? 

This would be a reasonable claim. If your competitor takes over your factory, you would have a right to reclaim damages from them for their agression against your property.

&amp;gt;[this requires government] otherwise larger companies with greater resources could destroy their competition however they liked [once they have the money to afford armies]

You believe a central army, i.e. government, will be more efficient and better than a protection company that you could hire which could not depend on a tax base, and hence has to be more efficient than its competitor. I don't.

Yes, companies can collude into price fixing. However, such cartels are either providing a good enough service that people prefer them over their competition, or there is enough incentive for one of the members to break the collusion and start selling cheaper.

 Thank you, what you've said makes a lot of sense, but a few things...

&amp;gt; Because in these cases, it'd be very hard to show in court that you are using the whole planet or the universe in a beneficial way (assuming you're not actually plowing, or building on, the whole planet)

This relies on the existence of courts powerful enough to enforce their judgements, presumably run by some extremely powerful third party with no vested interests in who wins or loses a settlement (which isn't always the case, even with government, but seems much more likely to be the case if a conglomeration of companies is the "court").

&amp;gt; This would be a reasonable claim. If your competitor takes over your factory, you would have a right to reclaim damages from them for their agression against your property.

Without a powerful interdicting party, this becomes "eye for an eye", even "our competitors have wronged us and will again at the next opportunity, we need to unmake that in the quickest, most economic way possible.  C4 their headquarters and murder all their researchers."

I don't want to sound like a bad dystopian novel, but there's a lot of science fiction written about boundless corporate states, where workers have to live under constant surveillance in company dormitories to avoid their capture or worse, where companies fight freely and openly, if only in border skirmish wars at the far bounds of society.  But they toy with people's lives in ways those people probably don't expect when they sign the dotted line.  

And while people should have things like oaths and loyalty to word and willingness to work and to work together, and I love serving a function and earning money for doing it, there's a difference between the system I work under, enforced by the government, and the system where a black man in Africa puts his mark on a piece of paper he can't read and has everything taken from him.  Which was also allowed by the governments at the time, but I cannot imagine a world without restriction on contracts, wages, rules regarding work, I fear it would quickly deteriorate into a nightmare.

&amp;gt; You believe a central army, i.e. government, will be more efficient and better than a protection company that you could hire which could not depend on a tax base, and hence has to be more efficient than its competitor. I don't.

Yes, I do believe that.  The only comparisons of "armies" that I have to go on here are the various democratic armies of the Earth versus those in Africa beholden to warlords who have made their money, have the laborers, and are only interested in stiffling competition.

That said, I'm not trying to turn this into a broader discussion about everything that even slightly rubs me wrong about capitalism and governments (in an ideal world, I prefer anarchy, I can take care of myself and mean no harm), just addressing the concept of ownership, or, at the moment, how it is enforced. Thank you, what you've said makes a lot of sense, but a few things...

&amp;gt; Because in these cases, it'd be very hard to show in court that you are using the whole planet or the universe in a beneficial way (assuming you're not actually plowing, or building on, the whole planet)

This relies on the existence of courts powerful enough to enforce their judgements, presumably run by some extremely powerful third party with no vested interests in who wins or loses a settlement (which isn't always the case, even with government, but seems much more likely to be the case if a conglomeration of companies is the "court").

&amp;gt; This would be a reasonable claim. If your competitor takes over your factory, you would have a right to reclaim damages from them for their agression against your property.

Without a powerful interdicting party, this becomes "eye for an eye", even "our competitors have wronged us and will again at the next opportunity, we need to unmake that in the quickest, most economic way possible.  C4 their headquarters and murder all their researchers."

I don't want to sound like a bad dystopian novel, but there's a lot of science fiction written about boundless corporate states, where workers have to live under constant surveillance in company dormitories to avoid their capture or worse, where companies fight freely and openly, if only in border skirmish wars at the far bounds of society.  But they toy with people's lives in ways those people probably don't expect when they sign the dotted line.  

And while people should have things like oaths and loyalty to word and willingness to work and to work together, and I love serving a function and earning money for doing it, there's a difference between the system I work under, enforced by the government, and the system where a black man in Africa puts his mark on a piece of paper he can't read and has everything taken from him.  Which was also allowed by the governments at the time, but I cannot imagine a world without restriction on contracts, wages, rules regarding work, I fear it would quickly deteriorate into a nightmare.

&amp;gt; You believe a central army, i.e. government, will be more efficient and better than a protection company that you could hire which could not depend on a tax base, and hence has to be more efficient than its competitor. I don't.

Yes, I do believe that.  The only comparisons of "armies" that I have to go on here are the various democratic armies of the Earth versus those in Africa beholden to warlords who have made their money, have the laborers, and are only interested in stiffling competition.

That said, I'm not trying to turn this into a broader discussion about everything that even slightly rubs me wrong about capitalism and governments (in an ideal world, I prefer anarchy, I can take care of myself and mean no harm), just addressing the concept of ownership, or, at the moment, how it is enforced. Thank you, what you've said makes a lot of sense, but a few things...

&amp;gt; Because in these cases, it'd be very hard to show in court that you are using the whole planet or the universe in a beneficial way (assuming you're not actually plowing, or building on, the whole planet)

This relies on the existence of courts powerful enough to enforce their judgements, presumably run by some extremely powerful third party with no vested interests in who wins or loses a settlement (which isn't always the case, even with government, but seems much more likely to be the case if a conglomeration of companies is the "court").

&amp;gt; This would be a reasonable claim. If your competitor takes over your factory, you would have a right to reclaim damages from them for their agression against your property.

Without a powerful interdicting party, this becomes "eye for an eye", even "our competitors have wronged us and will again at the next opportunity, we need to unmake that in the quickest, most economic way possible.  C4 their headquarters and murder all their researchers."

I don't want to sound like a bad dystopian novel, but there's a lot of science fiction written about boundless corporate states, where workers have to live under constant surveillance in company dormitories to avoid their capture or worse, where companies fight freely and openly, if only in border skirmish wars at the far bounds of society.  But they toy with people's lives in ways those people probably don't expect when they sign the dotted line.  

And while people should have things like oaths and loyalty to word and willingness to work and to work together, and I love serving a function and earning money for doing it, there's a difference between the system I work under, enforced by the government, and the system where a black man in Africa puts his mark on a piece of paper he can't read and has everything taken from him.  Which was also allowed by the governments at the time, but I cannot imagine a world without restriction on contracts, wages, rules regarding work, I fear it would quickly deteriorate into a nightmare.

&amp;gt; You believe a central army, i.e. government, will be more efficient and better than a protection company that you could hire which could not depend on a tax base, and hence has to be more efficient than its competitor. I don't.

Yes, I do believe that.  The only comparisons of "armies" that I have to go on here are the various democratic armies of the Earth versus those in Africa beholden to warlords who have made their money, have the laborers, and are only interested in stiffling competition.

That said, I'm not trying to turn this into a broader discussion about everything that even slightly rubs me wrong about capitalism and governments (in an ideal world, I prefer anarchy, I can take care of myself and mean no harm), just addressing the concept of ownership, or, at the moment, how it is enforced. Thank you, what you've said makes a lot of sense, but a few things...

&amp;gt; Because in these cases, it'd be very hard to show in court that you are using the whole planet or the universe in a beneficial way (assuming you're not actually plowing, or building on, the whole planet)

This relies on the existence of courts powerful enough to enforce their judgements, presumably run by some extremely powerful third party with no vested interests in who wins or loses a settlement (which isn't always the case, even with government, but seems much more likely to be the case if a conglomeration of companies is the "court").

&amp;gt; This would be a reasonable claim. If your competitor takes over your factory, you would have a right to reclaim damages from them for their agression against your property.

Without a powerful interdicting party, this becomes "eye for an eye", even "our competitors have wronged us and will again at the next opportunity, we need to unmake that in the quickest, most economic way possible.  C4 their headquarters and murder all their researchers."

I don't want to sound like a bad dystopian novel, but there's a lot of science fiction written about boundless corporate states, where workers have to live under constant surveillance in company dormitories to avoid their capture or worse, where companies fight freely and openly, if only in border skirmish wars at the far bounds of society.  But they toy with people's lives in ways those people probably don't expect when they sign the dotted line.  

And while people should have things like oaths and loyalty to word and willingness to work and to work together, and I love serving a function and earning money for doing it, there's a difference between the system I work under, enforced by the government, and the system where a black man in Africa puts his mark on a piece of paper he can't read and has everything taken from him.  Which was also allowed by the governments at the time, but I cannot imagine a world without restriction on contracts, wages, rules regarding work, I fear it would quickly deteriorate into a nightmare.

&amp;gt; You believe a central army, i.e. government, will be more efficient and better than a protection company that you could hire which could not depend on a tax base, and hence has to be more efficient than its competitor. I don't.

Yes, I do believe that.  The only comparisons of "armies" that I have to go on here are the various democratic armies of the Earth versus those in Africa beholden to warlords who have made their money, have the laborers, and are only interested in stiffling competition.

That said, I'm not trying to turn this into a broader discussion about everything that even slightly rubs me wrong about capitalism and governments (in an ideal world, I prefer anarchy, I can take care of myself and mean no harm), just addressing the concept of ownership, or, at the moment, how it is enforced.   Most ancaps follow the homesteading principle for land ownership.  If there's a plot of unowned land, the first person to mix their labor with the land is entitled to own it.  "Claiming" a mineral deposit means nothing under ancap legal theory - you must make a solid investment in something in order to get the exclusive right to keep using it.  This is pretty fair - only people who are interested in making good use of land will be able to keep others out, and you can't go around arbitrarily wrecking other people's stuff who were there first.  It gets more complicated and there are disagreements about when said property becomes abandoned (I say when you stop insuring it or if you have abandonment agreements with real estate firms), if homesteading land means homesteading airspace above and minerals below (I say no, but future claims must not interfere with pre-existing claims - eg I can't undermine your house because you don't own the land beneath it), how water rights work (I say that you own the watershed of land whose surface you own), and other nuances.

Those are property rights in theory.  You can agree that they're at least a nice principle whether or not they're practically enforceable without a state.  Here's why I think they are.

We probably agree that people are social and can create more wealth when working together than the sum of separate efforts.  When people do get together, there are nexuses of trust that naturally form.  People are confident in keeping thousands of their hard earned dollars in banks, Silk Road can deliver products to interested buyers far more safely than previous alternatives, and motorists take out insurance policies, knowing that they'll be covered in accidents.  While it is true that the state regulates the first and third, I propose that except in the case of a total or near monopoly, the bigger the institution, the *less* likely it is to break social norms.  In a competitive market, cheaters stand to make a large amount of money in the short run, but none in the long run.  Sometimes this is worth it.  In the old West, a con artist would hastily throw up a flimsy building, claim to be a "bank," and skip town after deposits were taken.  If he hadn't cheated, then he would have gotten a longer stream of smaller income, but he has such a large time preference that he's OK with cheating.  Now suppose he builds a very expensive, fortified building, buys a house, and preemptively agrees to loan some townspeople money.  He's stuck in the town because he made a non-salvageable investment.  Similarly, even as non-state protection agencies grow larger, they'll have more pressure to find the fairest way to treat their customers, since even a small deviation from social norms could damage a very valuable brand.

This is all assuming competitive markets.  Like you've pointed out, the state already is a monopoly and sucks.  But what's stopping the protection agency market tending towards a monopoly?  The short, smart-ass answer is that if we get to an ancap society in the first place, then we've already figured out how to break a monopoly on force.  The longer one is that collusion does not necessarily work in all markets.  Recently, a bunch of airlines all wanted to raise prices simultaneously, but Southwest stopped them because they'd prefer to compete on volume and knew that as long as they priced above their marginal cost they could suck business away from the airlines who raised their prices and make more money.  As firms try to move prices above their product's marginal cost, each firm has an incentive to chisel the price back down to marginal cost.  Even though it'd be better for all firms as a whole if they raised their prices all at the same time, each individual firm has agency and noncooperation is the dominant strategy. I think you've raised a lot of good points, but I'm addressing some of them with other commenters (you guys are way friendlier and more helpful than I expected, no offense, which I'm happy to find out!), but I just thought of something reading your comment:

&amp;gt; Recently, a bunch of airlines all wanted to raise prices simultaneously, but Southwest stopped them because they'd prefer to compete on volume and knew that as long as they priced above their marginal cost they could suck business away from the airlines who raised their prices and make more money.

This works in a lot of ways because of existing laws.  If all those other airlines lived in a non-governed state, they could sabotage (even if subtly and rarely) Southwest's aircraft, or they could just all participate in a massive, slanderous ad campaign.  Sure, southwest could compete insofar as it's able to buy advertisements that its competitors can't buy out, otherwise, they're done, collusion engaged.  It is always, and only, a question of *if it's cheap enough to do*, and I fear the answer might be "yes" for some long-run, massive-sunk-cost industries like airliners.  If another competitor appears after southwest, they can be shutdown with even less effort. I think you've raised a lot of good points, but I'm addressing some of them with other commenters (you guys are way friendlier and more helpful than I expected, no offense, which I'm happy to find out!), but I just thought of something reading your comment:

&amp;gt; Recently, a bunch of airlines all wanted to raise prices simultaneously, but Southwest stopped them because they'd prefer to compete on volume and knew that as long as they priced above their marginal cost they could suck business away from the airlines who raised their prices and make more money.

This works in a lot of ways because of existing laws.  If all those other airlines lived in a non-governed state, they could sabotage (even if subtly and rarely) Southwest's aircraft, or they could just all participate in a massive, slanderous ad campaign.  Sure, southwest could compete insofar as it's able to buy advertisements that its competitors can't buy out, otherwise, they're done, collusion engaged.  It is always, and only, a question of *if it's cheap enough to do*, and I fear the answer might be "yes" for some long-run, massive-sunk-cost industries like airliners.  If another competitor appears after southwest, they can be shutdown with even less effort.  http://www.bigheadpress.com/tpbtgn

this graphic novel was my introduction, can't remember where I was introduced to it about a year ago, but I've read it 3 times now.  It actually covers the basics of what you're asking plus it's an interesting story.  

Basically, property (beyond your physical person) comes from applying  effort to natural resources to improve upon them.  Mining/refining minerals, clearing a plot of land to build on, logging etc....  

If you claimed an entire mountain to mine, but only mined one spot, someone would challenge your claim of ownership. 

 I'm going to check that out, but as I'm taking in all these comments, can you answer me what keeps someone from "challenging" a person's claim on a mountain when that person intended to eventually mine all throughout it?

What if the miner that got there first said "You haven't built anything there yet either, I'm calling it mine and people are going to swing pickaxes there RIGHT NOW".  What happens if this escalates out of control absent any governing body?  As an anarchist at heart (but who thinks it is impossible in practice), I would be happy to live a few miles from that mountain if we could all be civilized, decent humans to each other, but if those two corporations started massacring each other on the spot, I'd keep my head low.  Only they could stop themselves, I'd just be left with regret for daring to live near some useful resource... http://www.bigheadpress.com/tpbtgn

this graphic novel was my introduction, can't remember where I was introduced to it about a year ago, but I've read it 3 times now.  It actually covers the basics of what you're asking plus it's an interesting story.  

Basically, property (beyond your physical person) comes from applying  effort to natural resources to improve upon them.  Mining/refining minerals, clearing a plot of land to build on, logging etc....  

If you claimed an entire mountain to mine, but only mined one spot, someone would challenge your claim of ownership. 

 The novel is pretty good, as well.          We try to keep the circle jerking to a minimum. Hope some of the answers here helped. I'll throw in my 2 cents. 

The most basic principle is that people ought to be free. Part of that freedom includes the ability to engage in dealings with other people without a third party intervening. Many people get hung up on anarchism because they believe it would not be possible to provide the same level of safety that government provides. First, the 20th century showed pretty well that government is an instrument of massive violence, not protection. Second, that argument is illegitimate because it presumes that some people can rightfully make decisions on behalf of others. None of us signed the constitution (or similar non-us document). Yet we are bound by the decisions of our rulers. Leaving any particular country is not a solution since states currently rule the entire world. And, anyways, I shouldn't have to flee my home to escape the rule of others.  I think tovsome extent you just opened up a big can of worms regarding things being decided for us.  Say I'm 12 in AnarchyLand, and I don't want to continue abiding some local rule (don't skateboard down the street, I guess) just because I was born there.  I could lay down some outcomes that would vary based on the "neighborhood law" that might be present, but most of it does come down to it *always being okay to dispense with consent of the "governed" under some circumstances*.  It would be absurd to do it any other way, and that's the opinion expanded on by anyone who's not an anarchist.

All that said, thanks for the additional insight.</snippet></document><document><title>Why Police Lie Under Oath (NYT)</title><url>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/03/opinion/sunday/why-police-officers-lie-under-oath.html?pagewanted=all</url><snippet>  Does anyone have any links to things that prove police lying about quotas? I'm not saying I believe they don't have them, but it's nice to show people up when they say cops don't have quotas. http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/18/opinion/the-nypds-obsession-with-numbers.html

Here's an article about NY quotas. Does anyone have any links to things that prove police lying about quotas? I'm not saying I believe they don't have them, but it's nice to show people up when they say cops don't have quotas. I don't find quotas *necessarily* wrong, but it's impossible to find any merit when we have the war on drugs and prostitution going on. These non-crimes waste precious time and resources.  I don't find quotas *necessarily* wrong, but it's impossible to find any merit when we have the war on drugs and prostitution going on. These non-crimes waste precious time and resources.  I don't find quotas *necessarily* wrong, but it's impossible to find any merit when we have the war on drugs and prostitution going on. These non-crimes waste precious time and resources.    Police are the front line defenders of capital and, in the US, of the color line. What the hell is a color line?  What the hell is a color line?  Pretty much what I expect from ancaps. Color line isn't a very common phrase.  Think about it for a moment. What do you think it means?
 Pretty much what I expect from ancaps. [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>The Contradiction of Collectivist Anarchy (X-post r/anarchism)</title><url>http://buffalo-samurai.tumblr.com/post/41925846929/the-contradiction-of-collectivist-anarchy</url><snippet>  But, but, they say *they* are the real anarchists and we're the fake ones. They used the name first, so it means whatever they say it means! [deleted]  How's DROs collecting refused restitution not violence against individuals? Criminals may be punished in proportion to their initial crime, along with stolen goods taken back, but nothing more. The consent by criminals is implicit, the legal principle is called estoppel.  So it's righteous violence against individuals because it has been established as truth by the people acting in consort calling themselves Dispute Resolutions Inc...  Was this really posted on /r/Anarchism? I can't find it or was it deleted? Was this really posted on /r/Anarchism? I can't find it or was it deleted? Yamfood posted both; sensationalizing this one as if it were a cross-post.</snippet></document><document><title>It hurts to watch...</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bNbMPz5CPY8</url><snippet>  Of course, the biggest difference is that the NFL doesn't take anything from any of its teams by force. Governments (including the Democratic Party of the United States) take things by force. Thank god you beat me to this comment.  Bill Maher is one big fucking idiot.   hahaha The MLB also has the winningest teams pick last in the draft.  And while the Pittsburgh Pirates haven't won in a long time, do the Mets, who spend absurd amounts of money on players, have any better of a chance?

If you want to talk about business models in sports, that's fine, but please get your basic facts correct first.       Lol that's a funny video. Yeah, if you don't want socialism where you live, perhaps you should get out of the US before the doors slam shut?   [deleted] If that's your criteria for a kill list, the country will run out of ink, before you finish writing this list.  [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Privatize the Ocean</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17u05a/privatize_the_ocean/</url><snippet>Just a thought I've had.... If the ocean was divided into privately owned plots, pollution would most likely be solved, wouldn't it?

I came to this line of reasoning when I began to realize that any person or organization dumping toxic waste into the sea would be accountable to the owner under a Polycentric Legal Order. If they were to buy a plot of ocean to dump toxic waste into, they'd surely devalue their own plot. Making pollution a poor economic decision. Not to mention the risk of legal trouble if the waste spread to a neighboring plot.

Anyway, just a thought. Not sure what you think...        </snippet></document><document><title>The Rise and Fall of the City - Hans-Hermann Hoppe</title><url>http://mises.org/daily/1959</url><snippet /></document><document><title>How would an anarcho-capitalist society protect itself from the less-off militantly organizing and attempting to seize property from the wealthy?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17uacl/how_would_an_anarchocapitalist_society_protect/</url><snippet>Inspired by a debate-a-communist thread, where the general consensus was the statist social-safety nets were required by liberalism in order to prevent popular revolt

Edit: I'm much more interested in people answering my question than I am in being questioned about my own personal politics.  Buy a drone with bitcoin dawg and use it to mow down the rioting masses? It solves the problem, I guess, but its ridiculously brutal. I can't see people anyone other the egoist psychopaths being able to do such a thing. Only a mass of rioting psychopaths would attack and steal from people better off than them. It's self defense.

But I'm pretty sure he was kidding about the drone. Well, if people are having trouble being unable to feed themselves or get shelter, and there is adequate food or shelter that is owned by others simply unavailable to them because they don't own it, riots will happen. Its been proven true throughout history, and unless there was weird temporary outbreaks of mass psychopathy that came and went, mental illness has absolutely nothing to do with it. You know what else history has proven? That poor people are much better off in free market societies than they are in statist shitholes.

Would you like to compare the living standards and starvation rates between South and North Korea? All free market societies are also statist shitholes. Do you have any examples of free market societies that aren't statist? I have no idea what you're trying to prove here. I'm pointing out the the situations that cause such outbreaks to develop are much more prone to occur in societies that depart from free market principles. By all accounts, history has shown the people are much better off when capitalism is free to take its course.

Not that revolts wouldn't occur in ancap societies, but if the people revolting hated capitalism so much, why would they choose to live in an area with strong market forces? How exactly would someone living in an area with shitty employers that don't play a living wage be able to move elsewhere into a land of milk and honey? Required [living wages](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ca8Z__o52sk) make the poor even poorer. Only a mass of rioting psychopaths would attack and steal from people better off than them. It's self defense.

But I'm pretty sure he was kidding about the drone. So who would decide, say, someone is taking food from your pantry, whether or not it is legal or illegal to shoot them dead?

Or say you own a grocery store, and there is a raid happening by workers who are unhappy with their wage? Similar things have happened in the past throughout history, and have happened in Spain a few months ago. Would it be self defense to bring in the predator drones on them? If someone is breaking into my house, then it's justified for me to defend myself. Ideally, you wouldn't kill the guy, maybe shoot him in the leg or something. It would be extremely difficult to target criminals and not hit innocent people using drones(Obama's killing of brown children in the middle east is proof of that), so it wouldn't be practical in most situations.

Private, armed security guards outside of your residence and/or business would quell most attempts at theft. I'm more curious about how you'd defend your private property rather than your personal property, such as factories, stores, etc.

And in the original question, I'm talking about massive anti-capitalist insurrection, though. I'm sure you're familiar with this, right? Historically there's tons of examples, but recently its happening in Greece, parts of Mexico, Spain, and Argentina. Would would happen if, in the company that you own, all the workers revolt and "fire you as their boss", and start to run it themselves. This happens all the time during periods of capitalist bust, and usually its the state who intervenes and squelches the insurrection (or in cases of high profile revolt, it can even turn into civil war). How would an anarcho-capitalist society prevent against this? I'm more curious about how you'd defend your private property rather than your personal property, such as factories, stores, etc.

And in the original question, I'm talking about massive anti-capitalist insurrection, though. I'm sure you're familiar with this, right? Historically there's tons of examples, but recently its happening in Greece, parts of Mexico, Spain, and Argentina. Would would happen if, in the company that you own, all the workers revolt and "fire you as their boss", and start to run it themselves. This happens all the time during periods of capitalist bust, and usually its the state who intervenes and squelches the insurrection (or in cases of high profile revolt, it can even turn into civil war). How would an anarcho-capitalist society prevent against this? &amp;gt;I'm more curious about how you'd defend your private property rather than your personal property, such as factories, stores, etc.

The difference between capitalists and anti-capitalists is that we understand how vital private property is to the individual and society. Here you are essentially making a plea to **primitive ethical intuitions** that what is "in the household" is okay to defend, but title-based property isn't. It's an anachronism whereby you excuse the familiar, handheld, and inhabited as legitimate property, and then attempt to justify the breach of title-based property rights. There is no difference between the personal and private to the civilized person, only to the paleolithic person who lived in a world without contract or trust. So if workers in your store started spontaneously stealing product, you would shoot them (aiming for the leg)? It would depend on a multitude of factors related to what was being stolen, how the theft was being carried out, the consequences I could predict, and the history I had with the workers.

If workers started randomly stealing shit and rioting out of the blue, I or my guards (aren't they workers too?) would do something to try gaining control of the situation (warning shots, calling for help, locking doors, speaking to workers, etc.). If the workers continued with some demonic, ridiculous glean in their eyes I would start the shooting and escalate as necessary.

Of course, I doubt worker riots would be at all frequent in an actual free-market society (unlike most contemporary and historical eras and settings you are likely to draw from to prove your strawman). &amp;gt;I'm more curious about how you'd defend your private property rather than your personal property, such as factories, stores, etc.

The difference between capitalists and anti-capitalists is that we understand how vital private property is to the individual and society. Here you are essentially making a plea to **primitive ethical intuitions** that what is "in the household" is okay to defend, but title-based property isn't. It's an anachronism whereby you excuse the familiar, handheld, and inhabited as legitimate property, and then attempt to justify the breach of title-based property rights. There is no difference between the personal and private to the civilized person, only to the paleolithic person who lived in a world without contract or trust. So if workers in your store started a steal-in, you'd shoot them all, aiming for the legs?  Labor is forever scarce and capitalists can always use more laborers, especially when there's no minimum wage they must be paid.  This means capitalists, if profit be their goal, will always seek to productively employ those "less-off."

The incentive structure for the "less-off" laborers is attain a criminal reputation, which would be very costly to rehabilitate, with an expected cost that would greatly dwarf any short-run booty (the exact reason why the market as a means of cooperation exists and a civil society is even known about, as opposed to humans being cannibalistic hermaphrodites) or cooperate in an employ that will be much more productive than working by themselves.

This means few rational actors will choose a life of crime, if they have long-term interests for themselves.  Add onto this private law and security and you'll have a system where crime is even less existent.

&amp;gt;where the general consensus was the statist social-safety nets were required by liberalism in order to prevent popular revolt

The ironic thing is it's actually *because of* them and the hyperregulation of employment why revolt is more likely to occur. Without a minimum wage, I imagine you're at risk of not getting a living wage from your employees. There are plenty of places without minimum wages and with very low employment that have strong militant labor movements, that often end up with riots.

Do you have any kind of statistics or studies or data that backs up what you're saying. Sure, it sounds nice in theory, but I can't see that really happening in practice. It seems too utopian to me. &amp;gt; minimum wage

all minimum wage does is keep people unemployed. claiming that it can do anything else is not just utopian, but empirical falsehood. &amp;gt; minimum wage

all minimum wage does is keep people unemployed. claiming that it can do anything else is not just utopian, but empirical falsehood. citation? 

And regardless, do you think it is possible for all employers to pay all employees a living wage, and not have unemployment? If that's true, than the minimum wage case would be entirely trivial anyways, as living wage is far above minimum wage in most places. Without a minimum wage, I imagine you're at risk of not getting a living wage from your employees. There are plenty of places without minimum wages and with very low employment that have strong militant labor movements, that often end up with riots.

Do you have any kind of statistics or studies or data that backs up what you're saying. Sure, it sounds nice in theory, but I can't see that really happening in practice. It seems too utopian to me. &amp;gt;I imagine you're at risk of not getting a living wage from your employees.

Not at all.  Food has demand primacy (you even implicitly agree by citing it as a potentially serious problem).  It may be sold cheaply in an advanced economy, but, even in a primitive economy, it would have much higher dedicated production.  So, the market always pursues production of those goods most in demand dynamically and towards a rational allocation; even when the market gets disrupted by arbitrary regulation, it still grinds toward a momentary equilibrium.

Another way to look at what you're saying as misguided is by understanding that an arbitrary increase in the "less-off's" income is going to raise the demand for food and, thus, its price, ceteris paribus.  So, the term "living wage" has no non-circular meaning, and, thus, disarms your objection (Humans have been able to provide for themselves plenty of food for thousands of years; starvation is really more political than economic).

People like not starving and are prepared to dedicate the vast majority or all of their income to food, if need be.  Whatever that income is, nominally, will be reflected in a great deal in the actual nominal price paid for food.  Market exchanges imply divisions of labor whose productivity incentivize many to give up on procuring their own food, leaving it to an enterprise more efficient, so they can pursue a higher income.

The tl;dr: markets take care of their participants.

&amp;gt;There are plenty of places without minimum wages and with very low employment that have strong militant labor movements, that often end up with riots.

Well, a minimum wage is only one in a plethora of ways that the market for labor can be dislocated.

&amp;gt;Do you have any kind of statistics or studies or data that backs up what you're saying. Sure, it sounds nice in theory, but I can't see that really happening in practice. It seems too utopian to me.

You know about the term "anarcho-capitalist," but you don't know what the Austrian rebuttal is to this? I reject austrian economics entirely. Believing in it requires more faith than your run-of-the-mill sky fairy. Then why even come here? to ask questions? Just because I don't agree with something doesn't mean I'm not interested in learning about it. I like to keep an open mind. It seems rather pointless though doesn't it? The answers you will get will mostly be comprised based off the Austrian theory. Clearly, you have already written off Austrian theory as wrong (comparing it to fairies), which means you will consider all our answers wrong. 

If you REALLY want to learn about the Austrian theory and Anarcho-Capitalism I suggest looking at professional works instead of coming to reddit. You should read some of David Friedman's works. 

 I've read Friedman, I've read Mises, I've read Rothbard. I know it all. I just asked one question, yet nobody seems to be willing to answer it, and are instead saying "In an anarcho-capitalist society, they're *obviously* be no poverty". I wasn't the one to bring up economics at all. Now you're putting words into mouths. No one said there would be no poverty. 

The problem is that your question can't be answered because there is no way to test it. Therefore, the answers you will get will all be based off theory, which you happen to disagree with. End of story. I've read Friedman, I've read Mises, I've read Rothbard. I know it all. I just asked one question, yet nobody seems to be willing to answer it, and are instead saying "In an anarcho-capitalist society, they're *obviously* be no poverty". I wasn't the one to bring up economics at all. Several people here (myself included) have given you an answer to your question.  Stop lying. I've read Friedman, I've read Mises, I've read Rothbard. I know it all. I just asked one question, yet nobody seems to be willing to answer it, and are instead saying "In an anarcho-capitalist society, they're *obviously* be no poverty". I wasn't the one to bring up economics at all. I reject austrian economics entirely. Believing in it requires more faith than your run-of-the-mill sky fairy. You "believe" in Austrian economics like you "believe" in maths. It is simply a useful theory that informs actual decision making. I reject austrian economics entirely. Believing in it requires more faith than your run-of-the-mill sky fairy.    I think your question rests on a premise that most people thinking about an AnCap society do not agree with.  Namely that there will be enough poverty that this would be an issue and that the society would not have adopted as a norm something like the NAP.

So, presuming there are masses of poor who do not recognize something like the NAP as the basis of ethical behavior:

If individuals violate property they will be repelled and compensation will be sought for any damage by the property owners DRO.  Anyone who is known to disrespect property rights will likely have a low reputation score and can lose access to other people's  more public-esque property (like roads and stores).

---
Also you might find the side-bar or a search of the subreddit helpful (this is not exactly an uncommon question). So you think its impossible for there to be impoverished desperate masses at all in an ancap society? I think the general thoughts of those who subscribe to the Austrian school is that poverty as it exists today will tend to decrease the longer the system is in place.  I am not sure I subscribe to Austrian economics specifically (its pre-scientific enlightenment thinking bothers me somewhat).  I would say that with the barrier to entry to the market being as low as is likely in a completely free market that the number of poor would decrease and the quality of life of the poor (on average) would increase.

---
None of this is an actual response to my answer to your question though. &amp;gt;(its pre-scientific enlightenment thinking bothers me somewhat)

You say that like the enlightenment period was philosophically more significant than what came before it (and not just nonphilosophical historians' treatment of it). I think you misunderstand my tone.  The enlightenment, and specifically the discovery of the scientific method were a progression from previous thought.  Ideas from before the enlightenment can be valid (the logical absolutes and the idea of particles making up matter predate enlightenment rather significantly).  The problem is that before the enlightenment the method of testing these ideas was flawed, thus science.

So, when there are unfalsifiable claims made, like those of the foundation of Austrian economics, which science *can not address* I can not (as a skeptic and scientist) claim that these ideas must be correct simply through reasoning.  I am agnostic about them.  I put only as much faith in those ideas as I do in other unfalsifiable ideas, namely as much as reality requires me to (like the denial of hard solipsism).  I think, in the end, Agorism will allow for a demonstration that the Austrian economists are right (or allow for correcting anything that is not right). &amp;gt;specifically the discovery of the scientific method

The Scientific Method is nothing but the codification of what humans had already been doing for thousands of years.  Even other animals think similarly in the small way they're capable of, of trying to tease out understanding of causalities from interaction within the world in which they live, so that they can better satisfy their ends.

&amp;gt;The problem is that before the enlightenment the method of testing these ideas was flawed, thus science.

No, the thinking has always been in every age; the only thing that separates them is technological progress, which affects what one may confidently test.  You act like there weren't tests done prior to the "Enlightenment."  You think, when a couple methods of creating fire were first discovered by primitive men, they didn't attempt to isolate what were the necessary conditions for its creation, by experimenting with the presence and absence of various factors?  That is textbook scientific reasoning.

&amp;gt;I can not (as a skeptic and scientist) claim that these ideas must be correct simply through reasoning

Do you know what analytic reasoning is?  Rationalism is hardly mutually-exclusive to skepticism and Science; indeed, the hardest-core skeptics *are* rationalists, and the foundation of Science--Philosophy of Science--is *all about* its rationalist roots.

&amp;gt;I put only as much faith in those ideas as I do in other unfalsifiable ideas

So, you require "faith" in a^2 + b^2 = c^2 ?  Pretty incredible. &amp;gt;The Scientific Method is nothing but the codification of what humans had already been doing for thousands of years. Even other animals think similarly in the small way they're capable of, of trying to tease out understanding of causalities from interaction within the world in which they live, so that they can better satisfy their ends.

This is a half-truth.  The scientific method replaced ended up subsuming analytic reasoning and gave a better understanding of the standard of evidence for having a rational justification for a belief in a truth claim.  It also applies to non-causal things, and is particularly good at pointing out when correlated events occur but are not causal.  Neither of which is distinctly true of pure Aristotelian reasoning.  I would not call what lower animals do 'scientific' so much as it is them expecting history to repeat its self.  That is not an investigation of the underlying mechanism.

&amp;gt;No, the thinking has always been in every age; the only thing that separates them is technological progress, which affects what one may confidently test.

This is (aside from being a gramatical mess) patently false.  It was considered perfectly acceptable for the wise and educated to assume through pure reason that something was true if they could not falsify the premises.  Some of the premises they accepted rested upon devine intervention or inspiration, and they saw nothing wrong with that.  With  the scientific method one gets methodological naturalism (or you could say it the other way, I do not think the distinction is important).  This did lead directly to technological advancement.

&amp;gt;Do you know what analytic reasoning is? Rationalism is hardly mutually-exclusive to skepticism and Science; indeed, the hardest-core skeptics are rationalists, and the foundation of Science--Philosophy of Science--is all about its rationalist roots.

You can not claim something is true through pure 'analytic' reasoning.  Only observation is enough to make that claim.  That is 'hard-core' rationalism.

&amp;gt;So, you require "faith" in [presumably the pythagorean formula with no context] ? Pretty incredible.

It is not faith if the space is Euclidean and a, b, and c describe the sides of a triangle in that space.  Unfortunately not all space is Euclidean, and not any three variables describe the legs of a triangle.  You can pick again if you feel like it, but if your question was supposed to be something like 'do you have faith that math works' then the answer is no.  I have a justified belief that math works because I test it.  Sometimes math gives perfectly valid mathematical answers which are not physical, that is why math is not the only part of science (merely a good language to write it in if one is properly rigorous). &amp;gt;This is a half-truth.

I'm not sure there's anything more frustrating than reading writing that presupposes expertise while not having it.  After reading your responses each iteration, I barely resist the urge to laugh and walk away.  Your position would be better served by asking me questions, rather than presuming to inform me, while providing me nothing but muddled reasoning.

That being said,

&amp;gt;The scientific method replaced ended up subsuming analytic reasoning and gave a better understanding of the standard of evidence for having a rational justification for a belief in a truth claim.

You probably don't even know who Kuhn was and are a die-hard falsificationist (hell, maybe you believe things actually can be proven; at this point, I shouldn't assume any philosophical sophistication).

&amp;gt;I would not call what lower animals do 'scientific' so much as it is them expecting history to repeat its self.

How modest.

&amp;gt;aside from being a gramatical mess

Or your reading comprehension inexperienced, leaving you fewer ways in which to read sentences.

&amp;gt;Some of the premises they accepted rested upon devine intervention or inspiration, and they saw nothing wrong with that. 

Yeah, examples of religious dogmatists disproves the existence of those capable of scientific reasoning.  Your claim rests on the supposition that Man one day ran into a new way of thinking that he was utterly incapable of before (we'll leave aside how he even then ran into it for the moment) and, now that he has discovered it, must pass it down onto other generations and inculcate it in them, lest we return to the "dark" ages.

Pretty incredible theory you have there, sir.  I wonder then how I was capable of scientific reasoning before I was even "taught" the formal method (and, by "taught," I actually mean was *not* taught, as what is presented in most science classes is falsificationism, something not actually believed technically possible by philosophers of Science.  I've only had one professor who knew who Kuhn even was.  They don't even teach Philosophy of Science in graduate level natural science programs, of all places.)

&amp;gt;This did lead directly to technological advancement.

Yes, we LITERALLY had no technology before the Enlightenment.  Then, something happened, and we had BOATLOADS of technology.  I guess this removes all doubt your position couldn't be seriously posed.

&amp;gt;You can not claim something is true through pure 'analytic' reasoning. Only observation is enough to make that claim. That is 'hard-core' rationalism.

Do you even know what Mathematics *is*?  Facepalm*epic proportions = you.

One by one, as you engage in these extended conversations with the regulars of /r/anarcho_capitalism, you're going to make blatantly apparent your lack of philosophical training, and, one by one, these regulars are going to try to, through good will, educate you and, when you chide *their* ignorance, they're going to be left with no choice but to laugh at your stupidity and hubris.

&amp;gt;because I test it

You don't *empirically/positivistically* test Mathematics, sweet jesus.  Were you actually the guy I was telling the others about and laughing with about how you thought we actually test 1 + 1 = 2?  Your name does sound vaguely familiar.  But, either way, at this point, I can't help but think you're just like or are, in fact, that guy. &amp;gt;I'm not sure there's anything more frustrating than reading writing that presupposes expertise while not having it. After reading your responses each iteration, I barely resist the urge to laugh and walk away. Your position would be better served by asking me questions, rather than presuming to inform me, while providing me nothing but muddled reasoning.

Cool story bro.

&amp;gt;You probably don't even know who Kuhn was and are a die-hard falsificationist (hell, maybe you believe things actually can be proven; at this point, I shouldn't assume any philosophical sophistication).

You are free, of course, to think what you want.  I am aware of the limitations on what can be known without assumption, and thus use an operational understanding of 'proof' like any other scientist.

&amp;gt;Or your reading comprehension inexperienced, leaving you fewer ways in which to read sentences.

You have done it again.  That is a fragment (and nonsensical).  If you mean the contraction 'you're' then I would simply point you to your original sentence to which I objected:
&amp;gt;No, the thinking has always been in every age; the only thing that separates them is technological progress, which affects what one may confidently test.

Your first clause has a subject, a verb, and then no object.  Your second clause (if one assumes the subject 'the thinking in every age') as what is being discussed via 'separates' by what 'one may confidently test' is what I pointed out was false.  The technical means to discover bacteria for instance existed long before its actual discovery.  It is the method of investigation which changed.  To say otherwise flies in the face of historical accounts.

&amp;gt;Yeah, examples of religious dogmatists disproves the existence of those capable of scientific reasoning. Your claim rests on the supposition that Man one day ran into a new way of thinking that he was utterly incapable of before (we'll leave aside how he even then ran into it for the moment) and, now that he has discovered it, must pass it down onto other generations and inculcate it in them, lest we return to the "dark" ages.

No.  This is (yet another) straw man.  My claim rests on the premise that a large group of people 'one day' realized that they could understand the world through careful observation and controlled experimentation.  It was a turning point phenomenon in the acceptance of a meme.  This must have been coming for some time, because it was not a singular event (and occurred at slightly different times on different parts of the world).  I made no claim about the future, and did not make the claims you seem to think I made about the past.

&amp;gt;They don't even teach Philosophy of Science in graduate level natural science programs, of all places.

It is odd that they think that scientists should have technical mastery and philosophers can debate the meaning of what they discover.  This crazy specialization of labor will be the downfall of us all...  In all seriousness though, many (perhaps most) scientists have an understanding of incompleteness, deductive and inductive logic, and what science can 'know' within the operational definition of 'know' (which is related to 'proof' as I used it earlier).  To say otherwise is silly.

&amp;gt;One by one, as you engage in these extended conversations with the regulars of /r/anarcho_capitalism, you're going to make blatantly apparent your lack of philosophical training, and, one by one, these regulars are going to try to, through good will, educate you and, when you chide their ignorance, they're going to be left with no choice but to laugh at your stupidity and hubris.

Cool story bro.

&amp;gt;You don't empirically/positivistically test Mathematics, sweet jesus.

You do when you want to use it as a model of reality, and that was my point. &amp;gt;I'm not sure there's anything more frustrating than reading writing that presupposes expertise while not having it. After reading your responses each iteration, I barely resist the urge to laugh and walk away. Your position would be better served by asking me questions, rather than presuming to inform me, while providing me nothing but muddled reasoning.

Cool story bro.

&amp;gt;You probably don't even know who Kuhn was and are a die-hard falsificationist (hell, maybe you believe things actually can be proven; at this point, I shouldn't assume any philosophical sophistication).

You are free, of course, to think what you want.  I am aware of the limitations on what can be known without assumption, and thus use an operational understanding of 'proof' like any other scientist.

&amp;gt;Or your reading comprehension inexperienced, leaving you fewer ways in which to read sentences.

You have done it again.  That is a fragment (and nonsensical).  If you mean the contraction 'you're' then I would simply point you to your original sentence to which I objected:
&amp;gt;No, the thinking has always been in every age; the only thing that separates them is technological progress, which affects what one may confidently test.

Your first clause has a subject, a verb, and then no object.  Your second clause (if one assumes the subject 'the thinking in every age') as what is being discussed via 'separates' by what 'one may confidently test' is what I pointed out was false.  The technical means to discover bacteria for instance existed long before its actual discovery.  It is the method of investigation which changed.  To say otherwise flies in the face of historical accounts.

&amp;gt;Yeah, examples of religious dogmatists disproves the existence of those capable of scientific reasoning. Your claim rests on the supposition that Man one day ran into a new way of thinking that he was utterly incapable of before (we'll leave aside how he even then ran into it for the moment) and, now that he has discovered it, must pass it down onto other generations and inculcate it in them, lest we return to the "dark" ages.

No.  This is (yet another) straw man.  My claim rests on the premise that a large group of people 'one day' realized that they could understand the world through careful observation and controlled experimentation.  It was a turning point phenomenon in the acceptance of a meme.  This must have been coming for some time, because it was not a singular event (and occurred at slightly different times on different parts of the world).  I made no claim about the future, and did not make the claims you seem to think I made about the past.

&amp;gt;They don't even teach Philosophy of Science in graduate level natural science programs, of all places.

It is odd that they think that scientists should have technical mastery and philosophers can debate the meaning of what they discover.  This crazy specialization of labor will be the downfall of us all...  In all seriousness though, many (perhaps most) scientists have an understanding of incompleteness, deductive and inductive logic, and what science can 'know' within the operational definition of 'know' (which is related to 'proof' as I used it earlier).  To say otherwise is silly.

&amp;gt;One by one, as you engage in these extended conversations with the regulars of /r/anarcho_capitalism, you're going to make blatantly apparent your lack of philosophical training, and, one by one, these regulars are going to try to, through good will, educate you and, when you chide their ignorance, they're going to be left with no choice but to laugh at your stupidity and hubris.

Cool story bro.

&amp;gt;You don't empirically/positivistically test Mathematics, sweet jesus.

You do when you want to use it as a model of reality, and that was my point. I think the general thoughts of those who subscribe to the Austrian school is that poverty as it exists today will tend to decrease the longer the system is in place.  I am not sure I subscribe to Austrian economics specifically (its pre-scientific enlightenment thinking bothers me somewhat).  I would say that with the barrier to entry to the market being as low as is likely in a completely free market that the number of poor would decrease and the quality of life of the poor (on average) would increase.

---
None of this is an actual response to my answer to your question though. Yeah. As a scientist myself, I am very very very wary of any conclusions and methodology of austrian economics. Yeah. As a scientist myself, I am very very very wary of any conclusions and methodology of austrian economics. Well, you should know that sound reasoning is one way to generate a hypothesis, and in my opinion that is what Austrian economics is.  Agorism is well on its way to testing the predictions. &amp;gt;that sound reasoning is one way to generate a hypothesis

It's the *only* way.

&#3232;_&#3232; Actually no.  Science typically requires inductive reasoning.  Unfortunately inductive reasoning presumes you understand something about a system.  It is possible to generate hypotheses  deductively, it is also possible to simply guess and test.  Using this last method there are automated programs that generate mathematical hypotheses and then let researchers test them in order to fully sample a phase space of possible hypothesis (which a human might not do). &amp;gt;Actually no.

lol, this is going to be fun.

&amp;gt;Science typically requires inductive reasoning.

Typically, or always -- which is it, if you know it?

&amp;gt;Unfortunately inductive reasoning presumes you understand something about a system.

Confident that you understand something well enough; all observations are theory-laden, yes.

&amp;gt;It is possible to generate hypotheses deductively

It's the only way; you're not understanding what I'm really saying.  All thinking is actually deductive; even induction is a form of deduction.  The only difference is that induction presumes validity of empirical data.  It says, "if my observations A and B are true, and our theories C, D, and E remain true, F must be the case about this reality."

Induction is not me opening up a flap of my brain and "letting in data" from the "real" world (rofl).  These "two" reasonings are really one.

&amp;gt;it is also possible to simply guess and test

Even "guessing" is done with something in mind.  Mises had handled this issue well in the beginning of Human Action.

&amp;gt;that generate mathematical hypotheses

Do you know how computers work?  A CPU has billions of CMOS transistors that can act as logic gates.  These logic gates emulate human *deductive* reasoning.  CPUs simply spit out whatever follows from billions of logical operations on given premises.  There is nothing *categorically* different about this act, only the speed at which it occurs. &amp;gt;Typically, or always -- which is it, if you know it?

All reasoning after a hypothesis is generated must be inductive.  As I said, generating an initial hypothesis need not be inductive.  Most of the work is done post-hypothesis, thus I said 'typically.'

&amp;gt;Confident that you understand something well enough; all observations are theory-laden, yes.

That is backwards I think, and missed the point of what I was saying.

&amp;gt;It's the only way; you're not understanding what I'm really saying. All thinking is actually deductive; even induction is a form of deduction.

You clearly did not read what I wrote.  It is possible to have a computer algorithmically (or pseudo-randomly) generate hypothesis to be tested.  I hope we can agree that 'random' generation to sample a phase space is not deductive (or inductive, though its purpose is inductive).

&amp;gt;Induction is not me opening up a flap of my brain and "letting in data" from the "real" world (rofl). These "two" reasonings are really one.

Nice straw man.  No, they are not one form of reasoning.  They are different in methodology and intent, they are foils of each other.  Unfortunately for us, deductive reasoning can lead to false predictions when premises are mistakenly included.  Inductive reasoning does not allow for this since the conclusion was not being constructed by adding premises but rather is generated by whichever observations happen to be included (accounting for statistical sampling errors).

&amp;gt;Even "guessing" is done with something in mind. Mises had handled this issue well in the beginning of Human Action.

Having 'something in mind' is not a form of reasoning, or at least not a valid one.  Also, as I have pointed out, the guessing can be done by a third party with no agenda (a computer), something I suspect Mises does not say much about.

&amp;gt;These logic gates emulate human deductive reasoning. CPUs simply spit out whatever follows from billions of logical operations on given premises. There is nothing categorically different about this act, only the speed at which it occurs.

You again discount randomness.  Believe it or not, generation of very random sampling can be done.  A human is still sometimes required to bound the space the computer samples, though I believe there are programs which set their own bounds for creating 'interesting' problems.  The fact that this can be done on a deterministic tool is not the point because the input can be random (or very, very close to it).  This is a cornerstone of a lot of advances in information theory and computational physics.

---

None of this is the point, it is a pissing contest (which by its nature I think you are losing and you presumably think I am losing).

* Austrian Economics is foundationally unfalsifiable.  True or False:

* Belief in something without evidence is irrational. True of False:

* Pure reasoning, alone, is not evidence. True or False:

* A claim which is unfalsifiable is untestable and can generate no empirical evidence.  True or False:

I answer 'True' to all of those statements, which leads me to my original objection to Austrian Economics.  Feel free to argue one of those premises.   I find it somewhat funny that, in particular, a lot of the Randists argue this line of thought, and say the poor would have too much power, while others argue that the rich and wealthy would take over because they would have all the soldiers and money. To sort of flip this, why do you not think the rich with their private armies and resources would be able to protect themselves?  Nobody will and can answer this question. Most AnCaps subscribe to the austrian economics and reject the notion that real poverty will even exist to the degree that it is a real issue. Anarcho Capitalism at this stage is a utopian ideology like communism and you'll find most supporters arguing that all bad shit and failures humanity showed and did over the arch of history can be attributed to a flaw in the system ("statism is a mental ilness produced by abusive parents", "the market wasn't just free enough" etc. pp) and if once corrected will vanish all together. 

Their line of argumentation is build upon the same tenets as every fringe ideology: 

1) the system inevitably will collapse due to it's inherent flaws or a revolution (soon).

2) people just need to be educated and if they have to ability to properly understand it they will recongize the truth, if not then they are in denial, brain washed or are profiting from the current system 

3) The ideology I advocate is vastly superior and will improve everybody's life significantly. The only reasons it hasn't been implanted yet is due the ignorance of the masses and the malice of a small group of elitist ("the capitalists", "the government")

Anarcho Capitalism has never existed in human history and it's blank page for all the hopes and dreams of people to draw their nice little utopia on it. Every answer of what would happen in situation xy can only be a product of phantasy, depending on the underlining perception the individual has of reality. 

The only honest you can get to this topic is: nobody knows and it will depend on the situation. You can see a rich man buying military gear and just massacering everybody who stands in his way. Or reacting to the situation by improving the wages or subsidation for food. Or you can deny that something like poverty will even exist which leaves the question mood.    </snippet></document><document><title>School district considers copyright policy that takes ownership of all students&#8217; and teachers' work</title><url>http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/education/prince-georges-considers-copyright-policy-that-takes-ownership-of-students-work/2013/02/02/dc592dea-6b08-11e2-ada3-d86a4806d5ee_story.html</url><snippet>   Are you in favor of intellectual property law?    </snippet></document><document><title>Is an attack on the government justified?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/17t7vd/is_an_attack_on_the_government_justified/</url><snippet>First, let me be clear that I am not suggesting anyone actually attack a government (or anyone else). They have tanks and all sorts of other weapons, not much a few redditors could do against that.

However. The government has already broken the non-aggression principle with their threats of violence; every government has. It would be justified according to the non-aggression principle if I fought against any government as it would be self defence and/or in defence of other people. This also extends to those who use the organs of the state to do their dirty work (banks and other crony capitalists), they are not really any different from a man who pays an assassin. The people who vote for any political party, even libertarian, are basically saying that they want to coerce me using the might of the state. Again, this is a threat of violence by proxy. Almost every member of every society is fair game at this point, according to the NAP. I am not sure what I think about this. What do you think?
  Nice try Homeland Security. Don't be silly. They don't need evidence or a trial or any sort of reasonable suspicion. Got beards? Muslims? Y'all are terrorists. You don't even need a beard or be Muslim anymore.  Saying "I don't like the government" is enough to earn you the label of violent terrorist. Also, if you pay with cash or store food. But I've also purchased silver with my credit card: terrorist. &amp;gt; purchased silver with my credit card

that's brilliant.  seriously.  Totally agree. That's asking for trouble down the road.  But I've also purchased silver with my credit card: terrorist. "How to defeat terrorism? Don't be terrorized." -Salmon Rushdie.  If this is true, we lost the war and gained a police state. DHS decided to defeat terrorism by offering superior terrorism that the terrorists couldn't compete with. Maybe they like competitive capitalism after all? Also, if you pay with cash or store food. Don't be silly. They don't need evidence or a trial or any sort of reasonable suspicion. Got beards? Muslims? Y'all are terrorists. Some "think tank" out of West Point said that those who believe in limited government, or self-government are to be considered potential terrorists now. Some "think tank" out of West Point said that those who believe in limited government, or self-government are to be considered potential terrorists now. Not doubting you, but source? That's a new low http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2013/jan/17/west-point-center-cites-dangers-far-right-us/ &amp;gt; Details about what makes an attack a &#8220;far right&#8221; action are not clear in the report,

Naturally. &amp;gt;It says anti-federalists &#8220;espouse strong convictions regarding the federal government, believing it to be corrupt and tyrannical, with a natural tendency to intrude on individuals&#8217; civil and constitutional rights. Finally, they support civil activism, individual freedoms, and self government.

Civil activism, individual freedoms, and self government... How radical!
 Nice try Homeland Security. do right-libertarians have any history of terrorist activity? If DHS was trying to entrapt anarchists, surely they'd go to the much more militant left-anarchists, no?  Justified, very. Foolish, absolutely.

The first step to getting free of government is to make sure they can't hurt you, or that you can hurt them enough that they won't bother. Attacking the government won't achieve that.

The NAP is just a principle upon which the law of a civilized society is based. It's not an automatic death sentence. Do you have any historic examples of government being abolished without violent insurrection?  Asking for an example of something in history as a prerequisite for its existence is fallacious. That's like having a conversation with Ben Franklin trying to argue that he can't invent a lightbulb in the future because it hasn't been done in the past. 

That being said, every violent revolution in history to overthrow a government has resulted in another government.  Well, obviously, since there isn't any anarchism now. But there's been periods of time where violent insurrection has overthrown the government and people have lived in an anarchist society for years aftewards before another (often fascist) force invaded them and imposed government on them. Do you have any historic examples of government being abolished without violent insurrection?    You cannot fix violence with violence.  I actually disagree with this statement as a whole. Not that I'm advocating using violence against the state, but violence can stop violence. 

Very small scenario: Your brother is being beaten, to a point that you are fearing for his life. If you shoot the assailant the assailant would be less likely to kill your brother. It only postpones and redirrects violence.  I actually disagree with this statement as a whole. Not that I'm advocating using violence against the state, but violence can stop violence. 

Very small scenario: Your brother is being beaten, to a point that you are fearing for his life. If you shoot the assailant the assailant would be less likely to kill your brother. You cannot fix violence with violence.  Someone breaks into my home, I shoot them. It gets around that you don't break into my home. Viola, violence fixed with violence. 

It's incorrect to throw out an Epithet and act like it s fact.

That's the point of owning means if self defense. It doesnt fix that situation, it ends it, but nothing there is fixed.  You cannot fix violence with violence.  Sure you can. Why do you believe that? Ive never seen it happen. Really? The US civil rights movement was violent as fuck. Slavery was ended in the US through violence. The Indian Indepedence movement was violent as fuck. The black panthers were ultraviolent. Stonewall was violent as fuck as was a turning point for gay rights. Violence stopped the nazis in WW2.          There are numerous **legal** ways to resist, protest, organize strikes, sabotage, unionize. It is not very difficult to **legally** crash the function of the state apparatus. Just be imaginative. Two of my heroes: Martin Luther King and Mohandas Gandhi. Not only did they affect revolutionary change by peaceful means, they changed people's hearts. It sounds cheesy but hey it's true. There are numerous **legal** ways to resist, protest, organize strikes, sabotage, unionize. It is not very difficult to **legally** crash the function of the state apparatus. Just be imaginative. If it's so easy to crash the state, then why is it still around? If it's so easy to crash the state, then why is it still around? If it's so easy to crash the state, then why is it still around? You mean, like Rome? Rome was crushed by invading Goths. Not through "legal ways of resisting, protesting, organizing strikes, sabotage or unionization". There are quite analysis that the collapse of Rome happened from the inside. The Goths were incidental.    It's justified to defend yourself or others and demand justice for previous offences. It is not justified to strike against a government without cause.

Anyway, I think the complicity of those who merely support the government, or want it to do something, is tricky since obviously they are not the ones actually committing the crimes. Many in the general population would also be complicit then. I guess you have have to define what constitutes a conspiracy to commit a crime. The government has a vested interest in making you think that it's only acting on your behalf so you can't criticize it. They commit an offence against me every time I pay VAT; almost daily then.                 </snippet></document><document><title>Jesse Jackson Urges Obama to Use Homeland Security to Patrol the Streets of Chicago - Reuters </title><url>http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/02/03/us-usa-crime-chicago-idUSBRE91200X20130203?feedType=RSS&amp;amp;feedName=politicsNews&amp;amp;utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;dlvrit=574655</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Chicago Murder Rate Far Worse Now Than During Al Capone Era With No Gun Control WLS-TV</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w1tSXK1AeBo</url><snippet>  they only told us the raw number of gun murders, what about the murder rate per 1000 people? or within the 1929 chicago city jurisdiction (assuming it has grown since then) Chicago is about 700,000 people less than it was in the late twenties and into the 30s and 900,000 less than its peak in 1950.  so the population has decreased since then? in that case the murder rate per 1000 people is about double what it was then </snippet></document><document><title>In homage to one of my favorite books, here's the wordle of the entire text of: A History of Money and Banking in the United States</title><url>http://www.wordle.net/show/wrdl/6321514/History_of_Money_and_Banking_in_the_United_States</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Romania's Underground Cancer Drug Networks - Liliana Ciobanu</title><url>http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2013/01/romanias-underground-cancer-drug-networks/272692/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>TAX COWS AREN'T MILKING ENOUGH! Hybrid owners protest $100 fee</title><url>http://wtop.com/120/3214136/Hybrid-owners-protest-100-fee</url><snippet>  Seems fair. Clearly the fuel tax method is outdated.
Time to start tolling roads so they can charge based on road usage?
Might as well privatise them while we're at it. It depends on what you mean by "road usage". Miles driven is just as bad.

If we we're going to go for a metric, the greatest charges should undoubtedly go towards semi-trucks. Sure their fuel-mileage isn't the best but it's still far too good to make up for the damage they do to the roads - we're talking orders of magnitude difference between the damage a fully-loaded 80,000 lb semi w/payload does and a hybrid. 

Neither mileage nor fuel usage can account for that. The fact that they're going after hybrid drivers to pony up while effectively subsidizing these trucking firms AND increasing their weight limit even further (I believe they're discussing raising the limit to 97K lbs) is a joke to me. &amp;gt;the greatest charges should undoubtedly go towards semi-trucks. 

What would lead you to believe it does not? Do you have any concept of what it costs in taxes to put a truck on the road? http://truecostblog.com/2009/06/02/the-hidden-trucking-industry-subsidy/ The road use taxes are just a small portion of the myriad of taxes, charges and fees paid by the trucking folks every year. The idea that cars cause around 1% of road damage is utterly preposterous. I'd be happy to look at your calculations. So far I've seen several different figures but all of them agree that the trucking industry doesn't pay nearly enough in use taxes. 

What other taxes they pay relative to what other auto owners pay isn't really relevant to this discussion because if we went to an ancap society with private roads a different formula would probably be applied - one that accounts for actual road damage. The fact that the trucking industry is even competitive at all over long distances with rail, which is far more efficient, suggests to me at least that there might be a subsidy that, whether direct or indirect, warrants more research.

I am most definitely not a civil engineer, but the 4th power polynomial relationship sounds reasonable and the idea that a loaded semi causes as much damage to the road as 9600 cars was taken from the Highway Research Board, NAS, 1962. &amp;gt;all of them agree that the trucking industry doesn't pay nearly enough in use taxes.

If they did, we would just pay more at the store for everything. Not a massive change. It would put the costs on people who buy the transported goods, while right now it just lays it on car drivers. On net, I suppose its more fair. &amp;gt;all of them agree that the trucking industry doesn't pay nearly enough in use taxes.

If they did, we would just pay more at the store for everything. Not a massive change. It would put the costs on people who buy the transported goods, while right now it just lays it on car drivers. On net, I suppose its more fair. The road use taxes are just a small portion of the myriad of taxes, charges and fees paid by the trucking folks every year. The idea that cars cause around 1% of road damage is utterly preposterous. This was a study done by several civil engineers who were more rigorous and suggested that the truck traffic accounted for 75% of highway damage:

&amp;gt;Percent of maintenance costs due to related truck traffic = 1.28/1.7 = 75%. 

&amp;gt;Thus, the average annual maintenance cost per mile of each pavement segment needs to be adjusted by a factor of 75% to isolate damage solely attributed to truck traffic.

(Page 55 and accompanying table showing 4 different road segments)

[Link here](http://matc.unl.edu/assets/documents/finalreports/Bai_EstimatingHighwayPavementDamageCosts.pdf) That still seems high but at least it's not completely laughable like the 99% figure. I'll agree 99% seemed too high to me as well, but for an approximate figure produced by an amateur using fewer figures from 1962 it's not terribly far off. 

Mostly what I got out of the posting was that the weight relationship is not linear and some sort of system that accounts only for fuel usage or miles driven would tend to be wildly inaccurate compared to the costs involved.

A market-based approach would likely be more rigorous, and it seems likely we would rely less on trucking and far more on rail, reducing road deaths, road damage, and pollution. 

Also the fact that the government is considering raising the weight limit significantly on trucks while these states are throwing $100 charges at Hybrid drivers, all of which are far below the average curb weight of the average vehicle? That's ridiculous to me. As a freedom oriented individual I would much rather have the 100 annual fee than a per mile charge. The concept of a government tracking device in my car makes me rage.  I like how it's perceived as some benevolent gift that the government taxes hybrids less.  </snippet></document></searchresult>