<searchresult><anarcho_capitalism /><document><title>The Libertarian Republic now has forum boards, including one for ancaps and voluntaryists.</title><url>http://thelibertarianrepublic.com/forums/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Adam VS the TSA. This is some creepy shit.</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_3ODNwr607E</url><snippet>  I noticed that the more of them that were together, the more aggressive they were toward him. I noticed that the more of them that were together, the more aggressive they were toward him. I noticed that the more of them that were together, the more aggressive they were toward him.  How does Adam Kokesh even sit down with testicles that huge?  How does Adam Kokesh even sit down with testicles that huge?     As much as I hate the TSA, these people are just trying to live their lives and really have nothing to do with the problem. Adam comes across to me as a dick who won't leave people alone. Maybe if he was talking to the people who decide what policies all of their superiors make them comply with I wouldn't think this guy was just a major douchebag.

Like anyone is going to say what you want and admit their job is a farce when it is their livelihood and by saying the wrong thing could be taken away from them. &amp;gt;As much as I hate the TSA, these people are just trying to live their lives and really have nothing to do with the problem.

These people are the pointy end of the stick.  They aren't some person doing clerical work in an office at city hall or a teacher living off of government largess.  These are the ones who would actually initiating physical violence against you.  They deserve no sympathy or respect.

The majority of bureaucrats and voting populace don't have the chutzpah to stick a gun in your face.  These are the pieces of filth that allow bureaucrats and the voting populace to force their will on society.  Saying they are the ones who would actually initiate physical violence against me is going a bit far, many of them seemed like quite nice people and I doubt they would resort to that unless I was being completely irrational. The dude at the end in his face, he probably would, i'll admit that.

You are failing to realize their motivation for "sticking a gun in my face" is because they are being paid to do this job. Does that make them a piece of filth? I guess if that's what you think, but I think most people are behaving rationally given their past experiences and are ultimately just a product of their genes and environment. This is just the line they have fallen in, their life is not under their control. Yeah sure, I would refuse to work any kind of job where I had to enforce policies I believed to be immoral or illogical or whatever, but I feel that very few people that live on this planet are afforded that ability. 

The problem isn't people, the problem is the beliefs and ideas that create a system like this. You need to educate people to get them to change, not ostracize them. Just doing your job is not an excuse.

Source: world war two It is if you were an ally.

Source: WWII Do you not know what sub you're in? I do, don't care though. You might know the name of the sub, but I don't think you have a solid understand of the philosophical underpinnings after that "ally" comment.   USSR commited countless war crimes, they weren't tried for them because they wont the war. Acutally, you didn't even need to be an ally to get an excuse. The people involved with Unit 731 weren't even tried for their war crimes.

The TSA agents are operating within the realm of the law, so why should they even need any excuse? I agree it's unconstitutional, but that doesn't matter in this country, only law. I don't understand why you blame them. If you convince one to quit because what they are doing is wrong, then another person will come to fill their place because it's a rational decision for most people to work there.

If you are going to fix anything, attacking these workers is not going to help.  USSR commited countless war crimes, they weren't tried for them because they wont the war. Acutally, you didn't even need to be an ally to get an excuse. The people involved with Unit 731 weren't even tried for their war crimes.

The TSA agents are operating within the realm of the law, so why should they even need any excuse? I agree it's unconstitutional, but that doesn't matter in this country, only law. I don't understand why you blame them. If you convince one to quit because what they are doing is wrong, then another person will come to fill their place because it's a rational decision for most people to work there.

If you are going to fix anything, attacking these workers is not going to help.  Saying they are the ones who would actually initiate physical violence against me is going a bit far, many of them seemed like quite nice people and I doubt they would resort to that unless I was being completely irrational. The dude at the end in his face, he probably would, i'll admit that.

You are failing to realize their motivation for "sticking a gun in my face" is because they are being paid to do this job. Does that make them a piece of filth? I guess if that's what you think, but I think most people are behaving rationally given their past experiences and are ultimately just a product of their genes and environment. This is just the line they have fallen in, their life is not under their control. Yeah sure, I would refuse to work any kind of job where I had to enforce policies I believed to be immoral or illogical or whatever, but I feel that very few people that live on this planet are afforded that ability. 

The problem isn't people, the problem is the beliefs and ideas that create a system like this. You need to educate people to get them to change, not ostracize them. &amp;gt;Saying they are the ones who would actually initiate physical violence against me is going a bit far,

Bull shit it is.  

&amp;gt;many of them seemed like quite nice people and I doubt they would resort to that unless I was being completely irrational.

If by "completely irrational" you mean minding your own damn business without being groped or having your disabled three year old be detained.

&amp;gt;You are failing to realize their motivation for "sticking a gun in my face" is because they are being paid to do this job. Does that make them a piece of filth?

Yes, people who initiate violence against other people for money are filth.

&amp;gt;The problem isn't people, the problem is the beliefs and ideas that create a system like this. You need to educate people to get them to change, not ostracize them.

Adam was trying to educate them. You saw how well that worked out, you even called him a dick for it.  
 It doesn't work if they don't know what they are doing is wrong.

I get and agree with your logic about freedom, but I really don't think this accomplished anything other than what you already experience by just having been in an airport at any point in the past 10 years. Yeah, they are mindless drones enforcing my enslavement the second they go on the clock, but do I blame them for that, no. If I am being robbed at gunpoint, I'm not even going to blame the guy that's holding me at gunpoint because he is not the problem. The problem is that their environment has put them in a situation where whatever they are doing is rational to them at that point in time. If you want to fix the system, make it irrational to do whatever they are doing. People are automaton; they are not filth, they are not good, they are not evil, these are subjective classifications you are inventing. They take an input of information, and then they act on that information to improve the survival of their genes. This is my perspective on why people act the way they do. The policies he is enforcing and his funding are the disease, he is only the symptom. What's the point in attacking the symptom and not what is causing it? As much as I hate the TSA, these people are just trying to live their lives and really have nothing to do with the problem. Adam comes across to me as a dick who won't leave people alone. Maybe if he was talking to the people who decide what policies all of their superiors make them comply with I wouldn't think this guy was just a major douchebag.

Like anyone is going to say what you want and admit their job is a farce when it is their livelihood and by saying the wrong thing could be taken away from them. &amp;gt;As much as I hate the TSA, these people are just trying to live their lives and really have nothing to do with the problem. 

I get what you're saying, but I think suggesting that they have "nothing to do with the problem" is a bit of a stretch.  They're not the source of the problem, that's true...  they're just regular people pursuing a paycheck to pay the bills like the rest of us.  

I don't blame them for that, just as I don't blame your average Marine for the Iraq War.  However, the ignorant enforcers of corrupt policies and organizations should be put under heavy scrutiny, which in my opinion, is all that's really going on here.

The ignorance that is used to control and regulate the rest of us needs to be exposed on the regular.

&amp;gt;Adam comes across to me as a dick who won't leave people alone. 

To me, he comes across as quality control for a service.  A consumer reporter, if you will.  He's basically trying to find out what kind of value they are providing, for the money they receive in exchange.

Yes, he's a bit "in your face" and aggressive... but that's pretty essential to being an effective investigative journalist.  

&amp;gt;Like anyone is going to say what you want and admit their job is a farce when it is their livelihood and by saying the wrong thing could be taken away from them.

It's an ugly truth that they are unlikely to admit.  I don't think the goal here is to convert TSA employees, but to expose them for the ignorant enforcers of state policy that they are. I agree with absolutely everything you said. I just don't think it's even necessary to interview these people because it only exposes something we already know and only interferes with their lives. I don't like people interfering with my life, so I don't want to do it to others while they are just living their life. &amp;gt;I agree with absolutely everything you said.

I love it when that happens. :-)

&amp;gt;I don't like people interfering with my life, so I don't want to do it to others while they are just living their life.

I hear ya.  The thing is though, The TSA people are making careers out of interfering with peoples lives, in rather aggressive ways.

Putting a camera on that and questioning it is a proper response, in my opinion.  I think monitoring them while they work is a proper response. I do not think asking them questions in this manner will accomplish anything though. 

Maybe if it wasn't a loaded question that forces them to address the illogicalities of their employment you could get some useful information out of them instead of just making them hate you. No, I think harassing them and making their lives uncomfortable is the proper response to people who seek employment where they threaten violence, hassle others, harass others, bully others, and sexually assault others. Merely putting a camera in their face is hardly either of these. Both master and slave are responsible for their conduct; "I was just doing my job" isn't a legitimate excuse for pretty much anything. In our society you don't need excuses for anything so long as you operate within the realm of law, so the argument about excuses doesn't matter. They are operating within the realm of the law, maybe not constitution, but the law is what matters. There are enough people that if a job exist, it will be filled by someone, so blaming the person really isn't an effective strategy for fixing the problem.

It doesn't really seem like any of you care about fixing the problem though, you guys just want to blame and persecute the people that are taking away your freedom.  I think monitoring them while they work is a proper response. I do not think asking them questions in this manner will accomplish anything though. 

Maybe if it wasn't a loaded question that forces them to address the illogicalities of their employment you could get some useful information out of them instead of just making them hate you. As much as I hate the TSA, these people are just trying to live their lives and really have nothing to do with the problem. Adam comes across to me as a dick who won't leave people alone. Maybe if he was talking to the people who decide what policies all of their superiors make them comply with I wouldn't think this guy was just a major douchebag.

Like anyone is going to say what you want and admit their job is a farce when it is their livelihood and by saying the wrong thing could be taken away from them.</snippet></document><document><title>:-) Meeting my own two hero Redditors, Rudd-/throwaway-O and shiinee, for the first time - Thursday 2/21/12 San Francisco, Statist-fornia </title><url>http://imgur.com/a/UojKt</url><snippet>  It's quite disappointing that throwawayo had something of a falling out with /r/anarcho_capitalism. That guy would just flat out beast-mode people.  Yeah, he's a die-hard deontologist.  It doesn't matter on which forum or which obscure comment section under a random news article you were in, if you advocated for the State, he would find you and make you cry.  Hah.

I came on the back end of the controversy, but I'm guessing he started to get disgusted with the growing number of moral nihilists / consequentialists here.  Some of whom I think he thought were dedicated trolls.  Maybe someone who knows more can clarify.  Anyone who wants more details can just search for the few threads, too. The proverbial straw was the Great Spanking Debate.  The proverbial straw was the Great Spanking Debate.  The proverbial straw was the Great Spanking Debate.  Greetings from south-western Ohio! Yeah, he's a die-hard deontologist.  It doesn't matter on which forum or which obscure comment section under a random news article you were in, if you advocated for the State, he would find you and make you cry.  Hah.

I came on the back end of the controversy, but I'm guessing he started to get disgusted with the growing number of moral nihilists / consequentialists here.  Some of whom I think he thought were dedicated trolls.  Maybe someone who knows more can clarify.  Anyone who wants more details can just search for the few threads, too. As far as I know, his leaving was primarily motivated by a discussion we had about six or eight months ago where people said it was okay to beat their own children.

/r/AgainstAllArchons formed out of that. Yeah, I was there.  I don't think everyone was saying it was good to hit children, though a small number might've said that.  I think most people were just giving him a lot of resistance with all the Molyneux idolatry.

Even from a consequentialist standpoint, it's beyond inane to hit your children if you're trying to raise mature, mentally healthy, and productive human beings.  The only forcible thing you really should do is keep them from unintentionally hurting themselves out of toddler ignorance. As far as I know, his leaving was primarily motivated by a discussion we had about six or eight months ago where people said it was okay to beat their own children.

/r/AgainstAllArchons formed out of that. Yeah, he's a die-hard deontologist.  It doesn't matter on which forum or which obscure comment section under a random news article you were in, if you advocated for the State, he would find you and make you cry.  Hah.

I came on the back end of the controversy, but I'm guessing he started to get disgusted with the growing number of moral nihilists / consequentialists here.  Some of whom I think he thought were dedicated trolls.  Maybe someone who knows more can clarify.  Anyone who wants more details can just search for the few threads, too. what's wrong with consequentialism? what's wrong with consequentialism? Yeah, he's a die-hard deontologist.  It doesn't matter on which forum or which obscure comment section under a random news article you were in, if you advocated for the State, he would find you and make you cry.  Hah.

I came on the back end of the controversy, but I'm guessing he started to get disgusted with the growing number of moral nihilists / consequentialists here.  Some of whom I think he thought were dedicated trolls.  Maybe someone who knows more can clarify.  Anyone who wants more details can just search for the few threads, too. [This is my understanding of what went down](http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/unppb/why_not_get_rid_of_the_downvote_button/c4x1rbz).  It's quite disappointing that throwawayo had something of a falling out with /r/anarcho_capitalism. That guy would just flat out beast-mode people.  Yep, and as they treated me to appetizers and drinks [they informed me]* that shiinee is often the one to proofread his ESL posts! Yay teamwork.  Forever an Australian =[ At least you have spiders, mate.  Yay.... =[ Forever an Australian =[ Forever an Australian =[ Join the Australia Mises group. We have yearly meetings/seminars where we get together and bitch about the state. Walter Block was at our last one.

http://www.facebook.com/groups/mises.seminar/ Forever an Australian =[ What is it like being a Voluntarist in Australia? Do you feel as though Australia does some things right compared to America?

According to freeexistence.org Australia is supposedly an overall freer country than America: http://www.freeexistence.org/freedom.shtml?Property=4&amp;amp;DrugRights=4&amp;amp;Taxes=4&amp;amp;Corruption=4&amp;amp;Speech=4&amp;amp;Inflation=4&amp;amp;LtdGovt=4&amp;amp;Business=4&amp;amp;GunRights=4&amp;amp;Reverse=false It could be, though I doubt it. The fact of the matter is though, finding any kind of Libertarian, or even somebody that knows what a Libertarian is, or finding somebody that's ever heard of a Libertarian is nigh impossible. It could be, though I doubt it. The fact of the matter is though, finding any kind of Libertarian, or even somebody that knows what a Libertarian is, or finding somebody that's ever heard of a Libertarian is nigh impossible. It might be relative. It seems Australia's drug laws aren't draconian like America's but when it comes to gun rights they are really strict it seems.

I always hear great things about Australia overall though. Seems like a relatively nice place to live even though its also a tad expensive....ignoring all the stuff that wants to kill you I mean. Yeah, I love living in Australia. Being a Libertarian is hard though, really hard. Still, I plan on moving to Japan for a few months to a year, so that'll probably give me a new appreciation for how relatively EASY it is to be a Libertarian here. What is it like being a Voluntarist in Australia? Do you feel as though Australia does some things right compared to America?

According to freeexistence.org Australia is supposedly an overall freer country than America: http://www.freeexistence.org/freedom.shtml?Property=4&amp;amp;DrugRights=4&amp;amp;Taxes=4&amp;amp;Corruption=4&amp;amp;Speech=4&amp;amp;Inflation=4&amp;amp;LtdGovt=4&amp;amp;Business=4&amp;amp;GunRights=4&amp;amp;Reverse=false  Ron, why didn't you tell us you played Jesse on Breaking Bad?   Which is whiiiiich?  Oh wow, I've yet to meet any ancaps here on the east coast.  The Bronx is a very state worshipping place. Oh wow, I've yet to meet any ancaps here on the east coast.  The Bronx is a very state worshipping place. I haven't met a single ancap IRL, we should meet up at some point. Eventually we'll have to plan some sort of event. I know of one other AnCap living in New Jersey, I'm sure there are more though. Sounds good. For any ancaps living in the NYC area, you can find me on Facebook by searching Will Shanahan. I'm the history and English double major at manhattan college. Dat Bow. hahah Rowing jokes, dig the bow tie I'll have to get myself a yellow and black one at some point if we have a meetup lol  I know which one is throwaway-o.  Is Rudd-/throwaway-o signifying the same person or are you talking about three people not including yourself?  I'm guessing it's just two people and you're the one on the left?

I do like it whenever this group is able to put faces to names though.  Any of you can add me on FB if you want.  Just look up Josh Jeppson and go with the one that says UNCG/NCSU.

Edit:

&amp;gt;Meeting my own **two** hero Redditors.

Forgive me, lol. You got it, Manuel goes by Rudd-O on his blog and on Decline to State,  and throwaway-O here on Reddit. shiinee is his gf with the hat that I'm jealous of. &amp;gt;his (gf with the hat) that I'm jealous of

or

&amp;gt;his gf with (the hat that I'm jealous of)

? :) You got it, Manuel goes by Rudd-O on his blog and on Decline to State,  and throwaway-O here on Reddit. shiinee is his gf with the hat that I'm jealous of. I was confused too, but he cleared it for me, a while back. Nice pictures, now I can finally visualize you Silicon Valley guys :) I know which one is throwaway-o.  Is Rudd-/throwaway-o signifying the same person or are you talking about three people not including yourself?  I'm guessing it's just two people and you're the one on the left?

I do like it whenever this group is able to put faces to names though.  Any of you can add me on FB if you want.  Just look up Josh Jeppson and go with the one that says UNCG/NCSU.

Edit:

&amp;gt;Meeting my own **two** hero Redditors.

Forgive me, lol. I'd imagine you are the only Josh Jeppson in the whole world that is friends with Bob Murphy and Jeffrey Tucker.   &amp;lt;_&amp;lt; Wouldn't happen to be any other AnCaps here in DC would there?

EDIT: If people want to meet offline, just send me a PM with contact info (facebook, email, etc.)  Pretty close yeah! Fairfax VA (also /u/E7ernal is nearby) &amp;lt;_&amp;lt; Wouldn't happen to be any other AnCaps here in DC would there?

EDIT: If people want to meet offline, just send me a PM with contact info (facebook, email, etc.)   I always wondered if [the pic I had](http://i.imgur.com/CqFqOY8.jpg) was actually him.  lol, was that directed at you? No, it wasn't.    You guys are hot shit :P   Obviously everyone should just come get a drink here in Houston. /r/houstonsocials meet up this Tuesday? Where/when? [Richmond arms 7ish](http://www.reddit.com/r/HoustonSocials/comments/18wclg/226_7pm_richmond_arms_meetup/)? Obviously everyone should just come get a drink here in Houston. Think TX's major cities seem to be growing a healthy amount of ancaps.  Is Scott Horton still down there? Think TX's major cities seem to be growing a healthy amount of ancaps.  Is Scott Horton still down there? We were gonna do a Dallas ancap meetup but don't think it ever happened I must have missed that. I'm in Tulsa for the next few months finishing up grad school, but will be moving back to Dallas. Hopefully this summer us Dallas guys can organize something.

Also, I've noticed you are active on /r/coys. I'm a fellow Spurs fan, coys!  Damn, wish I'd have known. I'm up in Lake County. Next meetup country-style?  </snippet></document><document><title>[ELI5] Why do AnCaps, Libertarians etc. value states rights so highly? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/194ha6/eli5_why_do_ancaps_libertarians_etc_value_states/</url><snippet>  Ancaps could care less in theory.  They tend to become apolitical.  That is the general not the rule.  A true libertarian uses it as a strategy and nothing more.  Less people closer to the individual and more likely to get liberty.  That doesn't mean, though is often confused by many, that we should support state tyranny any more than federal. I wouldn't throw out that "true libertarian." You're begging to get 'no true scotsmanned'.

I'd just say that the philosophically consistent position is that only individuals have rights and the states can suck it along with the feds.  Not just states rights, but county and city rights as well. As long as government exists, its best to have it divided up into as many pieces as possible. Some reasons are as follows:

* Somewhat holds back the growth of even larger government
* Better representation in government when power is local
* Increased competition between local governments leads to a more efficient and better product Not just states rights, but county and city rights as well. As long as government exists, its best to have it divided up into as many pieces as possible. Some reasons are as follows:

* Somewhat holds back the growth of even larger government
* Better representation in government when power is local
* Increased competition between local governments leads to a more efficient and better product Not just states rights, but county and city rights as well. As long as government exists, its best to have it divided up into as many pieces as possible. Some reasons are as follows:

* Somewhat holds back the growth of even larger government
* Better representation in government when power is local
* Increased competition between local governments leads to a more efficient and better product              If the states were independent there would be anarchy between the states. Capish?</snippet></document><document><title>Florida doesn't have enough doctors for Medicaid expansion, lobby group says</title><url>http://articles.sun-sentinel.com/2013-02-22/news/fl-doctor-shortage-medicaid-expansion-if-florida-20130222_1_medicaid-expansion-new-medicaid-patients-florida-medical-association</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>To any Bulgarians out there: This website is almost the Bulgarian version of Mises.org</title><url>http://ekipbg.com</url><snippet>  I'd definitely send this to my Bulgarian friend, but it seems to be a little light on introductory content.</snippet></document><document><title>Why organized crime is better than the state</title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Daxa4Ho03O0</url><snippet>  "The mafia actually wants your business to succeed."

That line was just epic, and is not something I really thought about before. But, Boardwalk Empire actually does go into this idea a bit.

EDIT: Wow, I just broke 10,000 comment karma with this post. Thanks everyone! :D   While I think this is amusing and appreciate it as a joke, we should be cautious with rhetoric like this. I do agree with the sentiment that the mafia would be *better* than the state, but I still wouldn't want them controlling things and they do use a fairly large amount of aggression to accomplish things, which is fundamentally no better than the state; even if their outcomes tend to be more efficient. No, I think from now on I shall proudly proclaim that my political philosophy is that the mob should run states.  Saw this one back in 2011 when I was still delving into an-cap thinking from minarchism.  

Good stuff. How long did you take?  Probably 2-4 months.   Also, everybody knows the mafia is just the mafia. It would never gain the size of operations the state has now. I'm guessing it sits in awe of the state and how it has convinced us that we're really "doing this to ourselves".   </snippet></document><document><title>Mark Schmidter Receives 145 Days In Jail For Freedom Of Speech Due To Judge Belvin Perry</title><url>http://voluntaryvirtues.com/2013/02/23/mark-schmidter-receives-145-days-in-jail-for-freedom-of-speech-due-to-judge-belvin-perry/</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Writing on health care</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/193ezn/writing_on_health_care/</url><snippet>How does a hospital differ from  any other private institution?  I understand they are mostly state run, please help.  </snippet></document><document><title>Hi reddit, I'm a student in need of help! Do anybody know the names of some famous capitalists from the 19th century?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/193jpj/hi_reddit_im_a_student_in_need_of_help_do_anybody/</url><snippet>I have searched on google for some answers but I couldn't fint any, so instead I hope you guys could help me out.  Are you looking for capitalists or economists that support capitalism? Because if its the latter, I can give a few examples.

In the 19th century you get some *great* free market thinkers, especially in the French Liberal School. So that'll give you people like Jean-Baptiste Say (the guy who invented the controversial Say's Law of Markets), Frederic Bastiat (the inventor of the broken window fallacy and a very convicted advocate of liberty), and Gustave de Molinari (the first recorded anarcho-capitalist). They'll give you some *great* material.

Furthermore, you also have the birth of the Austrian School of economics with the writings of Carl Menger (the founder of the Austrian School who greatly advanced the theory of marginal utility) and  Eugen von B&#246;hm-Bawerk (who wrote a scathing criticism of Karl Marx with his work [Karl Marx and the Close of His System](http://mises.org/books/karlmarx.pdf)).

If you want more on the history of economics, Murray Rothbard did a particularly detailed look from the beginning of time up until the birth of the Austrian School. I'll link them below.

[Economic Thought Before Adam Smith](http://mises.org/books/histofthought1.pdf)

[Classical Economics](http://library.mises.org/books/Murray%20N%20Rothbard/Austrian%20Perspective%20on%20the%20History%20of%20Economic%20Thought_Vol_2.pdf) I'm looking for the later option, and btw this was very helpful information, thanks!  Dunno if it's what you're looking for but there is Carnegie, Rockefeller, Harriman, and others.     http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:19th-century_economists  </snippet></document><document><title>The Money Masters (1996) [FULL DOCUMENTARY]</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDtBSiI13fE</url><snippet>  I think this movie is quite interesting, and covers a lot of mostly undiscussed history. But I don't like his solution of government created fiat money to replace federal reserve notes. I wish he supported private competing currencies. It was made in 96 The idea wasn't invented since then... Austrians have been talking about it for quite a while, although I suppose the new generation of Austrians hadn't heard of it until after 96. Virtually none of this is Austrian in the slightest. I didn't say it was. I was saying Austrians have talked about private currencies for a long time, long before this movie was made. The history of central banking is quite conspiratorial, which this movie covers well. It offers a shit solution. It was made in 96  </snippet></document><document><title>Herbert Spencer: Social Darwinist or Libertarian Prophet? - Peter Richards</title><url>https://mises.org/daily/4779</url><snippet>  Thank you for posting this&#8212;big fan of Spencer here.   </snippet></document><document><title>Jeffrey "the friar" Tucker is getting excited about Bitcoin</title><url>http://lfb.org/blog/my-new-bitcoin-life/c</url><snippet>  http://lfb.org/blog/my-new-bitcoin-life/ working url  We all start out skeptical of Bitcoin. If you have doubts google them, all the questions have been answered. Bitcoin is one of the most powerful tools we can wield, get into it.

"Truly, no amount of reading on this subject is as convincing  as actually owning and using bitcoins. That&#8217;s when the lights come on. I&#8217;ve not even owned bitcoin for 24 hours and my mind can&#8217;t stop racing about the potential here. It is actually a way for the people to take money back from the state. Remarkable"

Right on!  I'm still a bitcoin skeptic; its anonymizing purpose doesn't seem sufficient to me and there's the inevitable test coming of if it can survive State intervention.

But, I don't expect my caution means much to the current users of it. I'm not a fan of bitcoin either, but I presume it's anonymity function and lack of centralization in production make it unappealing or impossible for the state to "intervene" on it. That however, doesn't mean the IRS can't stick bitcoins on the list of capital gains taxable goods, although I presume the anonymous nature of the bitcoin make it impossible for the state to audit you if you don't claim bitcoin transactions.

What gets me about bitcoin is the *infinite* divisibility of bitcoin. It's great and all to be able to send .05 btc to people, but if we get to the price level of $500 per singular coin, exactly how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors? &amp;gt; how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors?

By using something other than that many zeroes, i.e., "200 uBTC" or "0.20 mBTC" or "2 Chimchams", or labeling it any other way.  Marketers are clever folk:) &amp;gt; how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors?

By using something other than that many zeroes, i.e., "200 uBTC" or "0.20 mBTC" or "2 Chimchams", or labeling it any other way.  Marketers are clever folk:) Fair enough, but wouldn't a market choose the dominant currency to be one that doesn't require measurements a la the metric system? The market tends to like Occam's Razor. Perhaps the market would prefer a currency whose denominations were simple. However, it would be foolish to think that the denominations and subdivisions are the only thing to consider when choosing a currency. The fact that it is easy to work with and cheap and instant probably have a much greater pull on a currency's viability. &amp;gt; However, it would be foolish to think that the denominations and subdivisions are the only thing to consider when choosing a currency.

This is actually a huge problem with the gold and silver currency movement. People are inherently confused as to how to denominate their worth in terms of gold and silver. Even if you do it by the ounce, that still means you have to figure out how to sell your goods and services in $1700 and $30 multiples, which can be done but it takes practice. People have to learn how to handle a currency and judge the value of it's denominations in such a way to use it in life.

I would argue that bitcoins have the inverse problem with divisibility. The infinite divisibility makes things incredibly complicated, and given how few people I know that can do scientific notation, I'm not quite sure these same people could figure out that .0002 bitcoin / 2 uBTC is worth anything meaningful, or figure out in scale how much more worth comes out of 1 more uBTC or 1 mBTC.

&amp;gt; The fact that it is easy to work with and cheap and instant probably have a much greater pull on a currency's viability.

This is true, but wouldn't it be simpler for me to write an IOU than boot up my computer and browser and type in a 60 character address, and simpler for the other person because he / she doesn't have to wait for the transaction to pass the blockchain? &amp;gt; However, it would be foolish to think that the denominations and subdivisions are the only thing to consider when choosing a currency.

This is actually a huge problem with the gold and silver currency movement. People are inherently confused as to how to denominate their worth in terms of gold and silver. Even if you do it by the ounce, that still means you have to figure out how to sell your goods and services in $1700 and $30 multiples, which can be done but it takes practice. People have to learn how to handle a currency and judge the value of it's denominations in such a way to use it in life.

I would argue that bitcoins have the inverse problem with divisibility. The infinite divisibility makes things incredibly complicated, and given how few people I know that can do scientific notation, I'm not quite sure these same people could figure out that .0002 bitcoin / 2 uBTC is worth anything meaningful, or figure out in scale how much more worth comes out of 1 more uBTC or 1 mBTC.

&amp;gt; The fact that it is easy to work with and cheap and instant probably have a much greater pull on a currency's viability.

This is true, but wouldn't it be simpler for me to write an IOU than boot up my computer and browser and type in a 60 character address, and simpler for the other person because he / she doesn't have to wait for the transaction to pass the blockchain? Divisibility is generally considered one of the defining characteristics of a "good" currency. What exactly is the problem? The problem is that they're so infinitely divisible that average people can't gauge value of bitcoins.

It's like when I hear about people saying bitcoin is $X. Is that good? What size of bitcoins is the average trade? Gold is, in a practical sense, infinitely divisible. Many historians argue that humanities first currency may have been something like salt BECAUSE it was so divisible. Fair enough, but wouldn't a market choose the dominant currency to be one that doesn't require measurements a la the metric system? The market tends to like Occam's Razor. I'm not a fan of bitcoin either, but I presume it's anonymity function and lack of centralization in production make it unappealing or impossible for the state to "intervene" on it. That however, doesn't mean the IRS can't stick bitcoins on the list of capital gains taxable goods, although I presume the anonymous nature of the bitcoin make it impossible for the state to audit you if you don't claim bitcoin transactions.

What gets me about bitcoin is the *infinite* divisibility of bitcoin. It's great and all to be able to send .05 btc to people, but if we get to the price level of $500 per singular coin, exactly how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors? I'm not a fan of bitcoin either, but I presume it's anonymity function and lack of centralization in production make it unappealing or impossible for the state to "intervene" on it. That however, doesn't mean the IRS can't stick bitcoins on the list of capital gains taxable goods, although I presume the anonymous nature of the bitcoin make it impossible for the state to audit you if you don't claim bitcoin transactions.

What gets me about bitcoin is the *infinite* divisibility of bitcoin. It's great and all to be able to send .05 btc to people, but if we get to the price level of $500 per singular coin, exactly how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors? &amp;gt;What gets me about bitcoin is the infinite divisibility of bitcoin.

What bothers me is the fact that its not a consumption good in itself; so, I have no idea how it can technically get priced into the market.  Not having that ability relegates a currency to rollercoaster values and eventually, with a wild enough swing, a hypercollapse.

What the bitcoin enthusiasts counterclaim is that its anonymizing ability *is* that consumption value, but I'm not quite as impressed.

I'm also bothered that it seems its the softer-headed segment of the ancap crowd, who need there to be some kind of technological progress into anarcho-capitalism, that are disproportionately going along with bitcoin.  I don't really put Tucker in that group.  He knows enough economics; either he's caring to ignore some of his principles for the same reason as the soft-headed crowd, or I'm just wrong about this consumption thing.

Tom Woods has recently decided to look into the bitcoin issue, too; I really look forward to what he has to say. I'm not a fan of bitcoin either, but I presume it's anonymity function and lack of centralization in production make it unappealing or impossible for the state to "intervene" on it. That however, doesn't mean the IRS can't stick bitcoins on the list of capital gains taxable goods, although I presume the anonymous nature of the bitcoin make it impossible for the state to audit you if you don't claim bitcoin transactions.

What gets me about bitcoin is the *infinite* divisibility of bitcoin. It's great and all to be able to send .05 btc to people, but if we get to the price level of $500 per singular coin, exactly how are you going to market goods at .0002 btc and expect that to make sense to non math-majors?  While I am not using it yet, I started mining a bit to see what it is all about. The price is quite insane now, I never thought it would go this high (and it is only at 50% potential from what I understand). While I am not using it yet, I started mining a bit to see what it is all about. The price is quite insane now, I never thought it would go this high (and it is only at 50% potential from what I understand). when bitcoins are fully mined out there will be 260 oz of gold for every 1 bitcoin in existence. if people seriously take interest in bitcoin that may give an idea of where it could go in terms of value. Why does the amount of gold matter? Can't someone makes some other type of bitcoin that does the same thing? Making it somewhat like fiat currency.  bitcoin has the network effect and some other currency would have to be "better" than bitcoin for anyone to care. Bitcoin shares a lot of properties with gold, and thus logically a lot of people who would be attracted to gold will be attracted to bitcoin once it can demonstrate a solid history. the reason the amount of gold matters is that bitcoin could eventually displace a significant portion of the gold market for "savings". How hard would it be to make a bitcoin like program? Bitcoins are just a program though. Very different from gold which is a commodity.  its open source, so you can just change the genesis block and create a whole new bitcoin-like currency. but nobody will care about it because it will be a different block-chain and incompatible. there is this thing called a network effect, which bitcoin has, and which any clones will not have. why would anyone use your bitcoin-like program when nobody else uses it, and meanwhile there is bitcoin existing and being used by people? also many bitcoiners regard bitcoin as a commodity. How hard would it be to make a bitcoin like program? Bitcoins are just a program though. Very different from gold which is a commodity.  How hard would it be to make a bitcoin like program? Bitcoins are just a program though. Very different from gold which is a commodity.  While I am not using it yet, I started mining a bit to see what it is all about. The price is quite insane now, I never thought it would go this high (and it is only at 50% potential from what I understand). I'm confused, how does bitcoin mining work? I'm confused, how does bitcoin mining work?  How can a currency that goes from $3 to $30 in one year, then from $30 to $3 the next, then back to $30 the next can be considered a 'stable' currency?

Look guys, I am all for an anonymous currency and one that nobody can print, but speculation has to end at one point.

Is it a good idea to have a currency fluctuate like the stock market? 

As a toy coin for sudden gain/loss it may be good, but for measuring the output of an economy not so.

 How can a currency that goes from $3 to $30 in one year, then from $30 to $3 the next, then back to $30 the next can be considered a 'stable' currency?

Look guys, I am all for an anonymous currency and one that nobody can print, but speculation has to end at one point.

Is it a good idea to have a currency fluctuate like the stock market? 

As a toy coin for sudden gain/loss it may be good, but for measuring the output of an economy not so.

  Jeff is a bourgeois douche He still dresses better than you. Jeff is a bourgeois douche If Jeff is a bourgeois douche, I'm a bourgeois douche too.</snippet></document><document><title>Student Grills Neocon John Bolton On Drones: &#8220;If YOU were identified as a threat by some nameless official in the administration, would YOU want due process?&#8221;</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DbeLJCiqm-I&amp;amp;feature=share</url><snippet>  That ending was much more interesting than the part hinted at in the title. "You know, if you want to discredit a movement - defend the confederacy"  What a fucking stupid, trite, anti-intellectual statement. That ending was much more interesting than the part hinted at in the title. "You know, if you want to discredit a movement - defend the confederacy"  What a fucking stupid, trite, anti-intellectual statement. Not to mention that defending the confederacy is rather easy from a libertarian POV...  We're not technically defending the Confederacy; just the Confederacy's *singular* act of seceding.

The Confederate constitution definitely had its problems and their government [managed that war absolutely horrifically](http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6F841BF6F4AE9CED).  There was no reason why they should've lost it going in, given the terms of success for each side. We're not technically defending the Confederacy; just the Confederacy's *singular* act of seceding.

The Confederate constitution definitely had its problems and their government [managed that war absolutely horrifically](http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6F841BF6F4AE9CED).  There was no reason why they should've lost it going in, given the terms of success for each side. Not to mention that defending the confederacy is rather easy from a libertarian POV...  Could someone lay out some arguments for defending the confederacy - I've read too much propaganda that vilifies them. Could someone lay out some arguments for defending the confederacy - I've read too much propaganda that vilifies them. What exactly are you expecting us to defend? I'm not sure that's why I'm asking... I assume it won't be slavery. That's a pretty safe assumption.

Basically, the argument goes, States were allowed to sucede from the U.S., the Confederacy did that, and were attacked. The Civil War was not a Civil War at all, but a case of one State (the U.S.) violently annexing another (The Confederacy). Of course people say the South started the war by firing on the US troops (ignoring the fact that the Northern troops moved further south into a southern fort after the succession) Lincoln was a master politician with that move.

I recommend checking out Thornton's playlist on the economics of the Civil War I linked earlier. That ending was much more interesting than the part hinted at in the title. "You know, if you want to discredit a movement - defend the confederacy"  What a fucking stupid, trite, anti-intellectual statement. Came here to say this.  Way to appeal to the ignorant masses that have no understanding of the non-federalist stance, make an argument with no chance for reply, and "win" the debate in his mind with a false statement he most likely **does** understand the nuance of. &amp;gt;with a false statement he most likely does understand the nuance of

That was his point.  He believes unpopular nuanced positions should simply be abandoned.  Practically every neocon or supposedly fiscal conservative checks that one off. Read your statement 5 times and don't know if I am thick headed or it's the internet factor, but what do you mean by the following:

&amp;gt;Practically every neocon or supposedly fiscal conservative checks that one off.

And is "he" the guy in the video or Washbag? That ending was much more interesting than the part hinted at in the title. "You know, if you want to discredit a movement - defend the confederacy"  What a fucking stupid, trite, anti-intellectual statement.  Interesting how killing tens of thousands of Americans was the "right thing to do". Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power. &amp;gt;Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power.

It's not "can," but "often do" because of the inherent incentives. Interesting how killing tens of thousands of Americans was the "right thing to do". Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power. Interesting how killing tens of thousands of Americans was the "right thing to do". Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power. Just because someone wrote it in the constitution does not mean individuals have an ethica and moral right to carry out the actions allowable therein.  Well the constitution means nothing to me or any ancap I would imagine Just because someone wrote it in the constitution does not mean individuals have an ethica and moral right to carry out the actions allowable therein.  Also, in this particular case, the constitution *was* in fact on "our side." Interesting how killing tens of thousands of Americans was the "right thing to do". Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power. Interesting how killing tens of thousands of Americans was the "right thing to do". Its fucking scary what type of people can get into positions of power. If you're talking about the Civil War, it's about 620,000 people killed.  If you're talking about the Civil War, it's about 620,000 people killed.  Yes but one could make the argument that since many of those were Federals, they cannot be counted among the "killed," even if they were conscripted (and of course, many of them *were* volunteers). Additionally, most of the 620,000 (or 800,000 according to some modern numbers floating around) died from disease and hence also might not be accurately classified as American citizens killed without due process. As I recall, the American Civil War was one of the first wars where combat deaths were confirmed to exceed deaths from disease contracted in army and navy camps and quarters. There were tens of thousands of civilians killed, most in the South, many during Sherman's campaign to Atlanta.  No. Disease accounts for a majority of Civil War deaths.  

Civilian deaths numbered around 50,000 and almost entirely consisted of Southerners. However, despite the suffering caused by the March to the Sea, it appears that relatively few civilian deaths (and death's in general) were caused by the March.

(source: James McPherson's *Battle Cry of Freedom*) You're right. For the North, almost half of their fatal casualties were resulting from battle. For the South, however, disease was the far greater killer. Both sides also held prison camps in squalid conditions, the South lacking sufficient supplies to keep the prisoners consistently nourished, and the North seeking retribution on Southern prisoners.  &amp;gt;and the North seeking retribution on Southern prisoners.

I'm not sure how wide-spread this is or if it is really the cause of any substantial number of deaths. There were many epidemics in camps and the Federal camps were horribly supplied as well (like the Southern camps). Just look at numbers of deaths among the Federal troops manning the camps; they are quite appalling. I simplified it somewhat, but the squalor in Northern prison camps was more often a result of punitive action against the prisoners, whereas the South was merely chronically undersupplied. Even Southern soldiers would notoriously sometimes subsist on ~1000 kcals a day or less, all while marching and navigating bush.

Nice that we can have this back and forth without slinging shit. Sometimes, I can surprise myself! &amp;gt;squalor in Northern prison camps was more often a result of punitive action against the prisoners

This seems unlikely to me. I'd really like to see some sources on this.  I've never heard someone defend the Civil War that poorly. It's said that many people only see violence as the best option to solve a problem. I think a lot of people just don't have much imagination when it comes to alternative historical scenarios.  They can imagine "Abraham Lincoln:  Vampire Hunter", but they can't imagine "Abraham Lincoln:  President Who Graciously Allowed States to Secede". I think a lot of people just don't have much imagination when it comes to alternative historical scenarios.  They can imagine "Abraham Lincoln:  Vampire Hunter", but they can't imagine "Abraham Lincoln:  President Who Graciously Allowed States to Secede".  I will never, ever, EVER accept that death and violence are an answer nor the "right thing to do." That is not our call to make. What a damningly shameful statement for Bolton to make. Nauseating.  Wow, what a fucking psychopath... Wow, what a fucking psychopath...    Where's the full episode of this?  I saw the Coulter one and enjoyed it, too.

My quip to Bolton is, if you want to destroy a movement even faster, completely contradict your principles; your movement will instantly evaporate. You misspelled "get elected en masse."  Get elected en masse by contradicting your principles?  What kind of 'victory' is that?

You think the people who put you in power aren't going to notice you're not who you said you were?  Or, more importantly, the entrenched interests aren't going to have an incentive to take you out?  That's like Molyneux's disbanding the Catholic church quote.

The real problem is the ideas in the masses' heads, not being in political office or not. You misspelled "get elected en masse."   </snippet></document><document><title>Anarcho-Elitism | SLA</title><url>http://sexliesanarchy.com/2012/02/03/episode-35---anarcho-elitism/</url><snippet>   After being recommended to check these three out, I have to say I'm really impressed with the level of dialogue.  The content isn't just the thundering of the same talking points, but very organic.

I also am very grateful for their kind of 'post-libertarian' direction.  It makes for a less boring program to listen to for people who've been an ancap for some time now.

Some of you certainly are already familiar with the show, but a search of this subreddit reveals no posts of them.  I think they deserve many more listeners.  Enjoy.  </snippet></document><document><title>If America Was A Startup We&#8217;d All Quit</title><url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/22/america-startup-quit/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</url><snippet>  This is true.

The reason political debates involve such harsh feelings is that the winner decides the fate of 300 million citizens, whether the citizens like it or not. In contrast, no one cares what startups do because people only opt in to use a startup's product; it is not forced on anyone.

Our government is poorly run, and with sufficiently low transaction costs, we would all move elsewhere. (Transaction costs include the cost of moving, learning a new language, making new friends, finding a new job, and so on and so forth.) The winner doesn't decide anything, congress does. This myth -- about how much worth there is in the punching bag called the "President" -- needs to end.

Every four years they kick the can down the road a little bit and feign progress towards a better future while inflating the defense and healthcare debts for the benefit of their criminal buddies. These elections that decide the fate of 300 million citizens are a facade in the same way the whitehouse.gov petitions are a facade -- voting in those petitions has the same effect as voting in real life.

Congress moves at a snails pace and it has done so since the beginning, the only reason we're stuck with this shit sandwich is because nobody cares about their elected State representatives or the Senate. The presidential election is a dog and pony show. &amp;gt;The winner doesn't decide anything, congress does. 

Congress doesn't decide anything.  The kleptocrats who pay bribes to Congress decide things.

Congress wanders around saying things like, "We have to pass the bill to find out what's in it." The winner doesn't decide anything, congress does. This myth -- about how much worth there is in the punching bag called the "President" -- needs to end.

Every four years they kick the can down the road a little bit and feign progress towards a better future while inflating the defense and healthcare debts for the benefit of their criminal buddies. These elections that decide the fate of 300 million citizens are a facade in the same way the whitehouse.gov petitions are a facade -- voting in those petitions has the same effect as voting in real life.

Congress moves at a snails pace and it has done so since the beginning, the only reason we're stuck with this shit sandwich is because nobody cares about their elected State representatives or the Senate. The presidential election is a dog and pony show. This is true.

The reason political debates involve such harsh feelings is that the winner decides the fate of 300 million citizens, whether the citizens like it or not. In contrast, no one cares what startups do because people only opt in to use a startup's product; it is not forced on anyone.

Our government is poorly run, and with sufficiently low transaction costs, we would all move elsewhere. (Transaction costs include the cost of moving, learning a new language, making new friends, finding a new job, and so on and so forth.)    Eventually, people will come to realize that P2P government is the solution to this current malaise.      </snippet></document><document><title>If someone owes you money, can you use force to collect the debt?  </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/192cf4/if_someone_owes_you_money_can_you_use_force_to/</url><snippet>If someone is refusing to pay their debt, are you allowed to use violence against them?  Or, must you simply accept the money as lost?    I don't think so. You can use social ostracism and other voluntary means, but you cannot forcefully collect from him. In the future, you should probably get insurance or collateral as a condition of a contract. Also possibly inform the borrower's bank about the contract he had signed and work it out that way if the person refuses to pay back the loan. But I agree that allowing the use force to collect debts leads down a dangerous road. That's a good addition. I am sure many banks would have in their contracts that they will turn over property if they are presented with a legitimate award of damages (which they will probably defined). Just like they do now. I think it's unlikely banks would do this without being forced to by government.  A customer will choose the bank that has the most favorable agreement for them. Some will and some won't. Banks seem to value appearing to be part of the community quite a bit to their customers. I'm not so sure all banks would be so willing to shield property of a person who is subject of a widely recognized award or debt.

&amp;gt;A customer will choose the bank that has the most favorable agreement for them.

A customer will make a cost benefit analysis. If the person you are negotiating a contract with has most of his property in a bank that does not honor awards or recognized debts, my guess is that his costs will go up (to cover insurance or put up collateral). That's a good point.  I did not consider the possibility that a creditor would require (or encourage by means of a lower interest rate) a debtor to have his assets in a bank that recognizes the validity of the debt.  Creditors doing no actual checks of assets is probably due to the artificially easy credit we have now. I think it's unlikely banks would do this without being forced to by government.  A customer will choose the bank that has the most favorable agreement for them. I think it's unlikely banks would do this without being forced to by government.  A customer will choose the bank that has the most favorable agreement for them. You show up here now? Welcome! That's a good addition. I am sure many banks would have in their contracts that they will turn over property if they are presented with a legitimate award of damages (which they will probably defined). Just like they do now. I agree with your initial comment, but disagree with the idea of banks. Banks taking money (outside of a contract with the depositor) would be just another form of violence. 

besides that, if there was a bank requiring you to surrender what you deposit to the first person that comes along with a judgement order, then I will create a bank that promises to protect peoples deposits from everyone. Who wouldn't wish to have their money safe in my bank with me on their side? I don't think so. You can use social ostracism and other voluntary means, but you cannot forcefully collect from him. In the future, you should probably get insurance or collateral as a condition of a contract. Force is needed to expropriate the collateral.  whatever the terms of the contract that for the loan presumably specify, i would imagine that violence as a means to collect debt would be something very rare, if its even profitable to collect debt that way  You can do whatever you want. The question is how the rest of society will react. Its highly unlikely that the rest of society would tolerate you going on a killing spree to collect some 2 dollar debts form your high school buddies.  No. Lending has risks, you should assume them.  Welching on a debt is similar to theft, so some (reasonable) coercion can be used to collect from unwilling debtors. Of course, there must also be some manner of bankruptcy procedure for unresolvable debt.

Otherwise, no one could ever safely lend money, which would be bad!  There are incentives to pay back loans other than coercion, such as the ability to incur future debt or be a valued member of your community.    In short, yes, but it depends.  More like a definite maybe.      The Amish don't. Let's all live like backwards cultists. The Amish make a choice to live without many of the benefits of modern technology. That does not mean we should ignore their example as a functioning free and Voluntary society.

70% of the Amish own their own business. Many of the rest work for their parents and will inherit their businesses. They do quite well selling fine-crafted furniture that end up in markets all over the world.

Each Amish community follows a written document called the Ordnung, a set of rules for the society. The Ordnung can be altered after careful deliberation. Any member of the community can petition to change the Ordnung, as they did when they changed it to allow phones to be installed outside their houses so they could conduct their business. This does not mean the Amish live in a "free and voluntary society."  I've had money stolen under the false pretense of "needing a loan," and never having any intention of paying it back.  One of my friends lost around $8k to someone that way.

That technically also qualifies as "fraud" however, I don't think playing "define the label" is necessary to recognize the above situation has a strong element of injustice and harm. You should have had a contract. Obviously that's ideal, however many/most frauds are perpetuated without a contract.              </snippet></document><document><title>New Plan to Create a Special Economic Zone on Native American Lands.  Board of Advisors includes Kinsella and Block.</title><url>http://www.generalgovernance.com/Advisors.html</url><snippet>  Get ready for "Trail of Tears 2.0" if this happens.  The website is so vague that it is impossible to determine the actual development plan. Casinos? Peyote? Suburbs? Why not all three? Because the guy in the thumbnail looks too young to see an R rated movie.  The website is so vague that it is impossible to determine the actual development plan. Casinos? Peyote? Suburbs?  ...and also includes a DHS bureaucrat as Governance Advisor who "brings a lifetime of government program planning, efficiency management, and policy knowledge to General Governance"  :( ...and also includes a DHS bureaucrat as Governance Advisor who "brings a lifetime of government program planning, efficiency management, and policy knowledge to General Governance"  :( &amp;gt; brings a lifetime of government program planning

The problem with the government is that it plans, but never executes (unless we are talking about *people*). &amp;gt; brings a lifetime of government program planning

The problem with the government is that it plans, but never executes (unless we are talking about *people*). &amp;gt; brings a lifetime of government program planning

The problem with the government is that it plans, but never executes (unless we are talking about *people*). ...and also includes a DHS bureaucrat as Governance Advisor who "brings a lifetime of government program planning, efficiency management, and policy knowledge to General Governance"  :(  "on Native American Lands"... so... the entire North America?</snippet></document><document><title>City considering privatizing police 911 dispatching services (the people who man the phones).</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/192fvr/city_considering_privatizing_police_911/</url><snippet>

["Current dispatchers have had a lukewarm reaction to the proposal, saying they don&#8217;t know enough about iXP and the pay and benefits the company will offer."](http://www.nj.com/mercer/index.ssf/2013/01/lawrence_may_become_first_in_n.html)

Because the pay and benefits are clearly the number one priority when trying to determine how to privatize an emergency service...  I do think we need to be careful about calling things like this 'privatization'. Sure, the company is hiring the workers and such, but the company itself is getting paid and contracted by the state through tax funding. Really this is just putting an extra middle-man between the tax money and the end service. Granted, that middle-man is probably going to be a lot more efficient than a government bureaucrat, so it will probably work better, but in the end it's actually not the privatization that we ultimately want. Step in the right direction? Possibly, depends on how it's handled. Things like this can easily backfire as well. (see private prisons) I do think we need to be careful about calling things like this 'privatization'. Sure, the company is hiring the workers and such, but the company itself is getting paid and contracted by the state through tax funding. Really this is just putting an extra middle-man between the tax money and the end service. Granted, that middle-man is probably going to be a lot more efficient than a government bureaucrat, so it will probably work better, but in the end it's actually not the privatization that we ultimately want. Step in the right direction? Possibly, depends on how it's handled. Things like this can easily backfire as well. (see private prisons) I do think we need to be careful about calling things like this 'privatization'. Sure, the company is hiring the workers and such, but the company itself is getting paid and contracted by the state through tax funding. Really this is just putting an extra middle-man between the tax money and the end service. Granted, that middle-man is probably going to be a lot more efficient than a government bureaucrat, so it will probably work better, but in the end it's actually not the privatization that we ultimately want. Step in the right direction? Possibly, depends on how it's handled. Things like this can easily backfire as well. (see private prisons)</snippet></document><document><title>Immigration Threatens Despots: "The walls in the United States that keep OUT also keep people IN. The ability to leave radically changes the dynamic between a people and its government."</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I983DHDok2w&amp;amp;feature=share</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Discussion about "what is anarchy" over at /r/philosophy. Sadly full of 2nd year philosophy student's misconceptions, especially about ancaps</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/philosophy/comments/1901jl/i_have_some_questions_about_anarchy/</url><snippet>  You'll never get left anarchists to stop arguing about "you're not a real anarchist" long enough to get anywhere. They are hung up on style, labels and language, no big surprise considering their double-think historical roots. Private capital isn't going away. They aren't even a credible threat to individual liberty. It has nothing to do with style or labels, it has to do with the feeling that a lot of us get that most of the ancaps we encounter haven't actually read any Marx.  Marx has offered a critique of why capitalist relations are not voluntary, so every time an ancap takes it as axiomatic that they are and gets confused when that is challenged, it tells us that they haven't taken the time to understand basic anarchist theory and are therefore in no position to be having a serious discussion about it. It has nothing to do with style or labels, it has to do with the feeling that a lot of us get that most of the ancaps we encounter haven't actually read any Marx.  Marx has offered a critique of why capitalist relations are not voluntary, so every time an ancap takes it as axiomatic that they are and gets confused when that is challenged, it tells us that they haven't taken the time to understand basic anarchist theory and are therefore in no position to be having a serious discussion about it. It's amazing that people still take Marx seriously, seeing as how he based his entire argument in Das Kapital on the labor theory of value.

By all right, Marx should have died in 1896 with the publishing of [Karl Marx and the Close of His System](http://mises.org/books/karlmarx.pdf), or at the very least with Mises' [Socialism](http://mises.org/books/socialism.pdf). It has nothing to do with style or labels, it has to do with the feeling that a lot of us get that most of the ancaps we encounter haven't actually read any Marx.  Marx has offered a critique of why capitalist relations are not voluntary, so every time an ancap takes it as axiomatic that they are and gets confused when that is challenged, it tells us that they haven't taken the time to understand basic anarchist theory and are therefore in no position to be having a serious discussion about it. I guarantee that far more ancaps have read Marx than ancoms have read Mises, or for that matter any fucking economic textbook that isn't a leftist echo-chamber. Oh yeah? So you took a survey or something? Could I see the methodology on that?  Oh, you mean you have nothing to base that on other than your own prejudices?  I'm sorry but I don't have time to debate people with so little capacity for critical thought that they confuse baseless assertion with serious discussion. You don't need a survey to know this. It's blindingly obvious by most of their arguments. Oh yeah? So you took a survey or something? Could I see the methodology on that?  Oh, you mean you have nothing to base that on other than your own prejudices?  I'm sorry but I don't have time to debate people with so little capacity for critical thought that they confuse baseless assertion with serious discussion. Wait just a minute here:

In your previous comment, you baselessly asserted that ancaps haven't read Marx, and when an ancap tells you that Marxists-Anarchists haven't read Mises, you get all worked up and call him out for a baseless assertion?

Pot calling the kettle black if I've ever seen it. Oh yeah? So you took a survey or something? Could I see the methodology on that?  Oh, you mean you have nothing to base that on other than your own prejudices?  I'm sorry but I don't have time to debate people with so little capacity for critical thought that they confuse baseless assertion with serious discussion. It has nothing to do with style or labels, it has to do with the feeling that a lot of us get that most of the ancaps we encounter haven't actually read any Marx.  Marx has offered a critique of why capitalist relations are not voluntary, so every time an ancap takes it as axiomatic that they are and gets confused when that is challenged, it tells us that they haven't taken the time to understand basic anarchist theory and are therefore in no position to be having a serious discussion about it. "Putting a gun to your head" and "refusing to share my wealth" aren't the same things. One is involuntary and the other is voluntary. If you don't understand that, you are in no position to have a serious discussion about free market capitalism. I can tell that you haven't read Marx because you can't even properly characterize our position to argue against it.  Do you see why it's difficult to have a discussion that way?  You've attacked a straw man, not my ideas, so I have no response. So you agree with me then? Cool. I hope you're just being flippant and that's not your actual response.  If that's really what you got out of my comment then it seems you're an intellectual coward who prefers the warm comfort of self-deception over the uncomfortable but critical task of self-reflection and self-questioning.   I am not agreeing with you, I think you know that, but if you don't wish to subject your ideas to scrutiny by having a serious discussion then I suppose there's not much I can do about that. I hope you're just being flippant and that's not your actual response.  If that's really what you got out of my comment then it seems you're an intellectual coward who prefers the warm comfort of self-deception over the uncomfortable but critical task of self-reflection and self-questioning.   I am not agreeing with you, I think you know that, but if you don't wish to subject your ideas to scrutiny by having a serious discussion then I suppose there's not much I can do about that. are you a representative of all of them? cuz i hear "not giving me food is the same as pointing a gun to my head" all the time in /r/anarchism You must be able to point to dozens of examples, huh? It has nothing to do with style or labels, it has to do with the feeling that a lot of us get that most of the ancaps we encounter haven't actually read any Marx.  Marx has offered a critique of why capitalist relations are not voluntary, so every time an ancap takes it as axiomatic that they are and gets confused when that is challenged, it tells us that they haven't taken the time to understand basic anarchist theory and are therefore in no position to be having a serious discussion about it. I've also read Marx. He does not successfully argue what you claim he does. Plus he often contradicts himself, even within the same work. "Never trust a bourgeois"

*IS* bourgeois

I think this was my favorite contradiction of Communist Manifesto.

And considering that he lived in the top 2% (Born into money, leeched off Engle and basically never had a job, aside from freelance writing for the bourgeoisie), he basically is the "useful idiot" he seems to advocate on using. &amp;gt;I think this was my favorite contradiction of Communist Manifesto.

Yeah, but didn't you know you're a Jew and thus incapable of understanding [his logic](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polylogism). You'll never get left anarchists to stop arguing about "you're not a real anarchist" long enough to get anywhere. They are hung up on style, labels and language, no big surprise considering their double-think historical roots. Private capital isn't going away. They aren't even a credible threat to individual liberty.  Guys, quit it with the fucking downvoting. You're not helping us seem credible, quite the opposite.

Whatever, this sub is slowly becoming a joke. I hope not. I started coming here after I realized /r/Libertarian became overrun by minarchists (at best) and Republicans (at worst).  I hope not. I started coming here after I realized /r/Libertarian became overrun by minarchists (at best) and Republicans (at worst).  Guys, quit it with the fucking downvoting. You're not helping us seem credible, quite the opposite.

Whatever, this sub is slowly becoming a joke. Thank you for this.

I try to remind myself that you guys aren't all asshole SRS style downvote brigades. Unfortunately, the few of you that I do enjoy discussing matters with, the calm and reasonable ones that enjoy interchanging ideas with the intent of expanding our horizons, don't follow the SRS style downvote brigades. Guys, quit it with the fucking downvoting. You're not helping us seem credible, quite the opposite.

Whatever, this sub is slowly becoming a joke. &amp;gt;Whatever, this sub is slowly becoming a joke.

[D':](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yn0Zbg5TVy4&amp;amp;t=40s) Not sure what hurts more, this sub going to hell, or listening to this song. Allow me to [redeem myself](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=esGP1PdNBgs&amp;amp;t=1m28s), sir. "Dead Fe&#8224;us - SL&#7530;&#8371;VE 4 U" What a title. Only the [best industrial](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qDiWd1P8PHs&amp;amp;t=17s) for you, my friend.  I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   If they don't like hierarchy, then they shouldn't use computer in the first place. The file system is hierarchy. Internet is hierarchy. Reddit is hierarchy. And so forth.



 If they don't like hierarchy, then they shouldn't use computer in the first place. The file system is hierarchy. Internet is hierarchy. Reddit is hierarchy. And so forth.



 I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   &amp;gt;Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.

Leftists only care about economics as an after thought really.  They spend more time beating the social justice drum. I beg to differ that us lefties don't think about economics.

http://www.mutualist.org/sitebuildercontent/sitebuilderfiles/MPE.pdf

and not to forget [Parecon](http://www.amazon.com/Parecon-After-Capitalism-Michael-Albert/dp/185984698X)
 Carson was really the only one to my knowledge who tried to attack the Austrians on their own ground.  He was still unable to rescue the LTV, though many Austrians like [Block respect his attempt](http://mises.org/journals/jls/20_1/20_1_4.pdf).

As far as the other work, I'm not familiar with it.  A few reviews in that link say it uses a moral foundation as its starting point.  If that's true, how is that good economic theory? I disagree that Carson was unable to save LTV.

Parecon does have moral foundation but so does every other economic theory. You cant possibly pretend that austrian, keynesian or chicago school economics dont have moral implications. Well, [Mises' position](http://mises.org/humanaction/chap39sec2.asp) was Moral Nihilism.  The Austrian purist position is Moral Nihilism.  Henry Hazlitt was also a consequentialist in this respect, too.  Mises didn't say Austrian economics leads to classical liberal conclusions, but Austrian economics taken with his preferences led him to personally advocate for classical liberalism.

Nielsio [does a great job](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fCUvlfOWL0U&amp;amp;list=PLA7FF865D89D7720C) compiling Austrian work in and explaining himself what morality is to Austrians. I wonder how NAP and private property makes it into this moral nihilism. Well, consequentialist ancaps advise the NAP as an effective legal principle.  They also believe open markets tend to naturally approximate the NAP simply because it elicits the most cooperation and is, thus, the most productive and self-reinforcing.

It's the same with private property.

But, the above implies a person wants productivity.  This is a subjective preference, one I, Mises, and many others have.  We like the productivity and we like it when people are freest to self-actualize themselves for a happier existence.

However, none of that is handled within economic science; it is value-free.  This is why I said Austrian economics does not lead one to conclude classical liberalism or anarcho-capitalism; we come to those conclusions by informing our subjective preferences with an amoral economic framework.

This is like using physics to inform one how best to build an airplane.  Science doesn't tell us to build airplanes; that's a separate, human input.

 I don't get how people can be against all hierarchy. Hierarchy is necessary in a lot of things, especially companies.   I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. My kitchen at work: a clear cut hierarchy. But it is also one that is completely voluntary. It puts people who are best at making certain decisions or performing tasks (generally) into the place where they can do so best for the team. Restaurants are actually a perfect example of why hierarchies are useless. 

&amp;gt;But it is also one that is completely voluntary.

Sure, the fact that they work there is voluntary. But the do not voluntarily submit to the hierarchy, they don't have a choice. If they don't submit to the hierarchy, they're fired. Their job is voluntary, their position is not. Try disagreeing with the head chef or sous chef some day, even if you're right see if you keep your job.

-----

After a bit of training, almost anyone in the back of house can fulfill any back of house position. The entire "hierarchy" is just a reward system designed to keep people working harder than their wages dictate in order to someday move up. Everyone "above" saute or grill is useless.

The fact that most restaurants have a "kitchen lead" is proof of the uselessness of kitchen hierarchies. That position is often rotated and that individual is responsible for timing and final preparation of the dishes before they are handed off to the FOH expo. I see this as proof that hierarchal-less work spaces are superior. After adequate training, the *worker* is fully capable of fulfilling any role. 

Same with front-of-house. Every server/bartender can perform every duty of the entire front-of-house. Management is just a useless tool to prevent abuse of comps and to give the public the illusion that something is being done when there's a problem. My job goes so much faster and easier after I am finally given "manager powers" on my access card. I have *zero* use for a manager after I have been granted the "power" to take care of my own comps. Zero. 

If anything, management in the front-of-house inhibits workers from completing the job they are perfectly capable of doing.  &amp;gt;I see this as proof that hierarchal-less work spaces are superior.

Great, let's all embrace political nihilism and see what emerges.  I severely doubt it will be mutualism though. From hierarchal-less work spaces directly to embracing political nihilism...

http://i.imgur.com/TqMS8.gif

I almost want to upvote you out of pity. &amp;gt;out of pity

Insecure much.

:DDDDD Restaurants are actually a perfect example of why hierarchies are useless. 

&amp;gt;But it is also one that is completely voluntary.

Sure, the fact that they work there is voluntary. But the do not voluntarily submit to the hierarchy, they don't have a choice. If they don't submit to the hierarchy, they're fired. Their job is voluntary, their position is not. Try disagreeing with the head chef or sous chef some day, even if you're right see if you keep your job.

-----

After a bit of training, almost anyone in the back of house can fulfill any back of house position. The entire "hierarchy" is just a reward system designed to keep people working harder than their wages dictate in order to someday move up. Everyone "above" saute or grill is useless.

The fact that most restaurants have a "kitchen lead" is proof of the uselessness of kitchen hierarchies. That position is often rotated and that individual is responsible for timing and final preparation of the dishes before they are handed off to the FOH expo. I see this as proof that hierarchal-less work spaces are superior. After adequate training, the *worker* is fully capable of fulfilling any role. 

Same with front-of-house. Every server/bartender can perform every duty of the entire front-of-house. Management is just a useless tool to prevent abuse of comps and to give the public the illusion that something is being done when there's a problem. My job goes so much faster and easier after I am finally given "manager powers" on my access card. I have *zero* use for a manager after I have been granted the "power" to take care of my own comps. Zero. 

If anything, management in the front-of-house inhibits workers from completing the job they are perfectly capable of doing.  You must work at a less than fancy restaurant. In the kitchen among the cooks it falls apart without a hierarchy.  You either must be a kitchen manager or work around highly incompetent staff. 

That or you work at a corporate chain. Try moving into fine dining instead, better standards for employees.

Everyone I work with is awesome and after less than 6 months are more than capable of filling every position. Kitchen Lead is rotated daily.  Not a KM, incompetent or corporate. You think michelin starred restaurants can switch their saute guy out with the pantry cook? Hell no. I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. &amp;gt;"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

I don't typically get this when I talk to folks that claim to be against all hierarchy. They never seem to mind establishing a hierarchy where their own views have supremacy.  If it helps, consider a qualifier to the idea "against *all* hierarchy".

We are against top-down hierarchies. Bottom-up hierarchies (teacher/student, parent/child) are quite beneficial. I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. &amp;gt;But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level.

This is what I've said for a while now.  It's the deontological ancaps who eventually convert to mutualists and the consequentialists who remain. I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. I would say the fundamental divide between "Voluntarists/AnCaps" and "Anarchists" is this:

"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against *all* hierarchy.

Voluntarists/AnCaps: Fundamentally against hierarchy *created by use of force*.

In my personal view, AnCaps have the advantage because they recognize humans are prone to hierarchical organization (ie. most people prefer others decide certain things for them). My opposition to the state is really more that it's an inefficient institution to allocate resources to individuals, not so much that it is morally repugnant. But if you're judging the state on a moral basis you're more likely to judge all hierarchies on the same level. (/rant)

Edit: [Aurini actually just covered this topic a bit.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q) I would say the part where he talks about democracy and the "flaws" of AnCap pretty much started to hit on my objections to left-anarchism. &amp;gt;"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against all hierarchy.

This is false as fuck.  Read Bakunin. How likely do you think it is that someone is going to actually seek out and "read Bakunin" when you make such a general suggestion? Why not suggest a particular work by Bakunin and even better a particular part of a work by Bakunin? While the chances of either are probably slim, my guess is the latter is more likely.

If you are attempting to do anything other than troll, go ahead and list specific reading. First, I can easily point to Bakunin's quote regarding the authority of the shoemaker.  It is foolish to ignore professional expertise, when you have none.  
  
More importantly, plenty of left anarchists believe that hierarchy can be derived through democratic voting.  In the case of worker ownership, it is often reasonable to have managers who help guide the business, as long as they are elected by the workers and are thus responsible to workers.  

I am very baffled as to how *I* am a troll, when I made a general suggestion (i.e. "Read Bakunin"), but Warrior21 is not a troll when he made the absurd generalization that "Left Anarchists are fundamentally against all hierarchy".  Oh wait, it's because he is an AnCap.  Mystery solved. Why are we assuming democracy (in a nation or a workplace) is an effective way of keeping those in power accountable or "responsible to workers"? I see no evidence of this anywhere democracy has been tried.

No, my main gripe with leftist anarchists is this foolish, egalitarian love of democracy. It's a religion. And it's very destructive.   First, I can easily point to Bakunin's quote regarding the authority of the shoemaker.  It is foolish to ignore professional expertise, when you have none.  
  
More importantly, plenty of left anarchists believe that hierarchy can be derived through democratic voting.  In the case of worker ownership, it is often reasonable to have managers who help guide the business, as long as they are elected by the workers and are thus responsible to workers.  

I am very baffled as to how *I* am a troll, when I made a general suggestion (i.e. "Read Bakunin"), but Warrior21 is not a troll when he made the absurd generalization that "Left Anarchists are fundamentally against all hierarchy".  Oh wait, it's because he is an AnCap.  Mystery solved. So you didn't make any specific citation or suggestion beyond "read Bakunin." That's about typical; it won't be productive, won't change anyone's views, and will probably just harden them. Great job! If you were trying to actually inform, you would have cited a specific example, explained why it was wrong, or suggested specific reading to help the misunderstanding. Instead of that, you wrote, "this is false as fuck."

You're are a troll because of your activities trolling, EPS, ELS, and various troll responses in this subReddit and others. I specifically said, "if you are attempting to do anything other than troll... ." Do you understand the difference? I guess not. If Warrior did this things, I would call him a troll too. I routinely call some AnCaps trolls. &amp;gt;So you didn't make any specific citation or suggestion beyond "read Bakunin." That's about typical; it won't be productive, won't change anyone's views, and will probably just harden them.

No I didn't, because that's the type of response that "All Left Anarchists fundamentally believe blah blah blah" deserves.  Such a claim is not "productive", won't "change anyone's views", and will "just harden people".  Perhaps if Warrior was "trying to actually inform", "citied specific examples", "explained why", or "suggested specific reading", I wouldn't have written simply that "this is false as fuck".  I apologize if you got your little panties in a bundle over the fact that one generalization spawned another generalization.  Had I known my vulgar response would cause sand to spontaneously appear inside your vagina, I likely would have clarified so that you would not be in so much distress.   "He didn't write a good enough comment so I'm going to troll." Got it. If that's the only verdict your petty mind can muster then I feel very very sorry for you. You haven't made an argument or presented evidence, only ad hominems and appeals to authority. If the original claim is false, provide evidence. Otherwise you are simply noise. If that's the only verdict your petty mind can muster then I feel very very sorry for you. First, I can easily point to Bakunin's quote regarding the authority of the shoemaker.  It is foolish to ignore professional expertise, when you have none.  
  
More importantly, plenty of left anarchists believe that hierarchy can be derived through democratic voting.  In the case of worker ownership, it is often reasonable to have managers who help guide the business, as long as they are elected by the workers and are thus responsible to workers.  

I am very baffled as to how *I* am a troll, when I made a general suggestion (i.e. "Read Bakunin"), but Warrior21 is not a troll when he made the absurd generalization that "Left Anarchists are fundamentally against all hierarchy".  Oh wait, it's because he is an AnCap.  Mystery solved. &amp;gt;First, I can easily point to Bakunin's quote regarding the authority of the shoemaker. It is foolish to ignore professional expertise, when you have none.

Please post the quote, I'm unfamiliar with it. First, I can easily point to Bakunin's quote regarding the authority of the shoemaker.  It is foolish to ignore professional expertise, when you have none.  
  
More importantly, plenty of left anarchists believe that hierarchy can be derived through democratic voting.  In the case of worker ownership, it is often reasonable to have managers who help guide the business, as long as they are elected by the workers and are thus responsible to workers.  

I am very baffled as to how *I* am a troll, when I made a general suggestion (i.e. "Read Bakunin"), but Warrior21 is not a troll when he made the absurd generalization that "Left Anarchists are fundamentally against all hierarchy".  Oh wait, it's because he is an AnCap.  Mystery solved. &amp;gt;"Left" Anarchists: Fundamentally against all hierarchy.

This is false as fuck.  Read Bakunin.  I was expecting something more substantial than a few replies reminiscent of your typical /r/anarchism fare in order to warrant this thread being made... I was expecting something more substantial than a few replies reminiscent of your typical /r/anarchism fare in order to warrant this thread being made... I was expecting something more substantial than a few replies reminiscent of your typical /r/anarchism fare in order to warrant this thread being made...  It figures I could come here to find the source of my downvotes. I'll be replying to the comments tomorrow or Monday if y'all want to come back and downvote me some more. It figures I could come here to find the source of my downvotes. I'll be replying to the comments tomorrow or Monday if y'all want to come back and downvote me some more.   </snippet></document><document><title>Certain things in society "Might" need government, such as Foster Care.  Help me work this out.  </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/1927to/certain_things_in_society_might_need_government/</url><snippet>1. My ex-wife is a social worker so I see the issues surrounding Foster Care quite often.  

2. Foster Children are "graded" from basically normal children to severely disturbed.  Obviously severely disturbed requires extensive training and costs to manage.  

3. Many foster children are middle of the road to severe.  so its difficult to find foster parents. 

4.  The amount of work it takes social workers to manage foster children is extensive, emotionally draining and thankless work that has little reward ( usually) 

5. If foster children are not managed, the cycle of abuse and damage will continue through each generation. If not managed,  the potential for crime, health costs, and social services escalates. 

SO... how do you run a foster care system in an AnCap society without government?  Currently there are many Non-governement organization that do a great job at managing foster care, BUT only because they have donations and grants from the Government. Without the government money, it would be impossible under the current system.  

So how do you pull children from abusing parents to enforce the NAP for that child, provide living conditions and rearing such that the foster child becomes a productive member of society after 18 and not let a care system designed around free market principles ( profit driven) not produce more problems than the parents did originally?  Because today thats what happens in half way houses and other group housing situations.  

So how do you handle foster children?  this is a tough one in my mind.   Not AnCap, just visiting. I'm curious about your thoughts on why many of these children are mentally disturbed. Any theories?

My two cents regarding your question: Try stepping outside the paradigm of "all the options include for profit enterprise, charity, or a government program"...at least this is what it often seems like among AnCaps. [Mutual Aid](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_aid_%28organization_theory%29) societies and [Co-Ops](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-obHJfTaQvw)(which run educational and retirement programs) are often ignored by AnCaps, but I doubt these options would get many objections here.

I might also add that it's doubtful that the state will fall all at once. So it may be worth prioritizing which programs are the most egregious and start with those. Perhaps end war and monopoly privileges for large corporations before tackling welfare state measures? The removal of barriers to entry to the market may help more people find resources to deal with these social issues before state welfare is done away with.
 Not AnCap, just visiting. I'm curious about your thoughts on why many of these children are mentally disturbed. Any theories?

My two cents regarding your question: Try stepping outside the paradigm of "all the options include for profit enterprise, charity, or a government program"...at least this is what it often seems like among AnCaps. [Mutual Aid](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_aid_%28organization_theory%29) societies and [Co-Ops](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-obHJfTaQvw)(which run educational and retirement programs) are often ignored by AnCaps, but I doubt these options would get many objections here.

I might also add that it's doubtful that the state will fall all at once. So it may be worth prioritizing which programs are the most egregious and start with those. Perhaps end war and monopoly privileges for large corporations before tackling welfare state measures? The removal of barriers to entry to the market may help more people find resources to deal with these social issues before state welfare is done away with.
 Well put it this way:  THis is a REAL Story....  You are 3 years old and crying because you haven't eating in days.  You drugged out mother gets pissed and decides to push your face into scalding hot water that she filled in the sink.  You suffer surgery after surgery through age 10.  IN the meantime, you are sent to foster care, where you are beaten regularly by the foster parent.  Eventually the court give you back to your mother who is now prostituting and starts selling you ( at 11) to john who want to beat a child or have sex with a young boy.  You endure this until you are 15 where you are removed and put into a group home.  You are regularly beaten, abused and now you have become a sexual predator as well because that is all you know.  By 18 you have been in jail 3 times, got a girl pregnant, have facial disfigurations and surgeries that now make it so painful to live you are on every drug known to man.  You scream out and hurt people because of your pain and now you are on the street and by 20 you are dead. 

You cannot imagine how common that story is in the foster care world.  Well put it this way:  THis is a REAL Story....  You are 3 years old and crying because you haven't eating in days.  You drugged out mother gets pissed and decides to push your face into scalding hot water that she filled in the sink.  You suffer surgery after surgery through age 10.  IN the meantime, you are sent to foster care, where you are beaten regularly by the foster parent.  Eventually the court give you back to your mother who is now prostituting and starts selling you ( at 11) to john who want to beat a child or have sex with a young boy.  You endure this until you are 15 where you are removed and put into a group home.  You are regularly beaten, abused and now you have become a sexual predator as well because that is all you know.  By 18 you have been in jail 3 times, got a girl pregnant, have facial disfigurations and surgeries that now make it so painful to live you are on every drug known to man.  You scream out and hurt people because of your pain and now you are on the street and by 20 you are dead. 

You cannot imagine how common that story is in the foster care world.  Perfect AnCap society:

&amp;gt; You drugged out mother gets pissed and decides to push your face into scalding hot water that she filled in the sink.

Kill the mother. She is a dysfunctional human being and society shouldn't have to deal with people like that. States love them to be part of their profitable prison system.

&amp;gt; you are sent to foster care, where you are beaten regularly by the foster parent.

Kill the foster parent. Society has a simple rule: non-aggression. so you better stick to it.

By this time everybody should know how to behave, so the kid can live a prosperous life in a loving home, be it the church, a charity, a commune, etc.

So from 5yo he/she should live a loving and peaceful recovery and reinsertion in society. Not AnCap, just visiting. I'm curious about your thoughts on why many of these children are mentally disturbed. Any theories?

My two cents regarding your question: Try stepping outside the paradigm of "all the options include for profit enterprise, charity, or a government program"...at least this is what it often seems like among AnCaps. [Mutual Aid](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_aid_%28organization_theory%29) societies and [Co-Ops](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-obHJfTaQvw)(which run educational and retirement programs) are often ignored by AnCaps, but I doubt these options would get many objections here.

I might also add that it's doubtful that the state will fall all at once. So it may be worth prioritizing which programs are the most egregious and start with those. Perhaps end war and monopoly privileges for large corporations before tackling welfare state measures? The removal of barriers to entry to the market may help more people find resources to deal with these social issues before state welfare is done away with.
  I think you're forgetting that much of what you're witnessing is because of government, not despite it. Government has an incentive to break apart families which leads to troubled children. Government steals peoples money, reducing voluntary donations to charity. Eliminate these factors and the problem gets reduced to what it was before government involvement (circa 1800s).  I agree.  I think that going back to the "way it was" or transitioning over time to a new model under AnCap and/or Libertarian principles will fix most of the problems.  My worry is more the transition.  How to we get from point A to point B with out some kind of defined governmental institution or tax mechanism to ensure that care is sufficient to make the transition.   I agree.  I think that going back to the "way it was" or transitioning over time to a new model under AnCap and/or Libertarian principles will fix most of the problems.  My worry is more the transition.  How to we get from point A to point B with out some kind of defined governmental institution or tax mechanism to ensure that care is sufficient to make the transition.    &amp;gt;So how do you pull children from abusing parents to enforce the NAP for that child, provide living conditions and rearing such that the foster child becomes a productive member of society after 18 and not let a care system designed around free market principles ( profit driven) not produce more problems than the parents did originally? 

It wouldn't be unjust to make sure the parents provide monetary support for the child, after all they where being aggressors against the child, varying amounts of compensation for the child would be in line throughout their childhood. Further, such punishment could spur other contractual obligations to lessen the burden for the parents, but, increase adverse outcomes for violations. That means, the money and whatever material support derived via the punishment for the aggression , goes to the child -- that's justice.  Some type of insurance like function could easily cover these children.  While, being a drain, it shows good will &amp;amp; could spur new customers for larger institutions. Not to mention donations towards organizations that also handle a function like this. There exists a myriad of possibilities.

When the abuser can't or won't make payment, than forced work is in line, after all, no one forced them to be aggressors &amp;amp; payment is due.  I think this is in line with insurance functionality, they force them to work &amp;amp; compensate their customer. 

&amp;gt;Because today thats what happens in half way houses and other group housing situations. 

Yes, the State is very problematic on this front. The money doesn't go to the child, it goes to an organization that has no contractual obligations to the child.  When abuse is shown to happen, the child doesn't get any sort of compounded compensation for that abuse by the hands of the abuser &amp;amp; fraud that has taken place against them.  


Sorry for the stream of consciousness  here, actually, I'm not sorry!  First of all, how much of the current problem can be attributed to the state? Including but not limited to welfare, public schooling etc. These days people can churn out kids without a care in the world for consequences, they may even profit financially from having kids and not give a fuck about them. Eliminating all this would arguably drastically reduce the problem.

In a free society individuals and organizations could take on foster kids without having to worry about hindering bureaucracies.

If it is true that society gets a net benefit from taking care of these kids, it almost guaranteed that it will be so. If its not true, then its still likely that a substantial amount of them will get help. Of course there will be those that do not get the help they need, but such is the case in any society and having a state clearly by no means guarantees that every single one of these kids will get taken care of.

  &amp;gt;Currently there are many Non-governement organization that do a great job at managing foster care,

So if people could stop paying taxes, not one person would move that savings to "saving the children"?  Not one?

&amp;gt;So how do you pull children from abusing parents to enforce the NAP for that child, provide living conditions and rearing such that the foster child becomes a productive member of society after 18 and not let a care system designed around free market principles ( profit driven) not produce more problems than the parents did originally?

A private society would have consequences (law suits) for people that made mistakes in pulling children.  Since there would be consequences for making mistakes, you'd think people that care about children would evolve methods for determining with greater accuracy if abuse is occurring.  For example, you could bribe doctors to notify you when physical abuse shows up in the doctor's office.  You could pay to set up a larger network that informs you of potential abuse.  You could find excuses to talk to kids that are potential recipients of abuse.  You could make it possible not to pull a kid from his home unless he secretly gives you permission first.

Finally, in situations of extreme abuse where the kid's life is in danger, you could pull the kid and then live with the consequences. What part of natural law or common law even allows outsiders to pull children from families anyway?

&amp;gt;  For example, you could bribe doctors to notify you when physical abuse shows up in the doctor's office

How is business this profitable?

&amp;gt; unless he secretly gives you permission first.

This seems very corruptible.

&amp;gt; Finally, in situations of extreme abuse where the kid's life is in danger, you could pull the kid and then live with the consequences.

Why should there be consequences?

 &amp;gt;What part of natural law or common law even allows outsiders to pull children from families anyway?

I don't know.  It's my understanding that common law has emerged from a history of dispute resolutions.  If there is no history of disputes between abuse rescuers and parents, I'd expect that a whole bunch of these disputes would have to occur before solid principles governing these disputes could be elucidated.

&amp;gt;How is business this profitable?

Austrian economics teach that all actions are thought to be "profitable" ex ante.  This is called an autistic exchange.  That said, if your "passion" is rescuing abused children, you can either raise them yourself, or I'd imagine a market could form whereby "vetted" parents could pay you to adopt these rescued children.

&amp;gt;This seems very corruptible.

Maybe.  See above about consequences.

&amp;gt;Why should there be consequences?

Is it possible to avoid consequences in life?  If you've figured out how to avoid them, I'm willing to pay you to teach that skill to me. &amp;gt; That said, if your "passion" is rescuing abused children, you can either raise them yourself, or I'd imagine a market could form whereby "vetted" parents could pay you to adopt these rescued children.

Not even CPS agents or foster parents work for free.

&amp;gt; Is it possible to avoid consequences in life? If you've figured out how to avoid them, I'm willing to pay you to teach that skill to me.

Consequences in this case are socially constructed. &amp;gt;Currently there are many Non-governement organization that do a great job at managing foster care,

So if people could stop paying taxes, not one person would move that savings to "saving the children"?  Not one?

&amp;gt;So how do you pull children from abusing parents to enforce the NAP for that child, provide living conditions and rearing such that the foster child becomes a productive member of society after 18 and not let a care system designed around free market principles ( profit driven) not produce more problems than the parents did originally?

A private society would have consequences (law suits) for people that made mistakes in pulling children.  Since there would be consequences for making mistakes, you'd think people that care about children would evolve methods for determining with greater accuracy if abuse is occurring.  For example, you could bribe doctors to notify you when physical abuse shows up in the doctor's office.  You could pay to set up a larger network that informs you of potential abuse.  You could find excuses to talk to kids that are potential recipients of abuse.  You could make it possible not to pull a kid from his home unless he secretly gives you permission first.

Finally, in situations of extreme abuse where the kid's life is in danger, you could pull the kid and then live with the consequences. I agree with you. I believe people would move money towards that purpose and I believe people would take it upon themselves to start organizations to help foster children.  But the nature of many children is SO severe that its almost impossible to "correct" them. They will be broken for life and finding people to deal with that situation is very difficult. 

Also, Im not sure that setting up processes that dictate ratting out you neighbors is a very AnCap belief.    If foster care is so critical and important why do we keep it locked in with national boundaries? Isnt that something everyone should be fighting to have in every country? Why dont you care about the third world? THis is really just a social problem no matter where it is in the world.  The question is not necessarily directed at the US, but at the issue.  </snippet></document><document><title>Democracy; Anarchy; Monarchy (Brings up Anarcho-Capitalism at 7:30)</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz_PQ5Ndr-Q</url><snippet>  I've been following this guy's youtube videos for a while. I disagree with half of the stuff he says but he's good at telling his perspective and quite interesting to listen to.  This is racist crankery par excellence. He is well spoken and well mannered and well dressed, so most people will believe his rhetoric, but hes full  of shit. He might make a good politician.

1.Start ancap territory with geniuses and no criminals

2.?????????

3.Monarchy! Step 2 usually is add water. I hope that helps.  This is racist crankery par excellence. He is well spoken and well mannered and well dressed, so most people will believe his rhetoric, but hes full  of shit. He might make a good politician.

1.Start ancap territory with geniuses and no criminals

2.?????????

3.Monarchy! This is racist crankery par excellence. He is well spoken and well mannered and well dressed, so most people will believe his rhetoric, but hes full  of shit. He might make a good politician.

1.Start ancap territory with geniuses and no criminals

2.?????????

3.Monarchy! &amp;gt;This is racist crankery par excellence.

Drop the "racist" shit. I don't see what he said that was "racist" unless by that you mean "he doesn't subscribe to the same notions of race as I do, therefore he's a race heretic TIME TO SLING SHIT OH YEHHHH." 

&amp;gt;1.Start ancap territory with geniuses and no criminals

&amp;gt;2.?????????

&amp;gt;3.Monarchy!

I agree that I didn't follow the logic of this bit here. I'm more of the opinion that property would be more dispersed than it is now, being that there would be no political means of consolidating and maintaining capital. It would all be up to what an individual could labor on and fruitfully exploit, whereas now politics jumps in the middle of that and allows politically connected people to profit at the expense of everyone else. This is one of those head-scratching moments this video induced while I was watching it.  So "mud shark" has no racist allusions... racist apologist fanboy.  I feel as though he made a major jump from "Some people just want to be engineers." to "So one person will end up owning 90% of the property." Did I just miss where he explained how that ends up being the case or what? I feel as though he made a major jump from "Some people just want to be engineers." to "So one person will end up owning 90% of the property." Did I just miss where he explained how that ends up being the case or what?  Hi everyone, just wanted to comment on a popular critique. I believe his reasoning for AnCap&amp;gt;???&amp;gt;Monarchy came from the following implied logic.

&amp;gt;People like to shirk responsibility for their actions onto others; this is mainly due to 1. time preference with having to learn about a subject and 2. humans generally not wanting to be held accountable. As such, people would, over time, in Ancapistan, seek to become "renters" rather than "property owners", in this way they wouldn't have to be held responsible for the property all the time, and they would trust others to understand property rights better than themselves so that they wouldn't constantly have to be adapting to fluctuations in property dispute resolutions. As more and more people began to trust their property to a more finite number of "property owners" they would eventually create local monopoly owners of land; this would lead to the creation of many small monarchy states.

I believe this was the implied argument that he was making. If you listen to his video again, the context of his statements about AnCap&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Monarchy seem to lead to the above thinking. (OR I was just reading too much into his video.)  Abolut bullshit is that 'there are smart and stupid people'. This has been shown to be false again and again, people are stupid if they have a insentive to be. People learn if they have to, otherwise they dont. 

Also some people are smart others not ---&amp;gt; BOOM --&amp;gt; mononarchy of smart people. What? How does that happen, even poor people would not just start paying tax because smart people tell them. Also smart people is not a stable groupe that can take power, the diffrent 'rich and smart' people have no common intrest under witch they can just unify.

There are good arguments against AnCapism, read the debate section of "Anarchy and the Law" and you will find some where smart economists debating the subject. &amp;gt;Abolut bullshit is that 'there are smart and stupid people'. This has been shown to be false again and again, people are stupid if they have a insentive to be. People learn if they have to, otherwise they dont.

People do respond to incentives, but people also act independently of incentives. Even when the shittiest, lowest paying honest jobs pay more than the typical loot a small-time crook rakes in and with less risk, there will still be small-time crooks. Similarly, we have Ron Paul and Justin Amash among others in a system where all incentives are for legislators to jump in, exploit popular opinion to profit as much as possible, and watch with horror from the sidelines as the lay retard reveals themselves to be more retarded than anyone could have predicted. As I say elsewhere, incentives can make that retard act more intelligently than they otherwise would, but all the great incentives in the world will not transform a pop culture-imbibing high time preference low-IQ into a cultured and systematically rigorous Mensa member. They dont have to be Mensa members, they have to be smart enought to buy insurance and have a DRO. Its not that hard.   Does Ayn Rand advocate completely getting rid of government? No. But, I forgive him for this mistake.  Starting at 8:55
"The fact of the matter is that we've had a disgenic breeding process for the last ten thousand years and we have this massive, genetically deviant underclass that can't begin to run their own lives, that is not intelligent enough to understand something as simple as a social construct or insurance or any of these other that go into the Anarcho-Capitalist society..."

and at 18:35
"... and he's from Singapore. He sees the same ugly degeneracy appearing in his own country. And his response? His response to these Singapore women who want to [mud shark](http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=mud+shark) with white men? White men, come fuck the shit out of these whores, use up their most fertile years. These degenerate sluts are never going to be part of any revival. Use them. I don't care. They're not part of the solution, they're part of the goddam problem."

Gotta love that racism there. It's a shame because he has some interesting points besides this, even if I disagree with them. Huh? What racism? He calls somebody a "degenerate" because they slept with somebody of a different race. He calls somebody a "degenerate" because they slept with somebody of a different race. That is not the reason he called her a degenerate. He called her a sexual degenerate because she was a whore; just like he calls the men sleeping with her just for sexual pleasure sexual degenerates. He denigrates these people not because of their races, he does it because of their behavior.

What does "racism" even mean? If I recognize *any* general difference between races, am I a racist? The use of "mud shark" shows that he clearly sees the racial dimension as a problem. Starting at 8:55
"The fact of the matter is that we've had a disgenic breeding process for the last ten thousand years and we have this massive, genetically deviant underclass that can't begin to run their own lives, that is not intelligent enough to understand something as simple as a social construct or insurance or any of these other that go into the Anarcho-Capitalist society..."

and at 18:35
"... and he's from Singapore. He sees the same ugly degeneracy appearing in his own country. And his response? His response to these Singapore women who want to [mud shark](http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=mud+shark) with white men? White men, come fuck the shit out of these whores, use up their most fertile years. These degenerate sluts are never going to be part of any revival. Use them. I don't care. They're not part of the solution, they're part of the goddam problem."

Gotta love that racism there. It's a shame because he has some interesting points besides this, even if I disagree with them. &amp;gt;Gotta love that racism there. It's a shame because he has some interesting points besides this, even if I disagree with them.

Judging people's political ideas based on a Trotskyite epithet is idiotic. 

Your heros Ludwig von Mises and Murray Rothbard were not racial egalitarians. 

There are racial average IQ gaps between the races. They have been studied **ad naseum** and it appears that they are caused by difference in allele frequencies between the races.  &amp;gt;Gotta love that racism there. It's a shame because he has some interesting points besides this, even if I disagree with them.

Judging people's political ideas based on a Trotskyite epithet is idiotic. 

Your heros Ludwig von Mises and Murray Rothbard were not racial egalitarians. 

There are racial average IQ gaps between the races. They have been studied **ad naseum** and it appears that they are caused by difference in allele frequencies between the races.  Regardless of the existing IQ gaps and their source, the author of the video goes out of his way to denigrate people for associating with another race. It is a textbook case of racism and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video. &amp;gt; It is a textbook case of racism and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video.

Holy fuck! How can you not see the irony in talking that way?

&amp;gt; It is a textbook case of **heresy** and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video.

Racism has no consistent application and no consistent definition. Whites and non-Whites are **never** held to the same standard when it comes to charges of "racism." 

Anti-racist really is a code word for anti-white.

Your'e the type of person who goes around calling white-nationalists Orwellian whilst endorsing the Orwellian speech codes of 21st century political correctness. 

['Racism is a bogus concept' by Ryan Faulk, a well known anti-statist.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ttguCMBy1Jw)
 
 &amp;gt; It is a textbook case of racism and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video.

Holy fuck! How can you not see the irony in talking that way?

&amp;gt; It is a textbook case of **heresy** and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video.

Racism has no consistent application and no consistent definition. Whites and non-Whites are **never** held to the same standard when it comes to charges of "racism." 

Anti-racist really is a code word for anti-white.

Your'e the type of person who goes around calling white-nationalists Orwellian whilst endorsing the Orwellian speech codes of 21st century political correctness. 

['Racism is a bogus concept' by Ryan Faulk, a well known anti-statist.](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ttguCMBy1Jw)
 
 &amp;gt;Anti-racist really is a code word for anti-white.

[For those unfamiliar with this phrase](http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Anti-racist_is_a_codeword_for_anti-white), it refers to the belief that white folks who marry non-whites (or allow such a marriage) are actually race traitors in disguise.

&amp;gt;Racism has no consistent application and no consistent definition. Whites and non-Whites are never held to the same standard when it comes to charges of "racism."

Yes, some people do use the term poorly (think "Black people can't be racist because they're black!"). For me personally, I am using [definition # 2 from the World English Dictionary](http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/racist) and it fits like a glove.

&amp;gt;You're the type of person who goes around calling white-nationalists Orwellian whilst endorsing the Orwellian speech codes of 21st century political correctness.

Freedom of speech entails that I respect your right to say anything you want, it does not require me to respect those words or their underlying ideas. We exist in a marketplace of ideas and it cuts both ways. &amp;gt;For those unfamiliar with this phrase[1] , it refers to the belief that white folks who marry non-whites (or allow such a marriage) are actually race traitors in disguise.

This is a complete straw man and you're citing RationalWiki, which is about as unbiased as Conservapedia. The reason I think anti-racist is a codeword for anti-white is because so many self described "anti-racists" are anti-white. Functionally and intentionally, their work and words add up to white genocide. [Just read Tim&#10017;Wise's essay.](http://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/2010/11/tim-wise-hates-white-people/http://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/2010/11/tim-wise-hates-white-people/) Go ahead and ignore the editorializing. Just **read his own words.**

I'm not a Nazi and I don't have any politically radical friends of family. I have been alienated by people like Tim Wise and SRSers from mainstream politics. People like you seem hell bent on pissing off as many white males as possible without worrying about the backlash. 

&amp;gt;For me personally, I am using definition # 2 from the World English Dictionary[2] and it fits like a glove.

**Exactly!** You have an **ESOTERIC**, personal definition recognized by no one else but you and your **CHOICE** dictionary. You're a prime example of why the word "racism" has become intellectually bankrupt. 

Since people like you keep using the word in this way, charges of racism have come to mean about as much as charges of heresy or blasphemy to people. People are waking up too, which is exciting. [This was on the front page of /r/AskReddit yesterday.](http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/18x5a2/why_are_white_communities_the_only_ones_that_need/
) The days when people like you can go around silencing people by crying "racism" are numbered. I hope you enjoy your dwindling power while it lasts. 

&amp;gt;We exist in a marketplace of ideas and it cuts both ways.

Exactly buddy, and you're stock price is dropping. As I previously said, [this post](http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/18x5a2/why_are_white_communities_the_only_ones_that_need/) was on the front page of /r/AskReddit yesterday. Tumblr and other social justice warriors have become so transparently anti-white that people are starting to just laugh it off.  

[There is an entire subreddit dedicated to it.](http://www.reddit.com/r/TumblrInAction/)
 &amp;gt;The reason I think anti-racist is a codeword for anti-white is because so many self described "anti-racists" are anti-white. Functionally and intentionally, their work and words add up to white genocide.

If you're talking about white people being killed with bombs and guns and the like on a mass scale for being white, please do tell me because I don't know where it is happening.

If you're talking about how unfair it is for you to have to suffer because some white person decided to mix the races by their own volition, I'd say let them go at it. It's their choice to make, not yours, nor should anybody look down on them for it. &amp;gt;If you're talking about white people being killed with bombs and guns and the like on a mass scale for being white, please do tell me because I don't know where it is happening.

You're willfully ignorant. It is difficult to contain my anger when speaking to people like you.

[Why are Afrikaner farmers being murdered in South Africa? - genocidewatch.org](http://www.genocidewatch.org/southafrica.html)

I bet you know who Trayvon Martin is. Do you know the names of any of the **tens of thousands** of Whites who have been murdered in South Africa? That's just the documented number of murders. South Africa is corrupt. We may never know just how many of our people have been murdered there. 

Rhodesia was even worse. 

People like you make me fucking sick. You go on and on about "racism" and genocide, but you don't even know about the South African, Rhodesian, and Haitian genocides against my people.

Seriously. Fuck you.  
 &amp;gt;If you're talking about white people being killed with bombs and guns and the like on a mass scale for being white, please do tell me because I don't know where it is happening.

You're willfully ignorant. It is difficult to contain my anger when speaking to people like you.

[Why are Afrikaner farmers being murdered in South Africa? - genocidewatch.org](http://www.genocidewatch.org/southafrica.html)

I bet you know who Trayvon Martin is. Do you know the names of any of the **tens of thousands** of Whites who have been murdered in South Africa? That's just the documented number of murders. South Africa is corrupt. We may never know just how many of our people have been murdered there. 

Rhodesia was even worse. 

People like you make me fucking sick. You go on and on about "racism" and genocide, but you don't even know about the South African, Rhodesian, and Haitian genocides against my people.

Seriously. Fuck you.  
 I'll be honest, I didn't know about the murders in South Africa and Haiti. Those are certainly deplorable.

It still doesn't change that most white nationalists [don't use the term exclusively in that sense](http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/White_extinction_hypothesis). &amp;gt;The reason I think anti-racist is a codeword for anti-white is because so many self described "anti-racists" are anti-white. Functionally and intentionally, their work and words add up to white genocide.

If you're talking about white people being killed with bombs and guns and the like on a mass scale for being white, please do tell me because I don't know where it is happening.

If you're talking about how unfair it is for you to have to suffer because some white person decided to mix the races by their own volition, I'd say let them go at it. It's their choice to make, not yours, nor should anybody look down on them for it. Regardless of the existing IQ gaps and their source, the author of the video goes out of his way to denigrate people for associating with another race. It is a textbook case of racism and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video. Regardless of the existing IQ gaps and their source, the author of the video goes out of his way to denigrate people for associating with another race. It is a textbook case of racism and should be denounced as such without having to discuss every little other detail in the video. Just look at his submission history.  He's one of the last people I want to be associated with. Starting at 8:55
"The fact of the matter is that we've had a disgenic breeding process for the last ten thousand years and we have this massive, genetically deviant underclass that can't begin to run their own lives, that is not intelligent enough to understand something as simple as a social construct or insurance or any of these other that go into the Anarcho-Capitalist society..."

and at 18:35
"... and he's from Singapore. He sees the same ugly degeneracy appearing in his own country. And his response? His response to these Singapore women who want to [mud shark](http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=mud+shark) with white men? White men, come fuck the shit out of these whores, use up their most fertile years. These degenerate sluts are never going to be part of any revival. Use them. I don't care. They're not part of the solution, they're part of the goddam problem."

Gotta love that racism there. It's a shame because he has some interesting points besides this, even if I disagree with them.</snippet></document><document><title>Ancap flag [in 1:03] in a clash against brazilian socialists who support Cuba (protesting against Yoani Sanch&#233;z) in S&#227;o Paulo.</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q5gHSxJ3L30</url><snippet>  I always find protesting as the worst way to spend time and energy. I mean really, does chanting random stuff change anything? I always find protesting as the worst way to spend time and energy. I mean really, does chanting random stuff change anything? political theater, lets all act like we're sick and tired and chant a lot all at the same time.  Just make sure you all have good timing and dont be that chanter that keeps changing when everyone else stopped lmao  Appeared on national television (Rede Globo) here in Brazil!

http://imgur.com/bEsvT3t

http://g1.globo.com/jornal-da-globo/noticia/2013/02/manifestantes-interrompem-novamente-agenda-de-yoani-sanchez.html

http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=fqOE0OeLxJw#t=40s
 Appeared on national television (Rede Globo) here in Brazil!

http://imgur.com/bEsvT3t

http://g1.globo.com/jornal-da-globo/noticia/2013/02/manifestantes-interrompem-novamente-agenda-de-yoani-sanchez.html

http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=fqOE0OeLxJw#t=40s
     "Cerca de 50 jovens ativistas, a maioria pertencente &#224; UJS (Uni&#227;o das Juventudes Socialistas), e outro grupo menor de militantes da direita, cuja maior parte integrava o grupo ***Libert&#225;rios***, se confrontavam em um clima tenso, mas pac&#237;fico, com cartazes e palavras de ordem, em frente &#224; sala 1 do Cine Livraria Cultura."

"About 50 young activists, most belonging to UJS (Union of Socialist Youth), and another smaller group of militants from right, most of which was part of the group Libertarians, confronted in a tense but peaceful, with signs and words of order, in front of room 1 at Cine Livraria Cultura."

http://operamundi.uol.com.br/conteudo/reportagens/27349/maratona+yoani+jardins+descobrem+paixoes+pro+e+anti-cuba.shtml

EDIT: Another video:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4aFNh5M3UQ0 haha the socialists are "activists," but the ancaps are "militants?"     </snippet></document><document><title>FDA aims to sterilize our food through the Food Safety Modernization Act

</title><url>http://foodriotradio.com/2013/02/dead-lifeless-food/</url><snippet>  Do you have like, a link to a scientific study? maybe a research paper or a medical journal? "Irradiation damages the quality of food. 
&#183; Irradiation damages food by breaking up molecules and creating free radicals. The free radicals kill some bacteria, but they also bounce around in the food, damage vitamins and enzymes, and combine with existing chemicals (like pesticides) in the food to form new chemicals, called unique radiolytic products (URPs). 
&#183; Some of these URPs are known toxins (benzene, formaldehyde, lipid peroxides) and some are unique to irradiated foods. Scientists have not studied the long-term effect of these new chemicals in our diet. Therefore, we cannot assume they are safe. 
&#183; Irradiated foods can lose 5%-80% of many vitamins (A, C, E, K and B complex). The amount of loss depends on the dose of irradiation and the length of storage time. 
&#183; Most of the food in the American diet is already approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for irradiation: beef, pork, lamb, poultry, wheat, wheat flour, vegetables, fruits, shell eggs, seeds for sprouting, spices, herb teas. (Dairy is already pasteurized). A food industry petition currently before the FDA asks for approval for luncheon meats, salad bar items, sprouts, fresh juices and frozen foods. Another petition before the USDA asks for approval for imported fruits and vegetables.
&#183; Irradiation damages the natural digestive enzymes found in raw foods. This means the body has to work harder to digest them. 
&#183; If unlabeled, raw foods that have been irradiated look like fresh foods, but nutritionally they are like cooked foods, with decreased vitamins and enzymes. The FDA allows these foods to be labeled "fresh."
&#183; Irradiated fats tend to become rancid. 
&#183; When high-energy electron beams are used, trace amounts of radioactivity may be created in the food"

http://www.organicconsumers.org/Irrad/irradfact.cfm The link you gave is a 501c3 non-profit website, do you have a reference number for a scientific journal?

I say this because, this news is old, 2 years old, and has nothing to do with irradiation.

&amp;gt; The Food Safety Modernization Act (FSMA), also called the Food Safety Act, was signed into law of the United States on January 4, 2011.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_Safety_Modernization_Act

&amp;gt;The law gives the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) the authority to order recalls of contaminated food, amongst other powers not here disclosed, a power it did not have prior to the possible enactment of the Food Safety Act.[2] As a major overhaul of food safety laws and regulations, the acts stated purpose is to provide a safer food supply and a more stable food industry, but, it will also vastly broaden the power of the FDA to regulate any aspect of food production.

so how does the FDA interfer and require producers to irradiate their food?,  well they don't, the only power the law gave them was to force them to create written plans.

&amp;gt;Under the new rules, the FDA's focus shifts to stopping outbreaks before they start, by requiring farmers to address places in production where contamination might occur and to require processors to implement written food-safety plans.



So I don't understand how you go from pencil and paper, to  irradiation. I'm not sure if this is much better, but here you go.

http://www.physics.isu.edu/radinf/food.htm

There's a table that shows irradiated food contains less vitamins than the non-irradiated foods. I should of clarified, I meant how is irradiation assumed as a result of the law which does not mention it anywhere.

I assumed the FDA had a research paper about the usefulness of irradiation in food production after an exploratory committee.  So..that should be in existence somewhere right?

I'm assuming there isn't one, because this is a hoax.
 Well, again, when you're talking about government things can get a little odd. People like Joel Salatin and Judith McGeary seem to think government ignores real science and work on behalf of interest groups. I tend to agree.  To address the 
&amp;gt;When high-energy electron beams are used, trace amounts of radioactivity may be created in the food"

portion of what you linked above.

It's called E-beam processsing.  Its been used since slightly before the 1950's, but somehow 60 years later, its a problem to them.

The bill doesn't force anyone in anyway to start using E-beam processing as its not effective in certain industries.  Its mostly used for bulk unprocessed harvests.

It also is the primary use of disinfection of medical products.  So if it is so dangerous it can't be used for food,  why has it been used for medical disinfection for decades with no outcry?  Yeah, that's my point. They started using these things in the 50's and 60's and we can see the results today - cancer, diabetes, and a host of other diseases that weren't prevelent 100 years ago. I find it interesting that my grandparents lived longer than my mom and that my girlfriend's dad passed away before his parents. Maybe it's just a coincidence.

If you feel the produce from Walmart is suffient fine, just let me have access to the non-irradiated kind, that's locally sourced. I mean, who generally funds these scientific journal you want research from? The link you gave is a 501c3 non-profit website, do you have a reference number for a scientific journal?

I say this because, this news is old, 2 years old, and has nothing to do with irradiation.

&amp;gt; The Food Safety Modernization Act (FSMA), also called the Food Safety Act, was signed into law of the United States on January 4, 2011.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_Safety_Modernization_Act

&amp;gt;The law gives the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) the authority to order recalls of contaminated food, amongst other powers not here disclosed, a power it did not have prior to the possible enactment of the Food Safety Act.[2] As a major overhaul of food safety laws and regulations, the acts stated purpose is to provide a safer food supply and a more stable food industry, but, it will also vastly broaden the power of the FDA to regulate any aspect of food production.

so how does the FDA interfer and require producers to irradiate their food?,  well they don't, the only power the law gave them was to force them to create written plans.

&amp;gt;Under the new rules, the FDA's focus shifts to stopping outbreaks before they start, by requiring farmers to address places in production where contamination might occur and to require processors to implement written food-safety plans.



So I don't understand how you go from pencil and paper, to  irradiation. Listen, I got this information from Judith Mcgeary, as stated in the article. She's the one looking over the 1200 pages of legalize right now. The bill was passed in 2011 but goes into affect this year. That's why farmers and consumers should be concerned.  Judith McGeary
Farm and Ranch Freedom Alliance (TX)


She's listed on the OCA Policy and Advisory Board: which is the non-profit site you linked.  

Other noted members of the board are

A Vermont Organic Farmer

A member of Consumers Union (NY)

An Ashland Community Food Store (Oregon) owner

and 2 Authors.

If there's a scientist on the board, please correct me. Judith McGeary
Farm and Ranch Freedom Alliance (TX)


She's listed on the OCA Policy and Advisory Board: which is the non-profit site you linked.  

Other noted members of the board are

A Vermont Organic Farmer

A member of Consumers Union (NY)

An Ashland Community Food Store (Oregon) owner

and 2 Authors.

If there's a scientist on the board, please correct me. I don't think so. Does there need to be a scientist to explain why this bill is bad? The link below may be able to help you... It look like a study was done on the matter.

http://www.physics.isu.edu/radinf/food.htm

 Its interesting that you linked that study because it refutes most of the arguments put forth by Judith. Blogs like this I always immediately go and look at the other articles listed. Sure enough, this is a site that is spouting the same nonsense claims that Natural News, the Huffington Post, and other woo health sites do. glad i'm not the only one.   I understand that it's a little obvious that /r/anarcho_capitalism wouldn't like the FDA, but I hope people don't just upvote it because they see FDA in the title.   glad i'm not the only one.   I understand that it's a little obvious that /r/anarcho_capitalism wouldn't like the FDA, but I hope people don't just upvote it because they see FDA in the title.   glad i'm not the only one.   I understand that it's a little obvious that /r/anarcho_capitalism wouldn't like the FDA, but I hope people don't just upvote it because they see FDA in the title.      The amusing thing is these people are freaking out over these regulations while asking for other regulations. "They're not doing *our* stupid shit! What an outrage!"

If people don't want irradiated food they can pay more. But while these nutters are trying to get the government to ban GMO and force labeling, well, you asked for the government to have their hands in your food. Enjoy the results. I'll enjoy my irradiated oranges. actually its rarely used in oranges if any at all. :P

You could say anything grain though. The amusing thing is these people are freaking out over these regulations while asking for other regulations. "They're not doing *our* stupid shit! What an outrage!"

If people don't want irradiated food they can pay more. But while these nutters are trying to get the government to ban GMO and force labeling, well, you asked for the government to have their hands in your food. Enjoy the results. I'll enjoy my irradiated oranges. I didn't ask for them to have their hands in my food, they just do, kind of like our currency. If their hands are in the food, though, they could at least label products correctly. I mean, I would like to know what I'm eating. I'm a libertarian/anarchaist myself and the one who wrote the article. The point I was making is that government limits our access to nutrient dense foods by costly regulations and failed/no science. 

The FDA approves drugs that kill 100,000 people every year. I don't trust them, sorry. That's from their own website. </snippet></document><document><title>Can't seem to find a list of non-government-funded, non-profit organizations. Anybody have any ideas? Would like to show it to people who think there would be dead poor people in the streets without government. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/192ag1/cant_seem_to_find_a_list_of_nongovernmentfunded/</url><snippet>  There would be dead poor people in the streets. But that doesn't justify putting a gun to my head and taking a huge chunk of my earnings in order to (unsuccessfully) prevent this. There's more to anarcho-capitalism than economic arguments. Also remind them that removing protectionist tariffs in industrialized countries would drastically raise the standard of living in poorer countries due to outsourcing. The average standard of living in the world would increase greatly from anarcho-capitalism. I don't think there would be, just look at the mutual aid societies in early 1900s. Lots of ways to deal with the poor that don't involve gvt coercion. </snippet></document><document><title>japan whaling industry would collapse without government subsidies </title><url>http://www.globalpost.com/dispatch/news/regions/asia-pacific/japan/130214/whaling-whalemeat-japanese-food</url><snippet>    https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_public_debt

According to Wikipedia, Japanese public debt is 208% of GDP (2011 estimate).  One would think that with debt that high they would be looking for programs to cut.  Like maybe subsidies to a failing industry? Nah bro they gotta fight deflation remember? /s https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_public_debt

According to Wikipedia, Japanese public debt is 208% of GDP (2011 estimate).  One would think that with debt that high they would be looking for programs to cut.  Like maybe subsidies to a failing industry?  </snippet></document><document><title>The Forbidden History of Terrible Taxes</title><url>http://youtu.be/WGHY8XpM6oI</url><snippet>  This one of the best economic arguments against the state i've seen. Love this guy already It's a really good video overall. But, I'm annoyed with his conclusions at the end. His point seems to boil down to "We just have to vote better to lower our taxes". We need to demand *no* taxes. Once you give the state the moral authority to levy direct taxes from its subjects, there will be no lowering of taxes. They will always tax their populace in a way that maximizes their revenue. 90% of the battle is getting people into minarchism first, especially when coming from economics.</snippet></document><document><title>Family Lives Without Money&#8212;By Choice&#8212;and Thrives | Financially Fit</title><url>http://shine.yahoo.com/financially-fit/family-lives-without-money--by-choice--and-thrives--190436599.html</url><snippet>  &amp;gt; Though Fellmer uses no money, he said Palmer does use a little, mainly in the form of child support she receives from the government, which is granted to all children.

Well, that's not really "living without money."

Food sharing sounds cool though. I often dumpster way more than I need, simply because no one else around here does it. But I'm sure I could find some people to give excess food to.

I like this point a lot:

&amp;gt; &#8220;Children need from parents love, attention, time. All these materialistic things are really ridiculous,&#8221; he said, adding that used baby clothes are as easily had as thrown-away food.

But this: 

&amp;gt; &#8220;Money is hampering our dreams. Most people have forgotten it, or are completely afraid of living without money, so they are enslaved by the monetary system,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I hope to motivate people to believe a little more in their dreams.&#8221;

I just disagree with this. I'm a freegan, and am /r/anticonsumption, but money is just a store of value. Sometimes things come up that are more expensive than your normal consumption level. Having a savings of money is like a future's market for yourself. You spend less now, so that you have more money for variables in the future that may make your cost-of-living rise. 

I'd get it if he was doing it to protest *taxation,* but doing it to protest 'money' just sounds kind of like pandering to people that follow David Graeber. If he's doing this for lifestyle, ah salute. But if Raphael Fellmer comes out with a book for sale at the low price of $19.99 about his experiences, then I'll know what his motive's really were. Freegan? http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freeganism

Basically dumpster diving for food, but also living simple by trading things with other people, buying used clothes, dumpstering furniture and other household goods, etc.

I think of it as a subset of agorism, since I'm not paying sales taxes on any of these things, which is most of the things that I consume.    I'm not sure about this one. 

With all the time he spends actually working for one thing or another it does seem like he's being productive while working around the money system.  "They got a name for that, Jules. lt's called a bum. And w&#161;thout a job, a res&#161;dence, or legal tender... that's what you're go&#161;ng to be, man. You're go&#161;ng to be a fuck&#161;ng bum."  &amp;gt;One is through the fast-growing German movement of &#8220;foodsharing,&#8221; in which adherents use the Internet to share edible food that&#8217;s been foraged from grocery-store dumpsters.

&amp;gt;Mostly, Fellmer hopes his money strike can help change others&#8217; lives. &#8220;Money is hampering our dreams. Most people have forgotten it, or are completely afraid of living without money, so they are enslaved by the monetary system,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I hope to motivate people to believe a little more in their dreams.&#8221;


All the more power to you, I don't really see dumpster diving for a meal being a part of my dreams. You'd be surprised. You should check out /r/dumpsterdiving. What better way to screw the State out of revenue than be getting your food tax free.  My personal preference would be to have them prepare my meal fresh for me and I pay them for it in order to help their business and get to eat freshly prepared food   Interesting article, but obviously this can't be applied at a global scale, and not everyone has odd jobs for people to do.  But it is good to see wasted resources being put to use, as well as odd jobs being done.  </snippet></document><document><title>Fractional Reserve Banking is Obsolete</title><url>http://themisescircle.org/blog/2013/02/22/fractional-reserve-banking-is-obsolete/</url><snippet>  Obsolete, huh? Why is it still the dominant banking system? Because we don't live in a neoclassical, perfect information wonderland. Market processes take time. Believe it or not, there are people out there who still use DVDs. Do you think full-reserve banking is the better option? Personally I want a free banking system and I feel like at some point full-reserve would become more popular overtime. Yes, full reserve is the better option since it prevents business cycles.

Free banking with gold and silver has always led to fractional reserve banking, crises, cartelization, and central banking. Free banking with bitcoins will always lead to full-reserve banking. Has always? When was there Free Banking and how were crises and cartelization its necessary outgrowths? Or were those results politically inspired rather. Free banking allows for fractional reserve banking. Fractional reserve banking inevitably entails financial crises. Financial crises cause concentration and cartelization. Banking systems always exist in a political context, public choice economics' understanding of political rent seeking and regulatory capture explains why we end up with a central bank, subsidized deposit insurance, and bailouts. Just remove the precedent of economic intervention and those aren't problems. In fact those things are more of a problem, in a public choice theory sense, under full-reserve because fractional reserve lending would be prohibited. That is an economic intervention. FracReserve requires only property and contract rights, no need for the precedent of intervention.

Crises cause concentration and cartelization? How about those big 4 that would have gone under in 2008 had it not been for the bailouts. Crises can be used for concentration if one of the banks has a foreknowledge or an excellent understanding of ABCT which allows it to prepare for the crisis, but what is the quality of crisis which necessitates concentration of the banking sector? &amp;gt;Just remove the precedent of economic intervention and those aren't problems.

lol

&amp;gt;In fact those things are more of a problem, in a public choice theory sense, under full-reserve because fractional reserve lending would be prohibited. 

No, it would be less of a problem because there would no financial crises and thus no premise for having a regulator.

&amp;gt;Crises cause concentration and cartelization? How about those big 4 that would have gone under in 2008 had it not been for the bailouts.

Yes, that's exactly what I'm talking about.

&amp;gt;Crises can be used for concentration if one of the banks has a foreknowledge or an excellent understanding of ABCT which allows it to prepare for the crisis

No, they're just more conservative and sensible bankers. J.P. Morgan did not have foreknowledge in a conspiratorial sense of the word, and knew nothing about ABCT

&amp;gt;what is the quality of crisis which necessitates concentration of the banking sector?

Exactly what you just said, some banks are more solvent and are able to acquire competitors on the cheap. Do you remember Washington Mutual? Yes, full reserve is the better option since it prevents business cycles.

Free banking with gold and silver has always led to fractional reserve banking, crises, cartelization, and central banking. Free banking with bitcoins will always lead to full-reserve banking. Because we don't live in a neoclassical, perfect information wonderland. Market processes take time. Believe it or not, there are people out there who still use DVDs. I'm not saying that complaints about a fractional-reserve system should be muted, but that calling it "obsolete" is not even the right word.  The author may desire for the existing system to be replaced and they may have good points, but calling it obsolete is a cheap propaganda technique. The definition of obsolete is "no longer in use or no longer useful". Deposit banking, whether it's full or fractional, is no longer useful because Bitcoin performs its' functions better by several orders of magnitude. I guess I could have made the title "Deposit Banking is Obsolete". 


&amp;gt;cheap propaganda technique

What on earth are you talking about? Doesn't propaganda have to have an element of dishonesty? I don't desire for the existing system to be replaced, I am simply noting that it will inevitably be replaced by Bitcoin and fractional reserve banking is thus no longer useful and disappearing. Propaganda is a method of engaging person by attempting to bypass their rational capacity; engaging them emotionally.  Propaganda is used by more than just governments and news organizations, people like you and I use it all the time without thinking about it.  

And to say that fractional reserve banking is no longer useful isn't accurate either.  Plenty of people and institutions find it useful. It's far from obsolete. Because we don't live in a neoclassical, perfect information wonderland. Market processes take time. Believe it or not, there are people out there who still use DVDs. Bitcoin has a distribution problem.  How so? If you dont have a mining rig you have to find someone who does in order to participate in the economy. So theres a bunch of bottlenecks to get wide spread participation at this juncture. Bottlenecks will go down over time were probably very early adopters on the curve but this is why wide spread adoption hasn't happened already.  &amp;gt; you have to find someone who does in order to participate in the economy.

No, there are online exchanges. They are fairly liquid markets.

&amp;gt; So theres a bunch of bottlenecks to get wide spread participation at this juncture.

Only bottleneck is transferring dollars from your bank account. Right now I think coinbase is the best option, 1% fee. This fee will go down, by how much is anyones guess. </snippet></document><document><title>Would you rather end government control over education or government control over money?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/1904yj/would_you_rather_end_government_control_over/</url><snippet>Just to define terms, ending government control over education would destroy government control over all schools, universities, and private media. It might have its own broadcast stations and politicians will still make speeches which the media will cover and teachers, professors, and journalists will all have their own opinions, but there would be no direct state control nor any backroom deals.

Ending government control over money would end all legal tender, central banks, and just for the heck of it end fractional reserve banking as well, so that means absolutely no inflation. No one trades any money that is not backed up with gold in the bank (or anything else the market decides will act as money). Money is entirely controlled by the free market and the money supply may not be artificially increased. The government may still attempt to impose price controls and regulations, and it will still tax people, but the government may no longer print money for itself, nor may it debase any currency, and it may only influence interest rates by price control.

Discuss.

Edit: To expand on the education side of things, I want to emphasize that this is just getting rid of direct government involvement with education as in schools and the media. I just mean that they won't be running the show. Governments could still manipulate education by hiring economists and people to talk about how "ultra-scientific" they are about everything. Getting rid of government education would *not* get rid of government apologists, it would simply mean that governments don't decide school curriculums and that governments can't manipulate schools by offering "subsidies" to colleges that are saying what they want.  Education. No progress can be made in any area until the indoctrination of our children with statism ends. But there are alternatives to state education.  There are no alternatives to using the dollar.  If you don't like your local public education you can send your kid to a private school or homeschool or just teach him/her the truth.  If the economy goes to shit because the dollar loses value then we are all SOL. There are alternatives to using the dollar, just as there are alternatives to using public education. The problem with both is that the government provides both so pervasively. In the case of education, this means that it bids away education resources from the private sector and reorganizes them according to bureaucratic will; then it makes it available free of charge, further reducing the ability of the private sector to compete for the low income student market segment.
In the case of the dollar, it is more a problem of people already using it, so past prices are known denominated in dollars. If price inflation sets in in a big way, people will likely switch to bitcoin or gold/silver.
I think education is more important to wrest from the state, because then children will not be indoctrinated as they are now, and that this will speed monetary secession. There are alternatives to using the dollar, just as there are alternatives to using public education. The problem with both is that the government provides both so pervasively. In the case of education, this means that it bids away education resources from the private sector and reorganizes them according to bureaucratic will; then it makes it available free of charge, further reducing the ability of the private sector to compete for the low income student market segment.
In the case of the dollar, it is more a problem of people already using it, so past prices are known denominated in dollars. If price inflation sets in in a big way, people will likely switch to bitcoin or gold/silver.
I think education is more important to wrest from the state, because then children will not be indoctrinated as they are now, and that this will speed monetary secession.  Money.  While it means things won't likely change in my lifetime, at least if education is opened up, there's a chance things will change with regards to money later.  Money, no doubt. I believe that one's subconscious thoughts about money-related motivation are much stronger than one's conscious ideological motivations. Since all our conversations occur in the conscious, ideological domain, I think we have a tendency to exaggerate the impact our conscious ideology has on our actions. Just look at how rare we see truly "ethical" people and I think you'll see what I mean.

With control of money out of the way, people will naturally fall into modes of action more conducive to voluntary interaction, and they'll do so even while (consciously) believing they should be acting differently. All the statist indoctrination pales in comparison to the power of immediate economic payoff.         Bitcoin and things like it is going to end the control over money and after that all things will naturally follow. It is inevitable. Edit: Education is already largely decentralized and beyond the control of government for those who choose to home-school or do self-guided education with the available online tools that already exist. I think the internet is going to inevitably end control over education as well. I don't think it's easy to say which is more inevitable.  Why not both?   I have decided after hours of agonizing self debate, that I would end the control over money. I already home school my kids, because of the crap they were learning in school. The loss of control of money by the government as you described it just seems to damn fun to not earn my vote. Sure they would squirm with the end of public indoctrination, but they would loose their ever lovin' minds if they lost control of the money. They would likely spend so much time trying to write bills to somehow usurp the process that we could probably pull the rug out on a few more key issues as well.  Education, the money would follow when the chiddin's start reading up on Wilson. 

And those that call themselves progressive may get a little blush during the argument of *Buck v. Bell*.

"Three generations of imbeciles is enough" could be replaced with Six generations starting in 1965 until the day we oust the teachers unions and amend what has been so badly damaged. Keep in mind, I'm not promising a perfect education. There will still be government propaganda, the "official story", and government apologists, many hired by the state itself. This would simply end government monopolies over education and partnerships with schools, universities, and the media.   Education.

Money by the goverment (assuming we are talking USA) here is not that bad. Its pretty good actually, I belive it is BETTER then what you are advocating, 100% gold standard and 

&amp;gt;  No one trades any money that is not backed up with gold in the bank

That would be horrible. Did you miss the part where he followed that up with "or whatever else the market finds acceptable"? Education.

Money by the goverment (assuming we are talking USA) here is not that bad. Its pretty good actually, I belive it is BETTER then what you are advocating, 100% gold standard and 

&amp;gt;  No one trades any money that is not backed up with gold in the bank

That would be horrible. Not trying to be a douche - but I've noticed it enough now that I looked at your post history: Why is your spelling so bad? I'm not a grammar nazi - I never correct how people write. But damn, it almost seems like you're misspelling a bunch of words intentionally. Non native english. 

Slight form of dyslexia where I am unable to find spelling error, meaning I either have to check spelling for every work (witch leads to grammer errors) or have it correct by somebody, witch is just not worth it for reddit.

Even in my native language my writing would not be much better. Education.

Money by the goverment (assuming we are talking USA) here is not that bad. Its pretty good actually, I belive it is BETTER then what you are advocating, 100% gold standard and 

&amp;gt;  No one trades any money that is not backed up with gold in the bank

That would be horrible. Well, I'd want whatever the market decides to be money as compared to being a 100% gold standard (although I think its very likely the market will use that.

Please give this pamphlet by Rothbard a read: [What Has Government Done To Our Money?](http://mises.org/books/whathasgovernmentdone.pdf) by Murray Rothbard I think this is one point where rothbard is very wrong and is not in line with his own defintion of property rights. 

There is simply no way that fractional reserve banking can be seen as fraud. Even many 100% bankers see that, now many clame it would simply loose in the market witch is inconsistent with historical account witch is acctally show that 100% banks where what the market put out of buissness and only exists because of goverment regulation. Well, I highly suggest you read it and get his side of the story, and see his arguments. At the very least it will convince you that money by our government is *not* "not that bad", even if we accept fractional reserve banking.

I don't understand how you don't consider it fraudulent though. I'm promising people something I don't have. Imagine if I ten people bought a car from me, but when they all came to claim what they had paid for they found that I only had one car in stock. That would clearly be fraud, and banks do the exact same thing when they put out more notes that are not backed up by what they claim. I recently saw a case presented by David Friedman where he pointed out that many other businesses would not be able to pay out their worst case scenario maximum obligations, insurance companies is the specific example I remember.  

Here I found the interview.  http://youtu.be/QDK-hLOqZZk?t=25m51s

Not sure what to make of the case, just some food for thought.        Damn, that's a fucking hard one.

I'm just *barely* going to go with money, but both are so foundational.  Money. The motivator of all evil and oppressive deeds. And it want be that after we use gold? And it want be that after we use gold? I don't think the pentagon would be spending $1 trillion on new weapons of death if they were unable to print it out of thin air. (new jet fighters, high-tech bombs, aircraft carriers, nuclear submarines, 3,000,000 man standing army, etc.)

Sadly, drones are rather cost-effective so they may still be used as an oppressive tool of terrorism and death.      http://i.imgur.com/gZvsI9H.jpg ["WOULD YOU RATHER"S DO NOT WORK THAT WAY! GOODNIGHT!](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQg8JKo_3ZQ) I dunno, settling for the lesser of two evils just doesn't seem to be the ancap way... Who said we would need to settle? I just want to know what people think would put us in a better fighting position.

That's why I think so many people here are trying to explain why picking their choice will lead to getting rid of the other one more quickly or why it would do more good. Perhaps then the thread topic should be "Would you rather *start* ending government control by privatizing education or money?"  The way it is worded here makes it sound like the two are mutually exclusive and they are your only two options.

I didn't and currently do not mean to ruffle your feathers.   Would you rather have your left arm and right leg amputated, or your right arm and left leg?

/s  Education. 

The way your hypothetical works, I'd have to take the gold standard and I couldn't have fractional reserve banking. The government could still tax and regulate people though. What a bum deal. 
  Education with out a doubt. Culture determines politics, an educated citizenry would vote out leftists and end the gvt control on money on their own, but they'd just reinstitute gvt control of money if we ended it but let the gvt keep the schools. Need to think long term here.  In choosing one does the other come under absolute control of the government?  If so, then I'd rather it was money that was de-regulated by the government.  If not, then probably education.   The other would stay in the state that it currently is in. So if you choose money, governments would still try to control the other one. But if you believe that the other one would fall without the support of the other, that could be a real development. </snippet></document><document><title>I need help choosing the best book to introduce a friend to the ideas of anarcho-capitalism.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/190g1i/i_need_help_choosing_the_best_book_to_introduce_a/</url><snippet>She's a liberal but basically just inherited her opinions from her parents and doesn't hold them strongly. She is also open to the idea of reading my crazy wacko free society crap. I was thinking *For a New Liberty* might be a good book for drawing someone who isn't familiar with intellectually-consistent libertarianism towards other meatier stuff. What does /r/ancap think?  I think being a liberal, the biggest thing to be taught is the power of the free market, sound money etc. So I would say economics in one lesson would be a good start. Its important to understand the economic benefits of having a deregulated economy, it's not all about making the rich richer as many liberals seem to assume. I know because I was one, I voted based on social issues every time, the economics I did not know.   Jeffery Tucker's "Bourbon for Breakfast, Living outside the statist quo" is a great read. While it is not an "anarchist manifesto" it does point out the many ways government interferes with our personal and private lives, that we may not have otherwise realized, being that we are born into a statist society. The book may not have the ideologies laid out of ancapistan, but it gets the reader to start thinking out of the statist quo    I think Chaos Theory by Bob Murphy is a great introduction to crazy wacko free society crap, but that only really has to do with law and defense. The Machinery of Freedom is another classic, and is soon coming out in a third edition.

but you should definitely shore her up with some more general libertarianish stuff as well. for example End the Fed is another great short, easy read, and Ron Paul's books usually have great easy-to-read reading lists in the back.  Anarcho-capitalism doesn't make any sense if you don't know economics first.

Start with Economics in One Lesson or Man Economy and State.   I *strongly* recommend Michael Huemer's [The Problem of Political Authority](http://www.amazon.com/Problem-Political-Authority-Examination-Coerce/dp/1137281650). I have read almost all of the other books recommended here (including For a New Liberty) and can say that without question, Huemer's book is by far the best I've ever read.

I picked it up after reading Bryan Caplan's [glowing review](http://econlog.econlib.org/archives/2013/01/the_problem_of_1.html) of the book, and everything Caplan says is dead on.

Seriously, I can't recommend this book enough for someone who is unfamiliar with libertarianism but is generally responsive to solid intellectual discussion.    I strongly recommend Bastiat's "What is seen and What is not seen" to get her into the mindset of thinking about economics without an associated contemporary political agenda.
        </snippet></document><document><title>Barrett (firearm company) essentially calls the NY government a criminal organization. </title><url>http://barrett.net/news/11</url><snippet>  Best letter yet from a manufacturer refusing to sell to the government. I'm glad that so many are stepping up. As far as I am aware they are still fulfilling military contracts. So take that as you will. The military may currently be engaging in unwarranted wars, however they are not yet being used to take away the rights of American civilians. &amp;gt; As far as I am aware they are still fulfilling military contracts.

Contractual agreements pretty important in an-capistan, as I understand it. Not when it's to a known criminal organization. Say!  That brings up a question in my mind.

( I'm coming at this as a guy who has known _of_ anarcho-capitalism for years but has only lately realized I am slowly coming to agree philosophically with an-cap world view. )

How does the opinion of some guy allow a 3rd party to renege on a contractual obligation?

--

I own BDunbar's Metal Works and Banjo Factory.  I contract with Mafia Inc, provide goods, payment is rendered, things are going great.

RyanPig points out they are known criminals and I don't need to keep my contractual obligation to them.  I think about it ... by golly he's _right_.

They look shady.  They _act_ shady.  I've heard they spit on the street and are tight with tips at the diner.  They're in and out of Jim Bob's Courthouse so often they have their own entrance.  I wouldn't trust my children with them, let alone my bank account.

Yet they're not reneged on their deal with _me_, or done me any personal wrong.

How does the mere opinion of some people allow me to cut up my contract with them?
 You'd have to deal with the fact that those who don't approve of Mafia Inc. are unlikely to purchase your products but if you're making more money with them it would be in your best interest to stay. Also, there isn't such a thing as a criminal organization here really. Right, agreed.

OP implied contractual obligations could be negated if one party was a 'known criminal organization'.  I'm still wondering how one can walk away from an obligation if the other party, without violating the agreement, turns into a band of dirty rats. Well if we went with the private courts scenario and enough people disapproved of the band of dirty scoundrels the courts might not rule in their favor because of popular opinion. Maybe that court has a bunch of contracts with people that Mafia Inc. has wronged. Outside of that it would be difficult to get out of the contract. As far as I am aware they are still fulfilling military contracts. So take that as you will. The military may currently be engaging in unwarranted wars, however they are not yet being used to take away the rights of American civilians. Given that American guns law is permissive by global standards and invaders dislike an armed populace the only reason Americans have the right to guns is because no foreign power has ever been able to invade. 

Now you could argue that an armed populace is sufficient to deter invasion but historically that hasn't been the case. An armed populace can't stop an invasion by a professional military. Obviously it is better equipped to mount an insurgency post invasion but a ruthless invader can terrorise people into not using their firearms, at least not against the occupation forces by collective punishment - i.e. destroy any villages that are suspected of harbouring insurgents. After that it can terrorize people into handing them in.

The US army is not a particularly ruthless invader when it comes to civilians - it doesn't use mass execution of hostages as a tool to suppress insurgency in the way the WWII era Russian, German and Japanese ones did. Still even it was able to suppress an insurgency in countries where virtually everyone had access to an AK-47.

So you really need the US army to have any chance of having liberal gun laws. Or liberal anything laws really. As far as I am aware they are still fulfilling military contracts. So take that as you will. The military may currently be engaging in unwarranted wars, however they are not yet being used to take away the rights of American civilians. Ah, that's too bad then. Something is better than nothing, I guess. Best letter yet from a manufacturer refusing to sell to the government. I'm glad that so many are stepping up. Anybody else but Barret? I seriously admire this company CEO - real hero. LaRue Tactical,
Olympic Arms,
Extreme Firepower,
Templar Custom,
York Arms,
Cheaper Than Dirt.

It'd get really serious if a company like Glock or Colt stopped selling to these governments. &amp;gt; Cheaper Than Dirt

Thats good to see, I've order from them a bunch of times, pretty good company. Cheap and not bad quality for what you order. They tend not to be cheaper than their competition.  Look into what they did after Newtown. Anybody else but Barret? I seriously admire this company CEO - real hero. Anybody else but Barret? I seriously admire this company CEO - real hero. Best letter yet from a manufacturer refusing to sell to the government. I'm glad that so many are stepping up.  Wow. I saw two black and yellow bumper stickers yesterday and a "special report" on television doing a hatchet job on soveriegn citizens. Now this. It really is happening. [It's Happening](http://www.animateit.net/data/media/353/ehlxld.gif) Wow. I saw two black and yellow bumper stickers yesterday and a "special report" on television doing a hatchet job on soveriegn citizens. Now this. It really is happening. Wow. I saw two black and yellow bumper stickers yesterday and a "special report" on television doing a hatchet job on soveriegn citizens. Now this. It really is happening. Wow. I saw two black and yellow bumper stickers yesterday and a "special report" on television doing a hatchet job on soveriegn citizens. Now this. It really is happening. Wow. I saw two black and yellow bumper stickers yesterday and a "special report" on television doing a hatchet job on soveriegn citizens. Now this. It really is happening.  Everyone is a libertarian when it's THERE liberty that is at risk. If only people cared enough for everyone elses liberty. You would think if you spent the effort to capitalize it you would at least get the grammar right.   Its a bunch of dumb posturing.  Ever notice how they never bothered to ban sales to the US Federal Govt. after Waco.  Or how about banning sales to the Feds based on the fact that they tax us all to provide subsidies to corn farmers?  Seems like that is a greater burden on us than any peripheral legislation about controlling magazine sizes.

Why wouldn't they do that?  Because they are just playing to a constituency consisting mainly of people that wouldn't get the point about farm subsidies.  And they won't take a stand against the Feds because the Feds give them too much money.

Bunch of horseshit. It sounds like what we need is a principled firearm manufacturer who refuses to to business with states and their assorted tentacles, period.

I wonder if you could build a profitable company that way or not.  Doesn't Barrett sell sniper rifles to the US Military? So they're not selling to the NY State government who probably didn't buy many anyway but they are selling the US military who buy presumably buy loads. It's a nice press release but it's not like they're taking any sort of financial hit.  Makes you wonder if he really even had many contracts with the government and is doing this as a calculated PR move.

But, if that's not entering into his thinking and he's just standing on principle, then good on him, I guess.  But, I doubt the move is going to have much effect; other contractors will more than happily fill whatever void Barrett would be creating. The Barrett semi-auto M82 is pretty much the premier rifle used by SWAT and similar to stop vehicles by destroying the engine block.  They were probably buying at least a few.  They stopped sales to the Commiefornia government when they banned .50 BMG.    Wow..regardless of the merit (or lack thereof) of Ronnie Barrett's comments here, this is horribly written and frankly, somewhat embarrassing. I had to read the first line several times to fully parse it. I didn't. Maybe your comprehension is an issue? Re-read the opening line for example. Re-read the opening line for example.   "...strip inalienable rights from the people that were given to all by our Creator."

LOL, I never knew the right to bear arms came from a supposed god. It bothers me when people talk like this. The only thing that was even given to us was life by our parents. To imply that our rights emanate from a higher power is ridiculous and self-defeating. In the struggle against authority I utterly fail to see how bringing in a god (aka an even higher authority) helps the situation. Where do rights come from then? My willingness to utilize &amp;amp; protect them and societies willingness to utilize and protect them. If either one breaks down this idea of rights goes to shit. "Rights" are also contingent of the context of the time. I don't recall many people talking about their god given right to own cannons 400 years ago. I agree with you but at the same time, if someone thinks I should be free because Jesus told them so, I'll settle for that. At least they think I should be free. "...strip inalienable rights from the people that were given to all by our Creator."

LOL, I never knew the right to bear arms came from a supposed god. It bothers me when people talk like this. The only thing that was even given to us was life by our parents. To imply that our rights emanate from a higher power is ridiculous and self-defeating. In the struggle against authority I utterly fail to see how bringing in a god (aka an even higher authority) helps the situation. Where do rights come from then? My willingness to utilize &amp;amp; protect them and societies willingness to utilize and protect them. If either one breaks down this idea of rights goes to shit. "Rights" are also contingent of the context of the time. I don't recall many people talking about their god given right to own cannons 400 years ago. "...strip inalienable rights from the people that were given to all by our Creator."

LOL, I never knew the right to bear arms came from a supposed god. It bothers me when people talk like this. The only thing that was even given to us was life by our parents. To imply that our rights emanate from a higher power is ridiculous and self-defeating. In the struggle against authority I utterly fail to see how bringing in a god (aka an even higher authority) helps the situation. Where do rights come from then? My willingness to utilize &amp;amp; protect them and societies willingness to utilize and protect them. If either one breaks down this idea of rights goes to shit. "Rights" are also contingent of the context of the time. I don't recall many people talking about their god given right to own cannons 400 years ago. "...strip inalienable rights from the people that were given to all by our Creator."

LOL, I never knew the right to bear arms came from a supposed god. It bothers me when people talk like this. The only thing that was even given to us was life by our parents. To imply that our rights emanate from a higher power is ridiculous and self-defeating. In the struggle against authority I utterly fail to see how bringing in a god (aka an even higher authority) helps the situation. Where do rights come from then? My willingness to utilize &amp;amp; protect them and societies willingness to utilize and protect them. If either one breaks down this idea of rights goes to shit. "Rights" are also contingent of the context of the time. I don't recall many people talking about their god given right to own cannons 400 years ago.   I don't have a burning desire to own a big honking rifle like the M82.

But I have more of a desire now than I did this morning.

Now if I could just talk the missus into letting me install it over the mantle.   </snippet></document><document><title>DHS Establishes Constitution-Free Zones</title><url>http://simplefactsplainarguments.blogspot.com/2013/02/dhs-establishes-constitution-free-zones.html</url><snippet>   Hawaii is screwed.   This type of shit has killed the US.  The only thing the Democrats were ever good for was protesting this kind of thing, and now that one of their own is doing it, they're just as gung-ho as any neoconservative ever was.        I wonder what percentage of the population is covered by that. The zone takes up most of the Great Lakes, North East, and California's populated areas.   its only 100 miles from land borders, not the ocean. So you think it's still okay if hypothetically a person driving in new jersey is stopped for no apparent reason, and gets thrown in prison for having a stash of weed or an unloaded pistol in his car?  </snippet></document><document><title>Democracy absurdity</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/190070/democracy_absurdity/</url><snippet>Imagine India having a referendum about whether they should become part of the US, and that the vast majority votes yes. Now India considers itself part of the US and that they are entitled to all the resources and things that come with that (like medicaid, public schooling etc). 

In the US, a referendum on this is held where the vast majority votes no. But even if that is the case, the voters in the US are vastly outnumbered by the 1 billion Indians out of whom a majority voted yes. As such, arguably any *true* believer in democracy *must* acknowledge that India is now part of the US and that Indians are entitled to the same resources and things as the rest of Americans are.

Just a thought experiment of mine, what do yall think about this?  The method behind democracy, popular vote, is practical in some situations. In many cases it is not practical or it is absurd and destructive.

Democracy can only be described as "fair" when the participants consent to the method and potential consequences. Otherwise, it is merely a ritualized form of might makes right. For that reason, whether or not democracy is used must not be a democratic decision. So, ultimately, no democracy. The method behind democracy, popular vote, is practical in some situations. In many cases it is not practical or it is absurd and destructive.

Democracy can only be described as "fair" when the participants consent to the method and potential consequences. Otherwise, it is merely a ritualized form of might makes right. &amp;gt; Democracy can only be described as "fair" when the participants consent to the method and potential consequences.

If participants consent to the method and potential consequences, then it's not democracy, which is *rule* or *governance* by the people. It's just people doing what they want to do, which may happen to depend on the opinions of a larger number of people.  Popularity is a horrible metric for determining who violence should be used against. It forces people to divide against each other for fear that they will be the target of violence.

You want another interesting thought experiment? Imagine you had the capacity of creating a million humans a day. You then use this power to obtain 51% of the vote. You are now a dictator.

Democracy can work for very small groups of friendly people. As it grows larger, the potential and chance for abuse grows exponentially along with it. Once you pass a few thousand people, you're going to start seeing a lot of corruption. Most democratic nations today have *many millions* of people. &amp;gt; You want another interesting thought experiment? Imagine you had the capacity of creating a million humans a day. You then use this power to obtain 51% of the vote. You are now a dictator.

I don't really get this argument. You would also have to ensure that the humans you create all vote the way you desire. But if you have that ability, you could be a dictator in *any* system, democracy or otherwise.  Great thought experiment.

You're preaching to the choir here. It would be interesting to hear a statist's view on this. I posted it in /r/democracy but for some reason it doesnt show up in the "new" section. I posted it in /r/democracy but for some reason it doesnt show up in the "new" section. I think they don't accept self-posts. That's lucky. I'd have to go there and clarify you weren't speaking for all ancaps. (This should go without saying, that no ancap speaks for our whole "party", but I very much doubt folks at statist subreddits would get it without some careful, patient explaining.) Great thought experiment.

You're preaching to the choir here. It would be interesting to hear a statist's view on this.   This is a bad critique of democracy, because it misses the point of how states work.

States are *sovereign*; this means there is no power above them. Legally speaking, the US is no more powerful than a tiny state like Nauru or a failed one like Somalia. Statist legal theory gives the state of Nauru (in principle) absolute power to do whatever it pleases within its territory, and the US doesn't get a say in that. This is the legal basis, for example, for the US not invading North Korea, and for it having had to ask the UN for permission to kick Iraq's ass in the 1991 Gulf War. (Statist legal theory holds that Iraq, by signing up to become a UN member, gave the Security Council permission to authorise interventions against it. If two non-UN member countries were fighting, it wouldn't be obvious how any UN member could act in that context, unless they invoked "humanitarian" principles, which are sometimes argued against this "states can do whatever they want" theory).

Included within the concept of sovereignty is the ability to choose whatever means of governance a state wants; that is, states can decide *how* to exert their sovereignty. Democracy is considered nice, but states have no legal obligation to adopt it. If they do, they are free to restrict the right to vote in their elections to their citizens and/or residents; there is simply no logic to the concept of Indians voting to become part of the US. I mean, India is free to do that, but the crucial point is that *the US has no obligation to accept that*. India can go ahead and adopt the US Constitution and laws, but the US has no obligation to recognise that. Besides, this would be an incredibly bizarre situation; given that the US wouldn't accept India, Indian citizens would be subject to US laws without having a say on how they're made, because non-acceptance by the US would mean Indians wouldn't be represented in Congress. The US wouldn't have to give India any of the "benefits" like welfare or even defence, for that matter, regardless of whether India collected its taxes according to the US tax code and sent the money to Washington. I mean, seriously, this is ridiculous and bizarre, and you shouldn't even have posted this on /r/democracy . It's cringe-worthy.

Now, to give an example which is more real, consider the recent referendum in Puerto Rico (which *is already* a US unincorporated territory, which is different from what most of the states were before they became states; they were *incorporated* territories). In the same day as the US elections last November, Puerto Rico held its own vote, which included a referendum on its status. The options were seeking independence, keeping its current status or trying to join the US as a state, and this last option won. What happens now? *Nothing*. At least not automatically, just as a consequence of the Puerto Rico vote. The government of PR will have to apply to join the US, and (according to the US Constitution) Congress will decide on that. Likely, the PR government won't even apply unless there's a clear signal from Congress that it would be accepted. And that signal is quite unlikely to come, mainly because PR is so much poorer than even the poorest state in the US.

tl;dr - this detracts absolutely nothing from the idea of democracy, because it is based on an absurdly wrong conception of what it really means, and this is definitely not how we'll be able to bring down the State.   Not saying I disagree with the point you're making, democracy can be destructive or have undesired results especially for the minority. However, in your situation, the US would have to first accept India as a part of itself before it could attempt to rid itself of it. I don't think the US and India would vote on the issue as a single entity, which is what I think you were implying. I know it's an extreme hypothetical but you really don't need something that extreme to demonstrate the problems with democracy. &amp;gt;However, in your situation, the US would have to first accept India as a part of itself before it could attempt to rid itself of it.

wat Maybe I worded that completely wrong, but why would India's vote on it have any bearing whether the US accepts them as part of it? If it wasn't in the US's interest they would reject the claim and not put it up to the combined vote of the people of both nations. The hypothetical is absurd and is unnecessary to demonstrate the problems with democracy. Not saying I disagree with the point you're making, democracy can be destructive or have undesired results especially for the minority. However, in your situation, the US would have to first accept India as a part of itself before it could attempt to rid itself of it. I don't think the US and India would vote on the issue as a single entity, which is what I think you were implying. I know it's an extreme hypothetical but you really don't need something that extreme to demonstrate the problems with democracy. You seem to be arguing against democracy to defend it. I'm not defending democracy, I'm just saying OP's situation is something that can NEVER happen in the way he described, and he doesn't need such an extreme example to demonstrate the problems with democracy. There are countless other examples of a vote hurting the minority. </snippet></document><document><title>TIL that North Korea marks the anniversary of the abolition of income tax in March of every year</title><url>http://www.koryogroup.com/travel_groupTours.php</url><snippet>      </snippet></document><document><title>Anyone else notice how China seems to be "hacking the US" more just as CISPA is being re-proposed in Congress?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/18yxuz/anyone_else_notice_how_china_seems_to_be_hacking/</url><snippet>  I imagine the Chinese are actually hacking into US government networks, and have been for some time. And the US is hacking them too. Many countries and corporations are hacking each other all the time. All sides get to use it as an excuse to crack down on their domestic populations.    </snippet></document><document><title>While I don't think libertarianism implies the need to remove traffic rules, I still found this experiment in decentralized decision-making rather interesting.</title><url>http://econlog.econlib.org/archives/2013/02/in_2010_alex_wr.html</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>has anyone ever made a "guide to political buzzwords"? for satire?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/190cm3/has_anyone_ever_made_a_guide_to_political/</url><snippet>you know there are the good buzzwords to use for anything good, democracy, organic, equality, fair share, etc. and then there are the bad buzzwords for anything that is evil, chemicals, profits, free markets etc. 

i'd want to see this in like an image that you would share on facebook...but i'm too lazy to make it lol  This sounds fun, give me some suggestions for design and words, I'll try to make something this weekend. It could be called something like "words that can be used when you have no good arguments"

We should try to make this a fun thing with a point, and make sure it doesn't become circlejerky  I've been seeing a whole lot of Heinlein references lately on this subreddit. Just after I started reading The Moon is a Harsh Mistress I saw a thread about Heinlein here, the first thread about him I've ever seen. Such an odd coincidence. That's funny, I read it about a month and a half ago. It might just be that we notice that kind of stuff after having read it. </snippet></document><document><title>Citizens are just Subjects of the State</title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fxQp6ZKpqDk&amp;amp;feature=youtube_gdata_player</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Stand-your-ground laws?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/18zpkc/standyourground_laws/</url><snippet>I was asked by my friends about stand-your-ground laws. I honestly had no opinion on them. Is there an an-cap opinion on these laws? Should they be repealed?      I don't really know what they even are. Essentially it says you don't have to run away in a conflict from a criminal. You can stand your ground to protect yourself or your property.    In practice, it depends on where the attack takes place. Three U.S. jurisdictions demand that you flee out a back door or window if your home is invaded. Twenty states allow you to defend your own home, but demand that you retreat if you are attacked when you are not at home. Twenty-eight states allow self-defense no matter where you are. For details see http://ccwvslaw.org/item/888.  </snippet></document><document><title>Tesco accused of using electronic armbands to monitor its staff (I'm interested in what the capitalist response to this is)</title><url>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/news/tesco-accused-of-using-electronic-armbands-to-monitor-its-staff-8493952.html</url><snippet>  Simple.  I probably wouldn't work there unless the pay was good.  Have you ever had a job?                </snippet></document><document><title>What is the ACist response to the "Genghis Khan argument"?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/18yk4q/what_is_the_acist_response_to_the_genghis_khan/</url><snippet>This is a argument that Jan Halfeld makes. (He's the guy that interviews people using the Socrates method.) He admitted in a debate that he advocates initiation of violence against peaceful people (taxation) to raise funds for wide scale military defense because he thinks that a alternative to this violence is total physical annihilation.

The standard argument against the threat of military invasion of an ACist society goes like this: it is unprofitable to conquer an area without established tax structure,

But I just finished listening to Dan Carlin's "Wrath of the Khans" series and it struck me that the Mongols murdered and pillaged both established states and empires as well as non-state societies. Whatever peoples they came into contact with had to either assimilate or die. Basically, a real-life Borg. The Borg does not care about profitability.

And while I don't think that such a threat is likely in today's world, how do you respond to minarchists like Halfeld?  How does anarcho-capitalism solve the problem of extinction-event meteor impacts? How does anarcho-capitalism solve the problem of extinction-event meteor impacts? How does anarcho-capitalism solve the problem of extinction-event meteor impacts?  The state didn't do them any good did it?

Why do "we" need an answer for everything? The implicit double-standard is annoying. "We need your alternative to solve problems so impossible even our solution can't reliably solve it! How will anarchy alone protect a lone sheep from a pack of hungry wolves?" We'll give the sheep an assault rifle, a couple hand grenades, and teach it to say "come at me bro." We'll give the sheep an assault rifle, a couple hand grenades, and teach it to say "come at me bro."  &amp;gt;to raise funds for wide scale military defense because he thinks that a alternative to this violence is total physical annihilation

Tell that to the Vietcong.

&amp;gt;The Borg does not care about profitability.

Things that don't care about material productivity can't sustain themselves long. &amp;gt;Tell that to the Vietcong.

They did their best in a terrible situation, but ideally you want to deter an invasion in the first place, or at least resist it before your country is totally occupied and you have to resort to costly guerrilla warfare.  The VC/North Vietnamese lost somewhere in the vicinity of a million soldiers, in addition to the hundreds of thousands of civilian deaths.  They might have been better off just surrendering. &amp;gt;Tell that to the Vietcong.

They did their best in a terrible situation, but ideally you want to deter an invasion in the first place, or at least resist it before your country is totally occupied and you have to resort to costly guerrilla warfare.  The VC/North Vietnamese lost somewhere in the vicinity of a million soldiers, in addition to the hundreds of thousands of civilian deaths.  They might have been better off just surrendering. Not to forget that the USA effectively could have beaten the Vietcong if they had the will to do that. For every killed American soldier you had twenty killed Vietkongs.  Not to forget that the USA effectively could have beaten the Vietcong if they had the will to do that. For every killed American soldier you had twenty killed Vietkongs.  The USA didn't bother winning because there was no profit in it.

 More like because they had a million angry hippies at home and a population that was shocked by brutality of the war that was seen for the first time on tv. haha. 

No that wasn't it. 

It's a lovely fantasy though. If you say so.  &amp;gt;Tell that to the Vietcong.

They did their best in a terrible situation, but ideally you want to deter an invasion in the first place, or at least resist it before your country is totally occupied and you have to resort to costly guerrilla warfare.  The VC/North Vietnamese lost somewhere in the vicinity of a million soldiers, in addition to the hundreds of thousands of civilian deaths.  They might have been better off just surrendering. &amp;gt;to raise funds for wide scale military defense because he thinks that a alternative to this violence is total physical annihilation

Tell that to the Vietcong.

&amp;gt;The Borg does not care about profitability.

Things that don't care about material productivity can't sustain themselves long. The VC were a very small part of the overall North Vietnamese war effort.  The VC themselves did not repel the US invaders.

Not to discount their efforts but it's just untrue to say that Vietnam was entirely, or even predominately, a guerrilla war. That's what my reading of US Army history and other sources told me.

Do you have a source(s) substantiating your counter-claim? I do have a few that I'll share.  I'm not at my home library so I can't dig up a ton of sources.

One of the biggest upsets of the war was the Tet Offensive, a massive surprise attack coordinated by the VietCong (VC, "Charlie", guerrilla irregulars fighting for the Communist North Vietnam) and the North Vietnamese Army (NVA, the regular organized army, supplied by the Chinese and Russians).   I'm just quoting from Wiki here so I reserve the right to edit this after researching at home, but essentially 80,000 Communist troops, primarily the regular NVA, attacked American strong points during a cease fire.   This was the largest military action of the war by either side.  The "massive" losses on the part of the Communist forces were sustained primarily by the NVA and, had those causalities been inflicted solely upon the VC, the guerrilla army would have perished.  The ability to wage such a large campaign, successful primarily as a psychological victory, and to absorb the huge losses was something that only a large regular army could have.

The Clifford Group determined that no amount of troop increase would be effective as the North Vietnamese were supplied with arms by a superpower and with men by a regional super-power. 

When 200-400,000 Chinese troops invaded Vietnam in 1978 (Sino-Vietnamese war) they were repelled and expelled by 70-140,000 Vietnamese regulars, not the Viet Cong.  

Vietnam has always fought a "Eastern mentality" war, using deceit and misdirection as primary tactics, but they fought those tactics with large regular units for the most part.

Now, none of this is to say that the Viet Cong didn't play a large role in the war.  Mao states that an guerrilla army needs, among other things, support from a powerful foreign nation.  The Viet Cong received this support, logistical and material, from the Russians, the Chinese and the North Vietnamese.   They were instrumental in moving the required supplies and regular troops, hidden, into South Vietnam for the Tet Offensive.

If you want to read some great books about the Eastern mentality of fighting, USMC GySgt H John Poole has written a bunch.  Phantom Soldier is probably the best but once you read one you'll want to read them all.

That's the real danger with a future Sino-American war, in my off-subject opinion.  The understanding of the Eastern method of war just doesn't make it too far above the grunts fighting in the sand (jungle, mud, etc).  I can't tell you how many times I've heard "China could never attack us!" (Or a unified Korea, etc) and usually the guy saying it is a student of Western Clausewitz-ian style of war.  The Eastern way won't let them attack us in a way that doesn't almost guarantee their victory.  We also can't look at a victory or loss as a function of military occupation.  If the Chinese really wanted to hurt America, it would be a combined cyber/financial attack crushing our world influence and ability to purchase necessary materials.  Comparing this to the original subject; this would be an example of Eastern-style warfare being executed by a large military force to attain a non-standard victory. &amp;gt;Mao states that an guerrilla army needs, among other things, support from a powerful foreign nation.

Mao may say that and want to believe it, but I don't.

The Iraqi resistance was supplied in part by Syria and Iran, but that merely added onto their already existing effectiveness; it wasn't a necessary condition for success.

I think what's cloaking this debate we're having is exactly this foreign support.  You see and point to it as something critical to success and I don't believe it.  I also hope we're on the same page as far as the metrics of measuring guerrilla warfare success; I don't mean the US dropping gallons of napalm and the other ways they wiped out thousands, but the economics of such warfare.

It's also kind of silly to think what helps a guerrilla force is conventional warfare.  That is the US's wheelhouse.  The US military wiped out the Iraqi military in less than a month, yet the occupation against guerrillas went on for years until they finally paid off a number of them.

Occupations, so long as they remain that as perceived by the native populace, are not sustainable.  Did you watch [this video](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3-FAa6TOG2o)?

&amp;gt;Vietnam has always fought a "Eastern mentality" war, using deceit and misdirection as primary tactics, but they fought those tactics with large regular units for the most part.

Eh, as much as I regard you as a learned person, it's beyond silly to regard this as particular to that region or those peoples.  *All* of war *everywhere* is deceit and misdirection.  Any military historian knows this.

&amp;gt;The Eastern way won't let them attack us in a way that doesn't almost guarantee their victory.

I think this is committing an opposite fallacy of assuming Chinese are somehow unnaturally clever people. I disagree with you regarding the Iraqi's.  Their regular forces had amassed and produced an astonishing amount of regular weapons (RPG's, belt-fed machine guns, explosives) and had them pre positioned to support essentially a "stay behind" force.

It's also important to understand that there are lots of enemy combatants in Iraq and not all of them are the "insurgency" (Ba'ath loyalists, supplied by the Regular army, fighting coalition forces).

The initial insurgency against the coalition forces, before AQAP and other Islamic forces became involved, was an intentional, well-supplied stay-behind operation of a major military force.  Once it was clear that the coalition forces were going to destroy the entirety of the structure of the regular army, they vanished into the population, taking with them the knowledge of hidden bunkers filled with weapons specifically beneficial to asymmetrical warfare.  While the material support was not, specifically, foreign it was the byproduct of support from a (now dissolved) regional super power with a large regular military.  If the Iraqi insurgency were forced to start off with "only" hunting rifles and AK47's they would have been very ineffective.  Having access to military weapons (RPG's, explosives and mortars specifically) allowed them to change their tactics to meet the reality of their war.


The large-scale battles that proved necessary in the past required maneuver warfare, artillery, large armored vehicles and, in some instances, fast attack air-craft.  These are not the tools of the insurgent.  Insurgents have great difficulty holding terrain against a technologically superior force.  They might be able to deny the terrain to an attacker (Stalingrad, late stages) but they can't take over the terrain without the assistance of regular troops.  

Iraqi insurgents are able to find safe-havens among the populace, another requirement of Mao's, but they aren't having much success in taking or holding critical objectives.

I'm not denying the importance of asymmetrical warfare. I'm saying two things. 

1.  Large, regular forces specifically indoctrinated in asymmetrical warfare are not necessarily participating in guerrilla warfare and their success should be chalked up to a combination of asymmetrical warfare and maneuver warfare.

2.  Guerrilla insurgents, if they are to take and hold ground, must at some point either evolve into regular forces or be helped by outside regular forces.   The NVA were assisted by the VC at Tet but if the NVA hadn't been there the ruse would have been much less impressive.   The guerrillas didn't push the Marines out of Saigon, the NVA did that with tanks, helicopters and huge waves of troops.    If the Ba'athists are to take power again in Iraq it won't be as a group of masked IED trigger men, it'll be an organized front with a regular uniformed army taking and holding positions.

Success is really the hardest part of this discussion to narrow down.  The Viet Cong were successful in attacking American supply lines but they were not successful in taking and holding towns and strong points.  Iraq and Afghanistan enemy factions don't hold any harbors, airports, large towns or strategic population centers, can we say that they are being more or less "successful" than the coalition forces?  Can we call the evacuation of coalition forces a victory for the enemy forces or for the coalition? 

Eastern nations, and Eastern influences nations, are always hard for traditional Western-thinking commanders to take over.  Afghanistan has been invaded many times.  The book I referenced earlier talks about the numerous invasions of Afghanistan and how their tribal network organizes into an insurgency.  That same tribal insurgent network doesn't work together to conquer outside lands (regular, manuever warfare), rather they make their lands inhospitable to the invaders.  It's worth noting that some of the later insurgents were only able to become highly effective when supplied with advanced weaponry from a technologically superior Western super power.

Unpopular occupations are unsustainable, for the most part, I agree with that.  When the occupying Army starts to pull out a power vacuum is created that is filled by the actors of a large, regular army.  I can not think of a time where a small, guerrilla force took over a nation and held power without evolving into a regular army.

There is a great deal to be learned studying the ways various people fight war.  What are the nations that America has failed to conquer and maintain control over?  Korea, Vietnam, Afghanistan, Iraq.  All Eastern-style combatants.   When Western forces were still marching around in long lines wearing bright colors, Mir Wais Hotak had pushed back a number of much larger regular Persian armies.   Hotak is another great example of a insurgent (against the Persian leaders) becoming a regular army (under a monarchy) that claimed tracts of lands and repelled enemy forces.  Western maneuver warfare conquered and vanquished the Nazi's and the Nazi resistance but it still hasn't managed to take and hold an Eastern-thinking nation.  Ten years in Afghanistan and we'll leave it just as we found it, a total clusterfuck of tribal warfare and low level power grabs.

 You've kind of overstated the grandeur of the Iraqi military, but I'm not terribly interested in getting into that.

&amp;gt;If the Iraqi insurgency were forced to start off with "only" hunting rifles and AK47's they would have been very ineffective.

I disagree.  A $30 IED can take out or severely damage a $65,000 Humvee.  The armored variant is 3-5x more expensive.

Information is also inherently decentralized in reality.  This is why command economies fail.  It's the same reason why guerrilla attacks tend to surprise the occupier more often than they are foiled.

Any time a state seeks to rule, a smaller group of actors are trying to control a larger group of actors.  As that video explained, this can really only sustain itself when enough of the larger group mentally consents and feels like the entire structure is a cohesive nation.

&amp;gt;Having access to military weapons (RPG's, explosives and mortars specifically) allowed them to change their tactics to meet the reality of their war.

You act like weapons can't be smuggled in, created, stolen from the occupiers, or that sabotage using other means can't be even more effective.

&amp;gt;but they can't take over... taking or holding critical objectives

You're implying they need do this.  All you have to do is bleed the occupiers to the point where whatever group animates policy feels it's no longer profitable.

&amp;gt;The NVA were assisted by the VC at Tet but if the NVA hadn't been there the ruse would have been much less impressive.

Well, the Tet Offensive wasn't even an American loss; it was just perceived that way by Americans back home.

But, I actually think guerrilla warfare has even more impressive economic efficiency when it doesn't receive conventional aid.

&amp;gt;Eastern nations, and Eastern influences nations, are always hard for traditional Western-thinking commanders to take over.

This has much more to do with mere different cultures than it has *anything* to do with supposedly radically different tactics.  I'm not saying guerrilla warfare is not radically different from conventional warfare, because it is.  I'm saying conventional warfare waged by the West or by the East is not sufficiently different; neither is guerrilla warfare as practiced by both sides historically.

But, having to occupy a significantly different culture is going to make acquiring enough of their consent much more difficult, and this widespread or sufficiently widespread dissent is what leads to these bleeding out scenarios.  If you watched that video -- which, going by what you've said so far, I assume you didn't -- this would be made apparent.

&amp;gt;It's worth noting that some of the later insurgents were only able to become highly effective when supplied with advanced weaponry from a technologically superior Western super power.

You're still not understanding.  You keep saying things like this like it's contrary to my position.  Of course getting technological help can multiply effectiveness as measured by short-term metrics like how many people were killed and how many vehicles destroyed in one day or one month.  But, I'm talking about economic efficiency and sustainability.

&amp;gt;I can not think of a time where a small, guerrilla force took over a nation and held power without evolving into a regular army.

This isn't even what's being discussed.

&amp;gt;and the Nazi resistance

The Nazis weren't quite as popular among all Germans as most Americans have been educated to believe.   One of the most annoying things about AC is the never ending debates.  To me AC is an experiment just like the experiments of theocracy, fascism, and democracy.  To me just start doing ACist things and the ecosystem will spring up. Exactly! Voluntarism isn't an end goal...it's a beginning. Exactly! Voluntarism isn't an end goal...it's a beginning. One of the most annoying things about AC is the never ending debates.  To me AC is an experiment just like the experiments of theocracy, fascism, and democracy.  To me just start doing ACist things and the ecosystem will spring up. &amp;gt;To me just start doing ACist things

What kind of ancap things you see as being possible to do under state domination?      A State is far less effective at defending itself than an anarchic society. The only reason anarchies were easily conquered in the olden days is because they were small, and manpower was the primary good in warfare.

Nowadays, technology is much more important. A single person with a machine gun can hold off thousands of people. Ummm. What?

Maybe a thousand people armed with sticks. The modern version of the khans have missiles, tanks and jets. 

Technology is important because of the communication. Communication is far more important than any weapon. There are no modern versions of the mongols. The mongol weapon system suited and complemented their nomadic lifestyle. Producing tanks and airplanes requires an industrial society, and all the restraints and incentives that go with it. There are no modern versions of the mongols. The mongol weapon system suited and complemented their nomadic lifestyle. Producing tanks and airplanes requires an industrial society, and all the restraints and incentives that go with it. I'm sure the people of Afghanistan and Syria are overjoyed at the restraints and incentives the respective states occupying them have because of the wonders of industrialisation. Ummm. What?

Maybe a thousand people armed with sticks. The modern version of the khans have missiles, tanks and jets. 

Technology is important because of the communication. Communication is far more important than any weapon. [Meet Vasily Zaytsev](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasily_Zaytsev). Yes and a handful of English defended against thousands of Zulu warriors using muskets. You comparing exceptional and/or well-trained people against common folk in a CoD like fantasy.

E7ernal makes it sound like a housewife could deploy an M2 or Mark 19 in the turret of her house and defend it against the American military. I'm not for banning people from owning those weapons but realistically I'd rather have people developing relationships that foster a faith in voluntary exchange and self-reliance instead of self-defense.

I think this is why freedom of speech was the first amendment, followed closely by the second.  [Meet Vasily Zaytsev](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasily_Zaytsev). A State is far less effective at defending itself than an anarchic society. The only reason anarchies were easily conquered in the olden days is because they were small, and manpower was the primary good in warfare.

Nowadays, technology is much more important. A single person with a machine gun can hold off thousands of people. &amp;gt;A State is far less effective at defending itself than an anarchic society.

I think we need evidence before we can claim something like that.  I agree that technology is more important than manpower these days, but I have a hard time imagining an anarchist society devoting a large percentage of their resources to defense research, the way that an expansionist state might. Well, the State is a monopoly/monopsony. There's horrible inefficiencies. Economically, there is no benefit to a single military, especially when you have to break it down into thousands of sub-organizations just to get anything done. It's funny, the US military tries so hard to mimic the market.

But, lets be honest, if individuals left to their own devices are capable of providing charity for the poor/disabled, laws, roads, and contract arbitration, I think they can provide some funding for defense research. I agree, they can provide some funding for defense research, but I don't think they'd be willing to fund it at the same level as an aggressive state would.  Also, I think one of the biggest advantages a state has over an anarchist society is the ability to do things like declare martial law and mobilize quickly in the event of an attack.  I think national defense is one of the few things that can be done more effectively by state coercion than by voluntary cooperation. &amp;gt; I agree, they can provide some funding for defense research, but I don't think they'd be willing to fund it at the same level as an aggressive state would.

Why not?

&amp;gt; Also, I think one of the biggest advantages a state has over an anarchist society is the ability to do things like declare martial law and mobilize quickly in the event of an attack.

How does taking people's freedom away help defend them?

&amp;gt; I think national defense is one of the few things that can be done more effectively by state coercion than by voluntary cooperation.

Yet you've given no evidence to support this position, and you're arguing against economic theory about central planning and monopolies. You're going to have to do better than "that's just my opinion, man." &amp;gt;Why not?

For the same reason that many people don't buy health insurance, save enough money for retirement, or keep survival supplies in their basement.  It's difficult to spend significant amounts of time and/or money preparing for events that are a long way off, and might never actually happen.  One effect of a state is that, for good or ill, it can force you to devote resources to hedge against far-off problems or low-probability catastrophic events.

&amp;gt;How does taking people's freedom away help defend them?

Curfews and forced evacuations can help keep people safe, or at least out of the way.  Increased police powers are helpful in catching spies or saboteurs.  I'm not saying that these are necessarily good things, but I think they have the potential to be useful in the event of an invasion.

&amp;gt;Yet you've given no evidence to support this position, and you're arguing against economic theory about central planning and monopolies. You're going to have to do better than "that's just my opinion, man."

I can't provide empirical evidence to support this, since there aren't that many examples of stateless societies defending themselves against invaders.  The examples that have been suggested, like the Viet Cong, tend to be guerrilla forces that take extremely heavy casualties until they make it too unpleasant for the invaders to stay.  The Vietnam War may have been bad for the US, but it was far worse for Vietnam.  The idea (in my opinion at least) is to have a military that can deter invasions, or at least repel them before large swathes of the country are occupied.

In terms of economics, I'm not sure I am arguing against the prevailing theories.  Free markets are clearly more efficient and better at providing people with what they want, at least in the short term.  However, as I noted above, I don't think that they're particularly good at devoting large amounts of money on an effort that has no short-term benefit to anyone, and might appear to be totally pointless if working correctly (by deterring attacks).  I could be totally wrong about that, but I don't think that most people are capable of effectively assessing the risk of invasion and spending their money accordingly.  Can you give me an example of a situation where the majority of people voluntarily spent large sums of money to prevent some problem that might not occur for many years, if at all? Well, the State is a monopoly/monopsony. There's horrible inefficiencies. Economically, there is no benefit to a single military, especially when you have to break it down into thousands of sub-organizations just to get anything done. It's funny, the US military tries so hard to mimic the market.

But, lets be honest, if individuals left to their own devices are capable of providing charity for the poor/disabled, laws, roads, and contract arbitration, I think they can provide some funding for defense research. You seem to be on a similar track to what I've been thinking will happen all along; a network governance. Technically anarchy, but not really anarchy because all information about a node's action is automatically known by the community and judged (common law, ostracization) accordingly. Military focused nodes would generally be embargoed and any secrets published. I'd surrender my sovereignty to an open source machine, once acceptable source code exists you'll probably have 15% of the planet's tech savvy population in agreement - no centralized mere human based sovereign could hope to compete. And those sovereigns who hold out N. Korean style are easily subverted by air drops of whatever smartphone or iGlasses allow me to access to the network.

Just as robots *could* eliminate the limitations of humans in air to air combat, i.e. reflexes, g loading, even tactical game theory, so too politics. Internet is a populous game changer, and I think our executive, namely FEMA, is expecting this fight. Well, the State is a monopoly/monopsony. There's horrible inefficiencies. Economically, there is no benefit to a single military, especially when you have to break it down into thousands of sub-organizations just to get anything done. It's funny, the US military tries so hard to mimic the market.

But, lets be honest, if individuals left to their own devices are capable of providing charity for the poor/disabled, laws, roads, and contract arbitration, I think they can provide some funding for defense research. Never mind the famous and historically spotless military dictum "Divide and conquer".... Right, because if things are going to be structured, they clearly have to be structured at the point of a gun. &amp;gt;A State is far less effective at defending itself than an anarchic society.

I think we need evidence before we can claim something like that.  I agree that technology is more important than manpower these days, but I have a hard time imagining an anarchist society devoting a large percentage of their resources to defense research, the way that an expansionist state might. A State is far less effective at defending itself than an anarchic society. The only reason anarchies were easily conquered in the olden days is because they were small, and manpower was the primary good in warfare.

Nowadays, technology is much more important. A single person with a machine gun can hold off thousands of people. Such a weak defense. Since the world started out as anarchy I dare say when the original state formed it was in fact smaller than the rest of the anarchy world. Then it took over.  &amp;gt; Since the world started out as anarchy

Not ancap - in the sense of private property rights, mutual contract, and non-aggression. If anything the world started anarcho-communist. I don't see this is any argument at all against my position. &amp;gt;If anything the world started anarcho-communist.

Dafuq!? Tribal societies were communes. Which is completely compatible with anarcho capitalism.           </snippet></document><document><title>US boss berates French for 'three-hour' working day</title><url>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/financialcrisis/9882422/US-boss-berates-French-for-three-hour-working-day.html</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Wikipedia is the greatest example of AnCap principles in action.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Anarcho_Capitalism/comments/18y8jd/wikipedia_is_the_greatest_example_of_ancap/</url><snippet>Is my statement correct? What are better examples?  Lets see what the Founder of Wikipedia has to say on this.

&amp;gt; Wales cites Austrian School economist Friedrich Hayek's essay "The Use of Knowledge in Society", which he read as an undergraduate,[16] as "central" to his thinking about "how to manage the Wikipedia project".[11] Hayek argued that information is decentralized &#8211; that each individual only knows a small fraction of what is known collectively &#8211; and that as a result, decisions are best made by those with local knowledge rather than by a central authority.[11] Wales reconsidered Hayek's essay in the 1990s, while reading about the open source movement (which advocated that software be free and distributed). He was moved in particular by "The Cathedral and the Bazaar", an essay and later book by one of the founders of the movement, Eric S. Raymond, which "opened [his] eyes to the possibilities of mass collaboration."[16] From his background in finance and working as a futures and options trader, Wales developed an interest in game theory and the effect of incentives on human collaborative activity, a fascination to which he credits enabling much of his effort with Wikipedia.[84] He has rejected the notion that his role in promoting Wikipedia is altruistic, which he defines as "sacrificing your own values for others", stating "[t]hat participating in a benevolent effort to share information is somehow destroying your own values makes no sense to me".[54]

I would not call it AnCap per se but it is a good example of how far voluntary collective action can go to produce or cope with externalitis.   Internet is anarchy.  *B-b-but muh TCP/IP protocol!* Bitch, I'm UDP. M, oo.   Google is an excellent counterexample to the "problem" of positive externalities and public goods. The largest, most powerful, most accessible search engine, email service, global mapping service, etc. doesn't charge a penny to its end users. They're funded with ad revenue instead.  I used Wikipedia once as an example for voluntary interaction to one of my old high school teachers and he thought it was a perfect example of why you need a government. He (like some others) hate Wikipedia and see it as useless. This of course lead to long discussion on how great and amazing something like Wikipedia is. 

I cant fathom how some people can hate it. One of the biggest collections of free information available. How can you possibly dislike that?  I think teachers hate it because it is "too easy" for students to get the information they need for reports and such. I always had teachers repeat over and over again how wikipedia is not a source we could use. Now I understand why, given the nature of it, anyone can edit articles, and not every piece of information comes from a verified source. However, for those who care about the sources of information, wikipedia offers the ability to cite sources of information.

I personally love wikipedia, because I can find information about just about anything. &amp;gt;I think teachers hate it because it is "too easy" for students to get the information they need for reports and such.

Teachers would probably vilify cheap education. Cheap information? Think of the horror!

&amp;gt;Now I understand why, given the nature of it, anyone can edit articles, and not every piece of information comes from a verified source. 

It goes through an approval process and many times changes are rejected because they are not supported. If you have ever worked for a publisher, peer-reviewed journal, law review, etc., the "verification" process isn't as excellent as some people would like to believe. &amp;gt;I think teachers hate it because it is "too easy" for students to get the information they need for reports and such.

Teachers would probably vilify cheap education. Cheap information? Think of the horror!

&amp;gt;Now I understand why, given the nature of it, anyone can edit articles, and not every piece of information comes from a verified source. 

It goes through an approval process and many times changes are rejected because they are not supported. If you have ever worked for a publisher, peer-reviewed journal, law review, etc., the "verification" process isn't as excellent as some people would like to believe. I think teachers hate it because it is "too easy" for students to get the information they need for reports and such. I always had teachers repeat over and over again how wikipedia is not a source we could use. Now I understand why, given the nature of it, anyone can edit articles, and not every piece of information comes from a verified source. However, for those who care about the sources of information, wikipedia offers the ability to cite sources of information.

I personally love wikipedia, because I can find information about just about anything.   </snippet></document><document><title>An Open Letter of Thanks to Dr. Lew Rockwell, the Mises Institute, LRC and All Contributors</title><url>http://thehumanecondition.com/2013/02/21/an-open-letter-of-thanks-to-dr-lew-rockwell-the-mises-institute-lrc-and-all-contributors/</url><snippet>   Brohan, you forgot David Friedman and Bob Murphy! </snippet></document><document><title>Speciesism and Moral Status: How does this apply to our understanding of treatment of individuals with respect to contracts?</title><url>https://dl.dropbox.com/u/50905467/Singer%2B_%2BSpeciesism%2Band%2BMoral%2BStatus.pdf</url><snippet>  I've heard the "some very smart chimps are more sentient than some very mentally handicapped humans" argument before, but I think it's absurd to say that this should demonstrate giving moral weight to animals.  We already pretty much resolve this - any human with a severe enough handicap as to be incapable of caring for themselves simply remains the ward of the family - just as children are.

Consider - a more "just" way of handling the distinction between "child" and "adult" would simply be to say that whenever the child wishes to do so, the child may enter into their own contracts and void the inherent one with their parents.  Until such time as that happens, the person remains a "child."  We've all met 15-year-olds that were more mature than some other 25-year-olds we've also met.  The 18-year distinction is arbitrary and it makes much more sense to evaluate that on a case-by-case basis, by the individuals involved.  So if you have a person of severe mental handicap, they'll simply never make that choice.  As a result, they remain under the care of the parents, unless the parents choose to discharge that care in favor of perhaps an organization with facilities better designed to care for that individual (like a group home, etc.).

While my proposed solution might not be perfect (like any solution, it's just one of a potential seven billion that could be proposed and adopted as merit dictates), doesn't it seem much more reasonable than some sort of sliding moral scale that includes monkeys in the NAP?  I never understood what cognitive capacity has to do with anything. I guess my ethical system is just different, I'm a pretty straightforward human supremacist. I don't consider non-humans to have *any* moral worth (no different than rocks or trees).  Why? My ethics is based on an interpretation of biology. The way I see it, there is correct and incorrect behavior. Humans share many of the same genes and as a distinct species can interbreed and readily interact socially. The ultimate goal of all our values and behaviors is to ensure the survival of our genes, so that means non-humans are of no measurable importance. It also helps that humans, as a distinct species, share the same values and behaviors (at least mostly). I am influenced strongly by evolutionary psychology and such. 

I suppose there are circumstances where a non-human could be said to have value, perhaps if humans were all but extinct or we had to compare against extraterrestrials.  biological imperatives go!

So, if aliens landed which were largely the same, could make moral decisions, etc., but could not interbreed would you consider them to have no moral worth? Yes, they would have no innate value within my ethical beliefs. They would be equivalent to a rock, even my pet dog would be worth more than them.  Hopefully you're not their first contact then :) They'd probably use their psychic abilities to read his mind then laugh at his disregard for their species. Which by definition makes them not so similar to us. </snippet></document><document><title>Capitalism, Socialism, Communism | A Quick Reference Guide | LOL</title><url>http://imgur.com/ryLayFp</url><snippet>  &amp;gt;Capitalism is essentially wasteful; commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

Because anything produced that would raise society above subsistence living is wasteful. Yeah but the people that work for someone else and produce things for people are *wage slaves*, you see, because voluntarily selling your labor instead of working for yourself is like slavery, man.  Or something. Yeah but the people that work for someone else and produce things for people are *wage slaves*, you see, because voluntarily selling your labor instead of working for yourself is like slavery, man.  Or something. Also, the fact that you can start a company and work for yourself doesnt matter in the slightest Fact? Say I have no capital.. You can sell your labor as an individual without any capital required.  But chances are, you enjoy the benefits that Mr. Capitalist offers you in addition to your wage (health benefits, climate-controlled facilities, job security).  By owning the capital, he assumes the risk that you refuse to assume yourself.

That said, it's not hard to acquire the means of production.  You have a computer, I'm assuming.  You can learn web design.  You can actually learn just about any skill you like, and use it to render a service.  You can do as many capitalists have done, and *buy* some.  Perform a limited service, earn money, reinvest in additional equipment, and offer more service, reinvest in other people, and provide even more.  

You see how this works?  The opportunity is there.  I don't feel bad for being successful, anyone can be.  The only thing I feel bad about is that kids aren't taught how this works in school, and aren't even capable of recognizing the opportunity that surrounds them. I don't get any of those benefits specifically. Most laborers in the world do not enjoy them!

Laborers without capital a *forced* to work for wages, it is not a privilege.

He assumes the risk I am unwilling to take? Thats a funny way to say he risks resources laborers were never themselves given the opportunity to manage. It's like doublespeak central with you.

You vastly underestimate the cyclical process of acquiring capital. Simply having a skill does not guarantee you much in life and many don't. They didn't have the capital!

I am on a phone, btw. And I don't think that I am typical.

The notion that anyone can be successful is retarded. Just like a slave could have been president. It's all just milk and honey to you. When you go to work, do you worry that if *x* amount of burgers aren't sold this week, that you aren't going to receive your paycheck?  Doubt it.  Did you do anything to earn the use of a fry-o-later?  Nope, but you still are allowed to collect an agreed-upon portion of the revenue from its use, even though someone else paid for it.  Did you make sure the A/C got repaired so your customers can enjoy their fries?  Didn't think so.  

This is the risk a business owner takes.  He invests the money HE worked for in order to create the facility and the position YOU work in.  You are not forced to work there.  If you want to go make your own burgers and try and sell them, you're more than welcome.  But you're not willing to do that, because you'd rather collect your paycheck and bitch about being oppressed.

&amp;gt;The notion that anyone can be successful is retarded.

You are unequivocally 100% correct.  Some people will NEVER overcome the entitled, selfish, lazy attitude that keeps them a "wage slave".  Some people will never be successful, no matter how many successful people attempt to instill them with common sense.  Some people simply enjoy being a victim.

As someone who went from homelessness to being a couple months away from quitting his day job and running his own consulting practice, I am living proof that there is opportunity out there for anyone who is willing to look for a way to create value in the world for others, because that's the prime #1 rule of business.  Create value for someone, and they will happily give you what you want in exchange...and you both walk away from the transaction wealthier for it. 

I didn't get any handouts from mommy or daddy.  I didn't get any grants or student loans.  I didn't even go to college.  I just decided that I wanted better for my life.  I've lived in a trailer in Mississippi, I've couch surfed with nowhere to call home, and I've slept in my car on cold nights, waking up every few hours to run the heater.  I don't want to hear how hard it is to succeed from someone who wants to be a victim. 

Learn from this conversation or don't.  You can either go be successful by providing value for someone (either as an employee or an entrepreneur), or you can keep working for someone else until they recognize your shitty attitude and set you free from your "slavery". Fact? Say I have no capital.. Everyone has capital, even if it is just their own bodies and minds. Thats all everyone used to have, yet here we are, in a world where people are complaining about how the overabundance of capital is a problem. People are not capital. Ass. You do not own yourself like a piece of cattle. You cannot be bought or sold but in slavery!

 Societies used to have communal ownership of the means of production, nobody prospered while another was left to starve.

The problem is obviously not an overabundance, but a misappropriation. I'm pretty sure I own myself, last time I checked.

&amp;gt;Societies used to have communal ownership of the means of production, nobody prospered while another was left to starve.

Well one part of that is right: "nobody prospered" People are not capital. Ass. You do not own yourself like a piece of cattle. You cannot be bought or sold but in slavery!

 Societies used to have communal ownership of the means of production, nobody prospered while another was left to starve.

The problem is obviously not an overabundance, but a misappropriation. &amp;gt;People are not capital. Ass. You do not own yourself like a piece of cattle. You cannot be bought or sold but in slavery!

Oh dear. Slavery isnt wrong because it involves buying and selling people, since if the slaves were given freely to slaveowners, it would be just as bad. Slavery is bad because it forces people to work without their consent. What good is making money, when you get whipped for leaving the plantation to spend it? If it is working without being compensated that you dislike, do you condemn volunteer work.

Slavery != buying and selling people

Slacery == forced labour.

&amp;gt;The problem is obviously not an overabundance, but a misappropriation.

In your opinion, yes, but havent you heard the arguments against, say, global warming? A slave is nearly by definition bought and sold in that it is indeed **property**. The value and nature of commodities is in that they are bought and sold in an  exchange, not given.

The point here is not that people are bought and sold *in general*, mind that, that should be evident. The point is that a person cannot be alienated from that exchange, a man cannot without contradiction sell himself into slavery.

Suggesting that men own themselves is logic seeking to justify wage slavery, in that they can sell themselves.

Clearly fallacious.

Volunteer work is voluntary. Working for wages is compulsory. Under direct threat of starvation.

I think you refuse to recognize slaves as labor because you seek to justify private ownership of capital. 

People are not simply forced to labor under the capitalist mode, all have had to labor for survival always.. It's that they are forced to labor for wages.

I've studied the economic impacts of global warming. What do you want to know? Ecological problems can be seen as a lack of taxation. Lol Yeah but the people that work for someone else and produce things for people are *wage slaves*, you see, because voluntarily selling your labor instead of working for yourself is like slavery, man.  Or something. Paying taxes is like slavery or something. 

We all make statements that are exaggerated. Paying taxes is non voluntary. Working for someone else is not voluntary. People can and do work for themselves.  Working for someone else is as voluntary as working for yourself. What. No. I am not bossed around because of freedom. How much you may be "bossed around" is only relevant to the quality of work and is thus factored into your decision whether or not that particular job is better or worse than another job or working for yourself.

Working under someone does not become "involuntary" simply because you get bossed around more.  Ok let me clarify. I don't work for wages because I have a choice not to, I do it becaused I DON'T have a practical choice not to. I'm not complaining exactly about the level to which I am bossed around.

What is involuntary is working for wages, not WHO you work for wages for. Lol So it's involuntary to work for wages because employers provide you with better opportunities than you could provide for yourself? Kay. &amp;gt;Capitalism is essentially wasteful; commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

Because anything produced that would raise society above subsistence living is wasteful. Don't worry, calculation in a true state-socialist and anarcho-communist global economy will set them straight once they realize half of their population goes without food and is producing more waste than they could have ever imagined possible in an economy with private property.  I'm pretty sure most of them and sadly the innocent would end up digging their own graves.  That is unless they can piggy back off of another economy that allows private property.  Though that can't last since according to them their end goal is to change even the economies that are outside their sphere.  It's destructive and will only result in more death and decay for innocent people.

Edit:  With egalitarianism comes equal suffering for everyone! What are you even talking about? Where'd you hear that about Anarcho-communism from that cultist Stefan? Don't worry, calculation in a true state-socialist and anarcho-communist global economy will set them straight once they realize half of their population goes without food and is producing more waste than they could have ever imagined possible in an economy with private property.  I'm pretty sure most of them and sadly the innocent would end up digging their own graves.  That is unless they can piggy back off of another economy that allows private property.  Though that can't last since according to them their end goal is to change even the economies that are outside their sphere.  It's destructive and will only result in more death and decay for innocent people.

Edit:  With egalitarianism comes equal suffering for everyone! That is a lot of assumptions in one comment. &amp;gt;Capitalism is essentially wasteful; commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

Because anything produced that would raise society above subsistence living is wasteful. &amp;gt;commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

The fact that they are being sold is proof that they are actually needed or wanted.

The sentence is typical from a person that believes one human can imagine what everyone else needs (and therefore central planning is viable). &amp;gt;Capitalism is essentially wasteful; commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

Because anything produced that would raise society above subsistence living is wasteful.  What an unbiased and level headed way to explain these three systems!  I wonder what computer/program this chart was made on?  I'm sure it originated in the Soviet Union.  I'm also sure it was made because this guy NEEDED it, not because it could be sold. Great comment!

+tip $1 verify Great comment!

+tip $1 verify Great comment!

+tip $1 verify Exactly how does this work? I always see this bitcoin tip thing.  And more importantly, what the fuck can I actually buy with it? Also isn't this the thing that the evil trendy leftists are using these days?  Someone doesn't understand...... much of anything lmao it really doesnt matter so long as they dont violently overthrow the capitalists ain't that the kicker though? ain't that the kicker though? attack the violence, not the socialism, its a larger target and a greater evil Expose that socialism necessitates violence and central authority. If we become Communistic through the free market, who cares? i dont see how we could become communistic through the free market, however people should be free to try no matter how unwise.... maybe set up a charity to send food when it fails if ur worried about a family member moving into the woods to set up a communist paradis

i just dont see it as a pressing issue compared to all the wars going on  Expose that socialism necessitates violence and central authority. If we become Communistic through the free market, who cares? Democratic control of the workplace (socialism) requires violence and central authority? Hahaha. And let me guess, you're going to say that private property doesn't and that capitalism is so liberating amirite? Do you own your own body?
 I am my body. attack the violence, not the socialism, its a larger target and a greater evil Why not both?

Socialism is a fundamentally flawed system, demonstrative of nothing more than bureaucratic arrogance. Why not both?

Socialism is a fundamentally flawed system, demonstrative of nothing more than bureaucratic arrogance. Someone doesn't understand...... much of anything lmao  Not sure why I feel this way, but something tells me the person who designed this may be a communist or socialist.. Not sure why I feel this way, but something tells me the person who designed this may be a communist or socialist..  &amp;gt; Under capitalism, technology is applied as a substitute for the workforce - increased productivity means higher unemployment 

&amp;gt; Technology frees people from the most heavy and simple tasks and frees them for other occupations, training and self-improvement. 

 No because when Socialism does it it's GOOD dummy! Technology is used to maximize profit, not lower our labor. And yet it lowers your labour anyway. Yes, but the point that Omega is making (I am guessing) is that under Capitalism (any kind), people depend upon their jobs entirely. The worker does not have claim to what they have produced. Their life is molded around their job and their paycheck. Furthermore, the worker does not have claim to what they have produced or the profit that comes from it. When a robot takes over the workers' jobs, those workers suffer.

Under socialism/communism, all workers/citizens of the community have equal claim to what they produce and the profit that comes from that as a whole. Using robots/technology then becomes a tool for the worker's benefit, as it frees up time. This allows one to become more efficient, spend time on social activities, or any number of things.

TL;DR - Capitalism's usage of technology to substitute for human workers deprives the worker, while socialism/communism's usage benefits the user.

Really, to understand the quote from above you only have to be able to read at a high-school level. &amp;gt;TL;DR - Capitalism's usage of technology to substitute for human workers deprives the worker, while socialism/communism's usage benefits the user.

Any productive worker will always be needed, so called "frictional" unemployment is a necessity in any economy, even a socialist one. If you've demonstrated your worth as a laborer, you won't have much problem finding a job in any economy thriving enough to be building robots. Meanwhile technology makes the goods the laborer strives to purchase cheaper.

&amp;gt;Really, to understand the quote from above you only have to be able to read at a high-school level.

Making such statements reveals more about your *own* immaturity and intellectual ineptitude than it could ever say about mine. Yes, frictional unemployment may always exist. There will always be a need for human workers, even if an industry is entirely robotic/technological. However, focusing on the individual worker who "has proven their worth" doesn't mean jack for the rest of society.

It doesn't matter how good you are at your job, when technology has dominated the workplace, a business will only need x amount of workers, a substantial amount less than needed if it were dominated by workers.

So again, capitalism's usage of technology to substitute for human workers deprives the majority of working-abled persons from a source of income and thus a life. &amp;gt;TL;DR - Capitalism's usage of technology to substitute for human workers deprives the worker, while socialism/communism's usage benefits the user.

Any productive worker will always be needed, so called "frictional" unemployment is a necessity in any economy, even a socialist one. If you've demonstrated your worth as a laborer, you won't have much problem finding a job in any economy thriving enough to be building robots. Meanwhile technology makes the goods the laborer strives to purchase cheaper.

&amp;gt;Really, to understand the quote from above you only have to be able to read at a high-school level.

Making such statements reveals more about your *own* immaturity and intellectual ineptitude than it could ever say about mine. &amp;gt;Any productive worker will always be needed, so called "frictional" unemployment is a necessity in any economy, even a socialist one. 

Yet that ignores the point that technology in socialism benefits the worker while in capitalism it hurts most workers. There benefits in both, safer workplaces, all that jazz; don't get me wrong.

----

In capitalism, a robot replaces the worker. The worker no longer has a job, no longer has income. What the robot produces goes to the owner. The worker is cut out entirely.

In socialism, a robot replaces the worker, and the worker keeps the capital that the robot produces in his place. The worker is supplemented.

Does this make sense?

To claim "*If you've demonstrated your worth as a laborer, you won't have much problem finding a job in any economy thriving enough to be building robots.*" displays some serious victim blaming. You lost your job to a robot, well that's your fault.  &amp;gt;Yet that ignores the point that technology in socialism benefits the worker while in capitalism it hurts most workers. There benefits in both, safer workplaces, all that jazz; don't get me wrong.

I'm saying it benefits the worker, so stop begging the question please.

&amp;gt;In capitalism, a robot replaces the worker. The worker no longer has a job, no longer has income. What the robot produces goes to the owner. The worker is cut out entirely.

The worker is productive, he finds a different job, and now that the money saving devices (the robots) are installed in production, the goods he wishes to buy are cheaper. Ergo, the worker benefits in the end.

&amp;gt;In socialism, a robot replaces the worker, and the worker keeps the capital that the robot produces in his place. The worker is supplemented.

Why does the worker keep the capital? He is no longer producing himself right?

&amp;gt;To claim "If you've demonstrated your worth as a laborer, you won't have much problem finding a job in any economy thriving enough to be building robots." displays some serious victim blaming. You lost your job to a robot, well that's your fault.

That's not victim blaming, it's economic reality. &amp;gt;Ergo, the worker benefits in the end.

By lowering his pay, but lowering his costs, did not really improve his life at all? The capitalist' pay went up, there's no doubt. The robot is cheaper, the product remains the same. That's also providing that the worker *could* even find another job. What capitalist would hire him? His entire life is not dependent upon the market, it is dependent upon the capitalist.

I'm for free markets, not capitalism.

&amp;gt;Why does the worker keep the capital? He is no longer producing himself right?

Is the concept of use really that confusing to you guys? Do you not understand how "worker ownership" works?

&amp;gt;That's not victim blaming, it's economic reality.

Only when morality has no place in economics... &amp;gt; Under capitalism, technology is applied as a substitute for the workforce - increased productivity means higher unemployment 

&amp;gt; Technology frees people from the most heavy and simple tasks and frees them for other occupations, training and self-improvement. 

 If this retarded luddite strawman was true we would have massive unemployment when we invented tractors, cars, assembly line and computers to do our work for us, but instead it opened up jobs in other sectors.

Socialism is the creation science of economics. Let's go back farther than that! What about when the first man made a fishing net, instead of catching fish, one by one? BOOM, that jerkface threw his colleagues out of work! Everyone died! If this retarded luddite strawman was true we would have massive unemployment when we invented tractors, cars, assembly line and computers to do our work for us, but instead it opened up jobs in other sectors.

Socialism is the creation science of economics.  Man, 7th graders are getting really good at making pretty 3d diagrams.   Top left corner. Read that first.  &amp;gt; Commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

This is what infuriates me so much about these people.  They seriously think they know what other people need and what they don't need. Prada 300$ glasses? If I want to take $300 and throw it down a storm drain I should have the right to do that. &amp;gt; Commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

This is what infuriates me so much about these people.  They seriously think they know what other people need and what they don't need. Means the following. 

Production for use is a phrase referring to the principle of economic organization taken as a defining criterion for a socialist economy, and is held in contrast to production for profit (or the profits system). This criterion is used to distinguish socialism from capitalism, and was one of the fundamental defining characteristics of socialism initially shared by Marxian socialists, evolutionary socialists, anarchists and Christian socialists.[1]

Production for use refers to an arrangement whereby the production of goods and services is carried out ex ante (directly) for their utility (or Use-value). The implication is that the value of economic output would be based on use-value or a direct measure of utility as opposed to exchange-value; because economic activity would be undertaken to directly satisfy economic demands and human needs, the productive apparatus would directly serve individual and social needs. This is contrasted with production for profit, where production is subjected to the perpetual accumulation of capital, a condition where production is only undertaken if it generates profit, implying an ex post or indirect means of satisfying economic demand. The profits system is oriented toward generating a profit to be reinvested into the economy (and the constant continuation of this process), the result being that society is structured around the need for a perpetual accumulation of capital.[2] In contrast, production for use means that the accumulation of capital is not a compulsory driving force in the economy, and more broadly, in society.

This principle is broad and can refer to an array of different configurations that vary based on the underlying theory of economics employed. In its classic definition, production for use implied an economic system whereby the law of value and law of accumulation no longer directed economic activity, whereby a direct measure of utility and value is used in place of the abstractions of money and capital.[3]

Some thinkers, including the Austrian philosopher and political economist Otto Neurath, have used the phrase socialization to refer to the same concept of "production for use", where total socialization involves calculation in kind in place of financial calculation and a system of planning in place of market-based allocation of economic goods.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Production_for_use Means the following. 

Production for use is a phrase referring to the principle of economic organization taken as a defining criterion for a socialist economy, and is held in contrast to production for profit (or the profits system). This criterion is used to distinguish socialism from capitalism, and was one of the fundamental defining characteristics of socialism initially shared by Marxian socialists, evolutionary socialists, anarchists and Christian socialists.[1]

Production for use refers to an arrangement whereby the production of goods and services is carried out ex ante (directly) for their utility (or Use-value). The implication is that the value of economic output would be based on use-value or a direct measure of utility as opposed to exchange-value; because economic activity would be undertaken to directly satisfy economic demands and human needs, the productive apparatus would directly serve individual and social needs. This is contrasted with production for profit, where production is subjected to the perpetual accumulation of capital, a condition where production is only undertaken if it generates profit, implying an ex post or indirect means of satisfying economic demand. The profits system is oriented toward generating a profit to be reinvested into the economy (and the constant continuation of this process), the result being that society is structured around the need for a perpetual accumulation of capital.[2] In contrast, production for use means that the accumulation of capital is not a compulsory driving force in the economy, and more broadly, in society.

This principle is broad and can refer to an array of different configurations that vary based on the underlying theory of economics employed. In its classic definition, production for use implied an economic system whereby the law of value and law of accumulation no longer directed economic activity, whereby a direct measure of utility and value is used in place of the abstractions of money and capital.[3]

Some thinkers, including the Austrian philosopher and political economist Otto Neurath, have used the phrase socialization to refer to the same concept of "production for use", where total socialization involves calculation in kind in place of financial calculation and a system of planning in place of market-based allocation of economic goods.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Production_for_use Means the following. 

Production for use is a phrase referring to the principle of economic organization taken as a defining criterion for a socialist economy, and is held in contrast to production for profit (or the profits system). This criterion is used to distinguish socialism from capitalism, and was one of the fundamental defining characteristics of socialism initially shared by Marxian socialists, evolutionary socialists, anarchists and Christian socialists.[1]

Production for use refers to an arrangement whereby the production of goods and services is carried out ex ante (directly) for their utility (or Use-value). The implication is that the value of economic output would be based on use-value or a direct measure of utility as opposed to exchange-value; because economic activity would be undertaken to directly satisfy economic demands and human needs, the productive apparatus would directly serve individual and social needs. This is contrasted with production for profit, where production is subjected to the perpetual accumulation of capital, a condition where production is only undertaken if it generates profit, implying an ex post or indirect means of satisfying economic demand. The profits system is oriented toward generating a profit to be reinvested into the economy (and the constant continuation of this process), the result being that society is structured around the need for a perpetual accumulation of capital.[2] In contrast, production for use means that the accumulation of capital is not a compulsory driving force in the economy, and more broadly, in society.

This principle is broad and can refer to an array of different configurations that vary based on the underlying theory of economics employed. In its classic definition, production for use implied an economic system whereby the law of value and law of accumulation no longer directed economic activity, whereby a direct measure of utility and value is used in place of the abstractions of money and capital.[3]

Some thinkers, including the Austrian philosopher and political economist Otto Neurath, have used the phrase socialization to refer to the same concept of "production for use", where total socialization involves calculation in kind in place of financial calculation and a system of planning in place of market-based allocation of economic goods.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Production_for_use &amp;gt; Commodities are produced because they can be sold, not because they are needed.

This is what infuriates me so much about these people.  They seriously think they know what other people need and what they don't need. Top left corner. Read that first.  Top left corner. Read that first.  This infographic is biased, vacuous garbage. Nice graphical design, but if you want to be taken seriously on an informational level, tone down the propaganda.

You literally say that technology in Capitalism is evil but under Socialism it is good based on the semantical argument that in the former it is used as a substitute for the workforce leading to unemployment, while in Socialism it's used as a substitute for work, leading to less work and 'bettering oneself'.

Out of curiosity, when a company buys a bunch of robots to replace their unskilled labor (so they get fired), doesn't the competition for more jobs amongst that labor lower wages, and as a result, lower prices for consumers? If not, please explain why.  This is an incorrect portrait of capitalism, socialism and communism. This is an incorrect portrait of capitalism, socialism and communism.   This thing is formatted horribly. I can hardly make sense of it. You gotta think with your emotions man. You seem to post here often, and this is the first time I've been to this sub so I'll ask you:

Why is this on the front page? Who upvotes this?

I mean, the discussion in here has been overwhelmingly negative toward the content. I don't understand the disconnect. You seem to post here often, and this is the first time I've been to this sub so I'll ask you:

Why is this on the front page? Who upvotes this?

I mean, the discussion in here has been overwhelmingly negative toward the content. I don't understand the disconnect. You seem to post here often, and this is the first time I've been to this sub so I'll ask you:

Why is this on the front page? Who upvotes this?

I mean, the discussion in here has been overwhelmingly negative toward the content. I don't understand the disconnect. You seem to post here often, and this is the first time I've been to this sub so I'll ask you:

Why is this on the front page? Who upvotes this?

I mean, the discussion in here has been overwhelmingly negative toward the content. I don't understand the disconnect. You seem to post here often, and this is the first time I've been to this sub so I'll ask you:

Why is this on the front page? Who upvotes this?

I mean, the discussion in here has been overwhelmingly negative toward the content. I don't understand the disconnect.  Well good, without wages and universal &amp;amp; unlimited access to whatever is needed, I'm sure we'll find plenty of people motivated to go to 12 years of medical school.  

Can't remember who I heard it from, but he said, "I always think it's funny how communist regimes have these 5 year plans where they're going to increase production of say Iron or something by this much percent.  In a Capitalist society, no one has any idea what's going to be needed or how much of it in 5 years."  Because people are incentivized to make new and efficient things you can't predict what breakthroughs we're gonna have!

Anyone else think it's pretty ironic that the hammer and sickle, widely used tools of production back in the day, are now being replaced through the market with automation and new farm technology?  Wait this isn't an explanation of the Zeitgeist movement? I discussed on YouTube quite a while ago with Zeitgeisters ... It was basically a futuristic communist / socialist utopia. They couldn't really explain if government was needed, only that technology somehow solved all problems, and calculated everyones "needs", so no use for money.

This calculation smells a lot like the central comitee of a socialist state, and I guess it also calculates how much work we should be doing (imagine the machine finds out the probability of an object hitting Earth, and start panicking and whipping humans to work to death). Well it depends on central planning for sure, resource allocation, all that. Watched Molyneaux debate this kid on Zeitgeist. Kid couldn't get that you need some kind of unit of measurement in order to allocate resources, no matter how fast your computer is.

I think where we really disagree with the Zeitgeist is almost inconsequential if we all agree on the NAP. They can go off and try their little experiment then come back and work for cheap after it falls apart. &amp;gt; I think where we really disagree with the Zeitgeist is almost inconsequential if we all agree on the NAP. They can go off and try their little experiment then come back and work for cheap after it falls apart.

I agree with you, but I think it is the computer that tells them when nap is good and bad.    &amp;gt;Under Socialism and Communism, Technology is a substitute for work...

So explain the uproar when auto manufacturers wanted to replace people with robots in the '80s? Not to mention that it states that in Capitalism technology is bad, but when socialists/communists use it it's justified. &amp;gt;Under Socialism and Communism, Technology is a substitute for work...

So explain the uproar when auto manufacturers wanted to replace people with robots in the '80s?  This graphic is biased but it's pretty well done. Major props for separating state capitalism and capitalism.   The graphic is decent. That's the best compliment I can muster. The content - well, we all know the quality of that, don't we?  This is the first time I've been to this sub. Why is this so highly upvoted when the content is clearly so vacuous and biased that it could have conceivably come from a propaganda machine?  Why are computers personal property and not private property? Seems like a nice loophole.   Commies and socialists can't even keep their stories straight, I've heard some of them say technology is evil because it kills jobs  so this subreddit is just 100% of the time a gigantic circle jerk?  Do they really think that the best goal for every citizen is to work? Holy fuck. Under capitalism things keep getting cheaper and people have to work less and less to live a decent life.      oh man, this thread is hilarious.  

funny how many "anarcho-capitalists" just *happen* to have shit-poor critical reading skills.  WEIRD, HUH?     Sweet poster! +1 </snippet></document><document><title>Terrifying: Poster in /r/silverbugs has stack confiscated by police during craigslist sting</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/Silverbugs/comments/18wbhj/i_had_20ozt_seized_by_the_police_yesterday_what/</url><snippet>  Yeah, just saw that. Fucking terrifying.

If this turns out legit, anyone want to help set up a defense fund?

EDIT: Alright, sent the dude a message to see if he can provide any additional details regarding his situation. I'd pitch in a 20 i'll throw in an ounce of silver I'll throw in a bitcoin. Same.  He'd get a Bitcoin from me. How do you do bitcoins, if you don't mind me asking?  I tried the other day and they wanted me to install all these programs, etc.  All I want to do is open an account and buy and sell bitcoins with low margins. Well if you just wanted to buy and sell you would just make an account on an exchange. If you wanted to use them you would download the program from bitcoin.org What exchange do you recommend?  Your project still going well? What exchange do you recommend?  Your project still going well? Well if you just wanted to buy and sell you would just make an account on an exchange. If you wanted to use them you would download the program from bitcoin.org You can also purchase through a service like Coinbase. Coinbase is relatively new, but it's a Y-Combinator backed startup so it's highly legit. You can link your bank account too, so buying BTC is much faster than doing the whole Dwolla thing, which can take up to a week. I would have suggested that, but he explicitly said he wanted to both buy and sell.  Same.  He'd get a Bitcoin from me. Yeah, just saw that. Fucking terrifying.

If this turns out legit, anyone want to help set up a defense fund?

EDIT: Alright, sent the dude a message to see if he can provide any additional details regarding his situation. Terrifying? Of course it's bullshit what the cops did, but terrifying? Calm down.  the possibility of being kidnapped and thrown into a cage is terrifying to most normal people. You mean arrested and jailed, not "kidnapped and thrown into a cage". Why do libertarians always use hyperbolic rhetoric? Taxes are "theft at the end of a gun", being arrested is kidnapping. Why not just make your case w/o being melodramatic about it? Yes, what happened, if true, is complete bullshit. A travesty of justice even. But lets keep things in perspective. &amp;gt;Why do libertarians always use hyperbolic rhetoric?

Actually, it's the opposite of hyperbole. Libertarians state it this way because it looks at the interaction from an objective angle. A person in a costume is taking you away to put you in a cage. It's the simplest way to describe the situation. Further, taxes...the word tax etymologically and historically doesn't have a positive connotation. It's only the recent progressive mindset that tries to get everyone to be all Kumbaiya about them as some sort of collective lovefest have they received a more positive spin. Even Oliver Wendell Holmes would be shocked at at how pervasive the tax system has become.  When are you referring to? Taxes had far less of a negative stigma back in the 89% Eisenhower good old days. How far are you going back?  You mean arrested and jailed, not "kidnapped and thrown into a cage". Why do libertarians always use hyperbolic rhetoric? Taxes are "theft at the end of a gun", being arrested is kidnapping. Why not just make your case w/o being melodramatic about it? Yes, what happened, if true, is complete bullshit. A travesty of justice even. But lets keep things in perspective. &amp;gt; Why do libertarians **always** use hyperbolic rhetoric?

There must be a greek word for these things? Very good point! I was unintentionally ironic. Let me rephrase: why do libertarians on this sub frequently use hyperbolic rhetoric? The examples you cite both are trying to make a point about human equality. "Violent acts are not more moral because they are made by a government official", or something like that.

You probably disagree, which is fine. You probably also missed the point, and that makes it sound like unarticulated angry screams to you.

So in that sense, whoever wrote this failed at communicating with you by using insider jargon. Then again, insider jargon is probably appropriate in a subreddit for a specific topic.

I hope this increased understanding by some small amount. No I get that it's jargon amongst an in group. My point is that the case for libertarianism is strong but y'all True Believers alienate yourselves by using that language. The average CNN fed American thinks of libertarians as Ron Paul lunatic fringe, people not to be taken seriously. But whatever, y'all talk how you want to talk, not my business, I'll shut up. You mean arrested and jailed, not "kidnapped and thrown into a cage". Why do libertarians always use hyperbolic rhetoric? Taxes are "theft at the end of a gun", being arrested is kidnapping. Why not just make your case w/o being melodramatic about it? Yes, what happened, if true, is complete bullshit. A travesty of justice even. But lets keep things in perspective. exactly what I'm doing. keeping things in perspective. being kidnapped by a man with a costume and a badge doesn't make it not being kidnapped. Ok, then millions of Americans have been kidnapped.  You mean arrested and jailed, not "kidnapped and thrown into a cage". Why do libertarians always use hyperbolic rhetoric? Taxes are "theft at the end of a gun", being arrested is kidnapping. Why not just make your case w/o being melodramatic about it? Yes, what happened, if true, is complete bullshit. A travesty of justice even. But lets keep things in perspective. Terrifying? Of course it's bullshit what the cops did, but terrifying? Calm down.  Bullshit is when you get pulled over by a cop for going 5 over the speed limit.

This was a premeditated sting operation, meaning the cops used unconventional means to uncover when and where this transaction would take place, planned and executed a raid with 8 squad cars and stole his money. Now, if the OP is telling the truth and he was just some Joe Blow without any priors wanting to get into silver stacking, it IS terrifying. Really? So the cops just orchestrated an organized robbery? With no pretense of a crime having occurred? I don't even think OP is claiming that. Sounds like he got caught up in the middle of an investigation and well now go through the agonizing process of retrieving his possessions from the police, and good luck with that. But you make it sound like a cop version of Ocean's 11, except at gunpoint.  And you're making it sound as if they came by with balloons and cake to ask him for his help in an important police investigation. When they catch the bad guy, they'll throw a parade and give OP a medal with the inscription: Official Friend of the Police. No I'm not saying anything of the sort; nothing I wrote can be can construed that way. For what it's worth, I fucking hate cops, all of them, even the "good" ones. I've been "kidnapped" several times and done serious time inside. No sir, your not painting me as some apologist for police. I'm just saying some perspective here please? I am just doing what you did with the Ocean's 11 comment. Nowhere did I lay out a fantastical tale of that magnitude. " the cops used unconventional means to uncover when and where this transaction would take place, planned and executed a raid with 8 squad cars and stole his money."

Sounds kinda Oceans 11 to me whereas my comment said nothing of police serving cake and shit. I haven't said the slightest thing defending the cops in all this, I simply objected to the use of the term(s) kidnap and cage. So tell me, if a cop arrests someone legitimately, is it still "kidnapping"?  I am a store owner. You steal from my store. I catch you red-handed and throw you into a holding cell in my basement while I figure out what to do with you. Is that kidnapping?  Wait a second, since when has trading in precious metals become illegal?  They don't really need the laws anymore, everything falls under the commerce clause.

He was probably just labeled a terrorist. Or drug dealer. I think they still pretend drug dealers have rights.  If they call you a terrorist, they can then just murder you or ship you to Guantanamo without a trial and without the media getting in the way. I think they still pretend drug dealers have rights.  If they call you a terrorist, they can then just murder you or ship you to Guantanamo without a trial and without the media getting in the way. I think they still pretend drug dealers have rights.  If they call you a terrorist, they can then just murder you or ship you to Guantanamo without a trial and without the media getting in the way. Or drug dealer. They don't really need the laws anymore, everything falls under the commerce clause.

He was probably just labeled a terrorist. They don't really need the laws anymore, everything falls under the commerce clause.

He was probably just labeled a terrorist. Wait a second, since when has trading in precious metals become illegal?  Wait a second, since when has trading in precious metals become illegal?   ...terrifying is also the word I would use.

That EASILY could have been me.  On top of that, I usually deposit the silver directly into a deposit box *(if I can manage the trade at my bank)*, meaning the police might have pursued a warrant and broke open and seized the box containing far more than $500 of silver. ...terrifying is also the word I would use.

That EASILY could have been me.  On top of that, I usually deposit the silver directly into a deposit box *(if I can manage the trade at my bank)*, meaning the police might have pursued a warrant and broke open and seized the box containing far more than $500 of silver. Do you sell/buy lots of precious metals? Nice try, Denver PD.  the thing I don't get is it must have cost them more money than they got from silver and currency to be worth it. Why the hell go after these people? the thing I don't get is it must have cost them more money than they got from silver and currency to be worth it. Why the hell go after these people? Do you sell/buy lots of precious metals?  ...Bitcoin users not affected.

Someone had to say it. I think it's a good idea to diversify. While I think BTC (or other digital currency) is the future, PMs will keep you going if SHTF and you can't access the internet, or when you're dealing with luddites. what other digital currencies are there?  http://about.ag/reporting.htm#.USVHE6VJPXU

If you're doing this in the US, you're running a big risk if you're not reporting the transactions and paying the taxes. The state isn't your friend. The cops can and will bring the hammer on you.

Much better to either trade within a sturdier legal entity or just take your stuff over the border and trade by mail.

This is just one of the many, many ways that US law favors corporations that can afford expensive compliance and legal defense and suppresses trade among individuals. Also, if you have capital gains on physical metals, you pay the taxes and keep records, or the state will bring the hammer down on you in a playful fashion, because this is their job.

Yet more reasons to move overseas. This is why I've chosen btc as my agorist medium, slightly safer.  http://about.ag/reporting.htm#.USVHE6VJPXU

If you're doing this in the US, you're running a big risk if you're not reporting the transactions and paying the taxes. The state isn't your friend. The cops can and will bring the hammer on you.

Much better to either trade within a sturdier legal entity or just take your stuff over the border and trade by mail.

This is just one of the many, many ways that US law favors corporations that can afford expensive compliance and legal defense and suppresses trade among individuals. Also, if you have capital gains on physical metals, you pay the taxes and keep records, or the state will bring the hammer down on you in a playful fashion, because this is their job.

Yet more reasons to move overseas. &amp;gt;Yet more reasons to move overseas.

Have you done this? I'm preparing. Working for a guy remotely from Hong Kong right now, and am getting advice from another long-term resident on how to make the career transition. Why do you ask? Just curious; looking for some insight from those who made the jump.  I didn't mean to sound like I was challenging you.

I always flirted with the idea, but, right now, I'm defaulting to TX unless someone can make a strong, long-term case for Singapore. Just curious; looking for some insight from those who made the jump.  I didn't mean to sound like I was challenging you.

I always flirted with the idea, but, right now, I'm defaulting to TX unless someone can make a strong, long-term case for Singapore. Fuck Texas. I live in the durty South and I fucking hate it. Florida is a science-forsaken cesspool; a marsh of endless heat and retarded fuckers roaming the streets. I'm leaving first opportunity I have. If Texas is anything like this, science help you friend. The South really isn't homogeneous.

It sounds like you're in northern Florida, which does have that awful reputation.</snippet></document><document><title>Buddhist Monk Son of celebrated French Libertarian philosopher is the world's happiest man ;)</title><url>http://india.nydailynews.com/newsarticle/7b470adb0a9b6c32e19e16a08df13f3d/buddhist-monk-is-the-worlds-happiest-man</url><snippet>  </snippet></document></searchresult>