<searchresult><himym /><document><title>Saw this on r/ImSavingUpForThis and instantly thought of Barney's TV</title><url>http://www.cseed.tv/design/movie.html</url><snippet /></document><document><title>The Captain is Returning!</title><url>http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/02/01/how-i-met-your-mother-scoop-kyle-maclachlan-returning/</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Lost a bet. Had to wear the ducky tie to the casino. Pulling. It. Off. </title><url>http://imgur.com/gallery/qIMO1DQ</url><snippet>   "Kids, one of the cocktail waitresses saw the tie and said "You're a fan of How I Met Your Mother!" and I said "Yes. I actually lost a bet". Then she scribbled her phone number down on a napkin.

That, kids, is how I met your mother" First you have to tell your kids the whole story of HIMYM at least up until the ducky tie part.  HAHAHAHAHA CHRIS!!!!!  

You get 2 guesses who I am. Haha.  Want a Tony Hawk rematch?</snippet></document><document><title>What H append To Your Mother? (X-POST From TLAB)</title><url>http://imgur.com/8hbKYLl</url><snippet>  I don't get it... </snippet></document><document><title>I like to think Robin still sees this on tv once in a while and it keeps her from getting too caught up in her success.</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IyYE8J-GiCw</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Legend....wait for it....Harry (x-post from r/funny)</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/VKowoH0.jpg</url><snippet>   Men in bow ties &amp;lt;3 Bow ties are cool.  That was my first thought. I love it when my fandoms overlap. just the timelines crossing  Men in bow ties &amp;lt;3    Wingardium LeviBROsa!!    Yer a bro-wizard, 'Arry!  Didn't realise it was a pun until I remember they pronounce it 'hairy' in the US Is there another way to pronounce Harry? No but there's a different way to pronounce Harry .... That's what I asked. Is there another way to pronounce Harry? I say it "ha-ree", which is the most common way here in the UK. Also, I got so confused as to why there were so many American guys called "Erin" - here we pronounce Aaron as "Ah-ron", so I didn't understand the American pronunciation. Is there another way to pronounce Harry? Didn't realise it was a pun until I remember they pronounce it 'hairy' in the US No one from my area (New England) pronounced it hairy.  Maybe your talking about southerners?  Accents vary across the United States.
  Is there something to be said about the size of their respective bow ties? Surely there's a joke in there somewhere...         </snippet></document><document><title>Who was your favourite of Ted's girlfriends?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17rftt/who_was_your_favourite_of_teds_girlfriends/</url><snippet>Of all the people Ted has dated or hooked up with, which one is your favourite?

The last post I found on this was [pre-season 8](http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/w9xgk/who_was_your_favourite_of_teds_girlfriends/) but Ted has done a bit more since then.  Definitely Victoria for me. If the show had of ended after season 1 I would have been happy with her being the mother. I'm not a massive fan of the "psycho" Victoria that we seen last season though. Definitely Victoria for me. If the show had of ended after season 1 I would have been happy with her being the mother. I'm not a massive fan of the "psycho" Victoria that we seen last season though. Definitely Victoria for me. If the show had of ended after season 1 I would have been happy with her being the mother. I'm not a massive fan of the "psycho" Victoria that we seen last season though. Could not agree more with this. Loved Victoria, she was hot, cute, and just had that personality that I think everyone loved. 

Unfortunately, when she came back onto the show, a lot of her fun was gone and now I don't much care for her, but man...season 1 she was the greatest and I wanted her to be the mom.  Mary the Paralegal, if only for a night...

My briefs are tight right now thinking about her.    Since this isn't a "which girlfriend would you want to be the mom" post, I honestly have to say that Zoey has been my favorite. Yeah she was strong willed and a bit crazy but she was gorgeous and had a great personality.  Really? I hated her. In my opinion she had some really messed up priorities when it came to the Arcadian. She just had a personal attachment to the building because she grew up in it. It's natural to have those feelings. I know, but it wasn't being used anymore and it was significant for Ted's career. I think she should have realized that it's just a building and her boyfriend's career should take priority over that. In one aspect, I agree with you. But if you look at it from her side, you may seem different.
Can I blow up the family home you grew up in and build a bank in its place since it would make me money? Yeah, I mean, I understand why she would be really sad about it, but to go as far as potentially holding back the career of someone she cares about? It wasn't just about the money, it would have been a good move for Ted's career. I dunno, that seems very messed up to me. Yeah I agree but you can't blame just her for that. She and Ted both chose to never have that conversation about it....maybe if they had discussed the situation more she might have changed her mind.
But beyond that, Ted did in the beginning feel that the Arcadian should be saved (as per the recording), so did he honestly change his mind about the building later or did he just decide that it was better for his career?

I look at the Arcadian situation as a metaphor for Ted's love life....he really doesn't know what he wants. Yeah--Ted and Zoey definitely had some communication issues and butted heads way too often. 

Well, he did say it should be saved, but Zoey basically manipulated him into feeling so bad for her that he would agree with anything she said. Plus, I think his developing feelings had something to do with it too. So I think he always felt that creating the new GNB headquarters was the best move, and he was just trying to please Zoey.  He did state numerous times that the Lion Head was an architectural landmark. Oh well, either way it worked out as it should.
I wonder if she'll be making a comeback since the Captain is confirmed to make an appearance. Yeah I agree but you can't blame just her for that. She and Ted both chose to never have that conversation about it....maybe if they had discussed the situation more she might have changed her mind.
But beyond that, Ted did in the beginning feel that the Arcadian should be saved (as per the recording), so did he honestly change his mind about the building later or did he just decide that it was better for his career?

I look at the Arcadian situation as a metaphor for Ted's love life....he really doesn't know what he wants. The Arcadian, much like the duck in the "Rabbit or Duck" episode, is a symbol of progress.  Zoey's love for the Arcadian is creditable, however she has to realize that the hotel is no longer inhabitable and therefore useless; the opportunity of the new building represents the decision to advance in life and progress into a brighter future, while keeping it will show the inability to let something go.  In a way, it fits in like a small puzzle piece to the puzzle that is "How I Met Your Mother". Ted has met and parted with a plethora of women throughout the show, including a handful of significant ones that he had to let go, (as in Robin and Victoria).  The eventual destruction of the Arcadian teaches us that change is inevitable, and can eventually be for the best, because as we know, if it had not been for the new building, Ted would never have met the mother. Since this isn't a "which girlfriend would you want to be the mom" post, I honestly have to say that Zoey has been my favorite. Yeah she was strong willed and a bit crazy but she was gorgeous and had a great personality.  She was a horrifically self important cunt! She married for money and whe she got board with that she cheated on her husband with another man. She never trusted Ted, keeping the recording and betraying him the moment he stood up for himself.   Has to be Stella. I love Sarah Chalke more than what's healthy. I have to agree, though i'm a bit biased because I LOVED Scrubs Stella was the Elliot we all wanted her to be. Until she left him at the alter.  Has to be Stella. I love Sarah Chalke more than what's healthy. Has to be Stella. I love Sarah Chalke more than what's healthy.  It won't be a popular opinion, but Robin. It won't be a popular opinion, but Robin. I liked her best as a character, but not as a girlfriend of Ted's.  I liked her best as a character, but not as a girlfriend of Ted's.   Karen, yes, she was terrible, but I loved seeing how she brought out Ted's douchey traits and it was fun to watch. Everyone remembers being a pretentious snobbish intellectual at some point and Ted still has that aspect of him to a certain extent. Just as Quinn was a "female Barney," I feel like Karen is a little bit of a "female Ted." Ted's douchey traits are always being shown. Haha.     I like the escort.  Nothing about her specifically, I'm just a fan of prostitutes.       Though not a girlfriend, I liked Vicky. The one Ted did the Naked Man on. Yea she was mean. but she was hot. </snippet></document><document><title>What was your favorite move from The Playbook?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17qwj9/what_was_your_favorite_move_from_the_playbook/</url><snippet>I would have to say my favorite one is the "He's not coming"

Get to the top of the Empire State Building. Then walk up to random girls and say "he's not coming." Keep doing this until you get someone to cry in your shoulder.   the final page i mean cmon that was so amazing! the final page i mean cmon that was so amazing!  The My Penis Grants Wishes...only if you rub it hard enough. The My Penis Grants Wishes...only if you rub it hard enough.      The Snasa. "have you been to the moon?"
"i've been to the secret moon"
      </snippet></document><document><title>Pixel people</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/V1OGEEc.png</url><snippet /></document><document><title>I'll be cool...</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/mfSnQPt.jpg</url><snippet>     Episode?</snippet></document><document><title>Just a little motivation from the Barnicle for this flu season </title><url>http://imgur.com/3R3J6EC</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Robin Scherbatsky's cute and all, but I've got a real crush on Robin Sparkles.</title><url>http://imgur.com/R4YyvEQ</url><snippet>    </snippet></document><document><title>All the 50 numbers from THAT episode! Can you find them all?</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/2QL1e</url><snippet>  Also what's the significance of the 50 numbers? Is there something I don't understand? It's the countdown to Marvin Eriksen Sr.'s death. Was there any hints of what the numbers represented beforehand? Or was it something put there for us to notice for a countdown of some sort? I also want to know this... I don't understand the countdown at all. Also what's the significance of the 50 numbers? Is there something I don't understand?  DEM FEELS WHEN IT HITS 1.... D:  3...2...1...heartbreak  I couldn't find 5 I couldn't find 5    Uhm. What's number 24? Basketball player's jersey number on the magazine.     Sorry about the subtitles </snippet></document><document><title>Saw this in /r/funny, but I thought it belongs here</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/nxx2OpZ.jpg</url><snippet>  I can see why you would think this might belong here</snippet></document><document><title>Look who's coming back to HIMYM!</title><url>http://www.vulture.com/2013/02/familiar-face-is-headed-back-to-himym.html</url><snippet>      </snippet></document><document><title>My Suitjamas arrived! PJ Suit up!</title><url>http://imgur.com/dgWej9v,9stizq4,ZLMDi5c#0</url><snippet>  Where can I get one? Just google "SuitJamas"

[Here is the top link](http://www.suitjamas.com/categories)  Are those actually comfortable?</snippet></document><document><title>Still My Favorite Scene Ever</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/TzortAv.png</url><snippet>  Why are each of the frames flipped?  Anyone ever notice that Barney changed in later episode. His attempts to pick up women went from lame and failure prone to Legend-wait-for-it&#8230;

dary? This mirrors Ted's feelings for him. When they first start hanging out with Barney, they see him as pathetic and mock his attempts to pick up ladies. As he becomes more sympathetic towards Barney, he remembers him in a better light.  This mirrors Ted's feelings for him. When they first start hanging out with Barney, they see him as pathetic and mock his attempts to pick up ladies. As he becomes more sympathetic towards Barney, he remembers him in a better light.  This mirrors Ted's feelings for him. When they first start hanging out with Barney, they see him as pathetic and mock his attempts to pick up ladies. As he becomes more sympathetic towards Barney, he remembers him in a better light.    Definitely a good scene. I think one of my favorites is in 'The Bracket' when they are trying to narrow the field of women potentially sabotaging Barney.    We are international business men    </snippet></document><document><title>Was rewatching the episodes and noticed something in the background!</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/j5lDyCt.jpg?1</url><snippet>  What are they? I opened the comments to search for OP's explanation. Not found. I am sorry for the bad quality. I really am. What i was going for here was that i noticed family photographs in the background, one including the wedding photograph of Ted in which the face of the mother is not shown but in the other two photos to the right, there is a woman in the photographs with two kids. Hope this helps you people. Again, sorry for the bad quality. It's my first time on this subreddit. I also wrote the explanation but i don't know where it got lost.

Edit: Also, you could watch this in the show. I noticed this in S01E6. I'll try posting a photograph with a good resolution! Now I feel bad... It's just that most pics, even in /r/pics, usually aren't very clear. And I'm just used to opening the comments expecting OP's brief explanation. Thanks OP!

I guess the mother is a brunette? Or Ted maybe went through his hippie phase in 20-something. No matter how it goes in the show, the writers could easily say it's Robin or their young daughter's selfshots..? I am sorry for the bad quality. I really am. What i was going for here was that i noticed family photographs in the background, one including the wedding photograph of Ted in which the face of the mother is not shown but in the other two photos to the right, there is a woman in the photographs with two kids. Hope this helps you people. Again, sorry for the bad quality. It's my first time on this subreddit. I also wrote the explanation but i don't know where it got lost.

Edit: Also, you could watch this in the show. I noticed this in S01E6. I'll try posting a photograph with a good resolution! What are they?  [this](http://i.imgur.com/1VpmSBM.jpg) is what OP was trying to show us [this](http://i.imgur.com/1VpmSBM.jpg) is what OP was trying to show us  Well that's one strange wedding picture. I get that they can't show the bride's face if she's the mother but who would display a picture where both the bride and the groom are missing their heads? With season 9, and Ted needing to impregnate his future wife by at least July 2014 so that his daughter is born in time for Trilogy Day 2015, it will probably end with Ted's wedding.  And hopefully there will be a story for why that picture has no heads and it's still on display.

I will forgive everything if they explain the wedding picture in season 9. I've seen wedding pictures like this, it's almost always when the bride and groom are cutting the cake... I've seen wedding pictures like this, it's almost always when the bride and groom are cutting the cake...   Well, I guess this favors the speculation of The Mother being brunette. I just find it odd that Ted (if it's Ted, is covered up). Did you hit Enter by mistake? I feel like you just kind of stopped in the middle of Lol! This cold is getting to me         this doesn't make any sense,  isn't the mother a blonde?  perhaps a picture of Robin? No she isn't a blond. We know this because when ted was thinking that Stella could be the mother, and the children were blond, imaging that his children would also be blind if the mother was too, however the fact that his children are brown haired, it implies that the mother is also brown haired Isn't brunette a dominant gene, thus more likely to produce brunette offspring if Ted was with a blonde woman?  No she isn't a blond. We know this because when ted was thinking that Stella could be the mother, and the children were blond, imaging that his children would also be blind if the mother was too, however the fact that his children are brown haired, it implies that the mother is also brown haired Well, then it ~~obviously~~ is the mother in the photos because it can't be Lily, it's not Robin. Who else is left who could be in those photos? Well, then it ~~obviously~~ is the mother in the photos because it can't be Lily, it's not Robin. Who else is left who could be in those photos? this doesn't make any sense,  isn't the mother a blonde?  perhaps a picture of Robin? Wait! Am I missing something? Are we sure that the mother is blonde? this doesn't make any sense,  isn't the mother a blonde?  perhaps a picture of Robin? I thought it looked like Aunt Robin. And the wedding photo~~s~~? Plus, who would allow their husband's ex's photo to be kept there like a trophy? I would bet it's a picture of Robin and the teddy bear is maybe covering up the man in the photo so that it doesn't reveal who Robin is with in the photo. That would allow people to speculate that Robin is the mother until later when she is referred to as "Aunt Robin". Yes. But there are three photographs. I am a 100% sure that it is NOT Robin in the righmost photograph. Yes. But there are three photographs. I am a 100% sure that it is NOT Robin in the righmost photograph. this doesn't make any sense,  isn't the mother a blonde?  perhaps a picture of Robin?</snippet></document><document><title>Barney's diamond suit exists!</title><url>http://www.extravaganzi.com/world%E2%80%99s-most-expensive-suit-by-stuart-hughes/</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>How I Met Your Mother - P.S. I Love You (Sneak Peek) - YouTube</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EQ_y19bGEi4&amp;amp;feature=youtube_gdata_player</url><snippet>   Barney destroyed Ted's VCR in the episode where he finds the sex tape Barney destroyed Ted's VCR in the episode where he finds the sex tape This is Lily and Marshall's apartment now, so they probably have one.   </snippet></document><document><title>In your opinion what is the best episode of HIMYM?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17q0q6/in_your_opinion_what_is_the_best_episode_of_himym/</url><snippet>I can't choose, there are so many episodes i love.   1. girls vs suits. I mean, you got the most revealing info about the mother, including seeing part of her AND barney's perfect song

2. slap bet. i mean you get the slap bet AND robin sparlkes.

what more could you want?  The Final Page  3.8- Spoiler Alert. (glass shattering)    The episode where Robin thinks she is pregnant, and she grapples with the fact that she never wanted kids. And she begins to really want to have this baby.

Only to find out shes actually infertile and will never have children of her own.

Such a sad twist of fate   Robin Sparkles 3, y'all! Literally just finished watching Glitter.

*Two beavers are better than one...* I like the guys reaction to: "... how's your beaver?"

guys: *Pfffffshhhh*      As someone who up until a month ago had never watched this show (I just spent the last month ingesting **every episode ever**)  I would have to say my favorites were: (in no particular order)  

*Sweet Taste Of Liberty, Slap Bet, The Window, Last Cigarette Ever, Swarley, Spoiler Alert, The Playbook, Home Wreckers, Mystery Vs. History and No Pressure.*

I feel like Season Five had consistently the best episodes.          </snippet></document><document><title>I couldn't resist buying it. </title><url>http://i.imgur.com/kmVMlBn.jpg</url><snippet>  I'm almost jealous that as a dude I can't wear that.
 But you're the property of Ted Mosby! I'm almost jealous that as a dude I can't wear that.
  Where did you find that? Where did you find that?  rolling my eyes at all the people that asked where you found it, when the link has been posted already, like how many times. oh by the way, where again?  http://www.redbubble.com/people/huckblade/works/9613683-mrs-mosby?p=t-shirt

http://www.redbubble.com/people/huckblade/works/9613683-mrs-mosby?p=t-shirt

http://www.redbubble.com/people/huckblade/works/9613683-mrs-mosby?p=t-shirt

http://www.redbubble.com/people/huckblade/works/9613683-mrs-mosby?p=t-shirt I love it!!! Where did you get it? I love it!!! Where did you get it?  Were did you find this? I would LOVE to have one :)  I would love to have this shirt! Please let us know where you bought it! http://www.redbubble.com/people/huckblade/works/9613683-mrs-mosby?p=t-shirt   Wait, isn't this the Morton Salt logo?  I was gonna buy that one. I loved it except the Mrs. Mosby part. If he had left that off I would have gotten it in a second!

Did you see the side art today of Dr. Horrible? That's ordered the second it hits Ript. I spend way too much money at that website.          </snippet></document><document><title>MURDERRRRRR</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjJmasprmBw</url><snippet /></document><document><title>How I Met Your Mother - P.S. I Love You (Promo) - YouTube</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GOJ8jmqoPcs&amp;amp;feature=youtube_gdata_player</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>That sounds familiar...</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/8Loykiz.jpg</url><snippet>     Someone stole your karma. Sorry bro</snippet></document><document><title>Could the mother's name be Tracy? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17qiqv/could_the_mothers_name_be_tracy/</url><snippet>Maybe this has been brought up but I'm rewatching season 1 right now and in season 1 episode 9 (The Thanksgiving episode) Ted is talking to a stripper at the end and she says her real name is Tracy. Future Ted then jokes to his kids that is how he met there mother and the kids say, "What!?!?!" Wouldn't that joke only work if their mother's name was Tracy?  I hate to break it to ya, but people have but thinking about this for years. Good find though! I figured as much but I've only been recently checking this subreddit and I never seen it mentioned even in topics where people are going over what we know about the mother. I would suggest you look to the right side of the screen, and read those two links, the common links and mother checklist. That might clear up why certain topics don't show up all that often. Thanks for pointing that out. Feel free to downvote me into oblivion everyone.   We see the story as Ted is remembering it, not how the kids are being told. He tells his kids at one point (season 6 spoiler coming up) that he can't tell them about the removal of the lion head stonework from the arcadian for legal reasons, yet we see ted, marshall, and barney taking it down. So he didn't tell his kids that he took it down, however, we, as an audience, were able to see this.

I don't think the writers intended on writing themselves into a 'corner' like that We see the story as Ted is remembering it, not how the kids are being told. He tells his kids at one point (season 6 spoiler coming up) that he can't tell them about the removal of the lion head stonework from the arcadian for legal reasons, yet we see ted, marshall, and barney taking it down. So he didn't tell his kids that he took it down, however, we, as an audience, were able to see this.

I don't think the writers intended on writing themselves into a 'corner' like that  </snippet></document><document><title>Can you guys help me remember?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17pn60/can_you_guys_help_me_remember/</url><snippet>Does anybody remember when were Marshall's slaps delivered? I remember than in 2x09 He delivered the first one, the third one in 3x09 Slapsgiving and the fourth one in 5x09 Slapsgiving 2: Revenge of the slap and that in 7x09 he delivered two more after Barney agreed to give him three more slaps to stop wearing the ducky tie. The thing is, there is another slap, the second one, that I can't remember when he delivered it, all I can remember is that it was during Barney's "theatre play", does anybody remember which episode was it?

Also, how many slap bets were made? I remember one between Ted and Marshall, but, were there any more?

Thanks :)
  WARNING: SPOILERS

The slap bet was made in the episode Slap Bet.

Originally, Barney and Marshall made a bet: Barney bet that Robin did Porn, Marshall bet that Robin was married.

When Robin lied to Ted and said she was married, Ted told the gang and Marshall slapped Barney. Later, Marshall finds out that Robin indeed was not married and told Lily (Slap Bet Commissioner). Lily tells Barney and awards him three slaps to make up for Marshall's premature slap.

Later, Barney discovers the first Robin Sparkles video ("Let's Go To The Mall") and after watching the first few seconds, assumes it is pornography and slaps Marshall again.

Robin, confused, asked for an explanation. When she proved it was not porn, Lily awarded Marshall extra slaps to make up for Barney's premature slap, but she let's Barney choose: ten slaps right now or five slaps over the course of now to eternity. Against Robin's good advice, Barney goes with the five slap option.

The following ensued:

1. Marshall slaps Barney right away (in the episode "Slap Bet")
2. Marshall slaps Barney after he forces the gang to endure his one man show (in the episode "Stuff")
3. Marshall employs slapbetcountdown.com before slapping Barney at Thanksgiving dinner (in the episode "Slapsgiving")
4. Marshall intends to slap Barney again at Thanksgiving dinner (in episode "Slapsgiving II: Revenge of the Slap") but awards it to Ted and Robin who fight over it before giving to Mickey who gives it to Lily who can't do it. Marshall slaps Barney anyway.
5. Barney convinces Marshall to let him take off the ducky tie for 3 more slaps; Marshall now has 4 slaps but uses two before the episode is over ("Disaster Averted")

Am I forgetting anything?

 </snippet></document><document><title>The one in the middle is my friend, and on the right is his wife. I don't know the guy on the left, but he reminds me of Ted...</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/Je1wOt3.jpg</url><snippet>  Salt, Pepper and Cumin! Frankenstein, his monster, and the apothecary Lady, tramp, and of course their plate of spaghetti  R2-D2, C-3PO and the droid that Luke's uncle almost bought from the jawas. Lewis and Clark and their canoe. Frankenstein, his monster, and the apothecary [deleted]  guessing the wife never made it to the end of the film. I honestly don't know. She might have not wanted to have been painted green. Beats me. Everyone else got painted! Where's the solidarity?</snippet></document><document><title>Was anyone else reminded of this when Lily's dad freaked her out about having her tonsils removed?</title><url>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0587635/</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>So, I gave my boyfriend the task of making a playlist for our 15 hour drive to my school...</title><url>http://imgur.com/at7eyCi</url><snippet>   SHOT THROUGH THE HEART AND YOU'RE TO BLAME     To be honest, I find [these ](http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/xw6zj/road_trip_next_week_how_i_plan_on_trolling_my/)[posts](http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/yxe57/my_sister_and_her_friend_are_going_on_a_road_trip/) pretty lame. Why wouldn't you just repeat the song? And OP is of course never the one who made the playlist... I can have him take a picture with the iPod if you're really concerned that this was a fake playlist? 
I don't know why redditors post passive aggressive comments assuming that everyone is lying to get useless karma. No, of course I didn't assume that it's a fake playlist, it just doesn't make any sense to create such a playlist, because you can simly play the song and press the repeat button. &amp;gt; it just doesn't make any sense to create such a playlist

It does if it's done as a joke, which this obviously was.</snippet></document><document><title>Barney's standards are lower than I thought</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/Nv3f19Q.png</url><snippet>  Maybe she just gained some weight since Barney spent the night with her  I believe that The Barnacle has mentioned a girl that put on 30 or 40 pounds after sleeping with him. I think it was the Crazy/Hot episode?   Slump buster? I believe the quote was "The Barnicle don't bang no fatties. Well, there was one, but she was a slump buster. And after that I went on a streak that you would not believe!"

 Amazing.  So this picture is actually accurate. Slump buster?  nice catch!   IS THAT YOU PATRICE?!?!     What episode is this from???  what does that say? I can't read it. Slept with Barney.    </snippet></document><document><title>What if the actor that plays Ted died (or was for some other reason I can't think of not available) and couldn't shoot the final HIMYM season and couldn't act in the episodes where Ted finally, FINALLY meets the mother? How do you think the writers would handle such a thing?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17ptg7/what_if_the_actor_that_plays_ted_died_or_was_for/</url><snippet>To clarify, I in no way want this to happen at all. I actually feel bad for even having thought of the scenario. But I did think about it last night while watching Netflix reruns. Curious as to your thoughts and ideas...  Just have Bob Saget take over the role, that would be the best they could do in that kind of situation.  I was honestly thinking about this yesterday. I think the best option would be for the writers to make season 9 from the mother's point of view. Then in the finale, she would be at the train station and they could use old sound footage to have Ted say something simple like "hey" or "hello." She turns towards him, we see Ted (again from old footage) and then we hear Bob Sagat's voice, "...and that, kids, is the story of how I met your mother."

But I hope we don't have to worry about it.  Use Jimmy Fallon to play Ted. Use Jimmy Fallon to play Ted.  If something this tragic did happen, I would much rather the whole show be cancelled than see someone else play Ted.   They'd re-cast Ted, like TV shows do when something tragic happens.  Well, that would be immensely unsatisfying as a viewer. I guess there's not really a good option. They did it Fresh Prince of Bel-Air. They just replaced Will's Aunt after 3 seasons. In Spartacus the lead actor passed away and they had to recast the lead. It's not the same, but he brings his own tweaks to the character. 

They really don't have much of an option unless they want to stop the show. But with a show like HIMYM it makes too much money for them to not finish the last season.  I agree that's probably what the writers would do. But replacing Will's Aunt or Daren on Bewitched and replacing Ted on HIMYM are very different. Ted is a main character, not like Will's aunt. I guess the actor would have to be pretty great.
 They did it on Spartacus. It's a guilty pleasure show of mine but Andy Whitfield was perfect for the role. Unfortunately he passed away and they were forced to replace him. They replaced him with Liam McIntyre and although he's not as good as Andy Whitfield, he plays the Spartacus with his own technique and ideas. Had some big shoes to fill and does it pretty successfully. And in my opinion, that role is harder to replace than Ted's from HIMYM.

Not ideal, but they could do it. Also, I would imagine Bob Saget would be a good back-up since he does the voice overs.  Oddly enough, I would vote for Bob Saget to do it. They could go all out and make Vicki (his former Full House love interest- yes I'm embarrassed I know that), the mother. They'd re-cast Ted, like TV shows do when something tragic happens.  Yeah, but shows don't often recast a main character. Especially one so fundamental to the story as Ted is. They do when something tragic happens...which is what the OP asked. Not that often though, usually they write it in e.g. 8 Simple Rules, when John Ritter died, he also died in show.

I suppose they could recast Ted, but I really don't think it would work. I can't think of any shows that have recast the title character and continued to work. Spartacus. Andy Whitfield died (aka Spartacus) and was replaced by Liam McIntyre. 

I don't think they could write off Ted dying in the final season if they haven't shot anything and he still hasn't met his wife in the stories he's telling.</snippet></document><document><title>What IS the difference between peanut butter and jam?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17praa/what_is_the_difference_between_peanut_butter_and/</url><snippet>I'm rewatching S4E20 "Mosbius Designs" and I'm just curious if anyone ever figured out the punchline...?  Do a search before posting. This has been asked 100 times.

PS. I can't peanut butter by dick in your ass  </snippet></document><document><title>Paused HIMYM, i think i might be drunk.</title><url>http://imgur.com/t1JYf</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>One of the luscious ladies Barney's slept with (S03E14).</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/XH0oGjI.png</url><snippet>    ...moist</snippet></document><document><title>HIMYM Merch</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17obir/himym_merch/</url><snippet>Anybody have any suggestions to some How I Met Your Mother merchandise? I'm not really looking for anything in particular, I just had some extra money and realized I didn't have much HIMYM stuff. I've on;y got the bro code and all of barney's books and stuff like that.  There's an official store at CBS's website. 

Personally, I'd go for the Maclaren's pint glass [for the lazy](http://www.cbsstore.com/how-i-met-your-mother/index.php?v=cbs-howimetyourmother) </snippet></document><document><title>How I feel about Barney and Robin's wedding date being on my 18th birthday.</title><url>http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m3l1cooAyf1rn78oa.gif</url><snippet>  High five for having the same birthday!  Triple high five with my sister! She's got the same birthday! High five for having the same birthday!       some people haven't gotten up to season eight yet :( Then you should not be on this sub.   You might have wanted to mark this with a spoiler. I'm mid season 2</snippet></document><document><title>Barney and Scooter with their adorable children</title><url>http://imgur.com/ZOFiuAB</url><snippet>  Look at them, destroying those kids lives with their homosexuality! Don't they know that kids who are exposed to two happy people their entire life grow up to become normal healthy adults who can accept all people readily? We can't have that. Look at them, destroying those kids lives with their homosexuality! Don't they know that kids who are exposed to two happy people their entire life grow up to become normal healthy adults who can accept all people readily? We can't have that. No one in this thread even brought that argument up...why did you? Can't we just enjoy the picture for what it is? A loving family having a good time together.  He's being completely sarcastic I understand he is, but I still don't think it was necessary to bring up. Just my opinion though.  No one in this thread even brought that argument up...why did you? Can't we just enjoy the picture for what it is? A loving family having a good time together.  No one in this thread even brought that argument up...why did you? Can't we just enjoy the picture for what it is? A loving family having a good time together.  No one in this thread even brought that argument up...why did you? Can't we just enjoy the picture for what it is? A loving family having a good time together.   *Neil and David What?! No way!! Those are real people with real names! I thought those guys were just playing themselves on the show! [deleted] I guess you don't understand sarcasm too well. Or irony, for that matter What?! No way!! Those are real people with real names! I thought those guys were just playing themselves on the show! [deleted] *Neil and David *Neil and David Some of the people in this thread didn't realize that David is Scooter.  BRO-PARENTS! Told you it works! Gotta say, they look 10x happier than most married couples.  Is it normal if I want to be adopted by NPH and David? Yes. Even if we're say, 21? All the better! You can go to MacLaran's with them! NPH (or Barney for that matter) would be the best dad ever to drink with Imagine all the plays you could run?  The "Father knows Breast"  Even if we're say, 21? In Japan, people adopt those who are 25-30! You're 4 years away!  This is how the show ends but with Wayne Brady and Ted   Yeah, gay marriage is really fucking up this country. Look at those miserable children.  Very cute! Never connected that his husband was scooted. Really? Did you know that Sandy Rivers is Alyson Hannigan's (Lily) husband?
And [Blauman](http://how-i-met-your-mother.wikia.com/wiki/Gary_Blauman) is Cobie Smulder's (Robin) husband. Respect to blauman for landing that hottie I didn't know that he's the one married to Cobie. One other little relationship appearance was Josh Radnor's  girlfriend, at the time, [Lindsay Price](http://img2.timeinc.net/people/i/2009/news/090629/lindsay-price.jpg) played Ted's girlfriend "chatty" [Cathy](http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_mbczeaTsR71rujeh5o1_500.png). Respect to blauman for landing that hottie He looks much better with longer hair. He's a regular on SNL and one of the funniest on it. Really? Did you know that Sandy Rivers is Alyson Hannigan's (Lily) husband?
And [Blauman](http://how-i-met-your-mother.wikia.com/wiki/Gary_Blauman) is Cobie Smulder's (Robin) husband. Really? Did you know that Sandy Rivers is Alyson Hannigan's (Lily) husband?
And [Blauman](http://how-i-met-your-mother.wikia.com/wiki/Gary_Blauman) is Cobie Smulder's (Robin) husband.   Their daughter... I can't even comprehend how she is doing that... Their daughter... I can't even comprehend how she is doing that...    NPH I love you but seriously, that seems a bit unsafe Nah, kids are unbreakable.    Just blew my mind, I didn't know they were married, hah. Engaged. Is it true though?
 Is it true though?
 Engaged. They didn't marry yet? Thought they did..     Someone please explain to me how NPH is holding his kid like that...  </snippet></document><document><title>How I Met Your Mother 8x15 Promo "P.S. I Love You" (HD) - YouTube</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_XVbOCZz56I</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>I thought of him right away...</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/e77QDIL.jpg</url><snippet>  He definitely doesn't remember every detail, though. Blah Blah agrees. Honey does too  So does the pineapple. And Strawberry Uhmmm. No. The girl's name was 'Strawberry'. Oh yeah, I was always forget that. And Strawberry That fucking goat... So does the pineapple. Pineapple wasn't Ted being forgetful. He just never found out. He was in the situation it was used in and forgot why it was there. People with hyperthymesia can remember every detail regardless of their level of sobriety. So does the pineapple. He definitely doesn't remember every detail, though. I wonder if people with Hyperthymesia can remember every detail of their lives after having as many sandwiches as Ted though... And do they remember all their bagpiping partners? Depends on the amount of sandwiches involved, again... He should have stick with weed... wat He definitely doesn't remember every detail, though. true, but I can't even remember what I had for breakfast this morning, and he can remember what he ate 20 years before...lol He definitely doesn't remember every detail, though.  I submit to you:  The Pineapple Incident.

Lawyered. Also the incident with the goat. He was off by a whole year on that one. Not to mention the Lilly/Barney mermaid argument. And lily pregnant with ice cream Also the incident with the goat. He was off by a whole year on that one. I submit to you:  The Pineapple Incident.

Lawyered.    Wait a minute is this a real thing? Because i could have some form of that. I remember every detail of conversations i had 20 years ago, even remember events vividly with complete recollection after about 4 years of age. You might, or you may have extreme memory. I have it and I can remember things from about 2 years, with really vivid memories kicking in around 4 I have something like that because I can just tell stories with people that are in the stories present and they are just like how do you remember all of that? The other week i was talking to my gmaw about how she took me to see the big green when i was little and how the lobby was a neat set up with all the differnet vendors and she was just flabergasted because i was 8 or 9. Its always fun to see people's reactions to it. But I don't know if you've ever been black out drunk, but its the only time I can't recall. Which is really trippy when you can remember near everything You might, or you may have extreme memory. I have it and I can remember things from about 2 years, with really vivid memories kicking in around 4 Wait a minute is this a real thing? Because i could have some form of that. I remember every detail of conversations i had 20 years ago, even remember events vividly with complete recollection after about 4 years of age. Wait a minute is this a real thing? Because i could have some form of that. I remember every detail of conversations i had 20 years ago, even remember events vividly with complete recollection after about 4 years of age. You might have a great memory, but people with this condition remember a crazy amount of detail.  For example, you can ask them about a randomly selected day 20+ years ago and they can tell you what they had for breakfast, what they were wearing and what happened in the news that day.  I have a very good memory but I was blown away by what these people can remember.  Actress ~~Marlo Thomas~~ Marilu Henner is one of the rare people with this condition and talks about it on TV sometimes.  Can people with Hyperthymesia remember while they are trashed? (i.e. The Pineapple Incident) Can people with Hyperthymesia remember while they are trashed? (i.e. The Pineapple Incident) Seriously when are the writers planning to tell us about the pineapple incident?  Never, that is kind of the point though isn't it? 

There are some mysteries in life that will never be figured out no matter what. Never, that is kind of the point though isn't it? 

There are some mysteries in life that will never be figured out no matter what.    Does anyone else hate Ted?  I know a woman that has it. She was on 60 minutes. If you ask her a question like "what days in march of 1987 did it rain?" And she'll tell you. Of course I have no idea if she's pulling random dates out of the air.           </snippet></document><document><title>BY FAR my favorite moment</title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jyq6kAMWWKc</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>What does HIMYM mean to you?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/HIMYM/comments/17mlx9/what_does_himym_mean_to_you/</url><snippet>All of a sudden, I've got curious why you guys are so into (or hate extremely) HIMYM. 
Somebody might watch this TV show to kill some time, but for somebody it could mean something like me.

For me, I had a very bad break-up with my ex-fiance. And this TV show was one of the TV shows we used to watch together.
After the break-up, I missed him a lot having miserable time.(Close to depression, to be fair-couldn't eat, sleep, or of course hang out other people at all for a while)
So I started watching this show and it helped me cry and let out all the sorrow inside of me. And sometimes I could even laugh watching the shows.
I often went through all season one night crying and laughing.
They have love, sad, funny, break-up, happy (etc.) moment, and I've learned that life goes on. It might sound silly, but it is true that I've got better from this TV show than the word "Cheer up" from my friends.
So I'd like to hear your stories as well.  I just enjoy the idea of a love story in reverse. The way Future Ted tells the story of how he met the mother makes me believe that everything I'm doing right now has impact on what is going to happen years away from now. The best example is S04E22 Right Place Right Time. It's just inspiring for me personally. It's the same with S06E03 Unfinished - Some episodes just have a special place in my heart which is why I love the show and still do in S08.  Definitely this. As a 20-something trying to figure life out, it just feels so relatable. The idea that everything eventually works itself out in the very end is quite comforting.  Have you ever looked back and thought 'Oh, I should have done this instead of that' regretting your decisions? [deleted] I just enjoy the idea of a love story in reverse. The way Future Ted tells the story of how he met the mother makes me believe that everything I'm doing right now has impact on what is going to happen years away from now. The best example is S04E22 Right Place Right Time. It's just inspiring for me personally. It's the same with S06E03 Unfinished - Some episodes just have a special place in my heart which is why I love the show and still do in S08.  I just enjoy the idea of a love story in reverse. The way Future Ted tells the story of how he met the mother makes me believe that everything I'm doing right now has impact on what is going to happen years away from now. The best example is S04E22 Right Place Right Time. It's just inspiring for me personally. It's the same with S06E03 Unfinished - Some episodes just have a special place in my heart which is why I love the show and still do in S08.   Not only do I feel the storyline is fantastic, but the characters as just so diverse and memorable. They're just a weird crowd of people that turn out to be best friends, and it's just really interesting to watch. Each person has that unique quirk about them.  Beyond the fact that I still find it funny and entertaining, it's helped me move on with my life. Long-story short: After one of the worst breakups in my life (one that lasted a strong five years until a whole assortment of bad shit happened all at once) is about the same time (a month later) that I started watching HIMYM on Netflix. I think I cleared two seasons in less than a week, and it's been six months since the breakup. The help progressed in two stages:  The first was the character Barney, and second, naturally, was Ted. 

Barney's line, "Whenever I'm sad, I stop being sad and be awesome instead." That stuck with me harder than I thought any simple mostly-joke could. I started reaching out to old friends and started being more social with people in class and out at bars and clubs downtown. I stopped playing so many video games. I started getting better grades, diving into a new major (psychology). I picked up things that I hadn't done in a while, like kendo and soccer. I became more fashion-conscious, and I started talking to more girls. The confidence shift that I experienced was incredible, and remembering the kind of fucked but awesome advice of Barney helped me find that.

I met two girls over the course of those six months and re-established ties with an old friend from high school - two were one-night stands (but the kind where we keep talking from time to time on Facebook). Don't get me wrong, the sex was awesome, but it felt...lacking. And this is when I was convinced that I'd become more like Barney to avoid the kind of emotional hurt that I felt then.

Enter Ted. Ted's character gave me hope - one of the biggest themes of the show. I was convinced that I'd never love again, blah blah blah. Time heals all wounds and such, but seeing Ted struggle for true love is what, in conjunction with the 'time healing all wounds' stuff, inspired me to start giving it another go, even if I'm still worried about experiencing that kind of heartbreak again.

The third girl, the old friend from high school, we kind of had drunk sex on new years eve, but when we woke up we didn't regret a damn thing. As of right now, we're not official in the slightest, but we still enjoy each other's company. It's one of those weird things - we talked about it, and we're both worried that if we try something more 'real' we could eventually not even be friends anymore. The way we act, though? You'd think we were together. So even if she isn't the one, she still helps me feel that way, you know? But we've made it clear that if we find someone else to go for it, and that we'd think about becoming official as time went on. It may sound weird, but it makes me happy. And the sex is awesome and more intimate.

The kind of hurt Marshall felt at the end of season one and the beginning of season two also resonated deep with me when I got to that part. Bloody feels.

Anyway, I know it's just a show, but it (and my close friends, of course) helped me get through the sort of emotions I'd never experienced before - massive, massive heartbreak. Bleh.

---

**tl;dr**: Heart broken after five year relationship, became like Barney, then became more like Ted, happier and more confident than ever thanks in part to this show and its characters. Wow. I am glad that I was not the only person who appreciates HIMYM that it helped me get over my heart-break. Thank you for sharing your story. And.. I've just started a new relationship as well. For me, I'd like to get really serious with him although I cannot get rid of the fear of bad bad feeling when I had to go through the break-up. 
And...I am really sorry to my boy friend cause I know that I am kinda bugging him because of my insecurities. So...if you don't me asking, are you experiencing the same thing?  I see myself in Marshall. I keep watching the show because it gives me hope for my future and how a I want my marriage to be (as long as my wife doesn't almost leave me like Lily).

Also, once I got to about the 3rd season I realized that there was no way out of it except for finding out who the mother is.   To me, it is an acronym of How I met your mother. True story.  To me, it is an acronym of How I met your mother. True story.   I have always loved this show. My ex-girlfriend and I used to watch together. So it kind of helps me remember the good times we had together Wow. So do you miss her, or only the memories? Both, really. But the memories are nice to have and remember  I just thought it was a funny show I caught on reruns (about 4 years back). I caught up quickly and began really liking the characters and their development. I liked that the characters evolve and grow.  At this point, I think that I would enjoy the show so much more if it weren't for the fact that the original intended premise always called for an endgame that nobody expected to be dragged out this long.  Although I'm not happy about the fact that there will be another season and we have to wait until then to meet the mother, I will watch it until the end. I don't watch much television and DVR everything I like, but this is the one show that I still watch as it's airing.  Well, I envy you that you can at least catch them up on TV. I cannot since I am in Korea. ;( We are not allowed to watch HULU here even. UNFAIR!!! That sucks! Can you catch them on Itunes?  I missed an episode once that my DVR didn't record and wound up watching it on Itunes, but I had to pay $1 for it.   Its funny background noise for when im doin homework after class.  I remember watching the very first episode when it was first aired in 2005 and thinking "This show is gonna be something special." And it has been very special and significant in my life. HIMYM means a lot to me because it gives me hope. I love the ideas and theories and ideology that the show covers. To me, the show does a really good job of featuring both realistic things as well as idealistic things. The show taught me you should take the leap, that somehow you will be in the right place in the right time, that sometimes you end up a doppleganger to who you once were, that there are times when you think you are okay in life but you are really crooked, that it's all leading somewhere for us, that it is possible to be on someone's hook and to have someone on your own hook and to let them go, that last words are important, and so many other lessons. Honestly, HIMYM is one of my favorite shows because of the lasting impact it's had on me.   I keep watching and love the show because it is the perfect love story about how even though Ted had so many women he remembers every detail to the T and found his one true love. All the characters are awesome! Love HIMYM  I personally love the show because I really identify with the characters, especially Marshall and Ted. The characters were obviously written to be relatable, but I find myself reminiscing about similar situations or emotional rides they go on in the show that I to have experienced. Then there's the little things, like the love of Star Wars, having a small, but right group of friends, and the pursuit of "the one" encompass the life of a college student looking to the future.     I am Ted! Right down to the quirky jokes to being a head over heels romantic. It is nice to sympathize and relate to a character so easily. Also there are morals in the story that have helped me through my high school life. Plus its funny as hell.  I am Ted! Right down to the quirky jokes to being a head over heels romantic. It is nice to sympathize and relate to a character so easily. Also there are morals in the story that have helped me through my high school life. Plus its funny as hell.  Do you have red cowboy boots as well? Haha. I wish!!! I would totally pull them off!   Lately, I've been pretty disenchanted with HIMYM.  I started watching in between seasons 2 and 3, and have kept up with it for the last 5-6 years.  Lately, it's just been feeling pretty generally lackluster, and I feel it has jumped the shark.

Then we got to The Robin.  The Robin reminded me, not only why I watched in the first place, but why I continue to watch it today.  It's a comedy that I can relate to.  I've chased the girl I thought was the one, and have been shot down.  I've been the guy who thought I'd be single forever, until one person changed that for me.  I've struggled with the loss of a beloved family member.  I watch it, and I see these deep emotional scenes, and I feel things that I rarely feel in real life.  Then I see scenes like The Robin, and I feel like everything will work out.

Sure it's only television, but it just helps me understand, and have a little bit more hope in, this crazy world we're all a part of.  HIMYM means "How I Met Your Mother" to me.  Acronyms; read up on them.</snippet></document><document><title>Sneak Peek for P.S. I Love You</title><url>http://youtube.com/watch?v=EQ_y19bGEi4</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>HIMYM renewed for 9th and final season will reveal mother!</title><url>http://www.thewrap.com/tv/column-post/how-i-met-your-mother-gets-final-season-and-reveals-mother-75416</url><snippet>  Why not reveal her this season and expand the relationship next season. Because the show's whole premise isn't about Ted's relationship with the mother, it's about his journey to finally meet her. Yes I get that, and they've had 7 wonderful season to show that. But it would be nice to give some screen time to the relationship as well. I'm sure they will but probably not a whole season. I think they're going to end with Ted's final relationship being perfect. To me, that's how they always describe the mother in comparison to all the other girls he has dated. In past seasons, they spend so much time on a relationship because they take it through all of the stages (first date, happy relationship status, a bit rocky, inevitable breakup). While we always knew how all Ted's past relationships would end (with a breakup), his journey through them is what was important. I think we will get to know the mother but I think they will represent that relationship as idyllic and thus, dedicate less screen time to it than they have done with past relationships.  Maybe once Ted finally meets the mother, there is like a quick montage of their whole life together (but it has to be very short, less than 10 seconds) and they flash through his eyes(like the time he was hit by a cab). Then he finally goes and talks to her. A little something-something to appease the fans? Yes I get that, and they've had 7 wonderful season to show that. But it would be nice to give some screen time to the relationship as well. Because the show's whole premise isn't about Ted's relationship with the mother, it's about his journey to finally meet her. Given 8 years of this teasing I think we can give them a pass on tinkering with the formula for one last season. As someone who just started watching this on netflix a few months ago I'm not sure I can allow that. As someone who just started watching this on netflix a few months ago I'm not sure I can allow that. Why not reveal her this season and expand the relationship next season. Why not reveal her this season and expand the relationship next season. For the same reason that they didn't show 30 minutes of Bruce Wayne and Selina Kyle living happily in Florence at the end of The Dark Knight Rises.   Huh? You can't just throw out any film/tv show that had somewhat of a romantic interest attached. Batman was not a rom-com sitcom.  It's called "dramatic tension" and it exists in every TV show, every film, every novel and every piece of music that can be enjoyed.  This is really stuff you should have learned in fourth grade English.  

- Rising action.
- Climax. 
- Resolution.

There's no fourth "continue watching after the tension has been resolved" step.  Not in a hollywood movie.  Not in Bohemian Rhapsody.  Not in a sitcom.  

Post-resolution stories are masturbation.  If you're interested pointless, boring, plotless entertainment, read fan-fiction.   It's called "dramatic tension" and it exists in every TV show, every film, every novel and every piece of music that can be enjoyed.  This is really stuff you should have learned in fourth grade English.  

- Rising action.
- Climax. 
- Resolution.

There's no fourth "continue watching after the tension has been resolved" step.  Not in a hollywood movie.  Not in Bohemian Rhapsody.  Not in a sitcom.  

Post-resolution stories are masturbation.  If you're interested pointless, boring, plotless entertainment, read fan-fiction.   Yes, thank you for your condescending reply. However, in the case of HIMYM, I feel it would add more to the show, to not only show the meeting, but the actual development of the relationship. IMHO. Just because you want vicarious gratification doesn't mean it's a good story. It's as if some fans think they're "owed" seeing Ted and Mother together after all this time. 

I'd prefer a good story. And just because you don't want to see it, doesn't mean your version is better. Last time I checked what makes a story good or bad is a matter of opinion. Check again.  The Godfather is a better movie than Manos: The Hands of Fate.  Period.  There's a reason one scores 100 points more than the other on RottenTomatoes, and it's not because every single critic *randomly happened* to share the same opinion.

Things like character development, and dramatic tension *matter.* I'm not saying those things don't matter, but once again you're proving me right, movies are based off of opinions. There are a ton of classic movies that I like, that other people can't stand. Does that make them wrong? No, because it's their opinion. You're trying to argue with things like story arch, dramatic tension, character development, etc..., but there are a ton of bad movies that also contain these elements. Yes, thank you for your condescending reply. However, in the case of HIMYM, I feel it would add more to the show, to not only show the meeting, but the actual development of the relationship. IMHO. &amp;gt;I feel it would add more to the show

Why?

I mean, I can understand why you *want* to see it.  At one point in time, I wanted to see a 20 minute lightsaber fight.  Then Star Wars, Episode III came out, and the 20 minute lightsaber fight was the most boring, mindless, indulgent, meaningless thing I'd ever witnessed.  It served no purpose other than the fact that it appealed to people who wanted to see shiny things moving fast.  

HIMYM is about Ted's emotional journey.  It's about his transformation from some naive guy who thinks that a relationship will solve all of his problems into the man who learns to love his own life, and in so doing, finally draws people to him instead of repelling them from him.  Then, at the end of that journey, when he finally learns that he can't get happiness from a relationship, he gets to meet the woman he'll one day marry.  

What do you think an extra nine months showing them living happily ever after will add to the story?  WAIT. SO WE WONT FIND OUT THIS SEASON? WAIT. SO WE WONT FIND OUT THIS SEASON? surely he gets to barney and robins wedding by around may, which is when the season will be getting to the end. so by past seasons, the last shot of this season will be the image looking at ted from behind the mother playing the bass at the wedding. I WILL BEAT A NIGGA DOWN IF THAT HAPPENS WAIT. SO WE WONT FIND OUT THIS SEASON? WAIT. SO WE WONT FIND OUT THIS SEASON?  I'm sorry, but it should've ended last season. The writing has been getting worse (in my opinion) and more or less they're just rehashing old storylines at this point. What's more, Ted is going to meet the mother in ~May-June 2014 and then virtually instantly knock her up so they can have their kid by something-2015.

I love(d) this show, but ever since season 8 started, I find myself thinking "Why am I still watching this?" every time, and that's a shame, I don't want to think that, I want to enjoy and cherish the episodes. he meets her May 25th, 2013. He does? Did I miss something completely obvious somewhere? You haven't been paying much attention to this current season, have you? Apparently not. :) Basically, we know the event they meet and the day that event is. Being vague to keep from possible spoilers. :) Oh, there's an actual date? I must've missed that. Watch the "Band or DJ?" Episode. It'll work itself out. He does? Did I miss something completely obvious somewhere? I'm sorry, but it should've ended last season. The writing has been getting worse (in my opinion) and more or less they're just rehashing old storylines at this point. What's more, Ted is going to meet the mother in ~May-June 2014 and then virtually instantly knock her up so they can have their kid by something-2015.

I love(d) this show, but ever since season 8 started, I find myself thinking "Why am I still watching this?" every time, and that's a shame, I don't want to think that, I want to enjoy and cherish the episodes. I thought S7 was pretty stale in the second half. It was almost like a chore "ugh, I have to watch new episode". I could literaly predict the plot for each episode some 4 min in. i thought it went downhill fast after S4. I agree, it want downhill, but it went from fantastic, to pretty good, at s5. By S6 it went to pretty okay, S7 meh and s8 is bleh. I always thought Series 5 was the worst. Series 6 was brilliant and series 7 was alright. Series 8 started slow but is now pretty good. THANK GOD Somebody feels teh same way as I do about Season 5. I think that season basically threw everything off. It's like they shot their load too early with Barney and Robin, realized it, then broke them up and then basically with that breakup, the heart of the show seemed to disappear. 

Season 6 brought the heart back, but there were still remnants of Season 5 in there but most of it was done well. Season 7 wasn't bad but it wasn't great. This season started out slow and crappy but has really built up to be kind of good. I agree, it want downhill, but it went from fantastic, to pretty good, at s5. By S6 it went to pretty okay, S7 meh and s8 is bleh. i consider S5 to be the absolutely low-point of the series thus far.  the other seasons have had their moments but side-by-side, pound-for-pound the last 4 con't even compare to the first 4.   I'm sorry, but it should've ended last season. The writing has been getting worse (in my opinion) and more or less they're just rehashing old storylines at this point. What's more, Ted is going to meet the mother in ~May-June 2014 and then virtually instantly knock her up so they can have their kid by something-2015.

I love(d) this show, but ever since season 8 started, I find myself thinking "Why am I still watching this?" every time, and that's a shame, I don't want to think that, I want to enjoy and cherish the episodes. I'm sorry, but it should've ended last season. The writing has been getting worse (in my opinion) and more or less they're just rehashing old storylines at this point. What's more, Ted is going to meet the mother in ~May-June 2014 and then virtually instantly knock her up so they can have their kid by something-2015.

I love(d) this show, but ever since season 8 started, I find myself thinking "Why am I still watching this?" every time, and that's a shame, I don't want to think that, I want to enjoy and cherish the episodes.  If the mother is going to be revealed in season 9, how are they going to end season 8? I can't take anymore cliffhangers. Probably end with Barney and Robin's wedding... then do the typical "show no face pan away" shot as Ted introduces himself to her... my best guess "I think I'm in love with you."

*roll credits* Probably end with Barney and Robin's wedding... then do the typical "show no face pan away" shot as Ted introduces himself to her... my best guess [spoiler](/s "the only thing is she is the bass player at the wedding.") [spoiler] (/s "Too bad that's not her.") huh? What did I miss? Nothing... I was just making a joke. Nothing... I was just making a joke. booooooooooo I"m sorry I can't imagine MC Clap Yo Handz saying booooooooooo Probably end with Barney and Robin's wedding... then do the typical "show no face pan away" shot as Ted introduces himself to her... my best guess If the mother is going to be revealed in season 9, how are they going to end season 8? I can't take anymore cliffhangers. Praying it's the end of season cliffhanger and we meet her in the season 9 premier.  Praying it's the end of season cliffhanger and we meet her in the season 9 premier.   Let me get this strait. Ted meets the mother on May 25, but the season finale will be May 13. Season 9 will start in September, 4 months later. Will the beginning of season 9 just be a bunch of flashbacks? Is all of season 9 with him and the mother? I don't think that the show is matching up with real time, but I could be wrong. So just because the season premieres in September doesn't mean that the season's story will begin in September. They have matched up with real time until now, reasonably at least.  Aside from some delays in certain seasons, September has been September, and so on. They account for summer months differently though.  I recall the first episode of Season 2 picked up right where Season 1 left off at the beginning of summer 2006.  They also told the story of summer 2011 during the last episode of season 6.  So it's not unheard of for them to account for what happened between seasons either during the first or last episodes of a season.  Let me get this strait. Ted meets the mother on May 25, but the season finale will be May 13. Season 9 will start in September, 4 months later. Will the beginning of season 9 just be a bunch of flashbacks? Is all of season 9 with him and the mother? My theory: Ted first *sees* her at the wedding on May 25 (which may or may not happen in the season finale). But given that she stands next to him at the train station and they're not talking right away, it would seem they didn't actually "meet" at the wedding. Then he realizes he loves her slightly too late and spends a whole season tracking her down.

[Sound familiar](http://how-i-met-your-mother.wikia.com/wiki/Victoria)? Given how many plot lines have been recycled lately, I wouldn't be surprised if this happens.  Let me get this strait. Ted meets the mother on May 25, but the season finale will be May 13. Season 9 will start in September, 4 months later. Will the beginning of season 9 just be a bunch of flashbacks? Is all of season 9 with him and the mother?  I hate to ruin the surprise .. but it's me. I hate to ruin the surprise .. but it's me. Your arm does look similar...

 CONFIRMED! This is the mother! Wha- .. How have you seen my arm?! :|  I'm sorry, but at this point, no matter who she is, there is no way she can live up to the hype.  This show stopped being How I Met Your Mother and became How Your Uncle Barney is Awesome a long time ago. I want to know what he's doing for a living!
  I really hope Season 9 will be ''How I Married/Banged Your Mother''.  I'm pretty sure one of those has already been made.  And I think one might be a porno. As if marriage could ever be a porno. Right guys? The wedding is not being delayed.  In the flash forward Ted talks to Cindy about how the band cancelled at the last minute, Cindy suggests the Mother's band and even COMMENTS on the fact that they just had a gig cancel so they would be free "this weekend."  It's happening in May. Everyone calm down.  

What I think will happen is the season finale will focus on all the shit that makes Barney and Robins wedding have some hitches, as Ted mentions in the flash forward in the Farhampton episode.  It will end with Ted at the bus stop in the rain, he begins to meet the mother and right before her face gets revealed, we get the cliff hanger.  Episode one picks up where we left off and we actually get to know her and understand why we should be happy for Ted. Who cares if the show isn't so much about how Ted meets the mother but dates her?  Would fans really be happy with seeing the mother for a split second and the series ends?  I want to get to know her at least a little!

Bays and Thomas would be DUMB to stretch the next four months over a season and a half. I think even they know better  Spoiler: Barney goes Transgender.   Barney and Robin's wedding is May 25, 2013: **4 months from now**.  Ted meets the mother that night at Farhampton train station.

Since the story Future Ted is telling follows present time, there are only two possible ways season 9 can exist:

* The mother's face isn't revealed until s09e01 and the show becomes *How I Dated Your Mother*.  I feel this is acceptible.
* The wedding gets pushed back.  This will infuriate the fans, and all but guarantees at least some, if not all, of season 9 is meaningless filler.

Bays and Thomas will make themselves into giant piles of confetti if they push the wedding back.  We've been waiting for it since s06e01... that's 3 bagpiping years. In the episode on 8/13 about the band or DJ, at the end they show Ted at the reception of the wedding and Robin dancing with her Father.  So they pretty clearly says they got married.

I would be that it is the first one.  We will find out in the early in season 9 who the mother is, and then the time spent dating her will be the season.  After all "How I met your mother?" does have to me just the first meeting, the dating seems like it should be involved.

Either way, I am glad they are putting a hard stop and giving us some closure on the series.  If there happens to be some sort of spin-off, which I could see, I'd be ok with that. There is no time stamp on that wedding scene. You are correct there.

We know it is at least Robin's because of the dance and in the beginning of the season he sees the base player at the train station.  I would like to think they aren't going to give us the run around like most TV shows and follow through with the Robin/Barney wedding, which would be on the date above. The only certainly definitive date we know of are the "4 months later" scene on the subway.  Every other mention of a wedding date is up in the air and manipulable by the writers:

The train station scene is still "a little ways down the road"

No time stamp on the wedding scene where Ted sees the bass player
Although Barney and Robin announced the date of their wedding, the writers could always put in a reason to push it back a year 

The "4 months later" subway scene does happen, but that doesn't definitively prove the wedding is still later that week; again, it could be written back a year

My only point is, the writers have left out solid information about the date of the wedding, so it may or may not happen at the end of this season I WILL STAB A CANADIAN IF THIS HAPPENS Pipe down, Hoosier. *Hoser.


A Hooiser is someone from the state of Indiana.  The only certainly definitive date we know of are the "4 months later" scene on the subway.  Every other mention of a wedding date is up in the air and manipulable by the writers:

The train station scene is still "a little ways down the road"

No time stamp on the wedding scene where Ted sees the bass player
Although Barney and Robin announced the date of their wedding, the writers could always put in a reason to push it back a year 

The "4 months later" subway scene does happen, but that doesn't definitively prove the wedding is still later that week; again, it could be written back a year

My only point is, the writers have left out solid information about the date of the wedding, so it may or may not happen at the end of this season Barney and Robin's wedding is May 25, 2013: **4 months from now**.  Ted meets the mother that night at Farhampton train station.

Since the story Future Ted is telling follows present time, there are only two possible ways season 9 can exist:

* The mother's face isn't revealed until s09e01 and the show becomes *How I Dated Your Mother*.  I feel this is acceptible.
* The wedding gets pushed back.  This will infuriate the fans, and all but guarantees at least some, if not all, of season 9 is meaningless filler.

Bays and Thomas will make themselves into giant piles of confetti if they push the wedding back.  We've been waiting for it since s06e01... that's 3 bagpiping years. Barney and Robin's wedding is May 25, 2013: **4 months from now**.  Ted meets the mother that night at Farhampton train station.

Since the story Future Ted is telling follows present time, there are only two possible ways season 9 can exist:

* The mother's face isn't revealed until s09e01 and the show becomes *How I Dated Your Mother*.  I feel this is acceptible.
* The wedding gets pushed back.  This will infuriate the fans, and all but guarantees at least some, if not all, of season 9 is meaningless filler.

Bays and Thomas will make themselves into giant piles of confetti if they push the wedding back.  We've been waiting for it since s06e01... that's 3 bagpiping years. Barney and Robin's wedding is May 25, 2013: **4 months from now**.  Ted meets the mother that night at Farhampton train station.

Since the story Future Ted is telling follows present time, there are only two possible ways season 9 can exist:

* The mother's face isn't revealed until s09e01 and the show becomes *How I Dated Your Mother*.  I feel this is acceptible.
* The wedding gets pushed back.  This will infuriate the fans, and all but guarantees at least some, if not all, of season 9 is meaningless filler.

Bays and Thomas will make themselves into giant piles of confetti if they push the wedding back.  We've been waiting for it since s06e01... that's 3 bagpiping years.   Great, this means she'll be introduced in the season finale this spring. we now have a year to actually get to like her after our hearts get crushed with disappointment. Where did you read that? The article seemed to say that we won't meet her until sometime next season, presumably at the end.   To me the article didn't read as though someone explicitly said that she would be revealed next season. I can't imagine how they could drag it out much longer if she isn't at least introduced in this season's finale.    Do you guys think that they'll have multiple potential mothers that he meets at the wedding, and that season 9 will be all about trying to figure out which one it is?  In a last minute mixup, the entire band is bassists.    [Let's celebrate!](http://data.whicdn.com/images/50447869/tumblr_leqiabtW581qg83bjo1_500_large.gif_) You forgot your closing bracket champ. Thanks! It's just...I guess I was just really excited.     The only way that this can work is if it's a shortened season. Like 10 episodes or something. I can't see them going a full 24 and actually making it work.  Don't ever underestimate the producer's abilty to add filler episodes. They will make it work as long as the money keeps flowing.  So why bother watching the rest of season 8? It just seems like a fucking waste of time. WRAP THE SHOW UP ALREADY GOD DAMMIT.            "Hey guys, Barney and Robin have delayed their wedding for a year due to some bullshit we'll explain with a throwaway line, now have a strung out arc about Lily having post partum and Ted having another hot/crazy girlfriend! Love, "Cocktease" Carter &amp;amp; Bays"  So if their wedding is at the end of this season, and he meets her AFTER their wedding, and WE meet her at the end of next season, you're telling me they're going to stretch a whole season of just Ted sitting on a bench until she walks up?

I call craps. doesn't seem like too much of a stretch at this point.   NO! Fuck this, I am done. I am so done.</snippet></document><document><title>I find this to be the best way to approach my 18 year little brother when he's engrossed in video games or calculus homework.</title><url>http://imgur.com/Df0RtsS.jpg</url><snippet /></document><document><title>I lost two friends and a girlfriend because of this</title><url>http://imgur.com/2dJjgvd</url><snippet>  Wait did you at least show it to them first? i showed it to my girlfriend and she hated it. as for friends, nope.
    </snippet></document><document><title>Guess what kids..</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/9dV5AWp.png</url><snippet>     god dammit, i wanted to know this season  Lily's hands?   Came here just to say Schmoseby looks amazing in that suit.</snippet></document><document><title>I know they mean nothing by it, but every time my coworkers call me honey, this is how I hear it...</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/sThs1.gif</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>What they all looked like young.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/wDcxlwL.jpg</url><snippet>  Josh looks exactly the same.  And the manliest, strangely.  I mean are all the pictures at the same age? He seems older than the rest. If they all are the same age that just means he went through puberty sooner.  Cobie's looks like it's a highschool photo; same with Segal's. That's definitely NPH's Doogie days so ...wow, he was 16 in that photo. Pretty sure that's 14 year old Alison from My tepmother is an Alien. And with that jaw, I would imagine Ratner's like 20 or so? Yeah I feel like everyone else's are yearbook pictures or from acting as a child like you mentioned but Josh's looks like it's a head-shot. It doesn't look like he started acting until his early-mid twenties so he's probably almost/at least 10 years older than everyone else.  According to google, Cobie is the youngest in the cast at 30.  Jason is in his early 30's, and the rest are in their late 30's.  Neil Patrick Harris is the oldest at 39. I don't mean how old they are now, I mean how old they are in the pictures. like dudemann said Alyson's picture is from "My Stepmother is an Alien" when she was 14, NPH's from Doogie Howser when he was about 16, Cobie and Jason's both look like they're high school yearbook pictures which would make them 14-18 but Josh's looks like a head-shot an actor would submit with their resume. Given Josh's first credited acting job was when he was 26 even if this was he first he's probably at least 24 or so in the picture, so 6-10 years old than the others are in their picture.  Ah, gotcha.  I thought you were talking about their actual ages.  I never understood why they can't just pull everyone's senior yearbook photo for consistency when doing these comparisons.  It's ridiculous to see an adult Radnor headshot next to Cobie's yearbook photo as though they were the same thing. Yeah, that would make the most sense, and is probably what would happen if this was made by a journalist for a magazine or CBS for a promo or something but I'm pretty sure this was just made by someone bored on the internet who googled "Young.. alyson hannigan, josh radnor etc" and then stuck them all together to make a jpeg. It's not like the average can, or will find out where they went to school and dig up their old yearbooks. I mean are all the pictures at the same age? He seems older than the rest. If they all are the same age that just means he went through puberty sooner.  And the manliest, strangely.  Josh looks exactly the same.  Josh looks exactly the same.   Alyson Hannigan is NEVER not hot. Ahh...you apparently stopped watching the show after season 5. Season 7, episode 3, Lily's boobs. Need I say more? Boobs do not compensate for a face that used to have incredibly cute perkiness, but is now sort of....saggy? Is that the word? I agree she isn't as hot, BUT I hypothesize that they are using make-up to make it look like she is going through the strains of, first pregnancy, then have to raise a kid (not to mention teaching kindergarten). That kind of stress can visibly droop a person's face and make someone appear less attractive. I think the writers/make-up artists are trying to convey that. Boobs do not compensate for a face that used to have incredibly cute perkiness, but is now sort of....saggy? Is that the word? Boobs do not compensate for a face that used to have incredibly cute perkiness, but is now sort of....saggy? Is that the word? I bet your face is perfectly perky, then! Why don't you go on TV and show us how it is to be hot all the time. Ahh...you apparently stopped watching the show after season 5. This comment is gross. Who cares; she's still a funny, beautiful, talented actress. Sorry she doesn't fit in your box of youthful hotness, I'm sure she loses sleep at night about that. Alyson Hannigan is NEVER not hot. she looks fantastic in this pic. She also looks 12. Not that I'm arguing anyone, just something to keep in mind. Honestly she doesn't look twelve to me here or maybe its becase i haven't slept yet and im a bit delusional. But i was only complimenting her lol. She also looks 12. Not that I'm arguing anyone, just something to keep in mind. I'm assuming you think she looks 12 because you're a bit older. She looks at least 16-18 to me, but I'm 24 and still see high schoolers all of the time.  I'm assuming you think she looks 12 because you're a bit older. She looks at least 16-18 to me, but I'm 24 and still see high schoolers all of the time.  How's it going, Swarles? I'm assuming you think she looks 12 because you're a bit older. She looks at least 16-18 to me, but I'm 24 and still see high schoolers all of the time.  Alyson Hannigan is NEVER not hot. [I beg to differ](http://i.imgur.com/A6SWA.jpg)

I do think that she is hot about 98% of the time though I still think she still looks cute here.  You keep on chasin them chubbies, sir. [I beg to differ](http://i.imgur.com/A6SWA.jpg)

I do think that she is hot about 98% of the time though [I beg to differ](http://i.imgur.com/A6SWA.jpg)

I do think that she is hot about 98% of the time though Alyson Hannigan is NEVER not hot. Alyson Hannigan is NEVER not hot. Apparently you didn't see American Pie. Are you saying she wasn't hot in American Pie? Not the first one. Shannon Elizabeth takes the cake for that movie. Not the first one. Shannon Elizabeth takes the cake for that movie. While Shannon Elizabeth is definitely awesome in that regard, I'd still go with Alyson After seeing Jay &amp;amp; Silent Bob Strike Back, I've gotta go with Shannon Elizabeth.  Cobie Smulders looks a bit like Milly from Freaks and Geeks.  Radnor is DEFINITELY not the same age as the rest in these pictures.  Yeah NPH looks like he is 8 years old, still classy as fuck though, really wish he was adjusting that tie with his hand...  Barney has been wearing a tie since he was six years old hahaha He had to be professional since he worked at the hospital Dirty sneakers aside  ....... how does Ted not age? He's saving his regeneration energy for when he transforms into Bob Saget. Ted is the Doctor?

So that explains why he's spent so long looking for a 'companion'.

/r/ShittyFanTheories Ted is the doctor after he loses Amy and Rory in New York and starts looking for a new companion because it's dangerous to travel alone. It all makes sense now He's saving his regeneration energy for when he transforms into Bob Saget. ....... how does Ted not age?  Cobie Smulders had a successful puberty!      This says it's from 9Gag on the left side.... So? they're supposed to steal content from reddit, not the other way around. reddit is so but hurt about all this. Of course we're butthurt. Because we complain how they steal and don't give us credit. Obviously 9GAG made that. And I see no other credit than that.  Do you pirate music? What's that matter.  This is about 9gag stealing from reddit. And resdit stealing from 9gag. It's the same thing.  I really don't care when someone makes silly content like rage comics and publishes to one website and someone else takes it and shares it on another website. Why does it matter at all? If you pirate music, even that is a bigger deal that this.

This reddit vs 9gag thing is so fucking childish. Why do you care?                 "My balls didn't drop until I was 16"- NPH          Alyson is the HOT here     Damn, Cobie still looked good Really? WTF is up with her lip!? 
She is not very pretty in this photo! 

Then again.. I don't even think she is hot now but that's just opinions. She has her moments though. It could be the picture but yeah, her lips look a bit different. That being said, she is a good looking lady, in my opinion. I wouldn't call her a lady in this picture. Too young!     Sorry for the 9gag label. </snippet></document><document><title>No, no, no, no, no, no...</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GLEW3V3QW1I&amp;amp;t=50s</url><snippet> </snippet></document></searchresult>