<searchresult><twoxchromosomes /><document><title>Dumped. Ex has a new squeeze. Would love some support, thank you in advance.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18vmgs/dumped_ex_has_a_new_squeeze_would_love_some/</url><snippet>Ahhhhh. I know this isn't the subreddit for this and to those annoyed, I am sorry. 

I just need to get this out right now. I got dumped with no warning 6 months ago, while on the cusp of finally getting out of a depressive episode. No warning, no discussion, no previous conversations about anything leading up to it. 

I've beat my own drum since then, working on myself, going to counselling, engaging in my interests in epic proportions, exploring an entrepreneurial path. Convincing myself with logic and reason that he was not the man for me even though I loved him most deeply when he decided to end things. I've tried to find a balance between allowing myself to miss him and understanding that it's over but in the back of my mind there is still this nagging, persistant notion that he was "the one" for me. Yes, I know this is silly but it's the most accurate description of the longing I still feel for him sometimes. 

I am being strong, venturing out on my own path but it is so goddamn hard to be hit with this. Hit with the fact that he is dating a woman who is successful, positive and strong. A leader. All those qualities that I lost in the depression. All those qualities that I am trying so hard to regain and re-establish. All those things I want to be and have always wanted to be. I know it's his right to pursue happiness in whatever way he sees fit but faaaaahhhhhhhk this feels shitty. 

I feel like I didn't get there fast enough. I feel like he upgraded to a better model. I feel discarded and unworthy. I understand these are just feelings. 

Thanks so much for reading.    </snippet></document><document><title>Help! My subconscious is a prude and it's making me seriously frustrated</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18vbbg/help_my_subconscious_is_a_prude_and_its_making_me/</url><snippet>Throwaway because this is kind of embarrasing and also really weird,, but I don't have anyone I can talk to about these things.

As a background, I was raised in a very conservative household which did give me good a sex education, but only as preparation for marriage. The underlying assumption was that abstinence until marriage is the only way to go. I don't identify as a conservative, and although I am not married, I'm not a virgin either.

The problem is, I can't have sexy dreams. Whenever I'm dreaming I'm hooking up with someone, something always happens in my dream to interrupt just as we're getting down to it. It's usually a family member barging in at the wrong moment and then hanging around for a while until the mood is dead. The worst part is that in most of these dreams, I'm aware I'm dreaming, so I'll just attempt to have the dream again, only to be interrupted once more.

What makes it even more frustrating is that I haven't had sex for 2 years, and I'm starting to get a little frustrated. I also haven't gotten the hang of masturbating, and my dreams are really the only sexual outlet I have.

I don't need to understand why this happens. It's textbook psychology. But I was wondering if anyone around here has had the same experiences? If so, how did you deal with your own subconscious?  I was raised in a very similar atmosphere to yours, but am a virgin.  Let me tell you, I have had all of three sexy dreams in my life, and two were interrupted by someone knocking on the door in the dream, and the other I woke up from when it was just getting good.  And since I don't know how to make myself have sexy dreams (not even about the man I'm dating who is wonderful, sexy, and ardent), I figured masturbation works just as well.  So get ye to the adult superstore/online catalogue and do some researching, or look at porn or whatever turns you on, and get it done.
Girlbrofist bump.  1 word.  hitachi.  I know they make little things like bullet vibrators that look like other stuff.  Maybe that could fly under the radar? Hmm I'll have to look into that. Thanks!  </snippet></document><document><title>Quote of the Day: The baby is &#8220;the largest organ in the body&#8221;</title><url>http://feministing.com/2013/02/19/quote-of-the-day-the-baby-is-the-largest-organ-in-the-body/</url><snippet>  A baby is now a woman's organ? That seems like a comparison they don't want to draw. I can remove organs from my body if they interfere with my quality of life, right? Isn't that why people get their gall bladder, appendices, wisdom teeth, tonsils, and adenoids removed? Exactly my first thought. Is it a person with rights or is it basically a kidney? Y'all can't have it both ways!  A baby is now a woman's organ? That seems like a comparison they don't want to draw. I can remove organs from my body if they interfere with my quality of life, right? Isn't that why people get their gall bladder, appendices, wisdom teeth, tonsils, and adenoids removed? A baby is now a woman's organ? That seems like a comparison they don't want to draw. I can remove organs from my body if they interfere with my quality of life, right? Isn't that why people get their gall bladder, appendices, wisdom teeth, tonsils, and adenoids removed? I wasn't aware that teeth were organs.  I wasn't aware that teeth were organs.  A baby is now a woman's organ? That seems like a comparison they don't want to draw. I can remove organs from my body if they interfere with my quality of life, right? Isn't that why people get their gall bladder, appendices, wisdom teeth, tonsils, and adenoids removed? [deleted]    Lol!!! Thanks to the author for making this horrible horrible attack on women funny for a moment. That was a great read. 

But now back to reality: uuuugh fuck that bitch!! I'm SO DAMN TIRED of having to fight for the rights we've already won! The right to * gasp * have control over my own body!   </snippet></document><document><title>Characteristics of Narcissistic Mothers</title><url>http://parrishmiller.com/narcissists.html</url><snippet>   Yup, that fits my dad to a "t"..Real asshole he was.&amp;amp;#3232;\_&amp;amp;#3232; Yeah, not that the article was wrong, but I'm not sure why it was narcissistic "mothers" rather than "parents." Yeah, not that the article was wrong, but I'm not sure why it was narcissistic "mothers" rather than "parents." Yeah, not that the article was wrong, but I'm not sure why it was narcissistic "mothers" rather than "parents."  </snippet></document><document><title>Tiger Eyes - First Judy Blume book to be adapted into a movie</title><url>http://www.tigereyesfilm.com/</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Aussie tampon tax. Apparently needing feminine hygiene products is a "luxury"</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18t38u/aussie_tampon_tax_apparently_needing_feminine/</url><snippet>So some of you may or may not know that Australia has a GST on tampons and other feminine hygiene products because they're considered a "luxury". Basically, if you're a woman of childbearing age and you aren't knocked up, you're gonna be taxed an extra 10% on tampons or pads.

As a 25 year old childfree Australian woman, I'm paying a tax on a necessity that is an inevitable byproduct of how I've chosen to not use my reproductive system until I hit menopause or this tax is removed. I, along with nearly 33,000 other people, see this as wrong. If you have a moment, please sign this petition to try and have the tax removed. http://www.change.org/en-AU/petitions/axe-the-tampontax-bloodyoutrage

Thanks for your time.  Here in the US 40 OBs cost $7.99 plus 7% sales tax, how does that compare to your prices?

That is an outrage, but there was (horrible) life before tampons.  My great grandma used rags pinned to her undies that she then *rewashed and reused* due to grinding poverty. I'm sure there are plenty of women the world over who do the same thing today.  And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do. (Kidding.)

 Anyway, I guess I'm counting my blessings. if the push to go back to reusable nappies for babies is good enough for us then maybe we should start doing that again too, absorbent cotton cloth liners that you wash and reuse. Sounds like a good niche market to me.  There's actually a few companies that make these.

http://www.newmoonpads.com/home.html if the push to go back to reusable nappies for babies is good enough for us then maybe we should start doing that again too, absorbent cotton cloth liners that you wash and reuse. Sounds like a good niche market to me.  lunapads.com  These pads are the most versatile pads I've ever used, and I've used TONS of cotton pads. Trust me. These are the ones. Like them on facebook and sometimes there are coupons, etc., sample pack offers. I'm partial to them, too, because I won their 'name this fabric' contest, and the strawberry print one is called 'Strawberry Jammin', my idea. :3

And for reusable tampon-alternatives, this cup http://www.lunette.com/ has entirely changed my period. I can do yoga every day of the month now! Good luck on your green period search!  oh yuck the strawberry jam one. oh gross. "yeah whhen i take this off it's gonna look like strawberry jam."

it'd be like naming a diaper brand "chunky cocoa pants" lunapads.com  These pads are the most versatile pads I've ever used, and I've used TONS of cotton pads. Trust me. These are the ones. Like them on facebook and sometimes there are coupons, etc., sample pack offers. I'm partial to them, too, because I won their 'name this fabric' contest, and the strawberry print one is called 'Strawberry Jammin', my idea. :3

And for reusable tampon-alternatives, this cup http://www.lunette.com/ has entirely changed my period. I can do yoga every day of the month now! Good luck on your green period search!  These sound really cool! thanks for the awesome link  lunapads.com  These pads are the most versatile pads I've ever used, and I've used TONS of cotton pads. Trust me. These are the ones. Like them on facebook and sometimes there are coupons, etc., sample pack offers. I'm partial to them, too, because I won their 'name this fabric' contest, and the strawberry print one is called 'Strawberry Jammin', my idea. :3

And for reusable tampon-alternatives, this cup http://www.lunette.com/ has entirely changed my period. I can do yoga every day of the month now! Good luck on your green period search!  I like this.

I don't like that they had to make coloured ones. What is the point? Well, cups can become discoloured over time from menstrual fluids, and coloured cups can mask that. Furthermore, the Lunette cup is coloured and is the only FDA approved non-transparent cup.  lunapads.com  These pads are the most versatile pads I've ever used, and I've used TONS of cotton pads. Trust me. These are the ones. Like them on facebook and sometimes there are coupons, etc., sample pack offers. I'm partial to them, too, because I won their 'name this fabric' contest, and the strawberry print one is called 'Strawberry Jammin', my idea. :3

And for reusable tampon-alternatives, this cup http://www.lunette.com/ has entirely changed my period. I can do yoga every day of the month now! Good luck on your green period search!  cheers :D 

I just had a derp though I was like "whats with the moon themed names for these things" urm DUUR Q!  -_- Here in the US 40 OBs cost $7.99 plus 7% sales tax, how does that compare to your prices?

That is an outrage, but there was (horrible) life before tampons.  My great grandma used rags pinned to her undies that she then *rewashed and reused* due to grinding poverty. I'm sure there are plenty of women the world over who do the same thing today.  And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do. (Kidding.)

 Anyway, I guess I'm counting my blessings. &amp;gt; And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do

Buy a Diva Cup and pay the tax only once? You can't just expect it to be perfect for every woman though, especially one who prefers tampons. I would think it would be more perfect for women who prefer tampons (over pads). Women who have difficulty inserting tampons would be unlikely to prefer menstrual cups, I would think. But you can't just say, oh they're the same thing, just switch! Because no woman is the same and preferences are important when it comes to our period hygiene. Cups aren't the end-all to period hygiene, everyone is different. Here in the US 40 OBs cost $7.99 plus 7% sales tax, how does that compare to your prices?

That is an outrage, but there was (horrible) life before tampons.  My great grandma used rags pinned to her undies that she then *rewashed and reused* due to grinding poverty. I'm sure there are plenty of women the world over who do the same thing today.  And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do. (Kidding.)

 Anyway, I guess I'm counting my blessings. quick search on the woolies website (they actually have the price worked out per tampon, for those who like value) it ranges from $0.14 (their own brand) - $0.54 (organic tampons) with the average seeming to be $0.30ish..

so, we pay a bit more than you guys do, but not by too much.. though it does depend on they brand Australian cost of living is also quite a bit higher, which means your wages generally are as well, so it probably balances out to be pretty close to even. Here in the US 40 OBs cost $7.99 plus 7% sales tax, how does that compare to your prices?

That is an outrage, but there was (horrible) life before tampons.  My great grandma used rags pinned to her undies that she then *rewashed and reused* due to grinding poverty. I'm sure there are plenty of women the world over who do the same thing today.  And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do. (Kidding.)

 Anyway, I guess I'm counting my blessings. What? That's sounds horribly overpriced. They're like under 5 euro here (Belgium), price depending slightly on type. Even with the currency difference, that's about a euro more expensive where you are.
Also you can buy pretty much identical O.B. clones from the supermarket for like 2-3 euro. There are no off brand no applicator tampons to be found in the US.  It's possible to find cheaper tampons, but they're all pretty expensive.  I'm surprised that they're about $2 cheaper in Belgium, the stereotype is that consumer goods are always more expensive in Europe.

Thanks for your input! From what I can tell (it's been a while since I've been in the U.S.) some food products are more expensive here, but it's harder to compare because it's actually *different* food products. 

But it seems like whenever I hear anything about feminine hygiene or contraception from the U.S. it's terribly expensive.

For example: the last time I bought Plan B it set me back about 10 euro - which I thought was pricey, until I heard it could be much more in other countries. What? That's sounds horribly overpriced. They're like under 5 euro here (Belgium), price depending slightly on type. Even with the currency difference, that's about a euro more expensive where you are.
Also you can buy pretty much identical O.B. clones from the supermarket for like 2-3 euro. Here in the US 40 OBs cost $7.99 plus 7% sales tax, how does that compare to your prices?

That is an outrage, but there was (horrible) life before tampons.  My great grandma used rags pinned to her undies that she then *rewashed and reused* due to grinding poverty. I'm sure there are plenty of women the world over who do the same thing today.  And if you really hate the tax, now you know what to do. (Kidding.)

 Anyway, I guess I'm counting my blessings.  To be fair I think it is just a misunderstanding of the word "luxury".   And what about toilet paper, do you want them to exempt that as well? It's also taxed by GST.  Same in the UK, on all feminine hygiene products. I often wonder if I went and sat on Mr Cameron's lap during my period would he still think pads and tampons a luxury? I have a vague memory of them taking the VAT off for about a month or 2 before deciding - nope, women choose to prevent their uterine blood leaving a trail once a month, luxury item it is!  It's fucking absurd.  

EDIT - I checked and it's charged at 5% instead of the normal 20% (yes my US sisters, we pay 20% sales tax over here!) but it's still classes as non-essential and therefore subject to VAT. I just came here to mention that feminine hygiene products are charged at a lower VAT rate than other products.

Doesn't change the fact that it's bloody ridiculous. Then again, a lot of the VAT rules about what is and isn't a luxury are absurd.  Same in the UK, on all feminine hygiene products. I often wonder if I went and sat on Mr Cameron's lap during my period would he still think pads and tampons a luxury? Its so ridiculous. I can't believe that a necessity for every woman, unless she has a hysterectomy before hitting puberty, is taxed at all. Where is the logic in saying tampons or pads are a luxury? I want to know what they think the alternative is here. And I think it's the same in Sweden (where I currently live), but here they also tax all food as well, rather than just the "luxury" foods as they do in the UK. 

It's only fair if they charge a tissue tax to men, obviously.  What really boggles my mind is the things that don't have a GST. For example, incontinence pads and adult diapers. If you can no longer control your bladder, you don't get taxed for using them and they aren't a luxury, they are a necessity. However, if you have your period, something you can't control or turn on or off without medication or a baby growing inside you, you have to pay an extra 10%.

At least Coles (one of the major supermarkets here in Australia) showed some forethought and understanding by lowering the price of all feminine hygiene products by 10% to offset the GST. The tax is still there but the supermarket now makes less of a profit off tampons and pads.

EDIT: Spelling &amp;gt;At least Coles (one of the major supermarkets here in Australia) showed some forethought and understanding by lowering the price of all feminine hygiene products by 10% to offset the GST. The tax is still there but the supermarket now makes less of a profit off tampons and pads.

Wow, that's fantastic! &amp;lt;3 Coles! And I think it's the same in Sweden (where I currently live), but here they also tax all food as well, rather than just the "luxury" foods as they do in the UK. 

It's only fair if they charge a tissue tax to men, obviously.  condoms? Its so ridiculous. I can't believe that a necessity for every woman, unless she has a hysterectomy before hitting puberty, is taxed at all. Where is the logic in saying tampons or pads are a luxury? I want to know what they think the alternative is here.  There is no "Tampon Tax." There is a 10% sales tax on most products. Some products are exempted, but no product is specifically targeted. By all means campaign to add an essential product to the list of products not covered by the tax. But don't pretend that the evil government targeted you with a tax designed specifically to hurt women. It is an oversight, best adjusted as part of a rational conversation rather than an apoplectic fit of pointless outrage. Isn't that the same as the U.S.? Sales tax on everything except food products? I'm not sure of the law.

EDIT: I'm in CA. I think that varies state-by-state.

I am lucky enough to live in a state that doesn't tax "necessities" which includes food and clothes. I have never bothered to check if tampons fall under the "necessity" category though. I'm going to have to check next time I buy some though, because now I'm really curious. Are all clothes untaxed in your state? 0.0 I'm in California and we pay the normal 8% sales tax on all clothing. Isn't that the same as the U.S.? Sales tax on everything except food products? I'm not sure of the law.

EDIT: I'm in CA. Isn't that the same as the U.S.? Sales tax on everything except food products? I'm not sure of the law.

EDIT: I'm in CA. Isn't that the same as the U.S.? Sales tax on everything except food products? I'm not sure of the law.

EDIT: I'm in CA. There is no "Tampon Tax." There is a 10% sales tax on most products. Some products are exempted, but no product is specifically targeted. By all means campaign to add an essential product to the list of products not covered by the tax. But don't pretend that the evil government targeted you with a tax designed specifically to hurt women. It is an oversight, best adjusted as part of a rational conversation rather than an apoplectic fit of pointless outrage. True, the GST is applied to a lot of products, and tampons are one of the things it shouldn't be applied to.

I'm not the one that came up with the name "tampon tax" and while I am pissed off, I'm not raging. I'm simply spreading this petition and talking to the people that comment on this post to try and get the GST removed from tampons and other feminine hygiene products. You used the phrase "tampon tax" in your title in a very misleading fashion.

I live in Canada, and pretty much every consumer good is taxed save for groceries. This is truly much ado about nothing. In Ontario, the HST is reduced for feminine hygiene products (down to 5% from 13%) basically, the PST is taken off.  Before the HST was implemented, only GST was charged on these.  I'm not sure if the equivalent is done in other provinces though.  In Alberta, where we only pay gst, tampons are taxed. Gst hits everything but groceries. It's nice if one province reduces it, but federally, Canada taxes tampons. You only pay GST on everything?  

...I'm moving to Alberta :D You used the phrase "tampon tax" in your title in a very misleading fashion.

I live in Canada, and pretty much every consumer good is taxed save for groceries. This is truly much ado about nothing. In (I think most of) the US, we aren't taxed for toilet paper, for example. I would call tampons and pads in the same level of hygiene groceries as TP. In (I think most of) the US, we aren't taxed for toilet paper, for example. I would call tampons and pads in the same level of hygiene groceries as TP. That's odd. TP is taxed the regular 7% in Indiana. I don't think it is here in FL. I know its on the list of stuff you can use most government assistance to buy.  True, the GST is applied to a lot of products, and tampons are one of the things it shouldn't be applied to.

I'm not the one that came up with the name "tampon tax" and while I am pissed off, I'm not raging. I'm simply spreading this petition and talking to the people that comment on this post to try and get the GST removed from tampons and other feminine hygiene products. That's fair. I just don't like the tone of the website you linked very much. I hope that tampons and other similar products are exempted from the GST soon. But I don't appreciate the kind of resentment politics chosen by the petitioners as the means of achieving that.  True, the GST is applied to a lot of products, and tampons are one of the things it shouldn't be applied to.

I'm not the one that came up with the name "tampon tax" and while I am pissed off, I'm not raging. I'm simply spreading this petition and talking to the people that comment on this post to try and get the GST removed from tampons and other feminine hygiene products. There is no "Tampon Tax." There is a 10% sales tax on most products. Some products are exempted, but no product is specifically targeted. By all means campaign to add an essential product to the list of products not covered by the tax. But don't pretend that the evil government targeted you with a tax designed specifically to hurt women. It is an oversight, best adjusted as part of a rational conversation rather than an apoplectic fit of pointless outrage.  In my state (in the US), you get taxed on *ALL* items that are not food or otherwise exempt.  That includes ALL pads, tampons, liners, etc.  

I don't see this as some anti-woman tax, or some bullshit 'luxury' tax.  It's called sales tax.  

Can you provide us with some legal information that shows the tax you're talking about is specific to menstrual products and is labeled 'luxury'?   The Australian GST must be charged on all goods and services sold by any company earning over (I think, it's been a couple of years since I lived in Australia) $75000 per annum (those with smaller incomes choose whether to register for GST, but of course if they don't charge it they also can't claim back any GST on goods they've purchased. Realistically, all grocery shops charge GST), except for those considered "essential". Items deemed essential range from proper staples like meat, vegetables, milk and bread to items like coffee or tea. All other groceries are subject to GST. Medical items are generally GST free, and that includes things like condoms, sunscreen and nappies as well as over the counter and prescribed medication. When the right-wing government brought in the highly contentious GST in 2000 tampons and pads were proposed to be included as an essential item, but this was dismissed by the then PM (he actually used the slipperly slope argument - saying that if they were going to make tampons exempt, other "special interest groups" would then seek exemption for other products!), so they are they are therefore subject to the tax. 

What it boils down to is that they're being called a luxury item as they're not considered an essential product under the Goods and Services Tax Act.  The Australian GST must be charged on all goods and services sold by any company earning over (I think, it's been a couple of years since I lived in Australia) $75000 per annum (those with smaller incomes choose whether to register for GST, but of course if they don't charge it they also can't claim back any GST on goods they've purchased. Realistically, all grocery shops charge GST), except for those considered "essential". Items deemed essential range from proper staples like meat, vegetables, milk and bread to items like coffee or tea. All other groceries are subject to GST. Medical items are generally GST free, and that includes things like condoms, sunscreen and nappies as well as over the counter and prescribed medication. When the right-wing government brought in the highly contentious GST in 2000 tampons and pads were proposed to be included as an essential item, but this was dismissed by the then PM (he actually used the slipperly slope argument - saying that if they were going to make tampons exempt, other "special interest groups" would then seek exemption for other products!), so they are they are therefore subject to the tax. 

What it boils down to is that they're being called a luxury item as they're not considered an essential product under the Goods and Services Tax Act.  The Australian GST must be charged on all goods and services sold by any company earning over (I think, it's been a couple of years since I lived in Australia) $75000 per annum (those with smaller incomes choose whether to register for GST, but of course if they don't charge it they also can't claim back any GST on goods they've purchased. Realistically, all grocery shops charge GST), except for those considered "essential". Items deemed essential range from proper staples like meat, vegetables, milk and bread to items like coffee or tea. All other groceries are subject to GST. Medical items are generally GST free, and that includes things like condoms, sunscreen and nappies as well as over the counter and prescribed medication. When the right-wing government brought in the highly contentious GST in 2000 tampons and pads were proposed to be included as an essential item, but this was dismissed by the then PM (he actually used the slipperly slope argument - saying that if they were going to make tampons exempt, other "special interest groups" would then seek exemption for other products!), so they are they are therefore subject to the tax. 

What it boils down to is that they're being called a luxury item as they're not considered an essential product under the Goods and Services Tax Act.  The Australian GST must be charged on all goods and services sold by any company earning over (I think, it's been a couple of years since I lived in Australia) $75000 per annum (those with smaller incomes choose whether to register for GST, but of course if they don't charge it they also can't claim back any GST on goods they've purchased. Realistically, all grocery shops charge GST), except for those considered "essential". Items deemed essential range from proper staples like meat, vegetables, milk and bread to items like coffee or tea. All other groceries are subject to GST. Medical items are generally GST free, and that includes things like condoms, sunscreen and nappies as well as over the counter and prescribed medication. When the right-wing government brought in the highly contentious GST in 2000 tampons and pads were proposed to be included as an essential item, but this was dismissed by the then PM (he actually used the slipperly slope argument - saying that if they were going to make tampons exempt, other "special interest groups" would then seek exemption for other products!), so they are they are therefore subject to the tax. 

What it boils down to is that they're being called a luxury item as they're not considered an essential product under the Goods and Services Tax Act.  In my state (in the US), you get taxed on *ALL* items that are not food or otherwise exempt.  That includes ALL pads, tampons, liners, etc.  

I don't see this as some anti-woman tax, or some bullshit 'luxury' tax.  It's called sales tax.  

Can you provide us with some legal information that shows the tax you're talking about is specific to menstrual products and is labeled 'luxury'?   &amp;gt;I don't see this as some anti-woman tax, or some bullshit 'luxury' tax. It's called sales tax.

Wait, I'm confused, why would the classification of taxes in *your* country have anything to with what taxes are called in completely different country? I think you missed my point - what happens in my country is obviously unrelated to what happens in Australia.  I was providing context and background - here, that is known as sales tax, not a luxury tax.  If you noticed, I then asked for someone to provide valid information that explains how this 'luxury' tax in Australia works.  

And if you follow the thread, someone with details on the Australian law in question provided a ton of great info that explained it.   You're implying that the Australian tax must just be a "regular" sales tax, based on... nothing, so far as I can tell. You literally said that you don't see this as anti-woman based on something completely unrelated. At best, your comment was a total non sequitur.  And yes, if *you* read the other replies to this thread, you'll see that necessities equivalent to menstrual supplies exempt. If necessities are exempt, it makes perfect logical sense to call the remainder luxuries.  Yeah, when you take it completely out of context and ignore what I was actually saying, sure, I'm implying that.

In *reality*, I was saying *that is how it works where I live*.  I wasn't implying a fucking thing about Australia.  

But go ahead.  Take it all out of context and make snide comments.  Ignore absolutely everything I'm saying with regards to what exactly I was trying to get across and make assumptions based on... whatever the hell it is you want to base your assumptions on.    How the hell can they consider tampons and pads 'luxuries' when *every single woman* will use them at some point in their life? It's like charging guys an extra 10% on their underwear.

Would it be cheaper to purchase from Amazon, or is the tax still applied? any time i've tried to buy anything off amazon, the price for S&amp;amp;H has been ridiculous.. i'm sorry, but it doesn't cost $40+ to ship a pair of leg warmers that probably weigh less than 200g How the hell can they consider tampons and pads 'luxuries' when *every single woman* will use them at some point in their life? It's like charging guys an extra 10% on their underwear.

Would it be cheaper to purchase from Amazon, or is the tax still applied? Import taxes might apply considering the quantity an Aussie woman would have to order to make it cost effective since there's no Australian Amazon, if they'd be shipped to Australia at all. We have to use the American store and a lot of stuff can't be shipped to Australia. How the hell can they consider tampons and pads 'luxuries' when *every single woman* will use them at some point in their life? It's like charging guys an extra 10% on their underwear.

Would it be cheaper to purchase from Amazon, or is the tax still applied? How the hell can they consider tampons and pads 'luxuries' when *every single woman* will use them at some point in their life? It's like charging guys an extra 10% on their underwear.

Would it be cheaper to purchase from Amazon, or is the tax still applied? Woman here who, without medication, surgery, or pregnancy, will never use a pad or tampon again.

I still get angry thinking about the fact that I did not learn about menstrual cups until 21 or so. That was my first reaction, too. Pads and tampons aren't necessarily a guaranteed purchase. Sucks for women who can't or don't like using a menstrual cup, but I'll never use anything else again.  I was laughing the last time this was pushed for, we had people dressed up as giant bloody tampons stalking politicians.   
While I've negated my need for tampons(yay Divacup!), i'll sign anyway, because its fucked.  I was laughing the last time this was pushed for, we had people dressed up as giant bloody tampons stalking politicians.   
While I've negated my need for tampons(yay Divacup!), i'll sign anyway, because its fucked.  Where did ypou get the diva cup? Shipping on most sites is expensive, I don't know if I can pay $60 right now for a cup.  How is this different than sales tax?   what the flying fuck? it's not a woman's fault that her body decides to bleed continuously for a week every month...why the hell does the government have to tax you for that shit? ugh, infuriating. :( what the flying fuck? it's not a woman's fault that her body decides to bleed continuously for a week every month...why the hell does the government have to tax you for that shit? ugh, infuriating. :( My thoughts exactly. The only reason I can think that the government says they're "luxury products" is because they think all women should be pregnant all the time and not being pregnant is a luxury. Then again, that might be my childfree mind in a babycentric country overthinking things and the government is just greedy =P  I think that all of you should just buy a mooncup :) 

(they are also environmental)


EDIT: But of course I signed this petition ;) Seconded, i just got a diva cup, i don't know how i put up with anything else all these years.  ...Can I ask you a question? Or a few?

Are they easy?  
Has it ever slipped and made you have an...accident?  
How often should you empty it, and what happens if you're still gushing while cleaning it?  
Can you feel it?  
*Has it ever slipped?*

The first time I ever heard of a menstrual cup was here in 2X, 2 years ago, and my initial reaction was "DISGUSTING". But hearing sooooo many women rave about it has got me really curious. Easy: yes, only a little more involved than a tampon. I find it less messy, but I guess it depends on what you find yucky about it. Also less uncomfortable, I can start wearing the cup right away when I spot without that dry feeling.

There are times when I don't quite get it sealed well or angled wrong and I have to adjust it or it can leak, but not too often. 

I empty mine 2-3 times a day (morning, afternoon/evening, before bed). It takes seconds to rinse and replace, not much longer than digging out a new tampon, taking out of package, etc. Never had a gushing problem. 

Sometimes I can feel it, but I find it on average more comfortable than a tampon. I have had to wear pads lately and miss my cup terribly.

A friend of mine couldn't wear the cup, it made her uncomfortable physically. If you can get over the gross out factor some people have, it's a good option to try. Thank you for the reply! So, obviously, panty liners are still a good idea. ...Can I ask you a question? Or a few?

Are they easy?  
Has it ever slipped and made you have an...accident?  
How often should you empty it, and what happens if you're still gushing while cleaning it?  
Can you feel it?  
*Has it ever slipped?*

The first time I ever heard of a menstrual cup was here in 2X, 2 years ago, and my initial reaction was "DISGUSTING". But hearing sooooo many women rave about it has got me really curious.    Didn't Coles and Woolies stop charging GST on pads and tampons a while ago? I don't know if they changed it back; I don't pay much attention to my receipts. Plus, it's usually the bf who picks them up for me  :-) Coles did, not sure about Woolies. Its one of those principal of the matter things though. Feminine hygiene products simply shouldn't have GST applied to them because they aren't optional, they're a necessity.         Well this is bloody ridiculous. Period.(Sorry... I'll see myself out.)  Obligatory menstrual cup plug: it is absolutely a luxury to use tampons, and a wasteful one at that. [Check out how much trash you're generating.](http://www.keeper.com/photographs.html)

I'm not criticizing your choice, but you seem to think that you have none, so.. I chose the Diva Cup brand because I could pick one up at my local market. There's a bunch of different brands and types out there, and every last one of them will save you hundreds of dollars a year on tampons, not to mention the stress of running out of tampons, possible relief of some menstrual cramps, overall improved hygiene... my reasons are many. You may disagree. Not everyone can use menstrual cups, and they're also not as easily available for everyone else as you imply.

Also, "hundreds of dollars a year" on tampons? Were you using tampons infused with gold or something? ... I dunno. I don't know what people spend, because I haven't spent on that stuff in years. And I believe in my next comment reply I went on to say I know that they're not for everyone.

I can't seem to escape the downvote brigade in TwoX lately. I didn't find out about menstrual cups at all until I was in my 20s. Excuse me for trying to help a sister out. Really, complaining about the "downvote brigade"? How is disagreeing with you in any way inappropriate? The downvote button is not the disagree button... And assuming that someone disagrees with you is downvoting you is just a little presumptuous, don't you think? Were you assuming that I was assuming that you were downvoting me because you were disagreeing with me? I have a bunch of downvotes on my cup comment, something I feel was valuable to the conversation at hand because OP made it sound like it was either tampons or the red river. So I expressed a little bitterness. You want to fight about it?

I don't know if it's just because I'm in a bad mood at the moment, but you're coming off like a big huge jerkface. So I'm going to go home and stop thinking about you. Goodnight. Good luck with your face. It's just because you're in a bad mood. Yeah, it had nothing to do with you being a condescending asshole. :P Obligatory menstrual cup plug: it is absolutely a luxury to use tampons, and a wasteful one at that. [Check out how much trash you're generating.](http://www.keeper.com/photographs.html)

I'm not criticizing your choice, but you seem to think that you have none, so.. I chose the Diva Cup brand because I could pick one up at my local market. There's a bunch of different brands and types out there, and every last one of them will save you hundreds of dollars a year on tampons, not to mention the stress of running out of tampons, possible relief of some menstrual cramps, overall improved hygiene... my reasons are many. You may disagree. hehe... *plug*

Also, I agree!  The savings alone are worth the initial investment.  I'm actually shocked when I see the prices of menstrual products when I'm at the store now.

Each to their own though of course, but I personally would never go back.

 I mean, some women have "vagina issues" (that's a quote from my sister who, for her own personal comfort, must use pads), so I wouldn't say that the cup is a choice that everyone can make, but I'd definitely stress that any woman who thinks the menstrual cup looks "gross" should really re-examine how filthy and disgusting tampons are. They're holding your waste up against your body, just begging to breed bacteria that cause Toxic Shock Syndrome. And you just wrap it up in toilet paper and toss it in the trash! *And the smell*... jeepers.   [deleted] Tampons are taxed in Canada. 

*edit- who the hell downvotes a simple statement of fact?? [deleted] "Regular tax?" The gst is the only federal tax. Canada taxes your tampon purchase, and taxes in individual provinces varies greatly. In Alberta, for example, consumers *only* pay the GST. What does a phrase like "regular tax" even *mean*?  Ontario has HST so that means I pay 13% on it. Never really thought about how they're taxed though. Probably because shampoo etc is too. "Regular tax?" The gst is the only federal tax. Canada taxes your tampon purchase, and taxes in individual provinces varies greatly. In Alberta, for example, consumers *only* pay the GST. What does a phrase like "regular tax" even *mean*?  [deleted] No I'm not. If anything it's more of a source of amusement that people would argue about the validity of taxes or how they work when from the outset, when their language betrays they don't even understand the fundamentals of what they're paying, why, and to whom.

For what it's worth, you just defined "regular" as "regular." Nice work.

*edit- thanks for the downvote. Who's angry now? [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>TwoX...I try and try and try, but I have little, almost zero, self-esteem. What do I do?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uy28/twoxi_try_and_try_and_try_but_i_have_little/</url><snippet>Hey all. 


I'm soon to be 19 years old, and I'm in my second semester of college, and I have an issue that's been eating at me quite a lot lately.


I've never felt so great about myself. Not to sound like a narcissist, but I have lots of reasons to be...lots of friends (now), good grades, loving boyfriend, "nice" body and lots of talents. However, my appearance has always been a concern of mine. I look much younger than I really am and it absolutely kills me inside when people think I'm 12, 13, 14. When I'm with friends it's not so bad, but **every** time I go out to eat with my parents and 7-year-old sister, I'm handed a kids menu, then have to listen to the waiter/waitress cut up with my parents about how young I look and hear how "you'll appreciate that someday". 


Another thing that bothers me about that is the looks people give me and my boyfriend occasionally when we're out in public. You see, my boyfriend is 25 (although I think he looks a couple years younger than he really is as well) and though I'm 19 I'm sure people make all kinds of crazy guesses about my age and think my boyfriend is some huge pervert, some "dirty old man" going out with a "little girl". 


I wear makeup on occasion but rarely fix my hair or wear anything other than jeans/sweatpants/casual clothes. One main reason? *I can't afford most "fashionable" clothes.* Yeah, every now and then I'll drop a couple bucks at Aeropostale or Rue 21, but I adore Aero sweatpants and have a hard time stepping out of my comfort zone in terms of clothing. I get $100 a month, and that has to go towards necessities (food, gas, prescriptions, etc.) to be honest, I could never picture myself in a lot of the more popular styles of clothing now...they're just outrageous to me!


Another thing is, I never know what to do with my hair. It's about boob length and it took nearly two years to get it this long (my hair grows really slow.) [Here](http://i.imgur.com/1T8E3hV.jpg) is me on an average day...braids, beanie, no makeup. I have been debating on getting my hair cut shoulder length, but I certainly don't want to do that if it would possibly make me look even younger. (I do want to keep my natural color though). 


**Long story short:** I need some advice on what I can do to make myself actually look 19 that don't involve me dressing like a "slut" (as one friend has ever so kindly suggested) or spending money I don't have on clothes I don't really like. Any suggestions in the line of makeup, quick and easy (but pretty) things to do with my hair in the mornings, possible haircuts or even suggestions as to what type of glasses could make me look older (please don't suggest contacts as I do not plan on getting them)...any advice would be greatly appreciated. 

Thank you ladies!
xoxo
  Being confident is a habit. Every time you find thoughts turning negative, tell them to STOP IT and then force yourself to start thinking about something happy, or do something to take your mind off of it. Over time, you'll find you don't have as many negative thoughts.

As for looking more your age, here are my suggestions:

* Ditch the pigtails. A single braid, a pony tail, or even just a couple bobby pins on one side are all good basic hairstyles. Pigtails invariably look girlish.
* Start wearing mascara ([here's](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSj2E_iiCBc) a good how-to). I think your glasses are really cute, so I'd keep those.
* STOP wearing sweatpants as your everyday pants.
* Start browsing /r/femalefashionadvice and thrift stores. You can find some really cool things without breaking the bank.

As for your clothing, the most important thing is that your clothes *FIT*. Nothing will say "high schooler" faster than baggy clothes. It's also very important that you have *some* clothes with structure. This means garments that aren't made out of stretchy fabric.

Wearing the same things, but in more grown-up styles, will help you transition out of your comfort zone. Like so:

* Straight leg or skinny jeans. Still jeans! but they have structure and are fitted. [They also look really nice with flats.](http://prommafia.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/cute-skinny-jeans-and-flats.jpg)
* T-shirts that FIT. The shoulder seams should hit *at* your shoulder bone. [Fitted](http://img0.etsystatic.com/007/0/5854980/il_fullxfull.373052140_3dzv.jpg). [Not fitted.](http://www.youngloverslabel.com/media/catalog/product/cache/1/thumbnail/5e06319eda06f020e43594a9c230972d/b/i/big-heart-t-shirt-fashion.jpg)
* An all-purpose jacket. Something non-stretchy. Black goes with everything.
* Flats. I've had cheap Target pairs that I loved, and amazing leather ones that lasted forever. Just anything that's not flip-flops or converse.

You'll still be wearing jeans and t-shirts, but you'll look [adult and put-together](http://missglamdan.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/20120913_094815.jpg), not [high school](http://storage2.ihigh.com/users/2152/photos/128050.jpg). Being confident is a habit. Every time you find thoughts turning negative, tell them to STOP IT and then force yourself to start thinking about something happy, or do something to take your mind off of it. Over time, you'll find you don't have as many negative thoughts.

As for looking more your age, here are my suggestions:

* Ditch the pigtails. A single braid, a pony tail, or even just a couple bobby pins on one side are all good basic hairstyles. Pigtails invariably look girlish.
* Start wearing mascara ([here's](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSj2E_iiCBc) a good how-to). I think your glasses are really cute, so I'd keep those.
* STOP wearing sweatpants as your everyday pants.
* Start browsing /r/femalefashionadvice and thrift stores. You can find some really cool things without breaking the bank.

As for your clothing, the most important thing is that your clothes *FIT*. Nothing will say "high schooler" faster than baggy clothes. It's also very important that you have *some* clothes with structure. This means garments that aren't made out of stretchy fabric.

Wearing the same things, but in more grown-up styles, will help you transition out of your comfort zone. Like so:

* Straight leg or skinny jeans. Still jeans! but they have structure and are fitted. [They also look really nice with flats.](http://prommafia.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/cute-skinny-jeans-and-flats.jpg)
* T-shirts that FIT. The shoulder seams should hit *at* your shoulder bone. [Fitted](http://img0.etsystatic.com/007/0/5854980/il_fullxfull.373052140_3dzv.jpg). [Not fitted.](http://www.youngloverslabel.com/media/catalog/product/cache/1/thumbnail/5e06319eda06f020e43594a9c230972d/b/i/big-heart-t-shirt-fashion.jpg)
* An all-purpose jacket. Something non-stretchy. Black goes with everything.
* Flats. I've had cheap Target pairs that I loved, and amazing leather ones that lasted forever. Just anything that's not flip-flops or converse.

You'll still be wearing jeans and t-shirts, but you'll look [adult and put-together](http://missglamdan.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/20120913_094815.jpg), not [high school](http://storage2.ihigh.com/users/2152/photos/128050.jpg).    </snippet></document><document><title>Hasbro&#8217;s Nerf Rebelle Blasters Bring Foam Warfare To Girls</title><url>http://www.coolthings.com/nerf-rebelle/</url><snippet>  Oh goody, it's pink. It's a fucking weapon. I can't begin to describe the ways making it pink is fucked up. This is just *more* reinforcement of girls and boys being fundamentally different. Why? Because ** if its exactly the se range as the boy need guns, why make a separate range? Why not just market the original nerf guns to boys AND girls?** I'll tell you why - because girls are different, and can only have boy toys if their different from the boy ones.  Oh goody, it's pink. It's a fucking weapon. I can't begin to describe the ways making it pink is fucked up. This is just *more* reinforcement of girls and boys being fundamentally different. Why? Because ** if its exactly the se range as the boy need guns, why make a separate range? Why not just market the original nerf guns to boys AND girls?** I'll tell you why - because girls are different, and can only have boy toys if their different from the boy ones.   Despite the pinkness I'm really excited about these. Apparently they have the same range and power as standard nerf line weapons. Gender biased marketing aside, I think this is still a pretty cool idea. Despite the pinkness I'm really excited about these. Apparently they have the same range and power as standard nerf line weapons. Gender biased marketing aside, I think this is still a pretty cool idea.</snippet></document><document><title>Soooo, my husband and I barely have sex anymore....</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v5j2/soooo_my_husband_and_i_barely_have_sex_anymore/</url><snippet>It's so weird to me, maybe if someone else knows how I feel, shed some insight, please. My husband and I are newlyweds, only married for 16 months and still young (25-27) I feel like we have to force the love making. When we were dating, we had sex all the time, 3-5 times a week and it was mutually enforced and we were totally into it. But now, it's like, I have to cross my fingers that he won't fall keep on the couch and save some energy for our bedroom.... And the nights where we are still awake and with energy, it's almost like neither of us make an effort to "start" up. It's like, "you're turn to start. I was on top last time. Ok I'll do you and then you do me a little". It a negotiation! Now adays we MIGHt have sex once a week, 2 if its a good week. And I have to ASK "can we have sex tonight?" It's crazy. I know I am more than willing to get back into the swing. i tell him all the time when i want to, that im "yearning"  and please dont fall asleepceqrly tonight, but knowing that it is such a chore turns me off. I feel like he doesn't want me like he used to. He used to be all over me, and vice versa. 
What is it? Is it boredom, laziness, marriage lull, or is he seeing someone else? All of the above!? Ahhhh please someone tell me it's a normal hiccup :/   When's the last time you two went on a date? Or the last time either one of you scheduled quality time together?   I think this is sort of normal.  I've been married now for 12 years and we go into little phases like this.  Here is my totally unprofessional advice regarding the matter.

We get comfortable.  We become like roommates.  We still love each other (and are even attracted to each other... imagine that!) but life just becomes routine.  You have your schedules.  You get up for work, get dressed, come home, do dinner... routine routine routine... with the occasional weekend fun night.  I think it's easy to allow every facet of your relationship fall into "routine" when you're faced with routine every day. Including sex.  He knows what gets you off quickly and you know what gets his engines going.  It's easy to go straight to that "go-to" when you are familiar with how easy it is to get someone off with it.

I have been to /r/deadbedrooms.  I have read all of the suggestions.  I have searched and searched everything and everything about whether or not this is normal and what can I do about it as the more seemingly concerned partner in the relationship.  I am currently in the midst of taking on the responsibility myself of reviving our dead bedroom.  I started by "faking it til I make it" (sounds awful, but bear with me).  Even if I don't FEEL like I want to initiate or wish he would instead, I do it anyway.  I grab him, kiss him, make advances toward him.  Honey, there's only been one time out of the few times I've done this where he has said, "No, I'm just tired."  And ya know what?  That's okay.  There were many evenings where I was tired too and he had to stop.  Why should this be all on your shoulders, you ask?  Simply put: Because right now, it needs to be.  Make him feel wanted.  Initiate.  Get yours.  Tell him what you like and want from him (as much as we'd like them to be all-knowing mind reading wizards, they for sure are not and probably never will be!) and ask him what he wants from you!  If he clams up, like my husband does and doesn't want to talk about it... quite frankly, too bad.  Don't let up.  Keep bugging him about it.  MAKE HIM TALK ABOUT IT.  

Also, I suggest having a heart to heart with him.  Have a nice bath or shower together (unless shower time is your time and you're not into having the man there), or lay in bed together snuggling and talking, or if it's more your style, have a date night where you both promise to talk intimacy.  One great resource to open up lines of communication about sexuality is http://mojoupgrade.com.  You fill out your survey, he fills out his, it matches up the things you have in common and keeps the things you don't confidential.  It's a nice way to start the dialogue about things maybe you'd both like to do, but haven't had the opportunity to talk about.  Also, be ready to have an open mind.  He may open way up and tell you about all the freaky things he wants to do.  If that happens, don't bat an eye.  Calmly accept what he is telling you and try not to be offended (as long as his desires aren't morally reprehensible... I think you know what I mean by that).  You can calmly tell him you might try it if you talk more about it or you can tell him it is absolutely off limits, however you do not hold any negative judgment toward him for what he likes.  

As they say, relationships take WORK.  People are lying to you or they are jaded if they think they don't.  This includes your marriage... FOREVER.  Always talk to your spouse.  Once you stop talking, you stop communicating and things will break down.  The honeymoon period might be over, but if you work on your communication, something bigger and better will take its place.  A long-lasting, trusting relationship filled with honesty, communication and openness.  Just because you don't get the flutters in your tummy anymore when you kiss or he doesn't strip you down in the hallway doesn't mean the attraction or sex is gone - it just means it's calmed down to normal and it's time to take the reigns and make sure it doesn't sink any further.  He married you because he loves you and is attracted to you and has probably just gotten very comfortable and maybe has begun taking you for granted a little because you're always there and he sees you as "accessible" and not as someone he needs to impress.  But again, if it's something you need... to be verbally complimented or physically shown love - you have to tell him that.  And he needs to respect that and do his best to do those things for you.  This is a great resource for figuring out what ways each of you need to be "shown" love: http://www.5lovelanguages.com/profile/  Take the quiz and talk about it.

Best of luck to you - do not despair and if you ever need an understanding female ear, please feel free to IM me anytime.. been there, done that, got the shirt, returned it. ;)</snippet></document><document><title>Anyone with knowledge on the Plan B Emergency Contraception Pill?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v0wa/anyone_with_knowledge_on_the_plan_b_emergency/</url><snippet>Okay, so, I am a 16 y/o female, and my boyfriend is 17. We have been dating for nearly a year, and have recently started having sex. Today was our fourth time trying it and the condom broke. I started to flip my shit as soon as he told me, but he remained level headed and suggested Plan B. We did some quick research and hopped over to the grocery store. I took it within an hour of having sex with him. It's been around seven hours since I've taken it. My boyfriend made and AskReddit post about it, and received reassuring answers, but I'm still a wreck and can't sleep. If anyone has any advice I'll gladly take it. Thanks.  First of all, props to both of you for being so responsible, and props to him for remaining level-headed and quickly picking a smart course of action. Second of all: you took it within an hour of having sex with him? You're going to be just fine. With how quickly you took it, it's as effective as it's gonna get. You're in the clear, now go get some sleep! And maybe invest in higher-quality condoms (and lube so the condom doesn't dry out and snap). =) The condom was latex and new(durex brand) but it was one if the ultra-thin super-sensitive ones (came in a three pack, either that or strawberry)
Thank you so much, by the way! I'm beginning to be feel better about all this. First of all, props to both of you for being so responsible, and props to him for remaining level-headed and quickly picking a smart course of action. Second of all: you took it within an hour of having sex with him? You're going to be just fine. With how quickly you took it, it's as effective as it's gonna get. You're in the clear, now go get some sleep! And maybe invest in higher-quality condoms (and lube so the condom doesn't dry out and snap). =)  Like everyone else said, don't be afraid to try new condoms. There are condoms I will not use because I've had multiple snafu's with breakage, and now I only use Lifestyles! 

Also, if you needed to hear it again: you're going to be fine :) good for you guys for getting on it so quickly! I hope your experience in buying it went without a hitch.  </snippet></document><document><title>Cuomo to expand abortion rights in NY</title><url>http://tv.msnbc.com/2013/02/18/cuomo-to-expand-abortion-rights-in-ny/</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>High arch help!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v6v2/high_arch_help/</url><snippet>I have very high arches.  I get thick, painful calluses on the balls of my feet and calluses on the top of my toes which curve.  Wearing high heels for me is often more comfortable for me than wearing flats.   

Wondering what you other ladies with similar foot shapes recommend  as far as shoes?  Any brand or shape that works best for you?  Also any tips on inserts or other advice to help with calluses and pain in the ball of the foot?  Thanks!!!  I also have very high arches - I LOVE wedges. I have a pair of 2-inch wedge boots that are insanely comfortable for me and also give my legs quite the workout! :) :)    What brands of heels do you find work well for high arches? I just got into wearing heels more often and I'd love to get your advice!   </snippet></document><document><title>Denis Mukwege: The rape surgeon of DR Congo</title><url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-21499068</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>I'm addicted to makeup.. Can anyone help me, please?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18vbqj/im_addicted_to_makeup_can_anyone_help_me_please/</url><snippet>According to Merriam-Webster dictionary, the definition of "addict" is as follows:

&amp;gt; to devote or surrender (oneself) to something habitually or obsessively.

I'm not entirely sure why I started wearing makeup, but I know it happened in the 6th grade, when I was only 10 years old (I started school early)

Of course, puberty and hormones got to me just like it did every other middle-schooler, and it reeked havoc on my complexion. I got bumps, just like every other kid. The only difference seemed to be that in a week the other kid's bumps would be gone, while mine stayed for months. They would get darker, they would leave marks, and sometimes they would even leave dents in my face.

I like to think that if my bumps had just gone away like they had with everyone else that I wouldn't feel the NEED to wear makeup, because everyone gets bumps and they will be gone in a few days, but instead I've worn makeup every, I mean every time I've gone in public, since the 6th grade.

I don't have a problem with needing to impress others. I have absolutely no problem going out in sweatpants and a ratty old tee with my hair pulled up in a messy bun. I've even gone to the store caked in icing from my godson's birthday cake, because I couldn't wash it off at my friend's house because I hadn't brought my makeup with me.

I see girls that wear a smidge of foundation and mascara and I want to be them. I just think that those girls are gifted with that gorgeous, natural beauty it makes me hurt inside. I don't want to rely on a mask. I want to feel beautiful in my own skin.

When I got out of the shower the other day my boyfriend was coming home from work, and I had left my foundation in my room. I bolted across the hall, slamming the door shut behind me, and when he came in to check on me I covered my face and told him that he had to leave my room until I had my foundation on. He wants me to be comfortable without makeup on around him, and he tried to get me to uncover my face, and I ended up in a ball on the floor covering my head with my arms.

I want to get over this addiction, but I don't think I can do it. I'm ashamed of my own face.

I've seen some very very inspiring stories on here, and I was wondering, does anyone have any personal stories about getting over an addiction to makeup? Does anyone have any tips on how to get rid of these scars? Is there anyone out there who can relate at least? Please, help me.  Honestly sounds like step #1 might be visting a good dermatologist. You obviously have some deeper seeded issues regarding your appearance but at the same time if you are dealing with a really difficult chronic skin issue that can be very hard.  I've wanted to for years, I just don't have the money or time. I'm a full time student with a part time job and I can barely afford my car insurance. It depends on your school, but some schools have clinics for students, and those clinics might be able to do a rudimentary examination of your skin. It probably won't be as good as seeing a dermatologist, but could still be helpful.  My skin got much better in college, while in HS it had been a bother.   I think part of that is hormones settling down, and the second part is my taking better care of it.  

It's frustrating to accept, but all the layers of foundation may be causing breakouts and slowing down your skin's healing process.  At the very least your makeup should be oil-free.  I like Bare Minerals loose powders, they've never caused any irritation.   I use them along with a Neutrogena spot concealer.  
I don't know how you manage at night, but you should make time for your skin to rest from makeup, breathe, and soak up moisturizers.    Overwashing dries it out, try looking into a cleansing toner or wash that does not require water.   
You're going to have to be very disciplined if you want great skin, here is what worked for me:
- Always use a towel that's set aside for your face ONLY to dry it.  Don't use bath towels or hand towels.  You can use soft paper towels to blot your face dry if you have trouble keeping a separate small towel on hand.   Wash your clothes, towels, linens with fragrance-free laundry detergent. 
- Switch your pillowcase often.   Every week works now, but when my skin was worse, I did it every four days or so.  Some people like to buy a stack of cheap washcloths and safety pin one on top for a fresh pillow every day.   If your boyfriend sleeps over, make sure he has his own pillowcase.  
- Be mindful of what touches your face during the day.   Wipe off your phone, don't rest your chin on your hands.  
- Watch your hair product use.   Hairspray = breakouts if it gets on your face.   Same with conditioner during shower time, that stuff shouldn't come anywhere near your front hairline.  
- Use lukewarm water to wash your face.   Hot water that feels nice to your hands is too drying on your skin and can irritate it.  
- Purchase Bio Oil or pure Vitamin E oil and use that on the fading acne marks.   They WILL improve and disappear.   This stuff is amazing, and you will see results after a few months.  Study day or lazy weekend?   Cover your clean face in Bio Oil and give it time to heal!   At the very least apply it before bed, nightly.  
- Neosporin for spots that have bled, scabbed, or are turning dry and flaky.   This has made some awful situations heal scar-free in my case.  
- Be very selective in the products you use on your face.   Oil-free makeup, and quality moisturizers, toners, makeup removers, everything.  A lot of cleansers can have alcohol which is too harsh!   So is salicylic acid, as stripping your skin of all natural oils will cause it to produce more.   The skincare reddit can suggest some good products and routines for you.  

I know you asked for how to get away from makeup and not give a fuck.   But I can tell that your fears stem from wanting to feel more like your amazing self, and taking better care of your skin will have results.   All of these routines above take less time and money than full warpaint daily!  You are very young and the dark spots can heal perfectly with the right care.  
One bonus to your makeup addiction is all the SPF protection you must be getting!    This is really informative and helpful, thank you. I wish I could give you more than an upvote! I'm going to make a new routine for myself doing these things every night. Wish me luck! :) So glad to help!   Don't give up.  One thing I forgot to mention is that lots of makeup has cornstarch or other starches added to soak up oil and give a matte finish.   This is awful for acne-prone skin, because the starch sits on your face all day feeding bacteria and causing breakouts!   I've had to give up on products I love, but it was absolutely worth the trade.   Blush or powders most commonly use this ingredient.   Bare Minerals does not!  
Also drink plenty of water.  :)  Do you currently have acne or post blemish discolorations?  It sounds like you just have acne scars from your youth, but no current acne issues.  For acne or discolorations, I recommend /r/skincareaddiction;for old acne scars, a good derm can help smooth them out. I still get bumps every week, and they still leave marks and scars. The old ones have just never gone away.
Thank you for the link, I didn't know this existed!</snippet></document><document><title>Just got engaged, any advice from married ladies?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18tpgm/just_got_engaged_any_advice_from_married_ladies/</url><snippet>As the title says, I got engaged to my wonderful man about a week ago, and I'm trying to avoid getting overwhelmed.  I am finishing up my master's thesis and now need to plan a wedding, so any stories/advice you lovely ladies have that could make things smoother would be awesome and much appreciated!    My biggest advice: run away and get married.

We started planning the big wedding, which quickly became an overwhelming pain in the ass.  Who to invite, where to have it, catering, blah blah blah.  Then one day my husband was on a business trip and texted me "Antigua?"  We dropped all our wedding plans, invited 20 friends and family members, and had a blast at our small ceremony where 99% of the planning was taken care of by the resort.   Honestly, I came to say this. I had a lot of pressure from friends and family to have a wedding locally, but I just couldn't take it. We booked a flight to hawaii, I got a custom dress off ebay, and we invited anyone who wanted to come, to come with us. We had a couple people join us, and it was amazing. There was no stress, no planning and we spent what we would have spent on an amazing honeymoon. When we got back, we had two receptions, one near his family and one near mine. We were able to splurge on the fun bits without worrying about napkin rings and seating arrangements. If you find planning overwhelming, don't be afraid to take charge and do what YOU want. This is not about anyone else's expectations or needs. This is between you and your future husband. Make yourself happy above all.  Your pictures are beautiful. :) Did you foot the bill for flights for whomever came with you two? My biggest advice: run away and get married.

We started planning the big wedding, which quickly became an overwhelming pain in the ass.  Who to invite, where to have it, catering, blah blah blah.  Then one day my husband was on a business trip and texted me "Antigua?"  We dropped all our wedding plans, invited 20 friends and family members, and had a blast at our small ceremony where 99% of the planning was taken care of by the resort.   My biggest advice: run away and get married.

We started planning the big wedding, which quickly became an overwhelming pain in the ass.  Who to invite, where to have it, catering, blah blah blah.  Then one day my husband was on a business trip and texted me "Antigua?"  We dropped all our wedding plans, invited 20 friends and family members, and had a blast at our small ceremony where 99% of the planning was taken care of by the resort.    Do all the premarital counseling you can! It's so worth the investment :D You might regret your color choices, or your choice of bridesmaid, but never, ever counseling. 

Besides - it can bring you closer together and help you get through the stress of wedding planning! This is such a honeymoon sweet time, don't forget to focus on the future, and the premarital counseling does just that. And the fights it prevents...geeze! Just do it! Can you talk a little more about what your premarital counseling was like? The only time I ever hear people talking about premarital counseling, it's usually religiously-based and, from what I've heard, kind of a waste of time. I'd love to hear what a solid premarital counseling program would look like. Premarital counseling should be done with a _real_ counselor! Like an LCSW, maybe. It should include things like planning for the future, financial decision-making, child-rearing and social issues. You discuss healthy ways to disagree and great ways to resolve conflict. 

It's absolutely not a waste of time - provided you see a qualified counselor and not just a concerned party (like the religious counselors you describe).  I would start your planning by making two lists: one of budget and finances including who is paying for what, second a ranking of what aspects of the wedding are most important to you and your fiance. Put most of your budget towards those things and be okay with letting the other things slide a little. For example if you guys want to have the tastiest dinner ever with an open bar, you might have to tell some of the relatives and friends that you are limiting the guest list and they can't come. But if it's super important to have absolutely EVERYBODY there, you will have to be okay with having a lesser quality dinner or venue or whatever you don't really care about it. 

Personally I am doing a destination wedding at an all inclusive resort. They are planning everything for me and all I have to do is show up ;). But doing this means the wedding is pretty much only going to involve family members and even then it's only the family members that have the resources to come. So figure out what the most important thing is to you guys and go from there! I just posted about my wedding at an all-inclusive resort.  Mine was at Sandals Grande Antigua, and it was amazing.  I'm so glad I had a destination wedding.  Where are you having yours? Montego Bay in Jamaica. So far I've heard good things from everyone who has a destination wedding (including my sister, but I didn't get to go to hers :( ) so I'm super excited!  Your wedding should be fun, not stressful. My husband and I did all (well, most) of our wedding planning at a pub with beer. We kept a notebook, and when we reached a point where we were getting stressed out, we stopped for that session. We would then assign tasks to each of us (call parents to see who we left off the invitation list, look up florists, etc).

Guest count is not a competition, you don't need to have the exact same number of family and friends coming. For that matter, when it comes to seating, encourage your guests to intermingle. Your families are being joined, don't separate them at the wedding. Our parents sat right next to each other.

Don't go into debt for your wedding. As long as you two are happy and excited about your location, your guests will assume that this is your ideal wedding. If you get married at a winery, big fancy church or under a tree at a park, as long as your happy, your guests will be.

Something will go wrong on the day of your wedding. It's ok. It happens to us all. Just let it go with a laugh, all that matters is that you are happily married at the end of the day.

If your parents haven't met his yet, make sure they meet before the rehearsal dinner.

Over all, keep communication open with each other. Make sure you both agree on things like budget, size of the wedding party, and how formal it will be. My husband was in a nice suit, his cousin was married in a tux. My sister wore a $99 wedding gown off the sale rack at David's Bridal, I wore my MIL's gown, a friend's mother made hers, and a cousin had a top-of-the-line designer gown. Each of these weddings was perfect for the bride and groom, from the back yard, to the vinyard, to the Knights of Columbus building.  YMMV with the intermingling- the OP and her fiance know best if this will work. For example, some of my relatives only speak Spanish and I would not want to make anyone uncomfortable by seating them with people they wouldn't even be able to talk to. That's a unique situation, but some people like friends might only know a couple people at the wedding and they would have a better time sitting next to each other at dinner.                        </snippet></document><document><title>Dating Someone 18 Years Older with a Daughter who is 5 Years Younger</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uopp/dating_someone_18_years_older_with_a_daughter_who/</url><snippet>Hey TwoX. For the last 7 months I have been dating a man who is 18 years older than me. For the record, I am 25 and he is 43. He's really great. It makes me happy to be with him most of the time. And, it's not quite as weird as it might be. For starters, he and I are involved in the same, niche, artistic community in our city, so we get eachother. He also looks like he's 28 - not kidding everyone is shocked when they learn his age. And, because of the community he is in, he stays out till three, drinks, engages in the same debauchery is me, only on a little bit more mature level. 

There's one thing. He has a daughter who is 5 years younger than me and is in college. She has no idea that I exist, or that he even has a girlfriend at all. I know that it's hard and it would be hard for us to meet. The last thing I want to do is rock or jeopardize their relationship. But, on the other hand, it makes me feel like a dirty little secret. I feel bad that he has this whole life with me, but can't share that he does any of that with her. I have told him that all this is very complicated and I don't know what to do with it sometimes. 

Furthermore, I have not introduced him to my parents, nor do they even know that I have a boyfriend at all. I just feel like they would judge me for his age. 

Also, I know that down the line, he and I are never getting married. There are way too many issues preventing that (like the daughter thing and the parents thing). 

ANYWAY, I bring all of this up to say. I'm in my 20s and I should be able to date who I want, right? Someone told me that I'm wasting my time or something. But I love this person. Also, despite all of this, is any relationship a waste of time if the other person makes you happy? Maybe it's not sustainable, and I need to prepare myself for this, but are most relationships we have in our 20s really that stable? Am I preventing some "one, true, love" from coming round these parts because I'm spending time with a guy who might not be in it for the long haul with me? 

I don't know. I can't really talk to too many people my age about this because it's such a complicated issue. My mom would judge me and probably tell me to break up with him. 

Confused! But okay, I think?  I have a feeling I am a part of the same kind of, uh, artistic community as you so I know of a lot of people that have similar more unconventional relationships that are very happy.  I think you just have to decide how important it is to be able to share your relationship with your/his family.  I can understand both sides of the situation and it's a tough call. really intrigued but not quite sure it's the same community based on your posts. Haha. I appreciate your answer though. Thanks!  Hey lady, I can relate on at least one level. First of all, you CAN date who you want because, try as we may, we cannot help who we love and who loves us. I speak from experience, as I was with a man (literally) twice my age and we had the best relationship I'd had at that point in my life. 

When you say you know you're never getting married, are you saying that because you don't want to get married period or that you are not planning on this as a life commitment? If the latter, then AGAIN I feel ya. With my fella, I knew after a lot of deliberation that I couldn't build a life with him because in our situation, the age really did come into play. He is 42, owns a shop in town and has already made his niche in the community. I, on the other hand, came to town to go to college and  have dreams of grad school in far-off places. 

You're not preventing your "one true love" from taking their permanent place in your life. That person will come around, if you so believe it, whenever they're 'sposed to! ;) You're appreciating the time you have with this person because you love them and that is what it's all about.

And, for the record, society can eat my shorts for all the hate they give  May-December romances because they're really beautiful and formative and maturing and amazing, given healthy circumstances. LIKE ALL RELATIONSHIPS!

Good luck, friend.   It sounds like you have a level head on your shoulders and reasonable expectations about the relationship. So yeah, have fun!  One of my close friends has parents with a similar age gap. Her mom is in her 50s (not sure early or mid, she looks younger than she is) and her dad is in his early 70s. My friend has a happy childhood and her parents have always been on good terms (they did divorce when she was little, but it was very amicable). Nobody I know ever really raised an eyebrow at the age gap, probably because her parents are older.


My point is, there's nothing inherently negative or bad about such relationships. If you're having a good relationship now, then enjoy it. If it turns out not to work out, that's fine too. If "mr right" comes along and it turns out its not that guy, deal with that when it comes. Don't worry about your relationship because of the age gap.


The awkwardness, though, of telling your parents or meeting his kid, is a bit tough. I think that really stems from you being young as you are. So I'm not surprised you're doubting. But thats something you can deal with. Its not a sign theres anything wrong with your relationship. One of my close friends has parents with a similar age gap. Her mom is in her 50s (not sure early or mid, she looks younger than she is) and her dad is in his early 70s. My friend has a happy childhood and her parents have always been on good terms (they did divorce when she was little, but it was very amicable). Nobody I know ever really raised an eyebrow at the age gap, probably because her parents are older.


My point is, there's nothing inherently negative or bad about such relationships. If you're having a good relationship now, then enjoy it. If it turns out not to work out, that's fine too. If "mr right" comes along and it turns out its not that guy, deal with that when it comes. Don't worry about your relationship because of the age gap.


The awkwardness, though, of telling your parents or meeting his kid, is a bit tough. I think that really stems from you being young as you are. So I'm not surprised you're doubting. But thats something you can deal with. Its not a sign theres anything wrong with your relationship. </snippet></document><document><title>Had an uncomfortable experience tonight and wondering if I can do something about it if there's a next time.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v9ph/had_an_uncomfortable_experience_tonight_and/</url><snippet>Tonight while working (pet boarding/daycare in a large retail store), a couple of kids ages 14 and 18 came in and acted like complete tools. They were a nuisance for every area of our store, but not quite near as bad as they were for my section. 

At first it was just annoying things: bothering the employees, trying to get into the employee-only section, cussing out loud in front of customers-- the usual punkass kid stuff. What made us really uncomfortable was that these kids started sexually harassing my co-worker, making comments about her butt and following it up with lewd, obscene shit that no 14 year old should be saying. My co-worker was appalled, even told them "One day you're going to get slapped for saying that to a lady", and eventually got fed up and told them that they needed to leave. They put up a fight, said "we're paying customers" (they bought a single fish, for god knows what reason), and "you can't make us go anywhere". Within 5 minutes or so, they left on their own.

The whole experience was really hard to sit through, but we honestly didn't know what to do. Our managers were MIA, and we didn't know what we had the right to do or say to these kids. If the harassment continued and they would not leave, could we have called the cops to remove them? Any help would be greatly appreciated. I'm really freaked out that they might come back in the next few days.  You tell them to leave the second they say something sexual to an employee.  When you let the first comment slide, they're more likely to make a second.  If they don't leave, is there security?  Could someone find the manager? </snippet></document><document><title>[ADVICE] Is painful orgasm normal?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v93w/advice_is_painful_orgasm_normal/</url><snippet>Hello. This is pretty embarrassing, but I'm not sure where else to ask for help. If someone could read this and give advice, that'd be superb!

I'm 18 and I have a lot of trouble orgasming, as in, I've never had one until two nights ago. I feel pleasure, but it never reaches a climax point; it's just static. I read that Kegel exercises can help, so I started doing a few. I've been doing them for two to four weeks--I don't really remember. They worked. Two nights ago I finally achieved orgasm (via masturbation since I'm a virgin; I don't know how important that is).

The problem is it hurt like hell. The first half was nice and pleasurable, but the second half felt like my labia was trying to sew itself together. The pain went from my lower abdomen (a little lower than the waist) to halfway down my thighs. My legs and hips started to convulse (although I think that's pretty normal). I then had trouble standing for a few minutes. There was no pain in the morning or today.

Is this normal? Has anyone else had this happen, with Kegels or otherwise? Will it pass by itself or should I see my GYN? Thanks so much!

TL;DR: Is a painful first orgasm normal, especially after doing Kegel exercises?  Shuddering, having trouble standing, and it feeling really intense is normal. Actual *pain* is not. Get thee to a doctor, madam!  Huh, well, I'm not sure what to tell you, other than to ask a doctor.  But I can tell you that my legs and hips to the convulsion thing, and wen I get really turned on, my vagina hurts because it wants something to grip around, but it always feels good for me.  Maybe you pulled a muscle?  </snippet></document><document><title>Hilary Mantel - Royal Bodies.  Her article for the London Review of Books.</title><url>http://www.lrb.co.uk/v35/n04/hilary-mantel/royal-bodies</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Confronting a roommate mixed with social anxiety. Any tips 2X?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uw7l/confronting_a_roommate_mixed_with_social_anxiety/</url><snippet>Hi [/r/TwoXChromosomes](/r/TwoXChromosomes) , I was wondering if you could help me. I have social anxiety and it is causing issues with me bringing things up to my roommate.

I posted this in [/r/socialanxiety](/r/socialanxiety) first but I figured this involved woman to woman talk, you might be able to help

We have been living together in a lovely apartment for 6 months and we are great friends, the only problem is I do ALL of the maintaining of the common area.

Not once in six months has she done the dishes, emptied the trashes, wiped down after cooking, swept, taken out the recycling or put her stuff back after using it and it is not only pissing me off but it is adding to my anxiety.

I tried bringing it up once before but I only got to "it would be great if you could pitch in a bit more in the common area" to which she responded positively. I took that as the cue to GTFO and panic in my room because I caused a 'confrontation'. Nothing has gotten done.

I know it seems like a little thing but trust me, when you're taking care of EVERYTHING it adds up, fast. Also, I don't wanna be mean cuz I know she's dealing with a lot right now (general anxiety, depression and a chronic illness) but if this keeps going it'll cause resentment and ruin our friendship.

HELP!  You need to set firm rules. I am good friends with my roommate, and I waited a semester before it was finally too much to handle. I was taking care of the common areas just like you were, and that included doing all the dishes. When I would drop a hint he would always say "just ask me to do it and I will" which was the most annoying answer ever - we are both adults and if he makes an elaborate messy meal I expect him to do his dishes in a reasonable time - not 4 days later after attracting flies in the sink. I could continue on with other things, but you get the idea. I would gently and passively remind him, but nothing would change. Finally this semester I had enough. After cooling off a day at my boyfriend's place (I was very upset) I came back and typed up rules on the computer about how the kitchen should be kept and taped it up by the sink. It includes plenty of rules that you would think are common sense, but every rule on there is only there because of something he did last semester that I always asked to do/not to do, but which he would apparently forget about in a days time. Let me tell you, life is so much better now that I have those up. He's only slipped up once. Unfortunately, now he has been taking to keeping dirty dishes in his bedroom, and let me say I'm so happy I'm not living with him next year. [Here](http://i.imgur.com/SGfYnK3.png) is the sign if you'd like to see.

**TL;DR** - Put up a sign with defined rules you expect to be followed. Your friend needs structure. I liked your rules. It's so easy to get passive-aggressive when posting rules, but you didn't do it. My friend was used to his mom always doing his dishes, and I was tired of being his replacement mom. You need to set firm rules. I am good friends with my roommate, and I waited a semester before it was finally too much to handle. I was taking care of the common areas just like you were, and that included doing all the dishes. When I would drop a hint he would always say "just ask me to do it and I will" which was the most annoying answer ever - we are both adults and if he makes an elaborate messy meal I expect him to do his dishes in a reasonable time - not 4 days later after attracting flies in the sink. I could continue on with other things, but you get the idea. I would gently and passively remind him, but nothing would change. Finally this semester I had enough. After cooling off a day at my boyfriend's place (I was very upset) I came back and typed up rules on the computer about how the kitchen should be kept and taped it up by the sink. It includes plenty of rules that you would think are common sense, but every rule on there is only there because of something he did last semester that I always asked to do/not to do, but which he would apparently forget about in a days time. Let me tell you, life is so much better now that I have those up. He's only slipped up once. Unfortunately, now he has been taking to keeping dirty dishes in his bedroom, and let me say I'm so happy I'm not living with him next year. [Here](http://i.imgur.com/SGfYnK3.png) is the sign if you'd like to see.

**TL;DR** - Put up a sign with defined rules you expect to be followed. Your friend needs structure. I created [this](http://imgur.com/8NB95dR) in the same vein your sign. Now I just have to decide if I'll post it. </snippet></document><document><title>(Update) I'm 16, will Planned Parenthood give me a Paragard IUD without parental consent?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uiy0/update_im_16_will_planned_parenthood_give_me_a/</url><snippet>So, I called PP. They have no objections to giving me the Paragard, but there's no sliding scale/financial aid in my state (GA), so it's going to cost me the full $600, even as a minor with no income/insurance. I counted up all the money I have in my room/loose change in my car...comes out to $512.48. I have never wanted $87.52 so badly. Do any of ya'll lovely redditors have any ideas?

Edit: Just opened the today's mail: got $30 from a cousin for a late Christmas present. Awesome, but i'm still $47.52 short

Edit 2: So I think my best bet is to just wait until I can get the last ~$50. This shouldn't be too hard, but it just kinda sucks. Honestly, going through all of this made me realize how important PP funding (or lack thereof!) can be. I'm lucky to live in an upper middle class family, so I shouldn't be complaining much, but I can't imagine how hard it is for women with a low income and a few kids to support to be able to afford birth control. 

Edit 3: So for all of ya'll Atlanta area peeps, does anyone know if the Planned Parenthoods around here offer any sort of financial assistance? When I called, the man said that none of the metro locations offered any sort of financial aid, but I found this on the website of the Midtown PP (it doesn't have this on the Cobb/Gwinnett  pages): "This health center offers a sliding fee scale based on family size, income and student status. This is made possible in part through United Way donations that help us provide prevention services like cancer screenings, STD testing and treatment and birth control."

Now I'm confused
 
Edit 4: Oh my goodness, so many edits! So I just remembered that I get out of school early for a few days next week (term exams), so I might be able to go to the Piedmont Avenue PP next Friday after class. If I'm going to need 2 visits (one for checkup/STD test, one for the actual insertion), could I just go to a closer PP for the initial exam and then bring those forms with me to the Midtown PP (I think they might have a sliding scale option?). Or do I have to do both visits at the same clinic?
  Um... where in Georgia are you? I paid $110 (total) for removal of my old Implanon and insertion of a new Implanon at the PP near Georgia State in Atlanta, because I was a student at the time and PP doesn't accept my insurance. When I got the first one at a private practice gyno, I paid almost $2000. I'm in the Norcross/Peachtree Corners area. I called the Gwinnett PP, and they said it would be the same price for all the locations in metro Atlanta, even though I'm a student If you don't have a job, or do and make very little money, you should also mention that. Maybe the student discount only applies to college students, but PP Midtown definitely provides discounted services unless something has changed drastically in the last year! I mentioned to the person who I talked to over the phone that I didn't have any sort of income and am 16, but apparently it's still $600 regardless of the location The cost difference are probably because Implanon and the IUD you are talking about are not the same thing. Implanon is a hormone bar that goes in your arm. 

Have you considered other options like this as well, especially since it's cheaper? Especially since there seems to be less restrictions about who they give Implanon too compared with IUDs. Unless you're looking for non-hormonal options in which case Implanon wouldn't work. 


edit: is there a particular reason why your can't discuss this with your parents? Other pointed out that if there's complications and you have to go to the hospital things could get really bad.  Um... where in Georgia are you? I paid $110 (total) for removal of my old Implanon and insertion of a new Implanon at the PP near Georgia State in Atlanta, because I was a student at the time and PP doesn't accept my insurance. When I got the first one at a private practice gyno, I paid almost $2000. Oh and I just checked the hours for the Midtown PP. It's not open on Saturday, so that's a huge issue for me, with school and all. It closes at 4:30 every day its open...I don't think I'd be able to make it, with enough time for an appointment, from my school (which Google Maps says is 22 minutes away), even if I leave right after my last class ends (at 3) To answer your last edit, yes, you can just have records of your STD/pregnancy test (they will require a pregnancy test) and pelvic exam transferred to the PP in Midtown. I had my records transferred from a private practice in Memphis. :]

PP Midtown is appointment-only one day a week and otherwise walk-ins only, so make sure to call first. Ah thank you! I plan on calling PP again when I have time. Do you know if the Midtown PP offers a sliding scale? I've gotten conflicting information from the website vs. person at PP who answered my call. They do, but they require proof of income (or lack thereof) and student status to reduce the cost of services. Like I said, my Implanon replacement was $110 at PP Midtown vs $2k at a private practice OB/GYN. What kind of proof of (lack of) income could I bring in? The forms of id I have are: School ID, driver's license, passport, copy of birth certificate, class schedule.  School ID and class schedule should do. I think being a student gets you the cheapest prices available. I brought in a pay stub, but you should be able to just note on the forms they have you fill out that you're unemployed.  Ah thank you! Another stupid question: what sort of things do they ask on the forms you have to fill out? Is it more about your sexual history or identification/income type stuff? Mostly identification/insurance/general medical history. There will be questions about your sexual activity, but those are asked when you go in for a pelvic exam. All pretty easy questions, nothing to worry about! Mostly identification/insurance/general medical history. There will be questions about your sexual activity, but those are asked when you go in for a pelvic exam. All pretty easy questions, nothing to worry about!  Paragard has a built-in Patient Payment Program that allows for monthly payments of $40 or less. Maybe give them a call at 1.877.ParaGard (727.2427) and ask how this works with getting it inserted? I'm sure they'll be glad to help you. I just checked online, and it only looks like it's available through credit/debit card. I only have access to cash, unfortunately I got my first bank account when I was 16. It's totally doable, if that's something you want.

Or, like another comment said, you could try calling a different Planned Parenthood and see if they'll give you a different quote. Honestly I'd feel so much more comfortable using cash. And besides, I don't think you can even open a bank account without parental permission? (I could be wrong on that, though) You don't need parental permission, but some places require a co-signer. I'd give your local bank or credit union a call and ask.

But I understand being more comfortable with cash. I suppose you can wait until you have the full amount saved up (doing odd jobs for neighbors and stuff can help get you there faster). In all honesty, though, a bank account is a good thing to have. Your parents might even help you set one up, since you are at a good age to start thinking about fiscal responsibility and all that. The person who answered the phone said that the price for the IUD is the same for all the metro area Planned Parenthoods?  Sorry, I saw that in your other comment and edited my post.  I am glad it is relatively within your means, that that is extremely mature of you to scrimp and save that much. Good luck getting the last $50, and I hope you can get in quickly after you make it.  I would advise you to wait until you have more than that extra $50. Or, make sure to check with PP to see if they cover follow-up care if something goes wrong. You don't want to be left with the only option being: tell your parents or have major medical problems. I would advise you to wait until you have more than that extra $50. Or, make sure to check with PP to see if they cover follow-up care if something goes wrong. You don't want to be left with the only option being: tell your parents or have major medical problems.  You can get the paraguard on a payment plan!
That's how I got mine as a broke ass college student with no insurance.  I've read about this, but I think it's only available for credit/debit cards. I really only have access to cash   Can I ask why you want the IUD? Because to my understanding, gynecologists generally dont recommend iuds for teenagers. Can I ask why you want the IUD? Because to my understanding, gynecologists generally dont recommend iuds for teenagers. I'm looking for a non hormonal birth control (bad family history of blood clots, strokes) that's long lasting and more effective than condoms and a diaphragm. 
Edit: see my previous posts/comments for reasons why I want it; I appreciate your concern, but I'm aware of the side effects and such :) Oh okay, I see. I dont know what the laws are where you are from, but it might be a bit tricky considering its an iud. But also considering your family history, the gynecologist might deem it as the only option. Also, just a friendly reminder, iuds do not protect you against any stis, which is why I think most gynecologists are reluctant to give them to teenagers.   I called Planned Parenthood and they said they'd absolutely insert one for me, but it's $600. 
And yes, I'm aware of the sti/std issue. I plan on using condoms for a very long time haha Oh thats great. Sorry I guess I was addressing the "would they do it without parental consent question". And glad to hear youre being smart!  Haha yep! I've actually been wanting the IUD for a while, I've just been too chicken to actually go through with it. Now is just the issue of the price ): Yeah. Its really unfortunate that theres so much opposition to free or lowered costs for birth control. Im guessing you can't go through insurance considering you dont want your parents to find out</snippet></document><document><title>Being a grown woman. Am I doing it wrong?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18u7zw/being_a_grown_woman_am_i_doing_it_wrong/</url><snippet>I've been doubting myself for the past few days. I also have no friends to ask (seriously.. haven't spoken to anyone other than family/bf/grocery store people in over a year).

A FB friend made a post asking if it was appropriate for older ladies to wear charm bracelets (she's 33 or 34). She got a ton of responses saying that only if it wasn't "cute" and only if it was made with real metals. Then they had a huge conversation about what was appropriate for older ladies. Only wear dresses and skirts to the knee or below, always have your makeup presentable in public (muted, conservative, classy), never ever wear anything cute, no low rise jeans or anything slouchy in public. The reasoning was that we are mature women and mothers and we don't want to look like we are trying too hard or trying to take attention away from young ladies.

I'm so confused. Now I'm afraid I'm a pathetic loser. I'm 32. I wear video game tshirts, jeans, hoodies, hello kitty shirts, skater tennis shoes. I've been known to try out strange eyeshadows in minimal amounts (hot pink/silver, etc). I play video games and love anything to do with html/css and javascript. I have no desire to start a baby factory. I don't really like going to elegant dinners that use fancy crystal and china.

So am I reaching too hard for my lost youth now that I'm supposedly old or am I chatting with a woman that has a Jackie Kennedy obsession? I've never thought of myself as older and I don't feel all that much different now than I did when I was 18 (except more responsible and no taste for drama).

Edit: 

I am quite happy how I am most of the time. Sometimes I'm very lonely since I've always been the weird one. I'm having trouble finding my peers. I do know what to wear when appropriate and sadly, I'm all too often appropriate.

Thanks for your responses so far. I've been doubting myself bigtime over this. The reason for the doubt is that the girl who started the conversation has always been a little strange, a bit quirky, pretty awesome... she always saw herself as a revolutionary for womens rights and girl power. Things have changed it seems and I need to shift my opinions a little. 

Also, apologies if I came off as hostile for the "baby factory" comment.     Are you happy how you are?  
  
If you said yes, you're not doing it wrong.   I think how you dress affects how other people perceive you. Yes, it's your right to wear jeans, hoodies, Hello Kitty t-shirts, etc., but you will probably be perceived to be younger than you are. I don't really see wearing Hello Kitty shirts and skater sneakers at age 32 to be age-appropriate, but that is my opinion. (I wore stuff like that in junior high.)   As a 32-year-old woman with a giant cardboard cutout of The Little Mermaid on my wall, I know what you mean. 

I do have adult interests and clothing as well, but there's still a lot of things I'm into (which I'm sure a lot of people think I'm too old for) that I've never really outgrown. 

I recently bought myself [this necklace](http://www.thepixelsmithy.com/collections/frontpage/products/skyward-heart) and "Hey, maybe I'm too old to be wearing this" never even crossed my mind until I saw comments on a post where a guy was asking something along the lines of "I'm thinking of getting this for my girlfriend, would you ladies wear something like this?" and there were some saying it's childish and no one should wear heart-shaped jewelry over the age of 12. It kind of baffled me, as I just never think of things that way; I either like something or I don't, you know?

I have noticed that this not-a-"Real-Grownup" thing is actually pretty common with people around our age, though. My best friend, who is also 32, is the same way, as are a few of my other friends.
  </snippet></document><document><title>Does anyone here have any experience with all-women gyms? I want to know if it's really a better experience than a unisex gym.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v30x/does_anyone_here_have_any_experience_with/</url><snippet>  Well, the only women only gym I can think of off the top of my head is Curves, which is little more than a designated napping station.  My gym had a women only section, fully equipped with dumbbells, power rack, barbells, and it was awesome because it was usually empty.  So it depends on your reasons for joining a women only gym, because a lot of them focus on ineffective cardio.   there's a privately owned gym in my town, where one of my friends works. it seems like a nice place, and all the staff members seem like they try to incorporate you into their community, make you feel at home, and encourage you to be healthy. 
 What kind of equipment do they have, and what kind of exercise are you planning on doing there? yknow, all the basics for cardio, a lot of weight machines and free weights, a buncha water aerobic stuffs.... possibly more. they also have a yoga area with mats and all that. they seemed to have all the basic gym stuff plus some extra.

i basically want to get in shape. i used to be about 30 lbs lighter with much more muscle on me. i climbed mountains, dude. then the obligatory post break up depression shit happened, so now i'm in the 'i want to look good in a bikini again' phase. Well, the only women only gym I can think of off the top of my head is Curves, which is little more than a designated napping station.  My gym had a women only section, fully equipped with dumbbells, power rack, barbells, and it was awesome because it was usually empty.  So it depends on your reasons for joining a women only gym, because a lot of them focus on ineffective cardio.   Ineffective cardio? I think they mean that curves is set up as a circuit where you're really almost encouraged to wander round the circuit peddling gently on the bikes or jumping gently on the mini trampoline while chatting to other ladies on the circuit, all without breaking a sweat. It's really not a great set up.   </snippet></document><document><title>Experiencing horrible mood swings during period for first time ever, help?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v2pf/experiencing_horrible_mood_swings_during_period/</url><snippet>I've been on BC (the pill) for roughly six years and I've never had any problems, but suddenly the aches and the mood swings are hitting me with a vengeance. I'm at a complete loss here, having never dealt with this, and I'm tired of lashing out at my wonderful boyfriend (who understands what I'm going through but can only take so much), so I turn to you guys for advice...

How do I manage the mood swings? They've started turning into arguments where I'll attack everything before I even realize it, and it's getting old :/ I don't want to lose my relationship over this, but since I've never dealt with it I have no idea what to do.   I also get really bad mood swings on my period, usually only when I'm off the pill. But my last period was bad (I was randomly inexplicably depressed for a week before), even though I've been on the pill for months. Anyway, my mom can always tell if I've gone off my birth control because I randomly get extra snappy and weepy for a a week. So I can kinda relate.


Have you had any large physical/mental stresses lately that might change your hormones? Either way, you might talk to your doctor about switching to another birth control. They can have different effects. I was once on a birth control that basically made me bipolar. Current bc has mixed results. At any rate a new bc with different levels of hormones might help even things out.


The next step, which it sounds like you may have already taken, would be a mix of awareness/communication. If you aren't aware of the moodswings coming on, chart your period so you can prepare for their arrival. Do something nice with your boyfriend before or after to help patch things up. Let him know when your period is coming and the moodswings are likely to start so he can be prepared. Remove yourself from the room before fights break out, even if its just to go cry bitterly somewhere else. If you have enough awareness to say, ok, this is a moodswing, tell your boyfriend that. And definitely try to remove yourself before you say things you regret.


If you've already done stuff like this, and its not working, and you really find you can't reign yourself in when you're affected, its possible that you could take some medication only during your period to help smooth your nerves. That of course would be something to talk to your doctor about, but its possible that an anti anxiety or anti depressant could help cool you down when you can't do it naturally.


Good luck, and keep working on it! It's odd - I've never had the mood swings before, it's part of why I'm so confused.

I've been under a lot of mental stress (and physical stress has been existent for the past few months now due to getting an virus that nearly killed me) and relocating home. I'm going to a gyno on Friday and I pretty much have to switch pills since the one I'm on isn't sold in the states (Marvelon), and I was thinking about maybe asking for a triphasic one instead.

I generally haven't had issues with periods in the past, but my boyfriend always knows when I'm going to give myself one (BC-induced) but I generally haven't had problems with side effects before.

I tell him that I'm having moodswings, but it's not like I can just unsay something that I've already said, so it doesn't quite make a difference :| If I say something rude, he takes it as something rude. I've been working on trying to leave the room before I say something I'll regret, but it's difficult. He's under a lot of stress as well, and that's maybe why I worry about things.

Thanks for the advice!  my cycle was as you describe yours.  when i started having a 'real' period i soon discovered i had uterine cancer.  not being an alarmist but do think about having a smear done soon.   I can't tell you how to make them go away but I can help with how to deal with mood swings. I tend to have a few days each month where my normal anxiety skyrockets and I become a huge ball of paranoid insecurity. I wish I were exaggerating when I say it feels like my world is falling down around me. I'm bipolar anyways so throw hormones into the mix and I lose it. For me, simply telling myself that my period is about to start and that my anxiety is because of it helps a lot. I have to remind myself often that these thoughts aren't real, these feelings are from my hormones and not real life events and that I will be able to handle things a lot better in a couple days. Give yourself a break and treat yourself nice. 

The first comment gave great advice on how to treat your boyfriend. Apologize if you over react and don't be afraid to tell him what's going on with you. When I'm feeling extra insecure on those days, I have no problem asking my boyfriend to tell me something sweet. He understands there are days I need extra love and your boyfriend will too. 

Honestly, mood swings are a daily battle for me. Random irritability, sad tears, happy tears, anxiety...I might as well be pms'ing all the time. I've picked up a lot of tricks over the years dealing with them and if you'd like to hear more, please pm me! </snippet></document><document><title>Democratic lawmaker apologizes for suggesting women afraid of rape can't be trusted with guns</title><url>http://dailycaller.com/2013/02/18/democratic-lawmaker-apologizes-for-suggesting-women-afraid-of-rape-cant-be-trusted-with-guns/</url><snippet>  Anyone who is overly paranoid about anything should not have a gun. Anyone who is overly aggressive should not either. so a girl who is afraid of getting raped is paranoid...? Seems like focusing on rape as an issue is a huge waste of time then. &amp;gt;so a girl who is afraid of getting raped is paranoid...?

Not necessarily, but if it's dark and you think someone's following you, there's a good chance you're going to be pretty scared, if not terrified. Whether you're afraid of being mugged or raped or murdered, you're probably not thinking 100% clearly in that moment.

Now, depending on where you are and when it is and what you look like and are built like--be you man or woman--the actual chance of you being raped, mugged, or murdered can be very high or very low. If it's very low, and your first response to hearing footsteps behind you is to think, "Oh my god, I'm about to be raped/robbed/killed," then you might be a bit paranoid, and, in the andrenaline-filled moments while every possible awful occurrence runs through your head, you might make a mistake and shoot someone who isn't really following you or a bystander.

Mistakes like that can and do happen both at the hands of men and women for various reasons. I think the fact that this guy singled out women and rape specifically (was he responding to someone) isn't right, but I think his point that just handing out guns as a main method of defense isn't logical or safe. so a girl who is afraid of getting raped is paranoid...? Seems like focusing on rape as an issue is a huge waste of time then. Anyone who is that worried they are going to be raped in a specific enough fashion to seek out a firearm and carry it at all times clearly is either doing things that could be considered unwise (i.e. wandering the streets of a third-world country at night alone - you should be able to do that, but statistics are a bitch sometimes. I don't want to blame victims, but neither do we live in a perfect world) or is responding to a serious threat (i.e. a stalker that should be handled by police) or is possibly paranoid. If the first case, fine, carry the firearm.  If the second, let the police handle it - fear is far more likely to make you react badly in a situation than to help you get through it. And in the third case, again, I think you're more likely to react badly. 

It has nothing to do with rape, and everything to do with panic and fear. I don't want someone shooting who hasn't assessed the situation with a level head, and it sounds like that's what this guy was saying. It's the same reason I think concealed carry on college campuses is a dumb idea - it's far more likely to result in some hungover kid freaking out when someone drops a textbook.  &amp;gt; If the first case, fine, carry the firearm

So you agree that they have their merits in self-defense, if in the first case, why not in the others? It doesn't become any less effective at preventing rape in the other cases. 

Of course it would be foolish to fire at someone because you *think* they might rape you, no sane person would do that - and to assume all women are inclined to do that is to assume they act irrationally and purely on emotion, if this were the case, than their right to vote should be rescinded - I'm sure we can both agree this isn't the case. You can't simultaneously paint women as helpless victims who are too reckless to know when and when not to shoot someone, and argue that they are just as capable as men in other fields. I choose to believe that they are as capable.

Ideally the firearm could be used as a deterrent, without even firing, or once it is clear a sexual assault is about to take place. If you don't want to be responsible for your own self-defense than maybe you should find a man who will do it for you, or hire armed security guards - because the police aren't going to be everywhere all the time.

The whole reason chivalry died is because women said they didn't need men to defend them anymore, so prove it.

&amp;gt; it's far more likely to result in some hungover kid freaking out when someone drops a textbook. 

Do you have any evidence to support this, Colorado has had it for quite some time and I don't think this has ever happened, but even if it did it would be the case of an individually acting irrationally, this does not mean others should have their rights revoked. You have clearly never handled a firearm, if your only experience with them is through Hollywood propaganda and the mainstream media you might think that people just fire without thinking, but that is not the case. If you are terrified of firearms then the media is doing its job. &amp;gt;You have clearly never handled a firearm, if your only experience with them is through Hollywood propaganda and the mainstream media you might think that people just fire without thinking, but that is not the case.

Based on this and your previous statements, you have clearly never studied psychology or sociology. Humans, even "sane" humans, frequently act irrationally, particularly when afraid. This irrationality doesn't always lead to a death or injury or property damage, but it does fairly often.

Giving everyone a deadly weapon that can kill from relatively long distances and encouraging the mindset that one can just "point this at bad people to make them go away" or "you need this potentially lethal weapon to be safe" can be dangerous. 

There are plenty of level-headed, responsible gun-owners, and there are plenty who aren't.</snippet></document><document><title>Alternative to Bras</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18udd6/alternative_to_bras/</url><snippet>So hey,

As the title suggests I am looking for an alternative to Bras, I'm not big chested, but I do kinda have to wear one. Google has come up with no results.

Any suggestions?

UPDATE: Bought a bandeau, I have to admit, I love love loooooooove it. it feels comfortable and it almost feels like I'm braless. Thank you 2x!   Depending on how much support you're looking for, a bandeau top or camisole with built-in shelf bra (just a band of elastic, no underwire or cups) could work.

Curious though, why do you "kinda have to" wear one? They're small, but they bounce when I walk down stairs, jiggle when I cut food and generally the little fuckers won't stay still. They're small, but they bounce when I walk down stairs, jiggle when I cut food and generally the little fuckers won't stay still. Do you pass the [pencil test?](http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Pencil+Test) The pencil test is really dumb and useless, in my opinion. You can still bounce and need a bra even if your boobs are self-supporting. The pencil test is really dumb and useless, in my opinion. You can still bounce and need a bra even if your boobs are self-supporting. Do you pass the [pencil test?](http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Pencil+Test)  You could try sports bras if you're looking for an escape from a traditional bra. kallisti_gold suggested a cami or a bandeau top, but depending on their shape and everything that may not stop the jounce when you're making quick movements.    [Bandinis!](http://www.amazon.com/Barely-There-CustomFlex-Fit-Bandini/dp/B008LWHH9G/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1361311164&amp;amp;sr=8-7&amp;amp;keywords=bandini)

I have a couple without foam. Seamless, versatile (can be worn with straps on shoulders or down as strapless), and sooo very comfortable. [Bandinis!](http://www.amazon.com/Barely-There-CustomFlex-Fit-Bandini/dp/B008LWHH9G/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1361311164&amp;amp;sr=8-7&amp;amp;keywords=bandini)

I have a couple without foam. Seamless, versatile (can be worn with straps on shoulders or down as strapless), and sooo very comfortable. [Bandinis!](http://www.amazon.com/Barely-There-CustomFlex-Fit-Bandini/dp/B008LWHH9G/ref=sr_1_7?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1361311164&amp;amp;sr=8-7&amp;amp;keywords=bandini)

I have a couple without foam. Seamless, versatile (can be worn with straps on shoulders or down as strapless), and sooo very comfortable.  Camisoles with shelf bras can be a good alternative. Why don't you like bras? I just find them awkward. Are you sure you're wearing the right size? I found bras horrible, uncomfortable and a general pain in the ass before I found out I was wearing bras that didn't even come close to fitting properly. Now I don't even realize I'm wearing one most of the time. :) Probably, but I dunno about getting a fitting. Check out r/abrathatfits! The ladies there will help you out and I believe they have a fitting guide on the sidebar. Also, if you go somewhere like Nordstrom, they'll fit you and it's not terribly awkward or anything. Protip: if you type a "/" before the subreddit, you get a link! /r/abrathatfits :) Probably, but I dunno about getting a fitting. Probably, but I dunno about getting a fitting. Victoria's Secret and most department stores will do them for free.  And they do like, twenty a day, so for them, it's just another set of boobs.  And they don't squeeze them or anything, they just use a tape measure and don't even really touch you. Sadly, Victoria's Secret is rather famous for putting people into bras that are the wrong size. So I wouldn't recommend going there for a fitting :( Victoria's Secret and most department stores will do them for free.  And they do like, twenty a day, so for them, it's just another set of boobs.  And they don't squeeze them or anything, they just use a tape measure and don't even really touch you. Victoria's Secret and most department stores will do them for free.  And they do like, twenty a day, so for them, it's just another set of boobs.  And they don't squeeze them or anything, they just use a tape measure and don't even really touch you.          A sports type bra? Duct tape? Comes in many colors and I even saw some hello Kitty duct tape at Walgreens the other day....

Other than that just the camis and t-shirts with the built in support as mentioned already. Oh..tank type bikini tops? </snippet></document><document><title>50 Years After "The Feminine Mystique": Are You Better Off Than Your Grandmother?</title><url>http://www.glamour.com/inspired/2013/02/the-feminine-mystique-50-years-after-its-debut</url><snippet>  Oh come *on*.  All of the things in the list that is supposed to make it seem as if we are on par or worse off than our grandmother's are actually positives:

1) Women work more but have difficulties with maternity leave in the US.  Well at least we aren't fired on our wedding day or after popping out our first kid, like was oh-so-common with our grandmothers.

2) "We've turned mothering into a comparable sport" where we are now expected to research our child's upbringing.  Isn't it terrible how nowadays we have access to a variety of options, instead of being expected to pop out a baby while under general anesthesia, are then told by the doctor that breastfeeding is bad for our children so good mothers must shell out for formula?  Oh, and your baby is likely suffering from unknown problems due to the cigarettes you smoked and alcohol you drank during your pregnancy, since no one had a problem with that back in the day.  Yeah, how terrible that mothers now have access to quality information and lots of different opinions!

3) "Our access to reproductive care is under siege."  Why is this even a point?  In the 50's and 60's, abortion WAS illegal, and you often had to be married to access birth control.  Oh, and the earliest forms of hormonal birth control were EXCESSIVELY strong and caused many deaths due to interactions with smoking (everyone smoked).

4) "The wage gap persists."  And, as the article says, is MUCH better than it was back in the day.

I AM better off than my grandmother.  Especially since both of my grandmother's died tragically at young ages: one from a lethal combination of heavy smoking and the first hormonal birth control pill (heart attack at 44).  That woman also raised 4 children single-handedly without child support from the deadbeat dad, who she had dropped out of college to marry (very common at the time).  

My other grandmother killed herself after the death of her husband in a mine (due to lenient safety standards of the time), when she found herself unable to get a job in Utah despite her college education because of her children, in addition to suffering from bipolar disorder which, at the time, was only treatable with electroshock therapy.

Frankly I find the insinuation that I may not be better off than them, due to what are, in the grand scheme of things, minor setbacks to be insulting to everyone involved.  Insulting to my grandmothers who suffered terrible tragedy in their short lives, insulting to my parents who worked hard to raise their daughters with more egalitarian values, and insulting to me, who has a pretty damn good life thanks to everyone who helped bring me here.

/rant Oh come *on*.  All of the things in the list that is supposed to make it seem as if we are on par or worse off than our grandmother's are actually positives:

1) Women work more but have difficulties with maternity leave in the US.  Well at least we aren't fired on our wedding day or after popping out our first kid, like was oh-so-common with our grandmothers.

2) "We've turned mothering into a comparable sport" where we are now expected to research our child's upbringing.  Isn't it terrible how nowadays we have access to a variety of options, instead of being expected to pop out a baby while under general anesthesia, are then told by the doctor that breastfeeding is bad for our children so good mothers must shell out for formula?  Oh, and your baby is likely suffering from unknown problems due to the cigarettes you smoked and alcohol you drank during your pregnancy, since no one had a problem with that back in the day.  Yeah, how terrible that mothers now have access to quality information and lots of different opinions!

3) "Our access to reproductive care is under siege."  Why is this even a point?  In the 50's and 60's, abortion WAS illegal, and you often had to be married to access birth control.  Oh, and the earliest forms of hormonal birth control were EXCESSIVELY strong and caused many deaths due to interactions with smoking (everyone smoked).

4) "The wage gap persists."  And, as the article says, is MUCH better than it was back in the day.

I AM better off than my grandmother.  Especially since both of my grandmother's died tragically at young ages: one from a lethal combination of heavy smoking and the first hormonal birth control pill (heart attack at 44).  That woman also raised 4 children single-handedly without child support from the deadbeat dad, who she had dropped out of college to marry (very common at the time).  

My other grandmother killed herself after the death of her husband in a mine (due to lenient safety standards of the time), when she found herself unable to get a job in Utah despite her college education because of her children, in addition to suffering from bipolar disorder which, at the time, was only treatable with electroshock therapy.

Frankly I find the insinuation that I may not be better off than them, due to what are, in the grand scheme of things, minor setbacks to be insulting to everyone involved.  Insulting to my grandmothers who suffered terrible tragedy in their short lives, insulting to my parents who worked hard to raise their daughters with more egalitarian values, and insulting to me, who has a pretty damn good life thanks to everyone who helped bring me here.

/rant  </snippet></document><document><title>I think I just made a mildly large mistake</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18tuzm/i_think_i_just_made_a_mildly_large_mistake/</url><snippet>So I have a rather thick, but very translucently pale lady-stache.  Today I finally got tired of it so I just shaved it off but now my upper lip is all stubbly and I can FEEL the razor-rash starting and I am convinced that I've made a huge mistake.  So, how often will I have to keep shaving the 'stache, and are there any tips for keeping it as unnoticeable as possible? I have really, really sensitive skin so I'm scared to wax it but should I?  Or are there other products I can use?    [deleted] [deleted]  I think you're fine.  I wouldn't recommend shaving the ladystache, but since you've got pale hair, it won't look stubbly coming back in.  In the future, I'd say to just wax it.  I use a hard wax (specifically, I love Parissa's hard wax) and find that it causes less irritation than strip wax.  I wouldn't use a hair removal cream for fear of irritation, but it's an option. Thank you so much! I will probably head out and grab some hard wax soon. I've never waxed before, though.  Is it really difficult to do correctly? Not super hard.  The hair has to be long enough (so if you just shaved it, you might need to wait a week).  I smear the wax with the grain of the hair, then pull it off in the opposite direction.  If there's still hair left, I do it the other way.  You can also get pre-waxed strips, but I find that my skin is slightly more irritated by those than the hard wax. Thank you so much! I will probably head out and grab some hard wax soon. I've never waxed before, though.  Is it really difficult to do correctly? I'd say do a test run on your leg first. It's defiantly not hard to do correctly but the leg is the easiest place to do it and there will be less of a chance to screw up.  I'd say do a test run on your leg first. It's defiantly not hard to do correctly but the leg is the easiest place to do it and there will be less of a chance to screw up.  Thank you so much! I will probably head out and grab some hard wax soon. I've never waxed before, though.  Is it really difficult to do correctly? Thank you so much! I will probably head out and grab some hard wax soon. I've never waxed before, though.  Is it really difficult to do correctly?     As another lady with sensitive skin and unwanted ladystache, I feel like I should warn you against depilatories.  Even the ones that say they are gentle enough for the face messed me up.  The only thing worse than a moustache is the telltale chemical burn on your upper lip. It's a red, painful  billboard announcing "I have stubborn upper lip hair!" Yeah, that's pretty much what terrifies me.  I tried waxing once (on my leg) and that erupted into a HUGE awful rash.  However, I think the wax was scented which probably set me off.  Yeah, that's pretty much what terrifies me.  I tried waxing once (on my leg) and that erupted into a HUGE awful rash.  However, I think the wax was scented which probably set me off.       /r/thegirlsurvivalguide probably has something on this     Laser surgery. It's way cheaper and getting way more popular. Only a few sessions and it'll be gone! Does it work on really fine hair? I heard that it works only on thicker and darker hair.    I have always been told not to shave facial hair, that it makes it tough and easier to see, don't know if that is true or not. I just have a little electric facial trimmer that works most of the time. Then I probably wax about every other month, if not longer. Hurts like a bitch though. You don't change how the hair grows when you shave, but you do cut the hair off at the base where it's thicker.  Hair that's had a while to come in contact with the outside world ends up tapered and finer, but if you shave regularly the whole length of the hair stays the same thickness as the base.

Rereading that is kind of confusing, am I making sense?</snippet></document><document><title>After a few weeks of research and debating, I had my Paragard IUD consultation today! They went ahead and measured my uterus, too, so I know what that feels like now. TL;DR: Not bad! Details inside.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uekt/after_a_few_weeks_of_research_and_debating_i_had/</url><snippet>Posing here instead of /r/birthcontrol because lots of ladies may not know about /r/birthcontrol. But now you do, and they could always use more traffic! So go check it out :).

**BACKGROUND**

*or, Why I Began Considering An IUD In The First Place*

I'm 23 and have never been pregnant. I've been on hormonal oral contraceptives since I was 16 or 17 (can't remember exactly when I started), and overall, I haven't had a terrible experience with them. The brand I take is Necon, and it makes my period super light (almost nonexistent), no emotional issues like anxiety or depression, no problems with breakouts or anything.

The main reason I started looking into IUDs at first was that I'm having trouble taking my pill on time consistently these days. I just went back to school full time and am working two jobs with weird/inconsistent hours (I'm a substitute teacher and a club volleyball coach), and because of those things I've got two gym bags, a regular purse, a school backpack, and a teaching bag. The result is that I may or may not be in the middle of something that I can't stop in order to go take my pill on any given day, and if I didn't remember to switch which bag my pack was in that morning, I'm screwed even if I do have a moment to take it. The final straw was when boyf and I had sex, and I realized the next morning that I'd missed my most recent pill and had to go buy a dose of Next Choice (another brand of emergency contraceptive like Plan B). It scared me, and I decided I needed to look into a more reliable option&#8212;especially when I realized that any contraceptive option I wanted would be completely covered by my insurance (yay, Affordable Care Act!).

**WHY PARAGARD**

The more I read up on living hormone-free, the more I was intrigued. My libido on my current HBC is straight up zero. I think my boyfriend is the sexiest man on the planet in every way, and I *still* don't enjoy sex until we're already into it. I remember having a higher drive before being on HBC, and I want it back. Plus, I have had a small amount of weight gain with the HBC that just won't go away, and my breasts grow at least two cup sizes every single cycle and then shrink again, which is incredibly painful and destroys all my bras. Finally, there's the mental side of living with synthetic hormones&#8212;something I hadn't even realized might be affecting me until I read more firsthand accounts over on /r/birthcontrol and other places like IUD Divas. Women were recounting the sudden disappearance of a "grayness" or "apathy cloud" (the most common descriptors), which some didn't even realize had been there until it was gone. That really resonated with me, and makes me wonder if synthetic hormones are behind some of my, "I just don't feel like it's always been this way," things that, until now, I'd attributed to just getting a bit older. Things rarely get me super excited like I remember getting in the past, I'm more negative about my body even though objectively I know it hasn't changed all that much, and other things of that nature that I just can't shake. Certainly not debilitating things, not things that I couldn't just brush off for years with relatively little issue. But things I would very much enjoy living without nonetheless.

**THE CONSULTATION AND SOUNDING**

So, last week I called a new OB-GYN (wasn't all that pleased with my other one, decided now would be a good time to switch) and went in for a consultation this afternoon. The nurse was wonderful, gave me all kinds of advice and assurances, and said, "She [the doctor] might even just put it in today, if you want." I was a little surprised by that, because I've read that the insertion experience can be incredibly intense and painful for some women, and I wasn't on any painkillers or my period (when insertion is easiest), and I needed to drive myself home. The nurse said that was fine and I was welcome to call when my next cycle started and they'd fit me in then, but that the doctor would probably go ahead and measure me today to make sure the IUD would fit. I agreed that was a good idea, but I was nervous&#8212;some people say the sounding (measuring) was even worse than the insertion itself.

Well, I have to say...it really wasn't bad. Like, at all. And I don't mean to discredit anyone for whom it was incredibly painful, but I want to put it out there that it isn't so bad for everyone! I cramped a little afterwards for maybe an hour, meant to take an Ibuprofen when I got home, and honestly forgot to (I'm sure the cramps after the actual insertion will be a whole other animal, though). It certainly wasn't *comfortable,* but it sort of just felt like an extended pap&#8212;that split second cramp you feel with a pap, but for maybe 15 seconds instead of an instant. A few deep breaths, and it was over. My legs were a bit shaky afterwards, but that was honestly due to my nerves, not the sounding. I sat up almost immediately and drove home just fine. My pain tolerance is pretty high, but I'd still only give it a 4.5 on a 10 scale.

**INSERTION PLANS**

Despite my being optimistic about the insertion, I'm still going to take some Ibuprofen beforehand, have it done while on my period (next week!), and my boyfriend is going to drive me there and back home, just in case. I'm also going to make the appointment when I'll have the rest of the day to recover, though my nurse and doctor said they think I'll be fine. What I'm more nervous about is that first period with the IUD in...it's supposed to be hell in a handbasket for some women, and that can continue for even the first year of periods thereafter. But what really struck me is that, even in reading all those stories, those same women almost all still loved and recommended the Paragard. So even if mine are awful, I'm committing to giving my body at least a year to adjust before I'll consider giving up.

That's it! If there's interest, I'll post an update after my actual insertion, again after my first period with it, and if any other developments occur. Feel free to AMA, I'll check in every once in a while.

**TL;DR**

Needed lower-maintenance contraception than the pill, did a lot of research and decided to ditch synthetic hormones, got sounded for a Paragard IUD today and it wasn't bad, insertion in a week or so, will update!  The nurse who put mine in said that the sounding is supposed to be the most painful part, but I found that the forceps were the worst. But even so, it didn't feel any more intense than some really bad cramps.

After I got mine in, I had occasional "waves" of bad cramping, but they passed after 10-20 seconds, usually. The weirdest part was feeling like there was SOMETHING INSIDE ME and that I needed to push it out. That only lasted a day though, thank goodness. :)  How is your overall pain tolerance? Mine is overall pretty low. Had my Paraguard consultation about 18 months ago, everything went well, but the actual procedure was extremely painful. I had it done during my period and I took some painkillers beforehand as well. I had to get a shot of morphine afterwards because I was still in so much pain after they cleared out of there. The cramping after the initial insertion disappeared a few hours later, and it took about 2-3 months to adjust to the intermittent cramping and spotting.


Not trying to scare you at all, just wanted to share my experience. Every second of that procedure was worth it, and it sounds like you are super prepared in case the procedure ends up sucking for you, too. Good luck! And yes, please post an update! My pain tolerance is actually pretty high, I think, so that may have contributed to my thinking it wasn't that bad. I might be eating my words after the actual insertion though! So glad to hear it's worth it! If your pain tolerance is pretty high, then it sounds to me like you should be just fine. There's always a chance it might hurt worse than you think, but the reality is that the procedure takes like 5, maybe 7 minutes *tops*. It'll be over before you know it. Thanks for the reassurance! I agree, I think I'll be alright :).  I also have a high pain threshold but I took 800mg prior to my insertion. It wasn't bad at all, though I guess I made up for it not two weeks later when I experienced terrible abdominal pain and got sent to the ER...? My physician was worried it was perforating. It wasn't, though; my uterus was just throwing an epic temper tantrum. That little jerk.

Sorry, I don't mean to scare you. Just letting you know that random pains are evidently pretty normal for the first little while afterward. I didn't know this -- I'd only heard that PERIODS could be painful, not that you could get random and pretty excruciating pains otherwise -- so I figured I'd pass that knowledge along. And know that, yep, despite this episode, I'm still pretty happy with my IUD. :)

Anyhoo, congrats on your upcoming Paragard. Watcha gonna name it? Take it from me: name it something happy and innocent. I named mine T-Pain and, well, you see where that got me. ;)

P.S. Even though you said you didn't have any huge issues on HBC, being off hormones is AWESOME!!! I totally experienced the apathy thing and was only aware of how bad it was once I was off (and before then, I was already pretty aware of it). I also had terribad mood swings (including depression), weight gain, etc... and I didn't *think* I'd experienced a dip in drive until I was off the 'mones and I couldn't stop trying to mate my friendboy *all the time*... Yikes! That sounds scary indeed. Good to know to expect random pain spurts...I'll be sure to keep some ibuprofen on hand for a while! I'll have to think of a good name, I'm a sucker for puns so I love T-Pain, but perhaps I shouldn't tempt fate. Happy and innocent it will be :).

I am so, SO excited to be off the synthetic hormones! I was hanging out with two girlfriends just last night, and they both quit the pill and were just glowing over how much doing so improved their quality of life. They weren't familiar with Paragard, though, so they've been using condoms/pulling out, and they both are excited to see how it goes for me and are thinking about giving it a try! And yes yes yes, I know that deep down inside there's a part of me that wants to jump my boyf like a goddamn rabbit, and I can't wait to feel it! By the way, evidently this pain was a cramp. It just didn't feel like a normal cramp. Apparently, the IUD's presence can make it feel quite different. I read the following quote in an archived topic earlier today and laughed 'cause it's so right:

"However, I do still get really bad cramps before my period, but it really is a different kind of cramp. Since your lil uterus is cramping onto the IUD in there, you can sometimes get sharp pains that echo throughout your entire body like the battle cry of a thousand demons."

...but! Most people report that this type of pain lessens or even goes away anywhere from three months to a year post-insertion. You may never have to experience it at all.

Best of luck and let us know how everything goes!</snippet></document><document><title>"ugly old lady hates pretty princess" if the comments had been made by Simon Schama, would anyone have noticed?</title><url>http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2013/feb/19/hilary-mantel-duchess-cambridge-scandal</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Ireland apologises for 'slave labour' at Magdalene Laundries. Taoiseach Enda Kenny forced into finally saying sorry for 'the hurt and trauma' caused to up to 10,000 Magdalene women</title><url>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/feb/19/ireland-apologises-slave-labour-magdalene-laundries</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Any advice for organizing/planning a bachelorette party?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uavw/any_advice_for_organizingplanning_a_bachelorette/</url><snippet>I (F24) was asked to be in the wedding of an old college roommate(F25) of mine and I accepted. There are seven bridesmaids.The other bridesmaids are her older sister that lives 2  hrs away (she is pretty shy and quiet) the grooms 3 sisters (two are in HS and one is 25) and two other friends from college. 

Typical wedding stuff is not really my thing but I know that the bride is going to want the whole sha-bang (wedding veil.. penis decorations.. all that junk). As her older sister is pretty shy/ I think would have no idea what she is doing... I'm going to offer to throw the bachelorette party. I guess I'm just looking for advice.

My ideas so far are to plan a dinner that the underage bridesmaids can attend and we can also open any gifts that people may have gotten her. I was thinking of getting either a couple hotel rooms or a suite that we can all have a couple pre bar cocktails at and also have a place to crash at the end of the night. **First question:** As a poor just graduated college lady is it okay to ask people to chip in for the hotel? What is the best way to handle that situation?

**Second question:** Should I have a theme or is that lame?
**Last question:** Any other input and ideas you lovely ladies could provide?    </snippet></document><document><title>Gender Through Comic Books, a free on line course that some of you may like.</title><url>https://www.canvas.net/courses/gender-through-comic-books</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Sherry Argov's "Bitches" Books.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v9jk/sherry_argovs_bitches_books/</url><snippet>I've recently started seeing a counselor for anxiety and general depression and I think just as a 'go to' recommendation for any of her female patients, she recommends they read two books. Why Men Love Bitches and Why Men Marry Bitches. Luckily my friend (also a patient of hers) owns them, so I borrowed them. I was able to skim through the both of them in under two hours and.. I'm not sure, I guess, what to make of them.

A bit of background. I've been in a stable/committed relationship for almost 3 years and it seems like all the 'advice' from these books is for someone who is single, or in my opinion, a girl who just got her first crush/first period (imho: that's really the only people I'd find getting use from this book). 

A lot of the advice seems to basically just be "be someone you're not,  fake being interesting and disinterested in him so that he'll come crawling to you". Now maybe these books have genuinely helped people but to me it seems like the same old self-help hoopla. 

I've been in my fair share of relationships, and not once did I ever really think I needed to turn to making myself fakely unavailable or disinterested would really help or even remotely be my cup of tea. I've always dealt with relationships in the same manner, and maybe I'm not the target audience for this book at all... Most because I always thought if you need a book to teach you how to find someone who loves you (but not you because remember you're basically lying about who you are and how you act) then buy some cats.

Lots of cats

Any opinions?  If you trust your counselor, maybe it is worth it giving the books a real chance, by which I mean a thoughtful considered read instead of just skimming.  If you don't trust your counselor, maybe you should give up on the books and find someone new to talk to.

I heard about Neil Strauss's book The Game and how objectionable it was on some talk show.  I read the book myself and was surprised that it was actually insightful (if unrealistic).  The characters in the book learn how to pick up women through a variety of mind games and begin exploiting their knowledge.  What happens as a result though is that they become depressed and unfulfilled, their shallow relationships are based on tricks and systematic deceit.  They can get what they want in terms of sex, but only by becoming someone fundamentally different and putting on an act.

I wonder two things about your "Bitches" series.  Is it concealing what may be a more meaningful message underneath a tawdry veneer?  Is any rules based system for approaching and managing relationships inherently prone to the same weaknesses that Strauss discusses in The Game?</snippet></document><document><title>Any girls good with words that could help me out??</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ughg/any_girls_good_with_words_that_could_help_me_out/</url><snippet>My niece and I are surprising my sister with a vow renewal "ceremony" before their anniversary dinner in a few weeks.  She has wanted to do this for several years and it always gets pushed back.  This being a big year, we want her to finally have vows renewed!  We want to keep it short, but I desperately need some ideas for what to have my niece say (she's "officiating").  I've looked everywhere online for ideas but it's just vows and everything is very generic.  I need something to start the "ceremony" with that makes sense coming from their daughter and some short renewal vows.  Does anyone have any suggestions?  I've never done anything like this so I'm open to anything! :)  


In case it helps... this is their 20th anniversary and my niece is 17.  I'd be happy to fill in anything else if it helps too!  Why don't you have your niece write it? Something short and sweet and personal will mean much more to your sister than something a stranger on the Internet can come up with. And who knows them better than their own child?   Look for anniversary toasts, as good examples.  But yes, personal from the daughter is always best.

A favorite poem, maybe?  "All throughout my childhood, a little girl playing with barbies and dreaming of princesses and the "happily ever after", I have assumed that love and romance meant one thing.... Being the perfect bride and meeting the perfect man who gives you the world. Everyone dreams of this, I think. As I grew up I learned and realized that this is NOT what true love is about. In 17 years I have seen my parents fight, cry, laugh, smile and even play wrestle, and nothing has become more clear to me. THIS is true love. Being REAL people. Not being the perfect husband or wife, but being the one to tell you are wrong, and then being the one to help you get it right. He might tell her the outfit doesn't quite work, but then he will be the one to help pick the dress that makes her feel beautiful. She will nag at the football game he wants to watch, but she will snuggle up next to him and ask questions to show her interest in HIM. It is not about finding the perfect person and marrying them, it has been about finding their perfect companion and being ABLE to spend every day with them. My mom and my dad still light up when they are together. Maybe they can't see the light all the time, but for 17 years, I have been blinded by it. As they renew their vows today, I want them to know how comforting it feels to know that true love still exists and marriage CAN last. I'm so happy for them both and wish them their own personal happily ever after."
Ill let you borrow this if you want ;) This is perfect!!! I sent it to her and she loves it. It inspired her to add her own memories and that's exactly what I needed to get her started. I wish I was better at that stuff. :) Thank you!!</snippet></document><document><title>Close female friend in jail...any tips/experiences?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18u5t1/close_female_friend_in_jailany_tipsexperiences/</url><snippet>Hi there ladies,

I'm going to keep this one brief since I have to attend an arrangement; I will expound more details later. But, basically, a close female friend of mine is about halfway through a 30 day jail sentence for her second DUI. I have gotten the chance to visit her, and she seems to be in ok spirits, but I am still obviously a bit upset at the whole situation. So, I am curious: have any of you ladies been to jail? If so, what would you look forward to? Putting yourself in my friend's shoes, is there anything you would want someone to visit you to do? Thank you so much for your help, it means a lot!
  Honestly, if it was my friend spending time in jail for their second DUI, I'd let them simmer for the duration. Maybe I'd visit if it was one of my more fragile friends, but I'd make it clear, if it wasn't already, that they made a highly stupid choice and are exactly where they should be. 

If it were me in there, I wouldn't want to see anyone, my shame would be pretty weighty. But, that's just me. Honestly, if it was my friend spending time in jail for their second DUI, I'd let them simmer for the duration. Maybe I'd visit if it was one of my more fragile friends, but I'd make it clear, if it wasn't already, that they made a highly stupid choice and are exactly where they should be. 

If it were me in there, I wouldn't want to see anyone, my shame would be pretty weighty. But, that's just me. Fragile would be a fantastic word to describe her.  Does she have issues with alcoholism? Most people who drive drunk don't actually get caught, and it's the people who do it a LOT who are the most likely to get DUIs, never mind *repeat* DUIs.  Actually, not at all. She averages going out drinking, maybe, twice a month. And only twice did she ever drive drunk. She just got caught both of those times. Our area strictly enforces drunk driving; like on a Friday night literally 2/3 of the force OS dedicated to stopping DUIs.  Oh, ouch. Well, that's one less hurdle for her to deal with. Hopefully after this she'll have a designated driver. Oh, ouch. Well, that's one less hurdle for her to deal with. Hopefully after this she'll have a designated driver. Honestly, if it was my friend spending time in jail for their second DUI, I'd let them simmer for the duration. Maybe I'd visit if it was one of my more fragile friends, but I'd make it clear, if it wasn't already, that they made a highly stupid choice and are exactly where they should be. 

If it were me in there, I wouldn't want to see anyone, my shame would be pretty weighty. But, that's just me. &amp;gt;I'd let them simmer for the duration.

Then obviously this hypothetical person didn't mean shit to you if you advocate letting her "simmer."

I have a family member who has had three DUIs and spent many months in jail for each one. Yes, he deserved it. And I only wish it actually helped him - it has not. I just don't know WHAT will help him. But anyway the point is I felt only pain for him being in jail, even though I knew that is where he should be, and I would never ever fucking say he should be left to "simmer." That's just so heartless!!! Jesus. My uncle was confined to a wheelchair at age FIFTEEN and in so much pain he's considered suicide because he was hit by a drunk driver who faced little to no repercussions for his acts.

The people who are getting DUIs are the selfish ones, not OP. Show me where I said a person with a DUI isn't selfish. Show me where I said a person with a DUI should not face jail time. I did not. All I said is that even though that person *should* be in jail, if you truly cared about that person, you'd still feel sympathy for her and wouldn't heartlessly say that she should "simmer."  When a person is driving under the influence that person is playing russian roulette with their lives and the lives of others. 30 days of sitting around isn't near enough punishment, *whether or not* you love the person.

Somebody who instantly forgives and forgets is an enabler, and not what the person with the DUI needs. &amp;gt;I'd let them simmer for the duration.

Then obviously this hypothetical person didn't mean shit to you if you advocate letting her "simmer."

I have a family member who has had three DUIs and spent many months in jail for each one. Yes, he deserved it. And I only wish it actually helped him - it has not. I just don't know WHAT will help him. But anyway the point is I felt only pain for him being in jail, even though I knew that is where he should be, and I would never ever fucking say he should be left to "simmer." That's just so heartless!!! Jesus. Well, that's just like, your opinion, man. [deleted] You know that people driving drunk or high routinely kill innocent people on the road, right? My sister has a drug problem, and if she ever gets booked for driving under the influence, she is a potential murderer. People who talk on cell phones and text message while driving also routinely kill people. Should we be putting everyone who gets caught on their cell phone in jail for 30 days?  [deleted] Yeah! Let's teach people that no matter what they do, we support them and don't want to see the reap the consequences of their actions! Can't let our friends be *sad* because they're in jail for a wittle itty bitty DUI. It's no big deal! Let's give them unbending love and care, even when they're reckless and stupid and endanger the lives of others! Anything else is clearly bloodless.

I'm not even going to address your utterly brainless, moronic assumption that I would take pleasure from such a decision. You sound like a child bereft of their favorite toy. Yeah! Let's teach people that no matter what they do, we support them and don't want to see the reap the consequences of their actions! Can't let our friends be *sad* because they're in jail for a wittle itty bitty DUI. It's no big deal! Let's give them unbending love and care, even when they're reckless and stupid and endanger the lives of others! Anything else is clearly bloodless.

I'm not even going to address your utterly brainless, moronic assumption that I would take pleasure from such a decision. You sound like a child bereft of their favorite toy. I never said a person shouldn't be in jail for a DUI. I never said that it isn't reckless and stupid. I never said it's no big deal. I never said the person can't be sad that they're in jail. 

I only said that if you had any heart, you too would be sad that your friend is in jail, even though you know that is exactly where she needs to be.

Don't get mad at me because I read your post exactly as it sounded: cold and heartless. 

*You* said "I'd let them simmer for the duration." 

Simmer means "(of water or food being heated) Stay just below boiling point while bubbling gently." When relating that to a person stuck in a bad place, that means that the person would be right at her breaking point but not quite over, suffering in consistent and constant pain. If you wish that upon your friend, then yeah, you're cold and heartless. Even though friends need to learn hard lessons, if you have a heart, you'll still feel sad that your friend is experiencing such pain.  You have no understanding of colloquial language, then, if that's the only meaning you can conjure from my use of "simmer".

FYI, I used "conjure", a verb, above, not to mean "Make (something) appear unexpectedly or seemingly from nowhere as if by magic." as the dictionary states it, but rather to mean "to envision or think up." What on earth did you mean by simmer then, if not to suffer?  Hi. I went to Joe Arpaio's Tent City for 30 days.

Is she in jail for entire duration, or does she have work release available? I'm assuming since visitation is allowed she's in for the duration. If that is the case, then in my own shoes I would not want to see anyone, however someone bringing a new book to read would be something I appreciate.

Each jail is different; being on work release myself the only thing I looked forward to was 1. Getting out in the morning for work during the weekday and 2. When they'd lock down the male side so the female inmates could go over to the vending machines. Hi, I am sorry to hear about your ordeal. What were you in for? She will be in jail for the entire duration. Actually, I think that means only another week for her, which is good! Still, obviously not somewhere I would want to be. Visiting actually did her a load of good. She is the type of person that constantly needs to be around someone she knows well, so to have friends visit her is great. She is kind of...hyper extroverted, in a way, which we were afraid of causing trouble for her. She says it is boring in there, which work would have helped with but oh well. 

She also mentioned having to get strip searched; did that happen to you too or did she just get a bad draw lol? DUI, I was under 21 at the time. Arizona is a zero tolerance state, meaning that if you have any alcohol or drugs in your system (even at the age of 21) you can be charged with a DUI.

I was never strip searched, though when we re-entered the area we were given pat-downs (less invasive than the TSA, actually) and allowed a towel, book and up to $40 for vending machines. It was honestly just a very boring time spent in uncomfortable military-style tents. That was nice of you to visit her, I'm willing to guess that that's about the only thing you can do for her right now, other than offer to give her a ride home when she's out. I see; I suppose it makes sense Arizona is that strict about that stuff, lol. Unfortunate, because it seems like a fairly pleasant state. Still, for a first time offense that sounds fairly intense. 

I'm happy you weren't strip searched. Sadly my friend got the full deal; get naked, spread cheeks, squat and cough, etc. My friend is inside, which is good because it gets cold up here lol. Yes, visiting is about all I can do for her right now. I actually think she has the ride home covered; she has a pretty solid network of friends so that is good. Like I said, she is super social/team oriented haha. 

Ok now this is just a purely logistical question, and if it's TMI you don't have to answer, but: if you were all living in tents, how would you guys shower and stuff? I'm just thinking about how that would work lol.  There are bathroom and shower facilities in the compound, attached to the office. I usually showered at home when i left for work release - youre out for a 12 hour period, and i worked at a restaurant at the time so i had a few hours to hang out at home before work. Well, it sounds like your stay wasn't so bad, then! Glad you are out of there either way.  Oh, no, it definitely sucked - it's not not "hell on Earth" or anything. =) Thank you.</snippet></document><document><title>PostSecret Advice and Guidance</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18v463/postsecret_advice_and_guidance/</url><snippet>At my highschool, I've stirred up enough interest to start a PostSecret bulletin board. For those who don't know what this is, PostSecret is an organization that allows individuals to submit their secrets, confessions, and desires anonymously through the internet or by mail.

Anyways, I'm somewhat concerned over the board's potential usage since the student body here is primarily feminine. This is because I am a male, and the only person willing to moderate and maintain this service for the school. I'm not sheltered or ignorant towards women and their own problems as I peruse 2XC regularly, but I know that there will be plenty of content I am not ready for, let alone the onlookers. I wish to be supportive of these anonymous submissions, yet not be generic or weak in this endeavour.

I would really appreciate some guidance and counsel from you lovely ladies as to how to best handle this potential issue. Thanks!

EDIT: This board will be welcome to anonymous supporters, as our school is still a small, close-knit one. The secrets will also be posted online as per the organizations normality. I am not questioning the appropriateness of the content for censorship. I just need to know if there's any potential confessions that I should watch out for, so that the poster will not be left hanging.  You should put a note up with information about helplines etc, or facilities your school offers for people who need help - like post secret does.

On another note, I hate the term 'females' - it seems like you're describing animals or something. Use women.  What's the issue? Are you writing commentary to each secret, or merely posting it as per PostSecret? Are you questioning what content is "highschool appropriate?" Can you just elaborate a little? :) Updating the post momentarily. DX

Thanks for pointing that out. Still a little confused of what "left hanging" means. Haha

I would take the school counselor route: if someone posts something about either harming/killing themselves or harming/killing someone else, you should report it to a higher authority. If you're getting some heavy stuff I think it would also be important, if this is a bulletin board or webpage, to list some phone numbers for your local area for the suicidal hotline, abuse hotlines, Planned Parenthood, places for psychiatric care or your school counselor's open hours. I'm sure the ladies here could give you plenty more advice, but those are the bare bones I can think of. Still a little confused of what "left hanging" means. Haha

I would take the school counselor route: if someone posts something about either harming/killing themselves or harming/killing someone else, you should report it to a higher authority. If you're getting some heavy stuff I think it would also be important, if this is a bulletin board or webpage, to list some phone numbers for your local area for the suicidal hotline, abuse hotlines, Planned Parenthood, places for psychiatric care or your school counselor's open hours. I'm sure the ladies here could give you plenty more advice, but those are the bare bones I can think of.</snippet></document><document><title>Next time you hear some say underage girls deserve harrassment for taking selfies: be aware some of those pics are obtained through extortion</title><url>http://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/2012/february/sextortion_021012/sextortion_021012</url><snippet>  Who the fuck says that? And even if they did, that argument is pretty awful even if extortion wasn't involved. Who the fuck says that? And even if they did, that argument is pretty awful even if extortion wasn't involved. Heard it on here a lot. Heard it on here a lot. Heard it on here a lot. Heard it on here a lot. No, you haven't. Check out Reddit response to Amanda Todd if you don't believe me. Searched Google, found six threads. The most overtly negative and bloodless one has negative link karma (well, more down than up-votes) and is full of comments lambasting OP. One is a post in r/news, and is just a link to an article, one is a post in r/teenagers that's only tangentially related to her, one is rallying against a facebook hate group bearing her name, and two are purposefully outrageous meme's posted in subreddit's explicitly catering to shock humor.

So, what you're doing is addressing the vast minority as if it were the majority in a particularly condescending manner.

Edit: Looked in to it further. If you search within Reddit's horrid algorithm, you'll find mostly posts from /r/ImGoingToHellForThis containing bad puns and easy jokes. You may find them tasteless, but none of them advocate her harassment. You'll also see a number of posts from places like /r/rant and /r/4chan, railing against her story, but that's all they're railing against, her story. Very few take it further and try to defend calling her suicide stupid, saying she shouldn't be swapping nudes online in the first place if she can't accept the consequences and suggesting that she should have alerted her parents and the authorities much, much earlier. To be perfectly clear, I haven't seen one post advocating the harassment of underage girls who post nude photos online. Thanks for providing links to this example.

In my (granted, limited) experience, I often see nasty, overtly misogynistic or pedophillic comments downvoted. However, I end up in the occasional thread--typically in a subreddit like MRA (not that MRA is always bad)--that have comments along the lines of "women are manipulative whores and deserve to be beat or humiliated" that have several upvotes. 

I don't think such extreme views are very popular in "mainstream" reddit, but there are plenty of subreddit cultures that support such views to some extent. 

I don't have any specific examples atm, however. I will keep an eye open for some in the near future, though. Anyone who's seen something similar can feel free to link to an example, as well. Yeah, I feel threads like these in subreddits like these always suffer from crippling confirmation bias. Discrediting evidence is often downvoted under the guise of some buzzword (derailing, trolling, misogyny, misandry, etc) and all you end up with is chirping birdies. Searched Google, found six threads. The most overtly negative and bloodless one has negative link karma (well, more down than up-votes) and is full of comments lambasting OP. One is a post in r/news, and is just a link to an article, one is a post in r/teenagers that's only tangentially related to her, one is rallying against a facebook hate group bearing her name, and two are purposefully outrageous meme's posted in subreddit's explicitly catering to shock humor.

So, what you're doing is addressing the vast minority as if it were the majority in a particularly condescending manner.

Edit: Looked in to it further. If you search within Reddit's horrid algorithm, you'll find mostly posts from /r/ImGoingToHellForThis containing bad puns and easy jokes. You may find them tasteless, but none of them advocate her harassment. You'll also see a number of posts from places like /r/rant and /r/4chan, railing against her story, but that's all they're railing against, her story. Very few take it further and try to defend calling her suicide stupid, saying she shouldn't be swapping nudes online in the first place if she can't accept the consequences and suggesting that she should have alerted her parents and the authorities much, much earlier. To be perfectly clear, I haven't seen one post advocating the harassment of underage girls who post nude photos online. Not links comments, and I've seen plenty I addressed comments in my post, and if you have no backing evidence then your claim is not worth making in the first place. http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/16w5se/a_cyber_nightmare_for_women_the_onus_of/

This whole thread That thread is just you arguing with people. It doesn't back up your point. You seem to take great umbrage at the initial reply of:

&amp;gt;I'm pretty sure posting sexy pictures is an invitation for sexual comments. The rest is true enough though.

The poster there is not advocating harassment, but just making the point that posting sexual picture of yourself online will result in sexual comments. You then go on to try to link that view with condoning the suicide of a 13 year old girl. http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/16w5se/a_cyber_nightmare_for_women_the_onus_of/

This whole thread That is a terrible, terrible piece of evidence to submit. You're aligning comments with harassment (and drawing no distinction between the two), and you're distorting the arguments made by the overwhelming majority of the people in that thread. **No one** said she, or anyone deserves that thing. 

In the process of writing this, I think I finally figured out why you're so off base. Expect &#8800; deserve. Two totally different verbs. That is a terrible, terrible piece of evidence to submit. You're aligning comments with harassment (and drawing no distinction between the two), and you're distorting the arguments made by the overwhelming majority of the people in that thread. **No one** said she, or anyone deserves that thing. 

In the process of writing this, I think I finally figured out why you're so off base. Expect &#8800; deserve. Two totally different verbs. Searched Google, found six threads. The most overtly negative and bloodless one has negative link karma (well, more down than up-votes) and is full of comments lambasting OP. One is a post in r/news, and is just a link to an article, one is a post in r/teenagers that's only tangentially related to her, one is rallying against a facebook hate group bearing her name, and two are purposefully outrageous meme's posted in subreddit's explicitly catering to shock humor.

So, what you're doing is addressing the vast minority as if it were the majority in a particularly condescending manner.

Edit: Looked in to it further. If you search within Reddit's horrid algorithm, you'll find mostly posts from /r/ImGoingToHellForThis containing bad puns and easy jokes. You may find them tasteless, but none of them advocate her harassment. You'll also see a number of posts from places like /r/rant and /r/4chan, railing against her story, but that's all they're railing against, her story. Very few take it further and try to defend calling her suicide stupid, saying she shouldn't be swapping nudes online in the first place if she can't accept the consequences and suggesting that she should have alerted her parents and the authorities much, much earlier. To be perfectly clear, I haven't seen one post advocating the harassment of underage girls who post nude photos online. Do you remember /r/jailbait? The whole argument for that was its ok because they were self shots. Please don't say she's never seen it because we all have.  You are discussing an entirely different series of events than what is being talked about above. Please up your comprehension before responding further. The thread is about this: someone asked who criticized self shots, and OP said she's seen in on reddit, you said she hasn't, she gave an example, you said you haven't seen much on that. I gave another example. Why does it matter if its not about Amanda Todd? No, that's not what we're talking about at all. We're discussing the frequency of people saying underage girls who take nude photos of themselves **DESERVE HARASSMENT** (emphasized so you can't miss it). She did not provide a link containing such an event, and neither did you. Searched Google, found six threads. The most overtly negative and bloodless one has negative link karma (well, more down than up-votes) and is full of comments lambasting OP. One is a post in r/news, and is just a link to an article, one is a post in r/teenagers that's only tangentially related to her, one is rallying against a facebook hate group bearing her name, and two are purposefully outrageous meme's posted in subreddit's explicitly catering to shock humor.

So, what you're doing is addressing the vast minority as if it were the majority in a particularly condescending manner.

Edit: Looked in to it further. If you search within Reddit's horrid algorithm, you'll find mostly posts from /r/ImGoingToHellForThis containing bad puns and easy jokes. You may find them tasteless, but none of them advocate her harassment. You'll also see a number of posts from places like /r/rant and /r/4chan, railing against her story, but that's all they're railing against, her story. Very few take it further and try to defend calling her suicide stupid, saying she shouldn't be swapping nudes online in the first place if she can't accept the consequences and suggesting that she should have alerted her parents and the authorities much, much earlier. To be perfectly clear, I haven't seen one post advocating the harassment of underage girls who post nude photos online. Can you provide some links? [I figure this is one step up from linking to "Let Me Google That For You"](https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3A+reddit+%22amanda+todd%22&amp;amp;oq=site%3A+reddit+%22amanda+todd%22&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.59j58j62l3.6500&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8) Heard it on here a lot. Why did TheGorgonQueen's comment go from +20 to -6 in the space of a few minutes? Why did TheGorgonQueen's comment go from +20 to -6 in the space of a few minutes? Who the fuck says that? And even if they did, that argument is pretty awful even if extortion wasn't involved. Who the fuck says that? And even if they did, that argument is pretty awful even if extortion wasn't involved.  I cannot agree with this story enough.  Truth is, I have a similar story and this way of getting pictures is nothing new.  I was preyed upon over the internet starting from when I was 14 years old (I am 26 now).  One of the men/pedophiles (yes, there was more than one) would use certain threats to gain more pictures: threaten to rape me and my sister, kill my family, send the pictures he had to my school/family and friends amongst other things.  I lived in constant terror for years. Once a girl falls prey to one of these sick individuals it seems to start a vicious cycle.  My heart goes out to these young girls who are going through this. I wish I had gone to my parents sooner...I told the story of what happened to me regarding threats and other issues to my mother only 2 years ago. As a mother of two young daughters, may I ask why you didn't immediately go to your parents?  One of my top hopes as a parent is that my kids will feel like they can ALWAYS come to me about a problem, even if they think it will upset me or make me mad.

And I am so so sorry that happened to you. At that point in time, I did not have any self-esteem or self worth. I had withdrawn so much from my family, I would fight with my mother and father all the times and I was going through severe depression.  At that moment in time I believed that if my mother and father found out it would make matters worse in my deteriorating relationship with them.  I believed that I brought this upon myself and it was all my fault.  There was so much hopelessness and a loss of sense of self that I didn&#8217;t feel that I could escape. With the faltering relationship with my parents, I did not believe I could go to them. Having your daughters know that they can go to you for anything is such an important thing.  I am so glad that is one of your top priorities. I can't even express how awful your story makes me feel, and it's so much worse for you.  :(  Thank you for answering me.  I want to go hug my girls now. </snippet></document><document><title>Skin irritation after facial hair removal</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ujt8/skin_irritation_after_facial_hair_removal/</url><snippet>After waxing or threading the hair on my skin, I sometimes get small pimples all over my face. My skin gets red and bumpy. The bumps might go away only after a few weeks and by the then the hair has already grown back. (It seems almost counterproductive sometimes to remove hair.) 

Any suggestion for what to do before or after waxing/threading the face to prevent irritation?

Thanks.   How many times have you waxed?
My first time, I bled and I got bumps everywhere. 
However, now I rely on my tweezers more so I have to wax less. Whenever i see a stray hair, I just rip it out. 

This may not be the greatest advice as I'm still new at this whole thing. I've waxed a lot of times. It's been a few years now. Threading works better for me even though my skin still gets irritated. There's something in the wax that I'm probably allergic to. Threading just gives me smaller pimples and my skin calms down more quickly, even though the process is more painful than waxing.

Removing stray hairs with tweezers requires lots of time. I don't want to keep checking my face in the mirror everyday. Thanks for the advice though.  </snippet></document><document><title>Fashionable Women of TwoX, I need your help again</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18tacu/fashionable_women_of_twox_i_need_your_help_again/</url><snippet>You all have been so helpful in the past, and here I am again with a question...

Where in the hell do you shop when you're not a 'big girl' but not a 'average/thin' girl either? I wear a 10/12, and the regular shops clothes fit, but aren't too flattering, but when I go to say, Torrid or Layne Bryant the 12 is way too big on me (which is a shame because I do love the way they look on girls a bit bigger than me).

I'm really lost because I'm losing weight, so I have to switch stores...but I have no idea where to go. There's not much around here, so if any of you know any online places, I'd really appreciate you sharing. :D Thanks!


Edit: THANKS to you all so much!! Glad I'm not alone on the in between size problem!   Try /r/femalefashionadvice the ladies there are quite helpful!
Also, it less to do with size and more to do with body shape (i.e. pear, hourglass, apple etc). 

If you know what suits you already thrift/charity shops are awesome, as well as etsy, ebay and preloved!    Have you checked out The Gap?  I'm a bigger girl and their XL size is really flattering on me, I suspect their clothes are cut for women, and not teens, like many mall stores clothes are.       If you have trouble finding clothes because you're busty, [BiuBiu](http://www.biubiu.pl/lang/en) and [Urkye](http://www.urkye.pl/en_US/index) are awesome and very reasonably-priced.       I think a lot of the trendy makers design clothes for the 17-year-old size zero, and then they just make it bigger for the rest of the sizes.  

When, in fact, a size-10 ass looks better in a skirt designed for a size-10 ass.  Don't bother with Target, Forever 21, Abercrombie, etc.  

Chico's, Eddie Bauer, LL Bean, even Marshalls and Loehmann's.  Good luck! Those are some of the least fashionable stores you could ever recommend.    </snippet></document><document><title>Pregnant, planning on an abortion, would like to get the Essure procedure at the same time but I'm having a hard time finding a doctor who does both. Austin, TX</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18tk93/pregnant_planning_on_an_abortion_would_like_to/</url><snippet>There is one clinic that I found that will do it, but they don't take my insurance. My insurance does cover sterilization and abortion, as long as it's in-network. I really don't want to have an abortion and then have to go somewhere else for the tubal, but I will if I have to. 

Does anyone have any recommendations? I'm willing to go to San Antonio or any other bordering cities.     </snippet></document><document><title>I went to a meeting of my university's feminist group today.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18t3cl/i_went_to_a_meeting_of_my_universitys_feminist/</url><snippet>It was absolutely amazing. I was initially scared that they'd be the Feminazi-type feminists but they really work to create a safe space for discussion of all sorts of gender-related issues and women's rights. It was this awesome experience and I'm really looking forward to getting more involved with the group in the future. I practically skipped back to my dorm afterwards, I was so excited and happy. :)  Honestly I hate the Femnazi stereotype because the vast majority of self-proclaimed feminists that I've met in person aren't like that, they're like what you described. I'm glad you had such a positive and eye opening experience. I wish more people could come to see the positive version of feminism. I've never met a "femnazi", I'm pretty sure that's something Rush Limbaugh and the conservatives made up to taint women's equality as a movement because they want to keep the patriarchy in place. Dunno why you got downvoted so much. Maybe people didn't like your wording? The "Feminazi" thing is just an awful term (Nazi?? WTF?!) and I honestly haven't met any feminists IRL who embody that stereotype. I went to a women's college where my entire circle of friends was feminists, most of whom were also lesbians. Even my old school feminist professors loved their husbands and encouraged open discourse. So yeah, not sure where exactly the "Feminazis" are hiding.  Pretty sure the MRAs are lurking.  

I hang out with a very active group of feminists which includes both men and women.  Everyone supports women's EQUALITY (the definition of feminism) not misandry.  I've never seen any feminist who wanted a matriarchy, feminism is about removing the patriarchy that hurts BOTH men and women and substituting it with an egalitarian society.

The kind of people who throw around "femnazi" as an insult are generally the kind of people who are most tied to traditional gender roles and feel threatened by the fact that feminism is the fight to remove these stifling constrains and to promote more choice and freedom.

See individuals like Rush Limbaugh, Todd "Legitimate Rape" Akin, Bob "Transvaginal Ultrasound" McDonnell.   Pretty sure the MRAs are lurking.  

I hang out with a very active group of feminists which includes both men and women.  Everyone supports women's EQUALITY (the definition of feminism) not misandry.  I've never seen any feminist who wanted a matriarchy, feminism is about removing the patriarchy that hurts BOTH men and women and substituting it with an egalitarian society.

The kind of people who throw around "femnazi" as an insult are generally the kind of people who are most tied to traditional gender roles and feel threatened by the fact that feminism is the fight to remove these stifling constrains and to promote more choice and freedom.

See individuals like Rush Limbaugh, Todd "Legitimate Rape" Akin, Bob "Transvaginal Ultrasound" McDonnell.   Pretty sure the MRAs are lurking.  

I hang out with a very active group of feminists which includes both men and women.  Everyone supports women's EQUALITY (the definition of feminism) not misandry.  I've never seen any feminist who wanted a matriarchy, feminism is about removing the patriarchy that hurts BOTH men and women and substituting it with an egalitarian society.

The kind of people who throw around "femnazi" as an insult are generally the kind of people who are most tied to traditional gender roles and feel threatened by the fact that feminism is the fight to remove these stifling constrains and to promote more choice and freedom.

See individuals like Rush Limbaugh, Todd "Legitimate Rape" Akin, Bob "Transvaginal Ultrasound" McDonnell.   MRAs are constantly lurking here. Its kinda sad how much time and effort they put into downvoting on 2x. Yeah really.  I don't go to their subreddit to downvote their bullshit.  I've got way better things to do with my life. MRAs are constantly lurking here. Its kinda sad how much time and effort they put into downvoting on 2x. MRA here! I consider myself an MRA and feminist (I'm male). Is that allowed? I browse both subs frequently.

Regarding the above discussion about feminazis; I have not personally met anyone who I would consider a "feminazi". I definitely have been offended by women who call themselves feminists before, but I frequently take issues with other MRA's as well.

I guess I just wanted to say that not all MRA's come here to downvote! MRA here! I consider myself an MRA and feminist (I'm male). Is that allowed? I browse both subs frequently.

Regarding the above discussion about feminazis; I have not personally met anyone who I would consider a "feminazi". I definitely have been offended by women who call themselves feminists before, but I frequently take issues with other MRA's as well.

I guess I just wanted to say that not all MRA's come here to downvote! I've never met a "femnazi", I'm pretty sure that's something Rush Limbaugh and the conservatives made up to taint women's equality as a movement because they want to keep the patriarchy in place. I've never met a "femnazi", I'm pretty sure that's something Rush Limbaugh and the conservatives made up to taint women's equality as a movement because they want to keep the patriarchy in place. They exist, but they are a vocal minority, which is unfortunate because they tend to hijack the discussion, distort the issues, and scare off male supporters. If they exist I've never met any, and I know a LOT of feminists, I'm pretty active in fighting for gender equality and I know a LOT of people in the Women and Gender Studies Department at my school.  None of them want a matriarchy, feminism is about EQUALITY and you aren't a feminist if you aren't advocating for equality. I've never met a "femnazi", I'm pretty sure that's something Rush Limbaugh and the conservatives made up to taint women's equality as a movement because they want to keep the patriarchy in place. I've never met a "femnazi", I'm pretty sure that's something Rush Limbaugh and the conservatives made up to taint women's equality as a movement because they want to keep the patriarchy in place. Honestly I hate the Femnazi stereotype because the vast majority of self-proclaimed feminists that I've met in person aren't like that, they're like what you described. I'm glad you had such a positive and eye opening experience. I wish more people could come to see the positive version of feminism. I offered to make a poster that they could print up (since I've got a decent eye for design and also Photoshop and Illustrator) and one of the biggest things on it is this:  
"Feminism isn't about hating men, it's about equality for everyone. Are you a feminist now?"

I posted it on the group's Facebook wall and haven't yet heard anything from the officers, but it's hopefully going to be printed and posted all over campus. :) And here I am, trying to break stereotypes one poster at a time. Haha. Honestly I hate the Femnazi stereotype because the vast majority of self-proclaimed feminists that I've met in person aren't like that, they're like what you described. I'm glad you had such a positive and eye opening experience. I wish more people could come to see the positive version of feminism.  A lot of people I know, many of them women, go with the "I agree with equality and some feminists, but not those crazy feminazis" line of thinking. It's kind of sad that a brand of feminism that basically doesn't exist in significant numbers is used to represent the entire movement in most people's minds. A lot of people I know, many of them women, go with the "I agree with equality and some feminists, but not those crazy feminazis" line of thinking. It's kind of sad that a brand of feminism that basically doesn't exist in significant numbers is used to represent the entire movement in most people's minds. &amp;gt; It's kind of sad that a brand of feminism that basically doesn't exist in significant numbers is used to represent the entire movement in most people's minds.

How do you know what the numbers are?  I think for any kind of thing like this, it's impossible to know the percentages of nice feminists v. crazy feminists, but the mean feminists have done a great job of making it look like feminism is THEIR movement.  What are the actual numbers?  Impossible to know. 

EDIT: Somebody want to explain why they downvoted this post?  &amp;gt;What are the actual numbers?

Zero, in my experience. Sorry, why is personal anecdotal evidence acceptable in this scenario, but is not when, say, debating the existence of institutionalized misogyny? Seems to me to be a rather glaring double standard... What I meant by 'in my experience' wasn't merely that I've never personally encountered a 'crazy feminist' but that I've never even heard of one or read their writings.

There seems to be no feminist equivalent to the Westboro Baptist Church, Anders Breivik, or militant Islamic fundamentalism. One would suppose that if such feminists existed, MRAs, Fox News and the like would be all over it, bringing them to our attention. But, nothing. [Here:](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Daly#Views_on_men) [these women](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jill_Johnston) [are all pretty nutty](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrea_Dworkin#Legacy_and_controversy).

And that only took five minutes on Google. They are out there. I took a class taught by one (not of the above, mind you) and sat in another class filled with them. They aren't everywhere, they aren't the majority, but they absolutely exist and in far larger numbers than you seem willing to accept. Fair enough, I would concede that Jill Johnston's quote from Lesbian Nation, "Man is completely out of phase with nature. Nature is woman. Man is the intruder. The man who re-attunes himself with nature is the man who de-mans himself or eliminates himself as man" is genuinely bonkers.

Personally I regard lesbian separatism as extreme rather than crazy. Likewise Andrea Dworkin's views. Belief in former matriarchal societies isn't supported by the evidence and seems to be now very much a niche view among experts, which puts it on the same level as global warming denialism rather than, say, creationism - irrational rather than insane.

It should be noted that all three women are now dead. This is second wave, mostly 1970s feminism rather than current feminism. &amp;gt;What are the actual numbers?

Zero, in my experience.   </snippet></document><document><title>Married 2Xers, how do you deal with your maiden name when applying for a job?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uv1u/married_2xers_how_do_you_deal_with_your_maiden/</url><snippet>Hello lovelies.  I just got married (squeee!) and have taken my husband's name.  Unfortunately, all of my work and education experience has been under my maiden name, and all my references know me by it as well.  I've been applying for a bunch of jobs and don't know how to bring this up with prospective employers.  Should I make a note in my resume? Wait and bring it up in the interview?

First world married lady problems...    </snippet></document><document><title>Do you ladies have any advice for a girl about to enter the dating world?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18utao/do_you_ladies_have_any_advice_for_a_girl_about_to/</url><snippet>I am sixteen and have never had a boyfriend. This bothers me, but not too much, because I assume that everyone's time will come. Lately I have been putting myself out there more and have grown closer to many of my guy friends, and I think that I am on the brink of entering the dating world. I just want to see what I should expect, and the do's and don'ts of dating :).    It sounds like you've got a good head on your shoulders! It is true that the time will come, so don't settle or rush in to anything! Sixteen is really not that old to have never had a boyfriend. It's hard to imagine that in the future you would regret waiting a little longer, but you certainly might regret rushing in to things!

Just remember to only do things that you are comfortable with. Your boyfriend should be someone who listens, makes you laugh, and truly cares about you. Don't let anyone pressure you in to anything. 

And this one is *very* important, don't forget to keep spending time with your friends!  I've noticed a lot of girl my age who lose their identities completely whenever they are in a relationship. Is this a fault of themselves or their boyfriend?</snippet></document><document><title>TwoX, I just got dumped....</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18uakq/twox_i_just_got_dumped/</url><snippet>And man does it hurt. I guess I'm just looking for a little extra support today. He did it last night over text (even admitting to being too much of a coward to do it to my face). 

Man o man, I wish I could fast forward a few weeks....           </snippet></document><document><title>Question about brown discharge...</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18tzxl/question_about_brown_discharge/</url><snippet>I'm 20, on birth control (tri sprintec), and not sexually active.  For the past few months, the week before my period I have had dark brown discharge leading right up to when my period starts.  No weird smell just really annoying.  It's been pretty consistent but even if it's "normal" I don't know why it would start out of the blue.  Any insight would be greatly appreciated.     </snippet></document><document><title>Ok, this is weird, but my mom won't stop mimicking my life choices.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18sij1/ok_this_is_weird_but_my_mom_wont_stop_mimicking/</url><snippet>Im 26, havent lived with my mom since I was 15. She thinks she was a great mother, I went though my younger life feeling basically abandoned. OK, fine, we're friends now. She can be supportive, she can be loving, she can be nuts.

But lately I have been transitioning from a career in research to a holistic health career, likely a doctor of osteopathy degree due to its stronger emphasis on quality of life/whole body care than an MD degree. Only moments after I told her this, she told me she had been considering the same thing...she has never taken a bio class in her life. She is super into hippie cures, which I am totally willing to investigate the efficacy of, but she is way beyond supplements and all the way to homeopathy. When I told her there are science prerequisites, she was just like oh, well maybe ill go to a naturopathic medical school- I didnt even bother explaining that (contrary to popular belief) they still require science prerequisites and aren't just schools of happy thoughts! Ok, fine, its not a big deal.

 But on top of that, we are going on a trip together, where I had arranged to interview native doctors (kind of an ethnobotany thing)- 2 months ago I find out that she's talking about her ethnobotany research she's conducting on our trip! What?!

I know, this sounds crazy and petty, but it feels like having a little sister. It unfortunately isnt just this set of circumstances, she also compares our romantic relationships nonstop, tells me I'm just like my mother on a pretty regular basis (I know I should view that as a compliment, but it isn't really said as though it is one. Also she is kind of nuts.), borrows my clothes (she weighs 100lbs more than I do). 

Has anybody else had this kind of thing? What the hell is going on? How do I respond? Any time I've ever tried being like, dude, let me have this, she gets insanely offended and defensive, regardless of what it's about. She also says things about how happy she is I've come over to "our side" when I tell her that one of her hippie theories is scientifically supported- I think thats why the latest incarnation of mimicking is pissing me off so badly, I feel like she is discrediting my education and how hard Ive worked to get to the point where I'm at.


Sorry, I know this is long! Any insight or advice would be so much appreciated...  Erg, I hate to copy you (wink, wink), but my mom is just like this. She was a single mom and had to raise me by herself, so I suspect she formed an unhealthy attachment to me as an extension of herself. Anything I like, football, plates, colors, hair highlights, foods, she just LOVES. She never cared for football in all the years I've known her, but as soon as I said I had watched a game on Sunday, she was all into it. From not watching to watching every Sunday and talking about it the next day. She loved the color rust for years and years, but as soon as I mentioned my fave colors were blue and purple, those were hers, too. 

On one hand, I could brush it off as her just growing and changing as we all do (just because you liked something 10 years ago does not mean you must always like it forever and ever) or as trying to find a new way to connect to me, but she does with it every fucking thing. If I'm sick, she's sick, too. If my skin is dry, hers is, too. She loved stargazer lilies and wanted to get me some. I declined politely, but she pushed and pushed, so I finally admitted that I despise them. I think they stink of funeral parlors and death. Guess who now doesn't like them either? 

The copying just goes on and on. I have a pet name for my son and refer to him as "my so-and-so." She, of course, immediately does the same. Any pet name I use for him, she has to use as well. She even went through a phase where she would "slip" and call herself "mommy" when speaking with him. 

It's like she can't figure out how to form a picture of herself, so she has to copy me in order to be someone. The *only* thing that I've found that works is to just not share anything with her or share only things I really don't care about. And that's really frustrating and tiring to remember. So, I've been working on just not giving a shit what she does as long as she's happy. Or happy-ish. ughhhhh this weirdly makes me feel better. I always feel a little guilty about feeling so freakin annoyed by her but i just don't understand why the melding is so appealing to her- she once even referred to my ex and i (while together) as "Dave and Lucy Jr." (her name and my dads).  what. The only method that works for me is to do things that she is incapable of copying- ie rock climbing, weight lifting, etc. But your advice is good- have been trying to figure out how that not caring thing works! Thanks for the response, some of those anecdotes are hilarious to someone who has been in your position- Although I think the thing with your kid would have pushed me over the line... mommy! agh!  Mid-life crisis. She is most likely trying to prove herself, not to you, but to herself, that she can still be young, and creative. She just may not know how to go about it and is therefore copying you, as you ARE young and creative with your whole life still ahead of you. She may also feel a sense of loss, a loss of the time you would have spent together when you were younger. You say she wasn't the best parent, and that you stopped living with her after you turned 15. Well, she may be going into all these things because it will mean spending time with you. What better way to make up for lost time than to spend the time you are together doing something you both seemingly enjoy.

I know this may be confusing time for you right now. Especially having your educational backround called into question by someone whose scientific backround is apparently moot, can be really rough. Try sitting down and talking to her. Ask her why she wants to do the things she is.  Ethnobotany, for example, will take a great deal of knowledge, not just in biology and botany but in anthropology as well. You must let her know that something as complicatd as this may be way over her head, especially if she is entering the situation with a severe biased perspective (you called it her hippie-ness).

Try not to let her "coming to our side" comment affect you. When she says things like this, simply tell her that (topic of discussion) is not on a side. Or simply that you are not on a side. When science and theory come together it is a beautiful thing. For a theory to be proven into fact is a rare and wonderful thing. 

I hope something I said helped. Good luck. :D

*spelling  I don't have kids but I've seen some of this on the other side in others. I'm going to wager a theory here. 

I'm going to guess your mom had you when she was young, before she established her own identity (anywhere from teens to mid 20s). Some people, and some women in particular unfortunately, shape their identity based off of others. Their friends and parents, and then boyfriends, and onto their kids. Emotionally they've never learned to be their own person. They never developed their own interests or pursued their dreams. Now they have adult children, and their romantic relationships are boring, predictable, or have fallen apart completely. I've met many women in their 40s who find themselves empty. They don't have anyone to glom on to or to pattern their life for. So they cling to their kids, who are adults trying to find identity of their own. 

You are in an awesome time in your life, learning stuff, developing as a person investing in yourself and your dreams. This can be done at any age, but it comes naturally to people in their late teens and 20s. You haven't settled down yet, and have low responsibilities. The older you get the more stuff you have to manage, and some find developing interests hard, especially if you never tried to do so in the first place. 

I think your mom is looking for the easy way out. You are doing something that seems pretty cool, and she'd like to do it but isn't interested in making the investment of time and energy to really learn it. I've met people like this before, they want to know, but don't actually try. 

So, what to do? Have you tried telling her how it makes you feel? That can be a hard conversation to have. You can try setting up boundaries so you don't feel like she's infringing or copying your life and in turn still support her in getting involved with her own interests. The other thing you can do is leave her be and let it play out on its own. Don't invest your time in training or helping her unless she's willing to work, but apart from that let her do her own exploring without any input from you. She will either take it somewhere or not. 

A thing you mom should know is its easier to reinvent yourself than you think, all it takes is an open mind, a little effort, and a willingness to take some small risk. Only she can do the work though, she can't make it happen through you. You know that, but that's something she has to figure out on her own.  

I don't know if that's actually helpful, but good luck!  No, I appreciate this viewpoint, and I think some of it definitely applies-the easy way out part especially. She actually had me in her mid thirties and has had plenty of identities since then-She has had a new interest every day of the week and has been reinventing herself every year or two for as long as i can remember- new jobs, new fiances, new names new religious affiliations. I guess I just feel resentful that she is underestimating how much of a commitment ive put in- plus telling me to look at programs on a website she sent me that is clearly a for-profit hippie scam school...I don't know, it just feels very invalidating. Its the kind of thing you wouldnt take personally if it wasnt your mother...thanks for the response though, i appreciate hearing that side of it- trying to be more compassionate in my responses to her.    My mom does that as well. I enrolled in law school, she started getting her paralegal certificate (despite having a degree and background in graphic design). Shes done it with her husband as well. Hes a "sociologist" so then she rematriculated in university to become one. He's a skier, so now shes THE ULTIMATE SKI FAN.  

Its annoying, I feel your pain. I haven't figured out how to address it. I think the healthiest solution I've had it to try and ignore it.  Oh boy...that is ridiculous...luckily i can usually count on my mom giving up  on anything that takes too much work (eventually)- i wish she's take up copying her husband though! You're probably right about ignoring it- I dont know about your mom but mine is pretty in your face about it, so that can be hard. oh moms!  My first thought is to wonder if you are my sister. But yes my mother has tried this with me. When I was in school and would bring home projects and art she would be competitive at me. When I moved around as a young adult she would try to follow. My mother is also a quasi hippy.
 I moved overseas so it doesnt happen any more but yikes. I sympathize. this thread has actually made me feel better, just because no one I know can relate and I was starting to think i was crazy...if i had a sister at least we could compare notes! so thank you :)          Sigmund Freud had a theory, which used to be well-accepted, don't know about now, that fathers have a very weak sexual attraction to their daughters and mothers had a very weak sexual attraction to their sons.  So weak that it usually didn't manifest itself as anything.  However, because of this weak sexual attraction, mothers saw their daughters as "competition" with their husband and that's why "momma's boy" and "daddy's little girl" are stereotypes - mothers usually have a stronger bond with their sons and see their daughters as "competition".

There is also residual DNA in women from our ape days that makes each woman want to be the "alpha female" (as to be able to mate with the alpha male).   

Maybe (and this is a huge maybe) your mother subconsciously sees you as "competition" - of course, there is no man for you to compete against, but she still stacks herself up against you, and since you are doing well in life, she wants to be like you so she can "conquer" you. 

Don't know, just a theory.  Most of Freud's hypotheses have been almost unilaterally dismissed by the psychological field because they were pretty much based on his day-dreaming about a couple of choice cases.

He came up with some interesting/innovative ideas, but almost none of them were scientifically sound. Ok well its kind of shitty that I am being downvoted just for posting a comment that talks about a theory that may or may not be true anymore.  Downvoting is for things that aren't contributing to the conversation. It's well-known in the social sciences that Freud's theories are unsupported. In my book, that means your comment is not helpful in the conversation at hand.

Don't take it personally. &amp;gt; It's well-known in the social sciences that Freud's theories are unsupported.

That's a shitty reason to downvote somebody.  Ahem, your theories have been disproven so I will make your comment disappear.  Did you read the rest of my comment? Yes I can read.  I didn't find it convincing.  It's still an abuse of the downvote button.  Ok well its kind of shitty that I am being downvoted just for posting a comment that talks about a theory that may or may not be true anymore.  &amp;gt;Ok well its kind of shitty that I am being downvoted just for posting a comment that talks about a theory that may or may not be true anymore. 

You complain about downvotes a lot. I've seen you do it other threads, too. That habit probably contributes even more downvotes. Luckily, karma doesn't have much real-world value if you try not to let it affect you. [deleted] Please keep the insults out of your comments here. Why didn't you say that to MeloJelo?  because melojelo didn't insult you? I consider this an insult: &amp;gt; You complain about downvotes a lot. I've seen you do it other threads, too. That habit probably contributes even more downvotes. Luckily, karma doesn't have much real-world value if you try not to let it affect you.

Either way, she made the conversation personal, which is inappropriate and derailing.  Sigmund Freud had a theory, which used to be well-accepted, don't know about now, that fathers have a very weak sexual attraction to their daughters and mothers had a very weak sexual attraction to their sons.  So weak that it usually didn't manifest itself as anything.  However, because of this weak sexual attraction, mothers saw their daughters as "competition" with their husband and that's why "momma's boy" and "daddy's little girl" are stereotypes - mothers usually have a stronger bond with their sons and see their daughters as "competition".

There is also residual DNA in women from our ape days that makes each woman want to be the "alpha female" (as to be able to mate with the alpha male).   

Maybe (and this is a huge maybe) your mother subconsciously sees you as "competition" - of course, there is no man for you to compete against, but she still stacks herself up against you, and since you are doing well in life, she wants to be like you so she can "conquer" you. 

Don't know, just a theory. </snippet></document><document><title>To any one who buys from Qwertee- Have you noticed the new sizing?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18twse/to_any_one_who_buys_from_qwertee_have_you_noticed/</url><snippet>There is a banner on the top which claims they are now doing larger women's shirts. (So an old Large is the same siz as the new Medium). 

The last t-shirt I bought claims to be a 2XL. It is the same size as the new XL, (I measured my shirt). BUT- there is now no 2XL. 

So it seems that they are not making larger sizes just renaming the ones that they do. This kinda annoyed me as I got excited because the 2XL is slightly too small, and would love to buy a new 2XL, which does not seem to exist!

For those interested: http://www.qwertee.com/
  </snippet></document><document><title>I seriously need someone to talk to. I am broke, living in a van in Louisiana, 5 weeks pregnant, and alone. I made an appointment for an abortion, what now?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18sf92/i_seriously_need_someone_to_talk_to_i_am_broke/</url><snippet>I hooked up with an ex about 3 weeks ago. We mutually regretted it, had a big fight and are not on speaking terms. I took the morning after pill but never had my period. I took a pregnancy test and it was positive. 

I can't have a baby, I'm a homeless person. Abortion is the only option for me, so please don't try to persuade me otherwise. Trust me, nothing you can say can make me feel more guilt, shame, fear, and anger at my self. The little grain of rice needs to come out asap. I feel like I've been on the phone and internet for 3 days trying to find services, finally I got to make an appointment, now all I have to do is come up with gas money for several trips there and back, $50 for "counseling", $400 for the actual service, which won't be until next month, just before the cut-off date.

I'm not on drugs, I'm not irresponsible, I'm not even in a bad place in my life. I have some income from being a street performer, but this is usually 400-600 a month, and it has been raining and I have been sick. I currently have about 200 $1 bills.

Has anyone here had an abortion in Louisiana? Does anyone here have any experience getting some kind of abortion funding? I really need to talk to someone who went through the same thing. It's Infuriating and terrifying that I might miss the cut off date because I didn't have $200. If that happens I don't know what i'll do, but I WILL do something and it might not be safe.

Update: I have my first appointment tomorrow at another clinic. Hopefully after that I will have a sooner appointment, which is good because I wont miss the cut off date, but bad because I have even less time to come up with funds, And I havnt had any meaningful contact with any funding organizations. I also got rejected when I went to apply for a payday loan, and broke down crying on the side of the road, and caused a scene. So, as much I resent doing this, I set up a PayPal incase someone wanted to help fund this. Pm me for the link, I want it to be anonymous, but I'll also prove that I exist. Please dont consider it charity, I want yall to have the option to be payed back, or if not then at least payed forward. I also made a post in r/loans, if you want to be more secure.  I live in Baton Rouge. I am also the state director of a woman's advocacy group, and I would be happy to help you out with rides. 

Also, contact the New Orleans Abortion Fund (I will have to get the email address for you, I have it on my home computer and I am traveling right now). They are part of the National Network of Abortion Funds, and their goal is specifically to help women who are in your situation and cannot afford an abortion. If you want my help in getting in touch with them, I would be glad to help out.

If you PM me, I will give you my email address and we can talk, either on Skype or over email.  http://neworleansabortionfund.weebly.com/contact-us.html

It might be easier to contact them through lussie, but this is all they offer for contacting them via their site. Yeah, I'm friends with a woman who works in public affairs for Planned Parenthood, and she knows them personally. I'll be able to get a direct line of contact with them through her.  Good. Do you know if they have someone to help them with their website? It appears to be unfinished, which is unfortunate since it might hurt their legitimacy. 

Since they appear to be one of very few resources for abortion financing in the state, that could be very detrimental to many women in that region. I live in Baton Rouge. I am also the state director of a woman's advocacy group, and I would be happy to help you out with rides. 

Also, contact the New Orleans Abortion Fund (I will have to get the email address for you, I have it on my home computer and I am traveling right now). They are part of the National Network of Abortion Funds, and their goal is specifically to help women who are in your situation and cannot afford an abortion. If you want my help in getting in touch with them, I would be glad to help out.

If you PM me, I will give you my email address and we can talk, either on Skype or over email.  If you are unable to raise the funds otherwise, I'd be happy to make a donation covering all medical costs. PM me and we can organize from there, if it's necessary. Even if we are able to raise the funds, I'd encourage you to donate to the Abortion Fund of New Orleans, or if you can't get in touch with them, donate directly to the National Network of Abortion Funds. The money is badly needed, especially in southern states where abortion providers are scarce and there are not many people donating to them. 

I haven't heard anything back from my friend at Planned Parenthood, but I just messaged her this morning, so I'll give it a few more days. We do need to hurry a bit though, because the longer OP waits, the more costly the procedure ends up being.  Even if we are able to raise the funds, I'd encourage you to donate to the Abortion Fund of New Orleans, or if you can't get in touch with them, donate directly to the National Network of Abortion Funds. The money is badly needed, especially in southern states where abortion providers are scarce and there are not many people donating to them. 

I haven't heard anything back from my friend at Planned Parenthood, but I just messaged her this morning, so I'll give it a few more days. We do need to hurry a bit though, because the longer OP waits, the more costly the procedure ends up being.  Planned Parenthood is already a permanent fixture on my yearly charitable donations, but I'll definitely take a look into these other organizations, especially if they're more in need. :)  http://fundabortionnow.org/get-help?zipcode=70551&amp;amp;hasclinic=2&amp;amp;clinicstate=LA&amp;amp;gestation=0

Here is a link that can help with finding funding.

Are there any women's shelters or services in your area? They might be able to help you with this dilemma and in general if you're looking to get into more a more stable living situation. Maybe if you find some people in Louisiana, they can point you to more local resources for BC and reproductive health services.

You seem very strong and level-headed, and I wish you the best of luck in both this situation and beyond. 
 LA isn't on the list. I called the two national funds, and then called all the clinics in the state to ask if they had any financial asistance programs, or would partner with the national fund, and they said "no". Am I doing this wrong? 

Also, I was feeling pretty happy and stable living in my van and being single. But not stable enough to be resposnsible for another human being. I guess i just fucked up, and I'm trying to get it together. Both funds say that you should have the clinic you've scheduled your appointment with contact the organizations. Have you tried that?

*Everyone* fucks up some time. It happens. It's how you react and deal with your fuck-up and how you work to prevent future fuck-ups as much as possible that counts most. I'd recommend looking into getting some cheap/free birth control as soon as possible after this, whether you decide to stick to your van or to try to find "permanent" housing. The clinic just said they don't take funding, I really can't imagine why, and I'm totally open to a different clinic.  The clinic just said they don't take funding, I really can't imagine why, and I'm totally open to a different clinic.  Have you considered a medical abortion instead?

I have no idea what the side effects are or if you still need counseling or how much it costs, but I know you can just take two pills instead, you could still be lucid for a cab ride. It costs more for some reason, the state requires "concilung". I would totally do it if it was affordable/convenient. Has anyone tryed the link on the sidebar, Women On Web? It says its 90 euro's for the pills, is this safe and effective? It costs more for some reason, the state requires "concilung". I would totally do it if it was affordable/convenient. Has anyone tryed the link on the sidebar, Women On Web? It says its 90 euro's for the pills, is this safe and effective?  &amp;gt;At the very least, maybe I could find someone who can drive me from New Orleans to metarie early next month so i don't have to sleep outside the abortion clinic

I just made a post about this. I strongly recommend not getting into a vehicle with a stranger.

Maybe instead you could set up a paypal account? Or crosspost this to /r/Assistance ? Three good points. I just thought it would be safer than sleeping in a part of town I don't know after taking painkillers. But i'll park by a friend's house and take a cab. Some clinics will let you hang around until the painkillers wear off. Can you call and ask?

Where's your ex in all this? Out of curiosity. If he's pro-choice and a semi-decent human being he should be willing to help you "clean up the mess" in some way or another since he's partially responsible. Three good points. I just thought it would be safer than sleeping in a part of town I don't know after taking painkillers. But i'll park by a friend's house and take a cab. Where in Metairie is it? If all else fails you can take the Canal street car up to the graveyards, then catch the bus that goes down Veterans. It would be much better to have someone with a car for when you are done. Good luck. You are right, I might do this and then take a cab back if I have the money.   I really hope a fellow TwoX'er could help out with the rides. 

Best of luck! I really hope everything goes well.  I really hope a fellow TwoX'er could help out with the rides. 

Best of luck! I really hope everything goes well.  &amp;gt;I really hope a fellow TwoX'er could help out with the rides. 

I really hope it doesn't come to that. I love this subreddit, but it's way to easy for a predator to come along and kidnap a woman under the guise of giving her a ride to an abortion clinic.    Here are some resources I found for pregnant women in Louisiana. There is a group that provides free and confidential care for you. [Here's their website](http://www.adifficultchoice.com). They can help you in your time of need and can also help you find more permanent housing as well. If you search your zip code, they will give you a number of shelters in your area that can help you. I hope everything turns out for the best. That site appears to be referring to "crisis pregnancy centers," which shove religious dogma and false information down the throats of women to guilt them, deceive them, and shame them into carrying pregnancies, regardless of whether that's the best decision for those women.

I *really* hope you did that accidentally.
 I realise this, s/he was only trying to be helpful. It's insane to me that they have one of these places in every neighborhood, yet Im having trouble finding an actual abortion clinic. Any way, its not a difficult choice for me, and I'm in the most permanent housing situation i've ever been in (no landlord, no roaches, no leaky roof. And I own it.)  That site appears to be referring to "crisis pregnancy centers," which shove religious dogma and false information down the throats of women to guilt them, deceive them, and shame them into carrying pregnancies, regardless of whether that's the best decision for those women.

I *really* hope you did that accidentally.
 That site appears to be referring to "crisis pregnancy centers," which shove religious dogma and false information down the throats of women to guilt them, deceive them, and shame them into carrying pregnancies, regardless of whether that's the best decision for those women.

I *really* hope you did that accidentally.
 Either way, OP seems to be a strong enough woman to stick to her guns and accept whatever help they can give her within her consent. If they can give her a warm, safe place to stay until her appointment, then isn't that worth giving her the information? Often times these places make the care that the give contingent on the woman making what the consider "the right choice." 

Also, who are you to decide what OP can and cannot handle? Even if she can handle it, she should not have to. They hand out false, unscientific literature, and do everything in their power to push their idea of what is "the right decision." I would hope that you can understand why a woman in OP's position should not have to go through that. There are much better groups out there that can help her without forcing their beliefs down her throat.  I was not aware that they had a religious affiliation. I'm not from LA so I looked up organizations and they seemed professional.  I was not aware that they had a religious affiliation. I'm not from LA so I looked up organizations and they seemed professional.  Either way, OP seems to be a strong enough woman to stick to her guns and accept whatever help they can give her within her consent. If they can give her a warm, safe place to stay until her appointment, then isn't that worth giving her the information? Here are some resources I found for pregnant women in Louisiana. There is a group that provides free and confidential care for you. [Here's their website](http://www.adifficultchoice.com). They can help you in your time of need and can also help you find more permanent housing as well. If you search your zip code, they will give you a number of shelters in your area that can help you. I hope everything turns out for the best.</snippet></document><document><title>IUD moved out of place. Considering changing BC-- opinions?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18u59k/iud_moved_out_of_place_considering_changing_bc/</url><snippet>So I know that there's been discussions about this on 2X before, but I couldn't find a thread that really went over all the options with all the pros and cons.

I've had a copper IUD for the last...18 months-ish? I got it checked for the first time in ~a year today, an the doctor said it had moved, wasn't protecting me anymore, and had to be taken out.

Now I've got some questions.

1. Is it true that I should be worried about pregnancy now? I tried to do some research and it looks like it's not really a risk unless it's, like, all the way out.

2. I'm considering changing for two reasons-- first, because the strings were poking my partner (I know that's a silly reason), and two, because it hurt SO MUCH the first time i got it inserted, and I'm scared of doing it again (...also kinda silly).

So, what do you use? What did you use before? What are the pros and cons? I'd love to hear.  Crap, I am due for an annual. Thanks for the reminder.

Did she do an ultrasound? Unless it's poking out, thats really the only way to tell where it is. I'd use a backup method just in case, it can't hurt.

I have a mirena - did you notice anything off about it? I worry about mine moving but my strings have stayed put for over 6 months, would love to know if you had any 'symptoms'!   I've been on the copper IUD for the exact same amount of time. From what I understand,

1. Yes. Even though the copper can act as a spermicide itself, you have the most protection when it's in place where it should be. I second curlyzz's suggestion to get an ultrasound, just to be completely sure where it is.

2. The IUD is great, but like any other BC, it's not for everyone. I can completely understand your apprehension on getting another one inserted...the surgery to get mine in place was some of the worse pain I've ever felt in my life (never given childbirth, granted). I would talk to your gyno/doctor to see which choice is best for you. [deleted]</snippet></document></searchresult>