<searchresult><twoxchromosomes /><document><title>Some "friends" called me condescending among other things that really stung. Could I get some advice?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18nj65/some_friends_called_me_condescending_among_other/</url><snippet>I will start off by saying that I have never counted these three particular people among very close friends. But they are friends. 
One of them is a girl who just likes to start drama for drama's sake (we'll call her Sarah). One is a guy who always has a very condescending tone of voice and who offends me on literally a daily basis, but I know he doesn't mean it maliciously so I let it slide (he will be Jake). And the last is someone who likes to argue about religion, politics, etc. for argument's sake (he will be Nick). 

Yesterday, I made a comment that Jake found offensive. I said that one of his friends was ignorant for trying to argue that the earth was only a few thousand years old while we were studying for a geology exam. He started freaking out about the comment, and when I realized he was really upset, I was really shocked (because he is always offending me), but I apologized anyways for saying the guy was ignorant and went on to say that I think he is a nice guy, and I worded what I had said poorly. However he didn't accept that and kept ripping my head off. Then Sarah chimes in, "Well people probably think YOU'RE ignorant!" and started going off as well about how I lump all Christians together and she finds it hurtful. However that is completely not true. I honestly don't know where that was coming from. I have never spoken to her about religion before, and I definitely don't talk down about any religion or try to say my views are better. In fact, I'm studying cultural anthropology because I love that people have such diverse ideas about the world around them and want to learn all about it. 

Jake and Sarah started calling me condescending and saying that I always talk down other people's views, etc. I was getting really upset at that point because those are two things that are so completely untrue and it really hurt to know that they felt that way about me. I tried defending myself but this is when Nick jumped in and started agreeing with them. Once they stopped ganging up on me, I got up and left. I was so hurt and in shock. I am aware I shouldn't have said what I did, and I really was sorry for offending him, but I felt their reaction was completely unnecessary. 

Later, Jake texted me and said he was sorry for biting my head off because he didn't want things to be tense, but he also went on to say that he won't apologize for any of the things he accused me of because he stands by them. I tried explaining that I think they are misinterpreting things if they really feel that way. When we talk about serious subjects, I will voice my opinions and defend them, but I will never talk down to anyone else, especially not for their beliefs. I am VERY sure of my beliefs, so maybe that comes off as condescending? I don't know. But I have not once thought I was above anyone for any reason. And he basically told me it doesn't matter what's really going on in my head because that's how it comes off and he said that he knows hearing criticism is hard but I need to stop taking the victim's stance because there's validity to it. 

I really still can't believe this is happening. I can't believe they think that of me. Every day Jake will say something rude about my major, he will say something really mean about my boyfriend, etc. But like I said, I know he isn't saying these things to be mean, so I let it go. Why wasn't I treated the same way? Especially after I apologized for it, why couldn't they let it go? 

I don't ever want to see them again knowing what they think of me. 

What should I do? =/

EDIT: The text conversation with Jake didn't make me feel any better. He stands by what he said about me and thought my explanations were just excuses. In the conversation he continued to be really rude to me, and it ended with him getting tired of talking to me and saying "Well I think we understand each other to a point now, so I'll see you around." 

EDIT2: The friend who I called ignorant was not around during this conversation. Actually I haven't seen him in well over a year because when he found out what my beliefs were, he started being rude to me and would lecture me every time I saw him on why I was wrong and he was right.   I have two questions.

Why would you take the views of a drama queen and someone who is consistently condecending and offensive seriously?

Why do you call these people friends? I really don't know. I guess because all of the really good friends I have aren't around as much, and it is nice to not be lonely. But really they are not very nice people. The one guy just upsets me on a daily basis and I can't take anything she says seriously because I know it is fake. 

But it is still really upsetting knowing people feel that way about me.  So make new friends. Keeping toxic relationships around because "it's better than being lonely" is bullshit. Yeah I know you're right. 
Should I say anything to these two? Explain why I don't want them in my life any more or just kind of disappear?  Yeah I know you're right. 
Should I say anything to these two? Explain why I don't want them in my life any more or just kind of disappear?  Yeah I know you're right. 
Should I say anything to these two? Explain why I don't want them in my life any more or just kind of disappear?   If they're mean to you every day and you guys are incompatible in your core beliefs, what benefits are there to the friendship? There are none except that we're always around to keep each other company. That really is all there is to it. If I cut them from my life, I'll be alone a lot more.     Some people take an insult towards one particular Christian as an insult towards all Christians, but of course there's a ton of denominations and types of people. But even die-hard Christians with more extreme beliefs generally know to suck it up and hide it when in a science class that conflicts with one of their beliefs. I remember having a physical anthropology class (the whole class was pretty much about human evolution and nothing else) where the teacher talked about getting a lot of teacher evaluations saying she was on a fast-track to hell. 

But yeah, light gossip about stupid things classmates said during class does not make you condescending. It sounds like your friends are too judgmental of you, I mean if you can't gossip with your friends a little bit, who are you going to gossip with? </snippet></document><document><title>I was seriously PMSing today, and then I found this.  I'm much better now.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/wYnLCOn.jpg</url><snippet>  Make sure you get one for next month too! I bought a bag of dark chocolate squares and I'm really enjoying them this shark week. =) Haha shark week.  I like to say "my kill room is ready".  People who casually over hear me always look a bit uncomfortable...  Haha shark week.  I like to say "my kill room is ready".  People who casually over hear me always look a bit uncomfortable...       This kind of shit keeps women a millennium behind.  ...chocolate keeps women a millennium behind? This kind of shit keeps women a millennium behind.  This kind of shit keeps women a millennium behind. </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] I like to do retro looks. Here's the 1930s.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/3nfhRWW.jpg</url><snippet>   Beautiful! Do you have any other era pics? Some bad ones, but I am thinking of doing more good ones and will probably post them here if I do! Some bad ones, but I am thinking of doing more good ones and will probably post them here if I do! If you live near a university, you should find a photography student and take some high-quality photos. Or you may just be able to find an aspiring photographer looking to build a portfolio.    I want to do this! Can I friend you so I know when you do other looks? :D Sure! Is that possible on here?! Also I did another look, but don't know whether to submit it today or not.   </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] This week, I learned that my "aunt" is actually my birth mother. This is me (20) and my "cousins"/half-sisters (8 and 10) Minecrafting together last Thanksgiving.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/TcysxS6.jpg</url><snippet>  That must have been kind of mind blowing for you! 

But as they say, the family that games together stays together. Or at least I like to say that. That's a very cute picture : )  My best friend got pregnant really young, and her parents adopted the child, so he is now her ''brother.'' How old were you when you were told you were adopted? If you don't mind me asking...  I've known as long as I can remember. I was always told that I "grew in someone else's tummy" and that "she loved me so much she wanted me to be with a family that could take perfect care of me." I've known as long as I can remember. I was always told that I "grew in someone else's tummy" and that "she loved me so much she wanted me to be with a family that could take perfect care of me."  So, is Minecraft the new Pokemon? I thought it was just a college nerd thing, but I'm getting the impression now that every kid in middle school plays Minecraft. So, is Minecraft the new Pokemon? I thought it was just a college nerd thing, but I'm getting the impression now that every kid in middle school plays Minecraft. So, is Minecraft the new Pokemon? I thought it was just a college nerd thing, but I'm getting the impression now that every kid in middle school plays Minecraft. So, is Minecraft the new Pokemon? I thought it was just a college nerd thing, but I'm getting the impression now that every kid in middle school plays Minecraft.   Nice kitchen Nice kitchen</snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] Yesterday I spent some time with my first, true love, drawing ponies. (X-post from r/drawing)</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/fd80c3x.jpg</url><snippet>  As someone who loves ponies, and loves to draw ponies on a daily basis....................... I can say I totally want this picture. Your hatching technique is pretty sweet!</snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] For my last day of work, my co-workers got me this. I have the best co-workers ever.</title><url>http://imgur.com/As3eEg3</url><snippet>  It's your last fucking day? You must be a sex line operator... JK :) Good luck in your future endeavors!! Hope the cake tasted as good as it looked    *Had</snippet></document><document><title>Why the Word 'Panties' Is So Awful (And What to Do About It)</title><url>http://www.theatlantic.com/sexes/archive/2013/02/why-the-word-panties-is-so-awful-and-what-to-do-about-it/273224/</url><snippet>   What a huge overreaction. This is exactly what I hate about some people, they're always looking for something, even the most little things, to get offended over.     In the UK we say knickers!  I think it sounds more funny than sexual.      </snippet></document><document><title>Can we make a rule against threads asking for rides to abortion clinics? It's very dangerous for both people involved.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18mfw5/can_we_make_a_rule_against_threads_asking_for/</url><snippet>Hi 2xc,

I've noticed you as a community are incredibly generous, giving, caring, helpful people, however, every time I see a thread asking for rides to an abortion clinic, I cringe.

For all we know, the people so helpfully offering to give a poor, heartbroken lady a ride to Planned Parenthood, are actually part of some pro-life propaganda group who would instead drive them to some church. Or a psycho who'd just kidnap them. Or on the other end, the person in need of help is really a scam artist who'd steal your purse and run.

There are other ways to help, for example calling a local taxi and playing (at least part way) for a ride, or calling Planned Parenthood and offering them the money to pay someone, or referring to the places someone made a thread of a few days ago.

tl;dr while most hearts are in the rights places, you never know who's who on the internet. Be careful offering or accepting rides from strangers.  I think this is a really fair point to make. By posting on the internet, "Hi, I'm going to have an abortion, here is where I am, I will be alone, waiting for you to pick me up in your car," you leave yourself *really* vulnerable to bad people. I know that people resorting to this aren't in a good situation, but I think finding a stranger on the internet for this is still unnecessarily risky, and I'm glad someone is pointing this out.  [deleted] Most cabs I've used had to report their pick-ups and drop-offs. I'm sure if I called the company and reported I was thrown out due to the drivers religious beliefs I could easily get a refund and the driver would be fired.

&amp;gt;a group of anonymous yet supportive women on the internet.

This would be the perfect place for some psychopath to prey on a woman feeling scared and helpless. [deleted] They also tell the cabs where the person is and needs to go. I doubt any sane cab driver would take it, or risk their job by taking them elsewhere.

Hey, I just see these posts from scared women, and scared people make great targets for scammers. I don't want to add to their grief by posting "NO DON'T TAKE THIS RIDE, THIS COULD BE A FREAK WHO'S GOING TO DRIVE YOU TO AN ABANDONED ALLEY AND RAPE YOU AT GUNPOINT!" instead I'm just asking that the mods enforce a policy of offering these people options that don't involve trusting a stranger to let them into your vehicle and take you to a secondary location. [deleted] Sorry, but I think we Redditors, especially in a subreddit like 2xc where we're all more polite and have way less sexism, forget that despite the good grammar and the posts from everyday people the internet is for everyone. Even "the bad guys". We should not be getting so comfortable here that we're getting into cars with strangers. [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>A Female Tarantino?: Women Still Blocked From Significant Roles As Actors &amp;amp; Filmmakers</title><url>http://eye.columbiaspectator.com/?q=article/2013/02/14/female-tarantino</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] My first free-hand embroidery! It was a housewarming/Valentine's/anniversary gift for my boyfriend.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/WFOUJTZ.jpg</url><snippet>  Edward Sharpe and the Magnetic Zeros? Edward Sharpe and the Magnetic Zeros?   Adorable!  I firmly believe that a piece of embroidery, made with love, brightens up any room.  I finished my first project a week ago and now I'm addicted!       that's really pretty! is this hard to learn? i would love to get into something like this, but ill definitely abandon the project if too much skill is required  Not at all! I'm not much of a sewer and don't have a ton of patience. I'll link you to a kit I bought on Etsy when I get back to my computer.  : )</snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] My boyfriend and I on Halloween.  Yes, that's his real hair.  Just dyed black. It's nicer than mine.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/yTYciJz.jpg</url><snippet>   Did everybody pick up on your Hunter S? Or did they just think you were dressing snazzy? Did everybody pick up on your Hunter S? Or did they just think you were dressing snazzy?  Let me just warn everyone...DO NOT use eyelash glue to stick on fake mustaches.  Especially right after you shave... </snippet></document><document><title>My boyfriend is good at many things - romance is not one of them. So I gave him a cheat sheet. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18m18q/my_boyfriend_is_good_at_many_things_romance_is/</url><snippet>I'm not sure why I'm telling you guys this, as I'm not positive it'll even work. But here goes: My dude is pretty wonderful, but he's clueless about romantic stuff. He's like an artsy Ron Swanson. After several months of trying to rid myself of the desire for sweet talk and romantic gestures, I concluded that it will always be important to me. I hate when people see a partner as a project, so I was skeptical about trying to transform him into rico suave. I kept wondering: Where exactly is the line between tweaking behavior so things run more smoothly and trying to change a person?

So we had a talk. 

I was like "Hey! I love you! You're awesome! BUT, you're not providing some basic stuff I need. Here are the things: (insert mushy stuff here). If this is more than you're willing to do, I understand. That just means we're not right for each other. If you're willing to try to be more romantic, I'm totally willing to be patient and help you out. What do you think? Also, feel free to air any grievances about me and I'm happy to work on 'em." Obviously I'm paraphrasing. It's hard to play it cool when you're 67% positive someone is about to be like "I'll see my way out".  


Thankfully, he wanted to work on it. So after figuring out that the problem was *remembering* to do/say sweet stuff (not lack of desire to do so), we decided I'd make him a TardGenius Cheat Sheet. I promise I'm not normally this anal.
 
Here are the categories: 

* The Basics - do these things and we'll be fine (nothing insane, stuff like "if you think I look pretty, tell me."
* Important Events - Dates that are important to *me*, i.e. birthdays, anniversaries, holidays I care about
*  How to Cure the Sads - What to do if I'm upset. It often involves wine and cheese enchiladas. (he's not an idiot, but sometimes he can't determine if I'm venting or actually need help)
* Gift Resources - Links to Amazon and Pinterest Wish Lists, list of stores I like, friends to contact for help with gift ideas
* Stuff I Like - activities, cuisines, floral varieties - anything that helps him hone in on what *I* like, not some stereotypical idea of romance. 
* Places I want to go in town - anything from specific restaurants to cheesy roadside attractions. I only listed stuff I'd want to do with him.

Making the list so specific makes it seem like he doesn't know anything about me, which isn't necessarily true. He's just less into variety than I am, so going to the same restaurant over and over isn't a problem for him. He doesn't think to try stuff he remembers from a random conversation we had two months ago. It takes doing it once and creating a positive association with the stuff for him to remember to do it again. I'm hoping over time, he'll be able to guess what kinds of things I'll like and he won't have to refer to the cheat sheet. Until then, I'm crossing my fingers. 

**TL;DR** Boyfriend isn't romantic. I made him a cheat sheet to try and inject some romance. We'll see what happens.   This is an awesome idea! Kudos for communicating about this rather than sulking/breaking up. :D  I'm not really a romantic myself so I'm not sure I really get it. Is is about getting stuff you want as a surprise rather than just asking for it? 

Edit: I should note I'm genuinely curious.  I'm not really a romantic myself so I'm not sure I really get it. Is is about getting stuff you want as a surprise rather than just asking for it? 

Edit: I should note I'm genuinely curious.  I was purposely vague about the specifics out of respect for my dude. Basically, the main issue was that he doesn't verbalize the nice things he thinks. It's important for me to hear "I love you", "you're beautiful", etc.   That really sounds like a great idea. My boyfriend forgot Valentine's day this year and it was a major bummer. Education is helpful!  Seems to me like you wrote a list of relationship demands, not helpful suggestions. I'm gonna have to disagree with you here. We came up with the idea together and he wanted to do it (and he'll probably make one for me too). I asked him beforehand and told him to talk to me about anything he had a problem with.   This sounds like something I should look into doing myself. My current boyfriend can be such a sweet guy, but he really has no idea how to treat me as his girlfriend. So often I feel like I'm just another roommate. It is very possible my communication skills are just not up to par so far to letting him understand me, so his responses to me end up making me feel even worse...
I'm wondering how specific you are without sounding "needy", and how someone who is not very good at getting across her feelings, can go about this process and start feeling like I'm in a relationship again.   This shit is brilliant! Even for my guy, who's amazing at this stuff. My dad sure could've used one before the divorce...  I feel like I should have covered this earlier in our relationship and it's almost too late. I tried bringing it up once and he said something like "I feel like I've done nothing different than what I've ever done in the past and even in other relationships" I've been so happy with him except for this whole side of the spectrum. You don't think after a year and living together it's too late? I don't want him to think that he has to change when he's been making me happy thus far. He just doesn't do anything romantic like this and I'm always the one creating the situations.  I think you should approach it similarly to OP. If it really doesn't work, then maybe he isn't the guy for you. If he understands where you are coming from, then he obviously wants to make you happy and make your relationship work. I feel like I should have covered this earlier in our relationship and it's almost too late. I tried bringing it up once and he said something like "I feel like I've done nothing different than what I've ever done in the past and even in other relationships" I've been so happy with him except for this whole side of the spectrum. You don't think after a year and living together it's too late? I don't want him to think that he has to change when he's been making me happy thus far. He just doesn't do anything romantic like this and I'm always the one creating the situations.  This is gonna sound REALLY cheesy, so brace yourself. I read this book called The Five Love Languages and it has really helped us. It's basically about figuring out the kinds of things that make you and your partner feel loved and doing them regularly. Often they are very different. I need verbal affirmations of love and my dude needs help around the house (mostly). Both of these things cause us to have the same feeling, which is INSANE to me. It's really hard to imagine that me changing his cat's litter gives him the fuzzy feeling I get when he tells me I'm beautiful. But it totally does! Caution: the book is marriage-centric and occasionally talks about God and prayer. That's not my bag, so I just ignore that stuff because all the other stuff is really great. Also, it's REALLY easy to skim through it and get the main ideas. I mostly read the chapters on the languages, which is like 6/10 chapters. Do you have a Kindle? I'd be happy to gift you that book! </snippet></document><document><title>My wife had an emotional encounter with an elderly couple and is shaken up about it. It's unreal and I need help helping my wife.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18kxyu/my_wife_had_an_emotional_encounter_with_an/</url><snippet>**Warning: This story may be a trigger.**

My wife works as a receptionist at a place that has many elderly people come in. On Wednesday (ash Wednesday), a husband and wife came in, clearly in their late 70s or early 80s.

The whole time, the husband was being mean and talking down to his wife about what to do, such as "sit and read your book we'll be here a bit" and "get your coat on, we're leaving", quickly followed by "take your coat off we're staying a bit longer". Clearly he was not a nice guy at all.

My wife ended up in the bathroom at the same time as the woman. My wife talked to her about what was going on. The woman responded:

"Oh he knocks me down every day and chokes me. It's been that way for **56 years** but it's my cross to bear."

This absolutely blew my wife away. She said she was shaking and sort of lost it all day. When I picked her up she started sobbing about it all. She did have an abusive father growing up, so I'm sure that didn't help her here at all. Now I'm trying to find a good way to make my wife feel better. Any ideas?

I hope that no one else ever feels stuck in a relationship like this poor woman. It is never a "cross to bear" and you can get out and get help. My wife is now going to post phone numbers for battered women in the women's bathroom at her job hoping it will help someone.

By the way, the kicker? The couple both had their ashes from that day. Clearly the husband thought he was a Christian. Ridiculous.

**TL;DR Elderly woman in an abusive marriage for 56 years, thinks it's a cross to bear.**  Friend of my mam's went to her local Catholic priest for marriage advice back in the mid-90s, and was told "Everyone has their own cross to bear, this is yours..." when she broached the topic of possibly leaving her abusive husband. 3 weeks later he tried to burn down the family home with her and her 2 young sons in it...    This is actually a common way of thinking of many old christian women, at least in my country. They have been raised to think that they must care for others and not for themselves and that they have to sacrifice themselves for the well being of the people around them. Even if that involves being trapped in a lifelong marriage with an abusive partner because, you know, the only mission on a woman's life is to pop out children and to please her husband... and life is just suffering and a "vale of tears" anyway.

Yeah, it sucks and I wish there would be something that you could do to help that old woman. I don't have much advice to give though, apart from being there for your wife and listening to her. I hope you both manage to help that woman somehow though. This is actually a common way of thinking of many old christian women, at least in my country. They have been raised to think that they must care for others and not for themselves and that they have to sacrifice themselves for the well being of the people around them. Even if that involves being trapped in a lifelong marriage with an abusive partner because, you know, the only mission on a woman's life is to pop out children and to please her husband... and life is just suffering and a "vale of tears" anyway.

Yeah, it sucks and I wish there would be something that you could do to help that old woman. I don't have much advice to give though, apart from being there for your wife and listening to her. I hope you both manage to help that woman somehow though. What does this have to do with Christianity?  People of all religions endure abusive relationships.   They definitely do, but it seems that their visible ashes (marking them as Christian) and her word choice ("my cross to bear") make the particular attitude and set of beliefs that come from a Christian perspective relevant.  [deleted] [deleted]   It might breach confidentiality agreements depending in where she works as a receptionist, but if I had the couples names I'd be all over calling Protective Services. Maybe she can talk it over with a supervisor or something and if there is a confidentiality thing going on, it can be overridden?  You know, it may sound crazy to us as young people from a different generation, but the woman may not _want_ help.  Maybe she doesn't want to have her life dramatically disrupted without her consent at this stage.  I would be very cautious about intruding into their lives _without consulting the wife about it first._ In my area, whether or not she wanted help would be irrelevant. Elder abuse falls under the same mandatory reporting laws that child abuse does, and I, as a medical professional, would be obligated to file a report. 

Now, I don't know what the specific laws are in the OP's wife's area, so I can't say if she has to file a report or not, but elders are very often included in mandatory reporting laws because they're a vulnerable population.  You know, it may sound crazy to us as young people from a different generation, but the woman may not _want_ help.  Maybe she doesn't want to have her life dramatically disrupted without her consent at this stage.  I would be very cautious about intruding into their lives _without consulting the wife about it first._ Yeah, that's something to consider, but her telling somebody else almost seems like a cry for help. Maybe there's a way to visit with her or something and talk about it? I would never want my grandmother or somebody to deal with this, especially was an elderly woman. I can see my grandfather becoming the same way (if he already isn't) to my grandmother, so it may be a sensitive issue to me.  That's true.  So my advice would be, if the wife's name is found, to talk to her about what _she_ wants, or to simply inform her that these options are available to her, rather than just having Protective Services show up and completely disrupt her life.  Which could be quite traumatic to an elderly person. You know, it may sound crazy to us as young people from a different generation, but the woman may not _want_ help.  Maybe she doesn't want to have her life dramatically disrupted without her consent at this stage.  I would be very cautious about intruding into their lives _without consulting the wife about it first._ That's what I was thinking too, but then, you know, if she doesn't want help it's only because she's in such a bad mental state that she doesn't realize she needs it. &amp;gt;she doesn't realize she needs it

Ehhh... I just don't know that any of us should judge for her what she needs.  That's why I think she should be informed and consulted before any decisions are made for her.  Maybe she'd like to know that counseling is available for them, for instance, but does not want the police to suddenly show up. But... a person who is being physically and emotionally abused daily *does* NEED to get out. 

It's like a person who was taken captive who developed a relationship with his/her captor. Does the fact that the person now has sympathy for her  captor mean that she never needs to be freed? Certainly not!  It might breach confidentiality agreements depending in where she works as a receptionist, but if I had the couples names I'd be all over calling Protective Services. Maybe she can talk it over with a supervisor or something and if there is a confidentiality thing going on, it can be overridden?  In my state, elder abuse is in the same category as child abuse and falls under mandated reporter laws. I don't know where the OP lives or what his wife does for a living so I can't 100% say for sure that they would apply to her, but if I were to encounter a situation like that in my place of employment, I would be legally mandated to report it. 

Adult Protective Services is very different from Child Protective Services. If APS investigates and the adult is deemed in danger and/or in need of services, he or she can refuse the services/help. So, if this got reported and investigated, the woman could tell APS to scram if she wanted to. If not, though, they could help her get away from her husband.  It might breach confidentiality agreements depending in where she works as a receptionist, but if I had the couples names I'd be all over calling Protective Services. Maybe she can talk it over with a supervisor or something and if there is a confidentiality thing going on, it can be overridden?  Most places have Tarasoff laws in place about confidentiality whereby if a person says something about seriously harming another person, it is legal to break confidentiality.   </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] I've been painting for 5 years and have finally found my style. Here are a few favorites!</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/8w8xs</url><snippet>  Is that a cat with its ears flattened and its back raised? I'm desperately in love with it.   I love that you did one of rats!  Rats are pretty much the most underrated pets ever.  I had several generations of pet rats as a kid and loved them, they're so friendly and smart, they're much more like miniature puppies then rodents in terms of their behavior.  I once trained one of the rats in my middle school science lab to do tricks, the first rat I ever had used to fall asleep on her back while having her belly petted. That's awesome! The picture is of my first two girls that have passed away. I'm currently in the middle of a piece featuring one of my new girls. I also like to spend a lot of time in r/RATS I love /r/RATS, the photos make me so happy.  I haven't had rats for many years and it makes me sad.  My roommate works in a lab with them and considered adopting us 2 or 3 babies for us to keep in our apartment but unfortunately animals aren't allowed :(.  I have to get vicarious enjoyment from seeing other people's rats.  I just miss their cuddles, I used to love having them sit on my shoulder and burrow through my hair whenever I watched tv. Yeah, I just got my new pair of girls last month, they are so sweet! Technically I'm only supposed to have my cat here with me, but I also have a fish and my 2 rats. Maintenance people come and go but no one has ever said anything. My cat isn't so sure about them. When she gets up on the sofa when they are out they love to run over and lick and nibble at the cat's fur. Usually the cat just runs away. :P        Wow, these are all fantastic! I especially love the rat duo and the bright orange cat. 

Do you have an etsy shop or something similar?  No, no shop, I just paint for fun. The rats were some pets of mine that passed away so it's kind of a memorial painting. And the cat is my female cat. I have a similar painting I did as a pair for that one of her brother. Here's the brother with the pair: 
http://i.imgur.com/oxGcNmP.png If you do decide to sell some of them, please let us know! Your work is awesome and I'd love to have something like this in my home. =) No, no shop, I just paint for fun. The rats were some pets of mine that passed away so it's kind of a memorial painting. And the cat is my female cat. I have a similar painting I did as a pair for that one of her brother. Here's the brother with the pair: 
http://i.imgur.com/oxGcNmP.png Do you have a tumblr or a Deviantart? I love the rats and the cats you've done. (Rats are such great pets, it's such a shame their lives are so short. Sorry about your girls.) I have a DA, it has some other mediums besides painting, but painting is still my favorite! 
http://a-s-rich.deviantart.com/ Awesome, following you!

(Ponies and Pokemon, too?!)  </snippet></document><document><title>Diva Cup Questions! Please help!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18mgdl/diva_cup_questions_please_help/</url><snippet>Hello fellow Twoxers, I recently purchased a diva cup and this is my second cycle with one. I was wondering how do you ladies put yours in. I've tried both of the recommended folds for insertion but I continue to have leakage. I understand it usually takes a few cycles to fully master the insertion correctly but I have VERY heavy periods and really cannot afford leakage! Any tips that you could provide would be great!    Neither of the recommended folds worked for me so I use an alternative folding method I found online. Push one side of the cup down into itself. It should look like this. 

http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mwvcz42PTKY/TX1ZELwgwzI/AAAAAAAAAEo/5p3_jQHiO38/s1600/IMG_1119.JPG

Sorry for the horrible link. Im redditing from my phone right now. Ive only gone through one cycle with my cup but never had a leak or incident whatsoever with it so far. Be sure to twist the cup after insertion. After twisting I usually stick my index finger in alongside the cup just to insure that its fully opened. Hopefully this fold works for you. If not try looking up folding techniques for other menstrual cups. Theyll work just fine with the diva cup. And welcome to the club! Youll never want to go back trust me. In just one cycle the diva cup has changed my life! this one! this one!  so much easier than the c-fold!!    I'm going to recommend http://menstrual-cups.livejournal.com/ 

Yes, it's a livejournal site, but it's really well-moderated and the ladies that lurk there are exceptionally helpful.     </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] My roller derby comment this week was very well-received, so here's me being a bad-ass on the track last weekend!</title><url>http://www.flickr.com/photos/kulshanpictures/8465787459/in/set-72157632748953766</url><snippet>  WOAH WOAH WAIT are you with Rat City? I've been wanting to check out one of your games so bad! Very cool, rock on. :D WOAH WOAH WAIT are you with Rat City? I've been wanting to check out one of your games so bad! Very cool, rock on. :D         I love to skate and have always wanted to be a derby girl but im super teeny and bruise like a peach. Perhaps ill revisit the idea once i have health insurance again.  </snippet></document><document><title>Natural hair revival among black women [video]</title><url>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-21455101</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] This is how I do romance: bacon roses, bacon maple beer, My Little Pony, and chocolate covered strawberries</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/L2X0eT1.jpg</url><snippet>  And a goddamn Kitchenaid Mixer!  I really really want one, but I don't have the space or money for one.    I bought my boyfriend that same beer yesterday! Spoilers: It is gross. D: Share it with friends for a laugh though. Update:  Boyfriend liked it a lot, said it was smokey tasting and would go well with meat.  I sadly didn't get to try it but am pretty sure I'd enjoy it too.


Then again I love bourbony dark high grav beers, so my taste in beers is not exactly the norm.     Everything was amazing except for that My Little Pony part. And the bacon maple beer. Which, in all honesty, was pretty fucking gross. He found it complemented the bacon really well though I came here to comment on the beer too. It's vile, but it looks good on a shelf. I love Rogue's chocolate mocha porter and Voodoo Doughnuts (anything, but ODB is the best!) but this combo is bad. The bacon roses are definitely something I should do for my fianc&#233; (we're /r/keto people)! Did you have a tutorial or just make them by guessing? Chocolate covered strawberries are such a popular thing; I think I'm the only human that dislikes the taste of strawberries. I wanted to grab the Valentine double chocolate stout, but they were out so I went with this Valentine packaging (keeping the bottle 'cause hey, it's kinda cool), and figured maybe it'd work out with the bacon roses.  The roses are something I've seen somewhere before, so I used this [Instructable](http://www.instructables.com/id/Bacon-Roses/) for the basic idea and cooking temperatures and time.  Definitely decided against using fake rose stems.  I also don't like strawberries, but the boy-dude-man loves 'em so I figured "sure."  I used the leftover chocolate on clementines and pomegranates for myself :)

[edit] I did, however, modify the instructions a bit so I wouldn't have to use a Dremel on a muffin pan: I used little [cupcake liners](http://winealittleeveryday.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/cupcake-liner.jpeg) that were hollowed out to hold its shape, used a toothpick to hold it in place, and put it on a rack for it to dip into a pan underneath in the oven. Which, in all honesty, was pretty fucking gross. He found it complemented the bacon really well though Thanks for noting that; I was really curious about the beer. Everything was amazing except for that My Little Pony part. I really don't understand the My Little Pony thing. I really liked them when I was little, had their mansion and everything. I'd probably still brush their stupid pony hair given the opportunity,but I don't get the craze. It's a cute, well-done, well-animated and well-written show that's geared towards children, but that's not so insipid and dumbed down so that adults can't enjoy it too. I like it, but lots of people don't, and that's fine. I love cartoons, I'm not hating on the fact adults like it, but the level to which the "bro-nies" like it is  just weird. Everything was amazing except for that My Little Pony part. </snippet></document><document><title>IFF: my first time actually having a valentine, and he did so good.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/RQ5oOui.jpg</url><snippet>   [deleted] The video game Ni No Kuni. I had to give it to him early so he wouldn't buy it himself! He's a nerdy guy. [deleted] I don't see why people set price limits for gifts, it doesn't matter how much or little you spend on each other, it's the thought that counts. 

Anyway, he's extremely good at picking out jewelry. Better than most guys I think. He knows what I like and what I don't like I don't see why people set price limits for gifts, it doesn't matter how much or little you spend on each other, it's the thought that counts. 

Anyway, he's extremely good at picking out jewelry. Better than most guys I think. He knows what I like and what I don't like [deleted] [deleted] Those pearls definitely aren't $2000 though.  They're freshwater.  $500 max and $90 if you know a wholesaler. Even if they were $5 I'd still love them. They're so pretty! Those pearls definitely aren't $2000 though.  They're freshwater.  $500 max and $90 if you know a wholesaler. [deleted] [deleted] [deleted] Genuinely curious, do you write "the" as "teh" because you think it sounds more "cute" or "silly" thus softens what you're saying? Also not trying to be combative, just find "internet linguistics" really interesting. [deleted]   I like this guy. He's a keeper!</snippet></document><document><title>I've waited all week to post mine too! He asked last Thursday but I hadn't told everyone yet so I couldn't post last [IFF]!</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/g6mDe2B.jpg</url><snippet>          Is that a pink diamond?  I love the ring design! </snippet></document><document><title>The clitoris explained</title><url>http://blog.museumofsex.com/the-internal-clitoris/</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] Finally it's Friday, I've been waiting all week. My fiance proposed last Saturday!</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/4r2GyTU.jpg</url><snippet>   We had just come back from an anime convention, and we're getting into the trunk to get our bags, and he grabs this carboard box, opens it, pulls out a ring box, drops to one knee in the snow and ice of the driveway, and asks me to marry him. It was totally perfect, the perfect ending to a totally perfect day.  Awww, that's really cute. :) Congrats, and I hope you have a very awesome future together! The ring is really pretty too, nice colors. (Today I learned what morganite is and *I love it*.) We had just come back from an anime convention, and we're getting into the trunk to get our bags, and he grabs this carboard box, opens it, pulls out a ring box, drops to one knee in the snow and ice of the driveway, and asks me to marry him. It was totally perfect, the perfect ending to a totally perfect day.   Is that morganite I see? Yes it is. :3  Congratulations! Your ring is very pretty. What kind of stone is that? Congratulations! Your ring is very pretty. What kind of stone is that?  </snippet></document><document><title>IFF: My boyfriend and I got each other the same thing for Valentine's</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/aM5kZ</url><snippet>   Coheed, delicious-looking beer, and hockey?!

Are you me??   Holy crap, are you me?? Mabye?! Can we be best friends if so?   Where did he get those cups? I need them!  Your beer is making me jealous. My SO and I got a bottle of weihenstephaner for valentines as well, but it had obviously been sitting on the shelf for quite some time. Sad day. That happened to me with a bottle of Legend Lager a couple weeks ago. It was cloudy and tasted kind of off. So disappointing.  Which Kitachino is that? I tried the ginger beer and it was good. I just love the little owl, I have to admit, although if I go for beer it'll probably be a Rochefort Trappist 10. It's the Weizen. I've had it before and it's absolutely delicious. If you like hefeweizens/witbiers it's perfect. They also have a white ale that I've been meaning to try.      </snippet></document><document><title>Five months ago, my husband and I eloped in NYC. Before we did, we secretly made our own rings! Here's mine - the process was so fun, it made me want to become a goldsmith one day.</title><url>http://imgur.com/4aVl1Ri</url><snippet>  That's awesome! Mind sharing how you did it? </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] I love doing photo-shoots with my silly cat.</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/hUwxA</url><snippet>  You look like Florence Welch!  WE HAVE THE SAME FURBY    

OMG  love it.  you're amazing! and YOUR HAIR! oh my goodness, I would love to have that color.  You remind me of Weird Al. That weird intensity and silliness combined perfectly. (:</snippet></document><document><title>Desperately trying to find a way to remove nude photos. Is there anything I can do?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18m80n/desperately_trying_to_find_a_way_to_remove_nude/</url><snippet>Hey ladies,

So I was an idiotic and naive 17 year old girl trying to gain some confidence about my body and sexuality, so I took naked pictures of myself. They were for private use but are now on the internet (probably somebody hacked my email...I didn't have the best PWs back then either). I found out about them when a guy I knew told me (so awkward). Now I am trying to find a way to remove as many of these pictures in order to prevent them from spreading. I really need help here because after hours of relentless searching, I've found nothing helpful. People just say there's nothing you can do or that I shouldn't have taken the pictures in the first place. I know that it might not be possible to remove all the pictures but if there's something I can do about it, I want to know.

After I found out that my photos were on the internet, I've really lost all my self esteem and just feel ashamed for what I've done. I feel disgusted that there are strangers fapping to my pictures. In the end, I know it was all my fault and I want to resolve this as much as I possibly can because I've grown up and I want to put my past behind me.

Thanks in advance, everyone.  &amp;gt;I've really lost all my self esteem and just feel ashamed for what I've done. I feel disgusted that there are strangers fapping to my pictures.

There's nothing inherently wrong with taking naked pictures of yourself. The people who should feel ashamed and disgusted are the ones who took the pictures without your permission and distributed them. Internet security is something to be aware of, as there will always be terrible people out there, but what happened is in no way your fault.    If you find any on the internet, you can contact the sites and report the picture as child pornography (at least if they are US sites, or ones that choose to abide by US law).  If it's on the internet, it's forever. As long as your real name isn't attached to them so they don't come up when you google yourself, you're pretty safe. Thanks. I know that it's impossible to remove them all but I want to lessen the impact if possible. </snippet></document><document><title>My parents hate my boyfriend. I need to vent and, for the first time in recent memory, I need advice. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18luqz/my_parents_hate_my_boyfriend_i_need_to_vent_and/</url><snippet>I met my boyfriend through a mutual friend a little over a year ago. He was a big, big-bearded, tattooed man. He still is. He's 25, I'm 21. He has gauges, a septum piercing, a lip piercings, and a few additional ear piercings. He is apprenticing as a tattoo artist for free at a local shop and works there doing piercings. He makes fairly good money for his age. He never went to college, but is considering technical college. It's obvious that he's come from hardship, but he's smart (very smart), sweet, respectful, multi talented, and overall, just completely genuine. He's a wonderful human being with an honest soul. Additionally, he's the only guy i've ever dated who takes me out on dates. Who buys me gifts (which is, admittedly, very pleasant). Who goes out of his way to open doors for me. He would beat up a man for saying something crude to me (which I'd never let him do, but it's a nice thing to know). He makes me dinners. He's so much better of a person than I am. 

It took me about 8 months to consider dating him, because I knew it would never work out. My parents are conservative. They're wonderful, hardworking people. But we are not the same. Although I have many conservative values, I still enjoy hanging out with eclectic people. I always have. My parents have only ever liked a handful of my friends. They've never approved of any of my boyfriends. The last time I had a "serious" boyfriend (It wasn't. I was 18 and had just moved to a new state, so when my boyfriend moved down it was more of a "yeah! I have a friend again!" rather than a "thank god, now we can get married!" sort of deal), my mom pretty much broke down crying, saying that I was ruining my life by dating that guy. 

Now, I'm apparently ruining my life because "despite how good or talented he is..." my life "will be hard with a man who is full of piercings and tattoos".  

Now, I understand where they're coming from. When they were growing up, my boyfriend's style's key features were reserved for only sideshow freaks, criminals and people on National Geographic. My parents don't realize how common it is. They also don't realize that tattoo shops can be perfectly respectable these days. So I get it. I'm not mad at them. 

I just don't know what to do. I have social anxiety, a pretty bad guilt complex and I hate talking to my family about anything. My boyfriend and I have been dating for four months (though I've wanted to date him since we met), and I am very much in love with him. But I don't want to risk losing my family over this again. 

I know it's all so stupid. I just don't know what to do. Any advice? People who have been in similar situations? I need help. 

**tl;dr: My parents hate my tattooed, pierced, punk boyfriend despite the fact that he's a wonderful person. Help?**

UPDATE: Apparently my whole family is against me on this. My brother and sister don't like him. I live with both of them. I should clarify: they both LIKE him, but they don't like him as my boyfriend. It makes this especially hard since I don't have anyone to talk to. 

They all think I've had too many boyfriends. I've had two serious boyfriends in three years. I've dated (gone on dates) with about 5 in three years. My mother thinks I'm complicating my life by submitting myself to these relationships. My sister, who is not very social, agrees. My brother, who believes himself the epitome of a moral person, also agrees. 

I enjoy meeting people. A lot of the people I become friends with are male. I do have an abundance of male suitors. I've had a handful of female ones. I'm not overly flirtatious (from my perspective, at least). I don't know what it is, but people get crushes on me often. I know how it looks, because people find it perfectly reasonable to tell me how they think it looks. 

It looks like I'm slutty. I'm not ignorant to the fact that a woman who hangs around men looks like the friend-circle-slut. I just think it's stupid. 

But my mom, apparently agrees. And so does my dad. And my sister. And my brother. 

And my boyfriend, they feel, is just an additional fling in their eyes. 

To remedy it, I've been trying to explain that it's a serious relationship. But I'm not sure where that's going to get me in all of this. 

  &amp;gt;It took me about 8 months to consider dating him, because I knew it would never &amp;gt;work out

Do you still feel this way? That it will not work out? Basically, I feel like you have to make a big decisions here. You either feel like this won't work because your parents have ideas and beliefs that they are set in and it will cause conflict and drama and you cannot deal with that. 

OR

You feel like maybe you could deal with that and you continue seeing him (and it sounds like he's great and you're very much committed to him at this point) and attempt to mediate and give your parents time. 

Is there any possibility they would come around eventually? Are you particularly close with them? Is their opinion something you value? 

I mean I know people who have said "eff it" and bulldozed on and eventually came to a very precarious balance with their parents and significant other. I've also known people where it's worked out nicely. Then again, I know a lot people that have had to deal with years of tension and a lot of resentment (and/or drama) due to similar situations. 

While I don't think you should allow your parents to control your choices into your adult life, especially when it comes to who you date and commit yourself to or build a life with...I do get that their presence in your life is important so you wouldn't want to create tension or conflict there if it could be avoided. 

Essentially, unless you think they would be receptive to a long discussion and somehow 'see the light' eventually, you're going to be fielding a lot of conflict in the future. 

Is this man someone you see being with long term? Do you depend on your parents financially in any way? Would they take drastic measures if you made it clear he's sticking around long term? (as in: would they stop speaking to you, treat you or him poorly, cause upset or drama, etc.)

I think you really need to consider a lot of things. Though you've only been dating 4 months, I realize you've known him much longer and by how you talk you are obviously committed to him and love him. So I guess it's like this: do you think there could be a tentative peace between your parents and your boyfriend if he is someone who is in your life long term? Would they be able to suck it up and treat you both with respect and act civil? Or is this a deal breaker for them? Would it cause enough upset they would want to cut off contact or something else severe like that? 

I'm sorry I can't give you something that will somehow make it better. I really wish I could because I've had many close friends in your position and I know how painful it can be to be caught within this situation. 

 My mom is a lovely, wonderful lady who can be a hardcore bitch if she wants to be. Dating him long term would simply mean that she would be mean whenever he's around. Not the obvious, malicious sort of mean. But the cold, passive aggressive sort. I know that if I were to marry him, they wouldn't introduce him as their son in law. They'd be embarrassed by him. Perhaps they wouldn't invite him to family gatherings. 

It would be a nightmare for me. 

For my boyfriend, probably not. He went through those trials with his own family already. He became aware of my family's distaste for piercings/tattoos when we first met. It was the reason I gave him when I turned him down (we're all in favor of honesty). He's also pretty resistant to the opinions of others when he doesn't know them personally. I know that, if he cared, it would only be for my sake. 

But that doesn't really make it easier. It would work if I didn't have a family. I honestly don't know if I'd be able to deal with my family if I continued the relationship. 

But i know that if I ended the relationship, I would resent them for a very, very long time.  &amp;gt;it would be a nightmare for me

Why? Your familys being ridiculous about this and obviously don't know as much about you and what makes you happy as they should. If your bf does then you deal with whatever shit they pull.   If you live at home, be prepared for a shitstorm, but it's still workable.

Tell your parents that you appreciate their concern and will keep their opinions in mind, but you are an adult and the decision is yours.

Then refuse to talk about it. If they try to bring it up, say, "I don't want to discuss this right now. Let's change the subject." That could piss them off, but it's a necessary part of becoming an adult.

&amp;gt;I have social anxiety, a pretty bad guilt complex and I hate talking to my family about anything

If you have the means, please look into therapy. Not only for the boyfriend issue, but as someone with some experience in guilt complexes, they're toxic, toxic things that you need to deal with. I'm considering going to a psychiatrist to get assessed. Honestly, although my family would never believe it, I think I have the female version of Aspergers, which would explain my history of anxiety and a good portion of the behavior they find so intolerable. Not that I'm looking at is as a solution. I have considered it for a long time.  &amp;gt; female version of Aspergers

&amp;amp;#3232;\_&amp;amp;#3232;

There is no 'female version of Aspergers'. From what I've read, girls with Aspergers have a more mild form of Aspergers. It's also a bit harder to diagnose in girls. *There are no boy or girl versions of Aspergers, if you have it you have it*. Honestly, Aspergers isn't the end of the world either.

Now...

&amp;gt; I have social anxiety, a pretty bad guilt complex

Going to see a psych is a good idea. They can diagnose you with anxiety and either give you medication to control it, or tell you how you can do it yourself.  &amp;gt; female version of Aspergers

&amp;amp;#3232;\_&amp;amp;#3232;

There is no 'female version of Aspergers'. From what I've read, girls with Aspergers have a more mild form of Aspergers. It's also a bit harder to diagnose in girls. *There are no boy or girl versions of Aspergers, if you have it you have it*. Honestly, Aspergers isn't the end of the world either.

Now...

&amp;gt; I have social anxiety, a pretty bad guilt complex

Going to see a psych is a good idea. They can diagnose you with anxiety and either give you medication to control it, or tell you how you can do it yourself.  Hmm.. as a total aside.. I wonder if that plays at all with me.. but it would be extremely strange dynamics in my case. If I have this very very mild Aspergers, talk about a confirmation of my gender identity.. but it would be a difficult diagnosis for me too, since my social development was severely impaired by being straight-up ostracized and bullied as a child, so we're talking a chicken-and-egg problem.. and while I display some of the verbal oddities, I'm aware of my quirky language play, and recover quickly from it.. usually.. ^but ^it ^would ^be ^odd.. ^I've ^tried ^to ^convince ^myself, ^thanks ^to ^my ^empathic ^range ^primarily, ^that ^no, ^it's ^not ^an ^autistic ^condition.. ^but ^damn ^me ^if ^the ^clog ^doesn't ^fit..


 www.reddit.com/r/aspergers/

Don't go on there looking for a diagnosis. But reading about different people's experiences can help you see if it's something you should look into it. 

http://www.help4aspergers.com/pb/wp_a58d4f6a/wp_a58d4f6a.html

Look at the images from that link. It's a list of aspergers traits in women. If you feel like the majority of them fit your life/behavior, maybe you should look into it more. 

Keep in mind that a lot of the testimonials from different people will include behavior that might not be related to Aspergers, so you could find yourself relating to perfectly normal, NT characteristics and mistake them for those associated with Aspergers. 

Good luck.  I started looking a little deeper, and damn me if I don't express a horde of those behaviors. :/ I'm starting to spend a little time on that particular sub.. but yaaargh. Upside, it's a piece to the puzzle of my history that I didn't have before.. downside.. it's a two hundred pound iron ball that makes it harder to move freely.  I'm considering going to a psychiatrist to get assessed. Honestly, although my family would never believe it, I think I have the female version of Aspergers, which would explain my history of anxiety and a good portion of the behavior they find so intolerable. Not that I'm looking at is as a solution. I have considered it for a long time.  Honey, a diagnosis will change nothing other than give you a label to hide behind. My advice to you is to be mindful of situations, try to watch your tendencies, question what is comfortable and step out of your comfort zone on occasion, when you are ready. This has worked for me:) I know. I haven't gone in for a diagnosis because I don't want to give myself a "crutch".  I get along fairly well. I just feel very, very repressed. I want to be something much different. But no one will let me, and I don't know how to express that without being told off for it. I'm aware that sounds childish, but I have a very hard time dealing with the things people find wrong in me. I guess I want the diagnosis so that I know. I just like knowing. 

Lol. This whole thread has made me feel insane and silly. But it's legitimately how I feel about things. I figure if I'm taking the time to write down my feelings on the current situation, I may as well put up my feelings about this too.  It definitely sounds like you need an outlet to express yourself fully, where you know you will be supported. It's not silly to feel this way at all, your feelings are legitimate. I know how hard it is pretending to be what people expect. I did this for many years.... And it isn't something I was able to just change overnight. Over time I was able to be more 'myself'; it meant dropping unsuportive friends and limiting my family interactions for a while when I sorted things out. It can be a lonely experience, so finding support is important. Whether it's a close friend, a therapist, or even a journal, having an outlet helps.

If I could tell you one thing, it would be this: you are already perfect as you are. There is nothing wrong with how your mind works, or your thought patterns. If you dont like the way things are, you can change. 

Your behaviour - and thought patterns- are a combination of the subconsciously (hormones, ingrained behaviour) or learned experiences, and conscious mind. Pay attention to how you are feeling, and ask yourself questions, like 'why does this make me happy," or "what about this situation makes me unhappy?". Soon you will see patterns and really get to understand why you react in certain ways.

You get to choose how you present yourself, and to whom. Understand that you can't control how people react to how you behave. Those who deny your feelings likely don't understand them. It doesn't mean that they don't value you! 

Good luck! :)  You are an adult (at least legally) and it is about time your parents stopped controlling your love life. Sit down with them and talk, calmly, about how you respect their values, but in your bf's case they have misjudged him. Tell them how incredibly stressful and sad it makes you that they are forcing you to choose between your relationship with your bf and your relationship with them. If your mom cries or tells you you're ruining your life, just tell her you can't talk to her when she's like that. End the conversation there. You're not a little girl anymore and are allowed to make your own choices, especially about who you choose to spend time with.  It's very difficult for me to talk to them calmly. Right now, our discussion has been conducted through texts, which works better. I stutter when I get upset sometimes, and my natural instinct is to yell to remedy it. This way I can look over what I say before I say it. It's been pretty civil, it's just an awful situation. 

Also, this way I won't have to deal with their emotions. I get that I'm their child and they'll always see me as a child...but the crying and hysterics is just bizarre. My dad will stop talking for a while, and my mom will just...I don't know. 

I think she's moodier today because my aunts know about it. I guess my cousins talked about it with them or something. I have a huge Catholic family, and everyone talks. So my aunts knowing about it puts extra pressure on my mom to fix it. 

God, it's awful. 

But you're right. I think if they try to talk about it, I'll just have to end it. But inevitably, it will cause them to yell. :/  I have a similar family. I urge you to consider seeing a therapist to discuss how you can set up appropriate boundaries with your family; not for your boyfriend, but for yourself. This sounds like something that will happen with whomever you date; he's not the problem, although with the whole tattoos/piercings bit, he might be a harder pill for them to swallow than most.

The setting up boundaries thing is not easy, and it takes time. I've been working on it for a few years now, myself. But I know that I am MUCH happier with the boundaries that I have been working on than I was before.

Also, if you can live apart from your siblings at some point, I think you'd be a lot happier. While I'm sure they wouldn't agree because my parents want me to live next-door to them for the rest of my life, our relationship improved by leagues when I moved out (and away, school a few hours by car).  [Go stalk this forum](http://community.babycenter.com/groups/a4725/dealing_with_the_in_laws_and_foo_family_of_origin)

Yes, it's technically a networking website for mommies, but the ladies on that specific forum will give you no-nonsense advice about how to handle your relationship with your FOO (family of origin) and how to prioritize your adult relationships. 
  I really doubt your family will disown you for dating a guy with tattoos. If he's such a nice guy and your parents really do care about you, why not have them meet and get to know each other? Your mom can appreciate his chivalry, your dad can appreciate his plans for trade school and maybe it will help them look past the colorful outer shell to his nice red insides. Just like everyone else. 

You're 21, so you should approach this like an adult. Have your boyfriend meet your parents like adults do. Don't be all embarrassed and ashamed of your bf because your parents "don't Approve" because it'll just reinforce their notion that you need guidance and parental interference in your love life since you're not yet confident enough about your relationship to be open about it.  You should have an honest talk about how much it upsets you that they can't accept him. Your family loves you no matter who you date, they will accept it in their own time. If you leave him solely because they don't like him how would that really make them feel? They would feel bad, regardless of how he looked. AND would you resent them if you left him and always wondered "what if"? They will respect you more if you stick to your guns.  I'm glad to see you are very understanding of them! I definitely would be stressed about this. 

My problem, even IF you did break up with him, would be question every time you like somebody: will they be good enough for them?

I think it is definitely important to stress that looks aren't everything here. There are so many respectable people who treat their SO's like crap, and you have this, from my understanding, GREAT guy. There's that much to it, and if it were me-why pass up that chance?

Good luck :) I think my boyfriend is absolutely, dashingly handsome. He's got these magical blue eyes, and this goofy hair that always stands up in weird positions. He's a heartthrob. Total stud. But you're right in that looks aren't everything. My struggle is to make my parents understand that. But they're seeing him from the angle of a potential employer. They don't realize that there are other ways to make good money that don't involve working in an office. 

And yeah, I always think about whether a potential boyfriend is good enough for them. Most of the time though, even when I come to the conclusion that they aren't, I date/go on a date with them anyway. I really struggled in the past to put myself first in situations like this. But once I did it, I never stopped. I just wish it was an easy thing to bridge.  It's definitely a difficult decision. I say you stick with him, but good luck!  I'm atheist and my boyfriend is a closeted atheist. His mom is extremely conservative, almost a caricature of a Virgin-Mary-complex Catholic Mexican mom. It took his mother (his dad has passed away) three years to accept me, but she finally did despite the fact that when she found out I was atheist she flipped infinite shits. 

What worked for three of us was a lot of politeness, friendly gestures, and a genuine effort to indicate that we wanted to make it work for my boyfriend's sake, because we both love him. I went to church and listened to her whenever she wanted to tell me things that had to do with faith, God, whatever and she was very kind to me, too, and tried to get to know me better. I called her occasionally to say hi, and she called me on my birthday. On holidays, she was welcoming of my traditions (I'm not American) and let me add food that made me feel closer to home. My boyfriend put in a lot of work, too. Whenever he could, he would slip into the conversation that what matters most about a person is what they do, not how they identify themselves. A kind, good person no matter what. Three years later (this past Christmas) she told my boyfriend that she likes me a lot now. 

It was difficult, but what really helped our efforts "click" was the realization that we loved the same person. She also realized that, even though she didn't like me and was afraid of my influence on her son, she had to trust his judgment and give me a chance. 

If your family and your boyfriend realize this (which I'm sure your boyfriend does already) then you can be well on your way to navigating some way of accepting each other. However, your family needs to trust your judgment and that is something that may not be fully in your control because, for some reason, some parents just don't trust their children completely. And while it may be tempting to refuse to talk about your boyfriend, don't hide him from your family completely. Don't throw him in their faces, either. But try to subtly drill it into their heads that (1) this is your relationship, (2) you have sound judgment, and (3) what people do and how kind they are matter more than what they look like. 

Best of luck! If it is meant to be, everything will work out and your family will accept him eventually! Just keep trying :)  This kinda reminds me of myself in a way. When I was in high school I didnt have many friends, and ended up hanging out with the geeky kids. Naturally, there aren't many girls in that group (at my school at least), so most of my friends were guys. I would hang out with my guy friends after school all the time, and my mom really didn't like it. 

She was fairly conservative, though never pushed those values on me, but she still let me know how she felt. I got my first boyfriend when I was 17, and immediately she thought I was spending too much time with him. That relationship lasted for almost 2 years, and I'd actually met my next boyfriend while I was still dating the previous. The next one and I ended up dating for almost 2 years as well. Again, she told me that I was spending too much time with him, and she didn't like me dating him. 

We broke up and I was single for a few months before I started dating again. As soon as I mentioned dating again to my mom, she immediately started saying I was seeing too many guys blah blah and I was being slutty blah blah. In those 4 years I'd dated like, 5 guys, and none seriously.

This continued on until last year (when I was 25) and I met my fiance. She still feels the need to tell  me that I'm  moving too fast and to not give myself to a guy. 

I find this very irritating, and it took me awhile to get over the hurt of her calling me a slut. Essentially I just had to realize that this is my life, not hers. She has her ideals, and thats fine, but my life and who I want myself to be isn't dependent on my families approval, but that also doesnt mean I don't love them. 

Just follow your own path regardless of what they say. If you're happy, that is the most important thing.  I'm tattooed, have piercings, and stretched lobes, and I am a medical student, work a placement in a hospital, and part-time in a shoe store. Your parents are judging him off his looks. </snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] I know most of you will disagree with my fashion choice, but I finally went out in the makeup to match my style, and I have never felt so liberated. This is me, and I love it. </title><url>http://i.imgur.com/yFJ7Hlg.jpg</url><snippet>  You look lovely. I applaud your choice to use your face as a canvas to display a part of yourself to the world. A lot of people think we should all try hard to look the same, but I think the world would be a better place if we wore our inner selves on the outside a little bit more. That should be the real point of fashion. Thank you so much! You're comment made me so happy. I've never been able to put my feelings about this into words, and you just did it so perfectly! I wish all people saw things that way. It would be so much easier for people to be themselves.  Thank you so much! You're comment made me so happy. I've never been able to put my feelings about this into words, and you just did it so perfectly! I wish all people saw things that way. It would be so much easier for people to be themselves.  You look lovely. I applaud your choice to use your face as a canvas to display a part of yourself to the world. A lot of people think we should all try hard to look the same, but I think the world would be a better place if we wore our inner selves on the outside a little bit more. That should be the real point of fashion.  I've always assumed that those cross-face chains would be really annoying to wear. Is it, or are they just special-occasion jewelry, or what? I wear it when I want to, not all the time. It's not annoying at all, but it does fall off sometimes because it is only tucked behind my ear. Little secret...It's only a bracelet ;) I'm sorry, but I have to ask. How do you blow your nose ? I'm sorry, but I have to ask. How do you blow your nose ? I think most people who just have a normal little nose piercing won't wear it if their nose is runny, so I'd imagine the case is the same for OP. :) I think most people who just have a normal little nose piercing won't wear it if their nose is runny, so I'd imagine the case is the same for OP. :) You have to wear it even if you have a runny nose- they heal up extremely quickly I normally just flip mine up when I have a runny nose, but I took it out once and lost the jewelry and found it like 2 months later and I could still get the ring in. It hurt, but the hole was still there :P  Wow... mine healed up (after 4 years!) in only a week. Where was yours- septum or nostril?  Really?? dang. Yeah, it was my septum. I guess everyone is different with how fast they close up.  Mine was nostril. Septums close slower because of the makeup, but nostrils heal crazy fast. It's been 6 months and you can't even tell there was ever a hole. You have to wear it even if you have a runny nose- they heal up extremely quickly I'm sorry, but I have to ask. How do you blow your nose ?  Your eye make-up is so pretty! How did you do it? Just apply under the eyes and then...drip water down?! It looks great.  Thank you! :) I just put on normal dark eye liner, then messy eye shadow above and below my eyes. After that, I used my eye liner to draw on the "tears" and then smeared it with my fingers :P 

[EDIT] I forgot to say, the white on my face (there's more on my forehead) is fishnet markings. I put my old fishnet stockings on my face and used white face makeup on a sponge to dap over the fishnets and make the print. You can do the same with lace too. So much fun! And I'm stealing that! Thank you! :) I just put on normal dark eye liner, then messy eye shadow above and below my eyes. After that, I used my eye liner to draw on the "tears" and then smeared it with my fingers :P 

[EDIT] I forgot to say, the white on my face (there's more on my forehead) is fishnet markings. I put my old fishnet stockings on my face and used white face makeup on a sponge to dap over the fishnets and make the print. You can do the same with lace too. So much fun!    For what it's worth coming from a stranger on the internet, I love *love* love it! How did you do the eye makeup?        Looks great! I love your lip colour.      kudos to you for being who you are :)
also, your septum piercing is awesome and you're adorable!     </snippet></document><document><title>The crazy is strong with this one: birth control turns women into fetus graveyards </title><url>http://rhrealitycheck.org/article/2013/02/01/they-are-coming-your-birth-control-your-womb-is-full-tiny-dead-baby-corpses/</url><snippet>  I don't know about everyone else, but I open my demon-hatch on my belly once every five months or so to scoop out the dead babies. This also keeps me pleasantly slim so that I can remain a constant temptation to the menfolk.

Seriously, though, I am amazed that with the wealth of knowledge available out there that people still get by with believing this stuff. I'm gonna go be a hermit now :( Dead babies make a good stew too.   I heard about this on Dan Savage's podcast. I didn't know whether to laugh or scream.      </snippet></document><document><title>Stranger sitting next to me in a coffeeshop pointed phone at me and took photos, pretended to not speak English when I casually asked what he was doing</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18leu6/stranger_sitting_next_to_me_in_a_coffeeshop/</url><snippet>What's the appropriate way to act here? I didn't want to grab the guy's phone in case I was wrong (and he'd just been taking photos of the window)  because that would've just been rude :/

I got off easy this time since a kind gentleman nearby picked up on what I was asking and translated it for me, forcing the guy to delete the photos he had taken, (they were of me) but I'm worried I won't be as lucky if this happens again. I should note that the guy DID indeed speak English but dodged the question by pretending he didn't.  Your best bet would be to take pictures of him taking pictures of you, or ask *loudly* what he is doing. People like that don't like having the sun shone on them.

Grabbing his phone could be considered an illegal act against him. If the photos hadn't been of me, would that have been awkward? I didn't want to seem really paranoid :/  First off, that's creepy/annoying.

However, your options are pretty limited, since it's legal to take pictures of people in public places without their consent.  I haven't found anything super-official, but sources seem to generally agree with [this] (http://www.ehow.com/info_8581945_illegal-pictures-people-permission.html).   </snippet></document><document><title>I'm not sure how to deal with the massive changes in my life. Any and all advice appreciated.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18lrrs/im_not_sure_how_to_deal_with_the_massive_changes/</url><snippet>Hey 2X,

For the past 5 months I've been writing posts to you all and then deleting them out of completely unnecessary fear and shame. I'm even using a throwaway. I don't know why. I shouldn't be scared or ashamed of what's happened but I do and for the past few days everything has got on top of me and I feel like I should be doing something to at least try and lift some of this weight.    



  Without going into too much detail, I grew up in an abusive household. Trouble is... I didn't even know (perhaps 'realise' is a better word) it was abusive until a few years ago when I moved away from home at 17 because everything was too much to handle and I suddenly realised that nobody else's dad behaved like mine. Now my mother has bravely taken a stand is going through an incredibly messy divorce.  
   


  I am finding it hard to cope with some of the things that happened when I was growing up. I'm finding it hard to cope with some of the things that are happening now. I'm finding it hard to cope with the uncertainty that my myself, mother and young sister are facing. I detest that my father has manipulated my brother and is using him as a pawn in this whole thing. I think I hate my brother too, for going along with it. I've not spoken to him in months and at the moment I feel like I never want to speak to him ever again. I also have to go to court hearings and give evidence. The first one is in a week. I don't know how to deal with it. I don't do public speaking because I have no confidence whatsoever. Speaking to strangers is a huge deal for me, even making phonecalls makes me have mini nervous breakdowns. I'm finding it hard to cope with every day tasks and communication. My head is a mess. I can't concentrate on school or work and I feel like it's not worth getting out of bed most days. I know this is a terrible mindset to be in. Don't get me wrong - there are positive things in my life. I have a great boyfriend who tries his best to help out and be supportive and I put on a brave face as best I can but I don't think he knows the extent of my unhappiness and confusion. I know that's probably my own fault for being shit at communicating but there are some things I will never tell anyone and I feel so weak for blaming every little thing that goes wrong on this whole thing that seems to be consuming 100% of my waking (and sleeping) thoughts.   



  Bottom line is I'm so sick and tired of feeling tired, fed up, scared, worried, stressed, upset, angry and confused. I just want to feel comfortable, be able to sleep easy, to not have tummy pains constantly, to not feel on the edge of tears 24/7, to have normal skin again and not feel like I have no control over my life. For someone that has done so much wrong, my father still has so much control and I hatehateHATE it. This is a long journey and we're only at the start. I don't know how I'm going to make it all the way through.   



   So I'm guessing all I really want to know is what coping mechanisms do you all have? Are there any books or foods or activities that help keep you positive or even just distract you from your worries? 
I really feel like I'm on the edge of quitting everything to stay in bed all day and feel sorry for myself. I want to be actively fighting all these bad, dark thoughts and feelings but I just don't know how to.    



  Thank you for reading. I hope this makes even a little bit of sense.


  EDIT: I am so sorry for the huge wall of text. I tried to keep it short :(
  I grew up in a household with an alcoholic, unstable-parent and a culture of silence that kept me from knowing the truth for years. I can relate to a lot of what you're saying - the anxiety, the stomach pains, the terrifying feeling of lack of control, the exhaustion. I want to let you know that there is a way out, and you can get there.


My therapist has definitely been invaluable for me. I highly recommend finding a regular therapist who has a background in abuse survivors. Their knowledge of the psychological effects and behavior patterns can become your tools to finding peace. Therapy has done wonders for me, though having my parent go sober helped a lot too. I'm no longer depressed, no longer self harm, my anxiety is reduced to the point where it no longer controls my life - I still have issues, particularly control issues, but I enjoy my life and I'm hopeful about the future.


One big coping mechanism for me has been self-correction. It's exhausting at first, but it really helps. When you get onto a bad subject or thought, and worry it to death, say to yourself out loud: "It's not helpful to think about this right now and you're only making yourself upset. Don't think about this right now." I've found that with a little discipline it has begun to work. My friend uses a keyword to break up negative thoughts when she's in a rut, she repeats the word "blue" to herself, calmly, once every couple minutes.


And when you're upset and obsessing, and it's only making you more and more upset and closer and closer to hysterical, doing something mindless, while avoidance, can spare you a breakdown. Reddit is good for mind-numbing. I also use logic and word puzzles. Something that takes up your attention and is addicting.


As for positivity, well...it's been a slow build for me. I don't know if you have the self esteem issues I did, but try to find something you're proud of, that makes you proud, and look for more opportunities to do it. For me it was translating and speaking a foreign language.


Lastly, for relaxing, I have two pieces of advice: comfort and physical exhaustion. Doing something very physically comforting, like swimming on a hot day or cuddling up in bed when it's cold, can make you feel good, especially if you're doing it with someone. And a good physical workout can help take the edge off your emotions, plus it releases endorphins.


I know its hard, but trust me, quitting and staying in bed is only going to make you feel worse. Some days its all you can do to survive - so just survive. Otherwise, you've got to keep fighting. You can make it. This *really* hit home for me. The alcoholic unstable parent bit is exactly what got me into this mess. Thank you so much for taking the time to respond, I will really take on board what you've said. I'm in the middle of trying to find a therapist that I can afford (being an unemployed student sucks!) and I will find something to throw my effort and concentration into. Thank you for your honesty and supportive words, you have me crying happy and relieved tears.  My coping mechanism is a really good therapist.  Are you in school somewhere that you can talk to a counselor?  This is more than you should have to bear by yourself, and this deserves more than just "think positive thoughts."  

You are definitely not alone in this.  Abusive households fuck your shit up -- low self-confidence, anxiety, depression, I had them all.  Still have my moments, too.  Really digging into it with a good shrink is what really helps me get past it.   My college is pretty bad, I'm not sure they have a counselor. I will definitely check into it though, you're right about this needing more. I am in waaaaay over my depth. 

Thank you for your advice and I'm so sorry you had to go through this too. It sounds like you made it out just fine, that's all I want!
  I promise with hard work and an honest commitment you can absolutely get through this stuff.  You've already started to identify what's wrong so you are way ahead of the game.  Lots of people stay stuck in this kind of stuff till they're in their 40s, 50s, 60s, or never do anything about it at all...  

My dad wasn't physically abusive to me, but he was erratically emotionally abusive all through my childhood because he has never dealt with his anxiety disorder.  (He's one of those people who's in his 60s and hasn't dealt with his own issues, which I find really sad.)  His MO was to snap and yell and scream at me because I did something that transgressed his rules, which was stuff like lying on the floor, dropping a towel while taking the laundry out of the dryer, etc.  I was in denial for awhile that this "counted," or that it had had as much of an effect on me as it did -- some people had it much worse than me, what was the big deal?  But people aren't born thinking they suck.  That's his voice in there telling me I suck because [I inconvenienced someone] [I didn't pay attention enough] [I wanted to do something the other person didn't want to do].  

That's just an example of how this stuff seeps in.  I don't know if you have similar issues courtesy of your situation, but I promise that this kind of thing *can* be untangled and dealt with.  

On a more concrete note, my other major shrink-related advice is to interview a few different therapists if you can -- not every therapist is a good fit and a good fit is really important.  You want to work with someone you feel you respect.    I will second what everyone else here has said: therapy! What you're dealing with is not an easy thing to deal with, especially by yourself. If your college does not have a mental health counselor, here is a helpful website that not only lists out some reasonable options to get you counseling but includes the websites to look for sources of counseling in your area through local/state agencies: m.everydayhealth.com/emotional-health/0329/ways-to-get-cheap-mental-health-care (note this is for the US, but maybe there is an equivalent if you're not in the US). 

On a personal level, when I'm dealing with bad things that happen, I prefer to stick around people that will nurture me when I'm having a down day but that I can also do "normal" things with. I also prefer people who have been through similar things when I'm having a tough time. Perhaps this is your SO, perhaps your family. 
Spend time taking care of you: sleep well, eat well, make positive strides in academics or work. Work out. Bring in positive things to your life to focus on. This might even be as simple watching a funny movie. 
Perhaps less helpful, I adopted a puppy when I had PTSD. The dog stayed with me while I cried, didn't ask questions, and licked away my tears. When I wasn't upset, admittedly, she ate my shoe once. And my MacBook charger. But she was a puppy, so I guess all was forgiven. She was extraordinary in helping me feel supported. Maybe something you can do is work at an animal shelter if that's interesting to you? The animals are in a similar place to you- a very low point in their lives, and you can each brighten each other's days by just being there for one another.  Thanks for replying, I'm from the UK but that was still a very useful website. I'm going to make an appointment at my local citizens advice bureau to see if there's anything similar over here because I really can't afford a therapist on my student loan.

Oh my gosh, I would LOVE a pet, unfortunately my student housing doesn't allow for such a thing. I'll also look into helping at a shelter, that's such a lovely idea. I hope you and your puppy are doing well. It's lovely to hear stories like yours, it has really lightened my mood. Thank you again!  Part of my coping mechanism is to fake it.
Pretend like I'm someone who's strong enough to get through the day, pretend like I'm someone who can do this no sweat, pretend like I'm someone who doesn't care about whatever horrible shit my family would do.  What would this woman do?  
I act like her and pretend like I'm her.  Sometimes it actually makes me feel a little bit like her.

Hope things get better.  First aid suggestions:

Getting Through The Day: Strategies for Adults Hurt as Children, by Nancy Napier.

Also, time to take care of your limbic system:  
Healthy diet. 
Very regular daily routine for sleep/wake/eat/exercise.
Long walks or walk/run most beneficial.
Hugs also beneficial when you can get them.
It's okay to say "no" to stressful stuff, it's okay to limit what else you do for now, because you're very busy processing and coping.
Get support--there may be support groups for abuse survivors, or Codependents Anonymous, or something like that, in your area.

Find a good therapist. It may take some shopping. But part of what's happening, probably, is that you're dealing with a lot of memories and emotions that you had to repress or dissociate while growing up in that environment, and they're coming up now, for healing.  It's fine to take your time with that, it will take some time.

Do your best to say "no" to antidepressants or other psych meds, or at least if you're considering taking one, read Anatomy of an Epidemic by Robert Whitaker first.

My heart goes out to you. I wish I could just hug you. This is a very rough time. You WILL come through it, though, and heal in ways that will amaze you. Hang in there. </snippet></document><document><title>Speaking Up is a Privilege and a Right. (former fat girl takes on the Gladiator run)</title><url>http://www.theslackdaily.com/2013/02/speaking-up-is-a-privilege-and-a-right.html</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>I love him but...</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18l4zg/i_love_him_but/</url><snippet>hi ladies, i need some advice, there's this guy we've been friends for ever, he's been desperately in love with me for years, We have great conversations, real, genuine connections, and he's very dear to my heart. 

so last week he came to me with this long, heartbreaking speech about how i was  the only woman he had ever wanted and i decided to just give it a go. i couldn't stand the thought of breaking his heart, so i decided to let him out of the friendzone. but here's the thing... he weighs like 350 pounds. 

no matter how i try i'm just, not, attracted. physically speaking. i'm a virgin so maybe it's just me being shy. but i've always liked guys who i can, you know, get my legs around their waist. i am very fond of him, and closer to him than to anyone else but he just doesn't give me that... rumbling in the depth, and now i just feel shallow and cruel and i don't know what do do.   Pity is no substitute for love.  Would *you* want to be with someone who doesn't find you attractive? This has nothing to do with you being inexperienced. You aren't shallow. No person is attracted to everyone. More like almost no one is attracted to anyone who's obese.  That's actually not true.  It's not culturally acceptable to be interested in someone who is obese, but quite a few people are still attracted to big guys, and gals. More like almost no one is attracted to anyone who's obese.  More like almost no one is attracted to anyone who's obese.   You aren't responsible for his happiness.  You don't owe him a romantic relationship because he wants it, when you clearly don't.  You aren't the caretaker of his happiness, and it is unfair of him to treat you as such.   Don't lie to yourself. You cant force attraction. Either youre attracted to him or you arent. Its not set in stone yet, of course, he could always lose weight, but thats his own choice only.


What it comes down to is that right now youre better off as friends. Dont sleep with someone youre just not attracted to. Whats the point in that?


Especially not if its your first time. Remember that you dont OWE him a relationship.

You can enjoy his presence without being his gf. Dont do something like this out of pity.


You could always casually suggest you two take up swimming/running or something else, that way he loses weight and you two spend time together.


Best of luck to both of you. i guess i'm mostly doing it because ive been on the other side of this equation and got my heart broken for it, i couldn't do that to someone else.  You realize that the longer you're with him, the *more* his heart will break when it eventually ends, right? i guess i'm mostly doing it because ive been on the other side of this equation and got my heart broken for it, i couldn't do that to someone else.  i guess i'm mostly doing it because ive been on the other side of this equation and got my heart broken for it, i couldn't do that to someone else.  i guess i'm mostly doing it because ive been on the other side of this equation and got my heart broken for it, i couldn't do that to someone else.  Don't lie to yourself. You cant force attraction. Either youre attracted to him or you arent. Its not set in stone yet, of course, he could always lose weight, but thats his own choice only.


What it comes down to is that right now youre better off as friends. Dont sleep with someone youre just not attracted to. Whats the point in that?


Especially not if its your first time. Remember that you dont OWE him a relationship.

You can enjoy his presence without being his gf. Dont do something like this out of pity.


You could always casually suggest you two take up swimming/running or something else, that way he loses weight and you two spend time together.


Best of luck to both of you.  When you do end it, I think if you can find a way to gently tell him *why*, you should.  He needs to hear it, for his health and his future.  I say this as an obese woman, not trying to hurt any feelings but if you give him some bullshit reason for breaking up he will never change the one thing he can change.  "Fat" is changeable.  Bad personality, boring, hideous, things like that are harder to change imo.  It sounds like he could be a good catch if he took better care of his body?  Self improvement doesn't hurt anybody.  He's cheating himself out of so much in the future.  :\      While it's true that dating him out of pity isn't a good way to do it if the only thing holding back from being in love with him is that you're not attracted to him and that you're not attracted to him because he is so overweight then that is something that can be worked on. It's important to know why he is so overweight. With the right encouragement and work you could help him get rid of that weight.

I am in no way saying that you should or that it's something you owe him or anything like that. I'm more saying that it is something you could work on. I agree with posters saying don't sleep with him out of pity or similar. If you think that you could fall in love with him if he became more attractive to you then try to find a way to tell him that. And then help him get there.

The both of you working on something like that could be something that will bring you both even closer. And even if it's something you both do and you still don't have feelings that strongly for him then as a friend you will have gotten him to a place where he may have the confidence to find someone else rather than just waiting around pining for you.

It is hard but I do agree that you should end it as a relationship now but as I've said if you think that it could be something more then let him know and work on it. A good strong relationship is something that is built up and maintained.  Hi, I have been in the same situation myself. My best friend of 5 years or so had been desperatley in love with me for like ever, but I had always rejected him because I just wasn't attracted to him. But then I figured I'd give it a try. I knew he was a great guy and I also knew if we'd ever have kids he'd be a fantastic father, I knew I could trust him with everything and so on. He just seemed perfect. I just didn't have a crush on him.

So here's what happened. He was my first boyfriend. We had a nice relationship, we talked a lot, we shared a lot. But I always seemed a little unsatisfied. I had worries and doubts. After almost 3 years I broke his heart and split up with him. Here's why:

1. I always wondered what it would be like to be with a guy I was really attracted to.
2. He always felt like a compromise. I felt like it was very unlikely I would ever find a guy who's as nice as him AND who would "make my toes curl" (I think that's what Rachels says in Friends). So whenever we passed obviously happy couples on the street I would think: "Man, I wish I had that, too". He actually deserves better than being a compromise.
3. The sex ist just... bad with a guy you're not attracted to. You'll never have the desire to jump him right here.
4. The pity thing.
5. He put me on a pedestral. He felt like I could do better than him and treated me like I was high above him. Because he didn't feel attractive himself, I seemed to be what made him confident. He would never go out without me.
6. I kinda always hoped it would change. Or I would change. But nothing happend. And after 2-3 years I realized I started being disgusted by him. When I hadn't seen him in a while, I would shudder when I first saw him again and think "Oh my god, THIS is MY boyfriend?" I know it's unfair. But the closer we got, the more i was repelled by his outside. I felt like our physical intimacy couldn't catch up with what we had intellectually. Now, with my current boyfriend, I always have the urge to show him around and tell everybody: "See what a great guy I have? Isn't he awesome?" I'm so proud of being his girlfriend. This is the feeling you should have. If you're not having it, something isn't right.

Here's one truth I've learned: It's never going to work out if you don't really have a huuuge crush on him. Which, of course, includes that you're physically attracted to him.

The worst thing is, today I think I should have known from the start. I could have spared him a lot of trouble. Also, this ended our beautiful friendship. I've barely seen him in the past 2 years. I mean, back then when I said "I love you" I really meant it. I thought I did. I liked him so much and I wanted him in my life.

The friendzone thing is there for a reason. Maybe some girls use it to play with guys, and that's the type of girls who should let their friends out of the friendzone. But the right way of letting someone out of the friendzone is always telling them what you really feel about them. And if you can't be honest to him, because you're afraid that you might hurt him... well, than that's not a good basis for a friendship, let alone a romantic relationship which should always be built on honesty.

I just hope you don't do the same mistakes I did. Wish you both the best of luck and a lot of strength to go through this. It will take a lot... I just think friendships with people who are in love with you are a bad idea. It never ends well when one person wants to be with someone and the other doesn't. Friendships should only be about friendship. If I was in that situation then maybe I would try to set them up with someone else and see if that works, but if it didn't and they were still in love with me then I couldn't keep hanging out with them. It would be uncomfortable and in the long run its only hurting the person who's obsessing over you. I just think friendships with people who are in love with you are a bad idea. It never ends well when one person wants to be with someone and the other doesn't. Friendships should only be about friendship. If I was in that situation then maybe I would try to set them up with someone else and see if that works, but if it didn't and they were still in love with me then I couldn't keep hanging out with them. It would be uncomfortable and in the long run its only hurting the person who's obsessing over you.           It sounds like you have reservations about this other than his attractiveness, so I don't even think that needs to come into it.  It's entirely about not being physically attracted to him, and there's absolutely nothing wrong with that. Regardless of what anyone claims looks matter to most everyone.     [deleted] But then he loses a friend, too. If I refused to be friends with anyone who had ever shown interest in me (or if anyone refused to be friends with me because I had shown interest in them), I would have very few friends. As long as both parties communicate honestly, I don't see why they can't still hang out. The "friendzone" is a self-built cage. But then he loses a friend, too. If I refused to be friends with anyone who had ever shown interest in me (or if anyone refused to be friends with me because I had shown interest in them), I would have very few friends. As long as both parties communicate honestly, I don't see why they can't still hang out. The "friendzone" is a self-built cage.</snippet></document><document><title>A Dress-Code Enforcer's Struggle for the Soul of the Middle-School Girl - Jessica Lahey - The Atlantic</title><url>http://www.theatlantic.com/sexes/archive/2013/02/a-dress-code-enforcers-struggle-for-the-soul-of-the-middle-school-girl/273155/?google_editors_picks=true</url><snippet>  I'm torn about this article - I agree that women, especially the ones stepping over between girlhood and adulthood, need to be reminded that they are more than their body, or beauty, or "decorative" nature. They should be urged to be a good person, have respect for their minds *and* bodies, and be encouraged to pursue their artistic and intellectual interests.


But...so should everyone. Not just girls. Not just boys. Everyone.


And I'm afraid that by continually harping on girls on this manner (maybe harping isn't the correct term) we enter back into that iffy territory that suggests men and boys can't do anything if distracted by a bare shoulder or cleavage and therefore, it is the woman's responsibility to make herself "not distracting." 


This article hits a touchy spot for me because I developed early. I was the girl who was *continually* sent to the principal's office for my clothes...and when I was found to be well within dress code, I would still get a myriad of suggestions of how to downplay my body like, "Well, maybe sit with your book bag in your lap?" when my skirt was just above my knees. 

=/</snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] He choo-choo-chooses me.</title><url>http://imgur.com/juJe1gR</url><snippet>   Jinx! I painted this for my boyfriend - http://i.imgur.com/T08Jtcy.jpg</snippet></document><document><title>Diva cups in Canada</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18mrif/diva_cups_in_canada/</url><snippet>Hey Ladies! I was just wondering if anyone knew of a store that sells diva cups in Canada (specifically BC). I've looked in Saveon, london drugs, Walmart, and Thrifty's and found nothing! Is there any hope?  Wait, I just found a store locater on their website: http://divacup.com/where-to-buy/store-finder/    </snippet></document><document><title>Don't know which path to take.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18mbuk/dont_know_which_path_to_take/</url><snippet>I have an amazing boyfriend and a really good job with consistent hours. Just saying that makes me wonder how I can complain. I don't have a lot of stress in my life but sometimes I just break down wondering if I'm going in the right direction. We are planning on getting married but we are both 20 and would like to wait longer to be more financially stable. I am not in school now and I feel like such a slacker because of it, but I had a really hard time my first year and pretty much gave up. I always got amazing grades in high school, but now have no real passion for anything school related. I wouldn't even know what classes to take besides general ed. Any advice for me?   There's nothing wrong with wanting to see what else is out there for you!

General ed is actually really amazing in that it requires you to take a variety of subjects. I never would have fallen into my major and passion if I hadn't taken one class that made me think, "Huh. That's kinda like comic books. I like comic books. Let's do this."

I also found I really enjoy anthropology, languages, literature analysis, creative writing, and a bunch of other things. (I also learned I hate geology and programming.) If you can afford it, I'd go ahead and take some general ed classes, with the express intention of broadening your horizons.   At 20, it makes perfect sense that you might not be feeling a huge passion for school, given that you haven't had much actual living time, so far, when you were not IN school.  

Maybe some people think at your age you need to get all grownup and make a bunch of serious decisions about where your life is going, but I am not one of them.  

Actually, your brain is still adolescent until you're in your mid to late 20s.  And it sounds like you're being very sensible with your life, not being wild and crazy. I think this is the perfect time to just settle into being you, learn who you are, experiment around a little, maybe try doing some things you've never done (like if you've never done art, do some art, for example). 

I would say take different interesting courses, but you say you're not feeling real motivated about school, and I can certainly understand that. You can actually learn more about stuff just by getting out there in the real non-school world and getting your hands into it anyway.

I say, if you feel like it, this is a great time for exploring and learning more about who you are and who you're growing into being.</snippet></document><document><title>[IFF] This teddy bear is a bigger deal then he realizes. (Story inside)</title><url>http://imgur.com/YlljtAv</url><snippet>  My grandfather passed away one year ago, on Valentine's Day. My SO was pretty much a pro about handling the day. Leaving work early to find me curled up on the couch, driving me 2 hours to my parents house. I was 20 minutes late to say goodby and he knew I was blaming myself internally for being late. He stayed with my family that day and was a comfort to everyone. (He's pretty good at making my mom laugh). This year I told him, no, I don't want to do anything, he did enough last year to last for years to come.

I'm going to name him Charles, after my grandfather, and he's my new cuddle buddy :) A few alterations and this could have been my post - my grandma died on Valentine's day three years ago. My husband and I were away from home/my family at the winter Olympics but my mom told us to stay to see the event we had tickets for even though I just wanted to catch the next flight home. My husband was my home away from home and everything turned out okay. 

I'm glad you had something to smile about yesterday :-)  My grandfather passed away one year ago, on Valentine's Day. My SO was pretty much a pro about handling the day. Leaving work early to find me curled up on the couch, driving me 2 hours to my parents house. I was 20 minutes late to say goodby and he knew I was blaming myself internally for being late. He stayed with my family that day and was a comfort to everyone. (He's pretty good at making my mom laugh). This year I told him, no, I don't want to do anything, he did enough last year to last for years to come.

I'm going to name him Charles, after my grandfather, and he's my new cuddle buddy :) I'm so sorry to hear this.  My dad died on valentines day in 2005, and I am still not over it.  I am glad your SO was able to make the day nice for you.</snippet></document><document><title>looking for some new hobbies!  What are some examples of some of the hobbies that you do? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18lxr6/looking_for_some_new_hobbies_what_are_some/</url><snippet>          </snippet></document><document><title>Got in trouble at work... For the size of my boobs.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18jhlm/got_in_trouble_at_work_for_the_size_of_my_boobs/</url><snippet>I work at an IT department. When I started, there was no dress code. I never wore revealing clothes, but I did wear some that were lower cut than others (Which I haven't worn after 2 months of working since I caught some coworkers looking down my shirt.) I am a 38 DDD and it's hard to find clothes that fit me. I never show cleavage, and when I do, it is on accedent. When I notice my shirt has been pulled down a little bit, I just tug it back up into place. 


There is another woman who works where I work. She was just promoted. She deserved it, and she is a sweetheart. Today she asked me to come into her office. She had me sit down, and said, "So I was asked to talk to you by the boss about your clothes. He has had a coworker comment on your breasts and he (the boss) thinks it is inappropriate and wanted me to tell you that you need to wear more covering, loose shirts." 



I wasn't upset at her. 


I was upset at the fact that because someone said something about my boobs, I can't wear any of my clothes I have now. And now I have to pay money to get the "official" work shirts (that no one ever buys because it's $30 a shirt.) Or I can wear pull over hoodies, which can get hot very fast when you are lifting computers and running around the office. 

I wear flattering shirts that make me feel better. I don't wear anything too small or anything. I know it is in a business environment, but I am not showing anything. I am appropriate at all times. It was never my intention to have people stare at my boobs. 



I agreed with her and told her I will dress better. 




EDIT: For refrence on my lowest cut shirt I wear for work, [this is it.](http://imgur.com/2N9BT0y)



2nd Edit: I wouldn't have cared if my male boss talked to me. I would have thought the same things as if my coworker said what she did about it. But yeah, it would be a little more awkward.



THIRD EDIT: Someone PMed me and sent me [this picture](http://i.imgur.com/4FBBi.jpg) which made me feel a little better. 





FINAL EDIT: I ended up wearing [this shirt](http://imgur.com/H6UdKc3) to work just to see what they say. I got called into her office and said these are the kind of shirts she was talking about. She said, "your boobs would work very well for tips, but not in this business."



I talked to my dad and he is getting a hold of his attorney and they are going to contact the presedent of the school I work at. 



Thank all of you for your comments and knowing I am not alone. I would have just left it alone and would wear anything they wanted me to, but I know now to fight issues like this. I feel violated at work now.   Wait wait wait, your lowest cut shirt that you wear to work is a tee? Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. You need to have a talk with your boss. Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. That doesn't make any sense, though. How would a tee be a shirt that you'd have to "tug back up into place" so your cleavage doesn't show? I'm not trying to tell you that you're in the wrong, but there is just no way I can believe that, unless this guy is legitimately just talking about your breasts and not your shirts. I just... don't understand. I've worn tees much like the one the OP posted. When you bend over, the view is very different than when you're standing up straight. If she's in a job where she has to move around a lot (in IT, I imagine there's a lot of bending over computers to plug shit in, reinstall hardware, etc.) then the view she has in the mirror is different than the one people get when she's involved in work. It's rather startling to realize how much can be seen from that dip in the fabric when you thought you were dressed conservatively.

Of course, someone has to be *looking* for it, but I won't make assumptions about her coworkers.

In addition, she said "running around the office", so there'd be jiggling no matter what. I'm pretty sure I jiggle even in a hoodie, if I'm jogging from one place to the next.

And just for some perspective: I'm nowhere near the OP's breast size, and I've noticed this issue. I'm a 34B and I jiggle. I'm a guy and I jiggle. 

We're all meatbags. Jiggling's what we do.  I'm a guy and I jiggle. 

We're all meatbags. Jiggling's what we do.  I've worn tees much like the one the OP posted. When you bend over, the view is very different than when you're standing up straight. If she's in a job where she has to move around a lot (in IT, I imagine there's a lot of bending over computers to plug shit in, reinstall hardware, etc.) then the view she has in the mirror is different than the one people get when she's involved in work. It's rather startling to realize how much can be seen from that dip in the fabric when you thought you were dressed conservatively.

Of course, someone has to be *looking* for it, but I won't make assumptions about her coworkers.

In addition, she said "running around the office", so there'd be jiggling no matter what. I'm pretty sure I jiggle even in a hoodie, if I'm jogging from one place to the next.

And just for some perspective: I'm nowhere near the OP's breast size, and I've noticed this issue. I can tell you from experience there is no way a t-shirt like that will show any cleavage even when you bend forward. It is just not loose or low necked enough.  I can tell you from experience there is no way a t-shirt like that will show any cleavage even when you bend forward. It is just not loose or low necked enough.  That doesn't make any sense, though. How would a tee be a shirt that you'd have to "tug back up into place" so your cleavage doesn't show? I'm not trying to tell you that you're in the wrong, but there is just no way I can believe that, unless this guy is legitimately just talking about your breasts and not your shirts. I just... don't understand. I go to all my classes down the hall, and I wear all my cute stuff to class which involves lower cut shirts. I go to work immediately after school and I always have an extra shirt in my bag or a hoodie. ... Is it possible that those are the shirts that your boss saw instead of the tshirt?  I take 3 classes a day in one room, but I do t think I've seen my boss while I'm at school.  I go to all my classes down the hall, and I wear all my cute stuff to class which involves lower cut shirts. I go to work immediately after school and I always have an extra shirt in my bag or a hoodie. That doesn't make any sense, though. How would a tee be a shirt that you'd have to "tug back up into place" so your cleavage doesn't show? I'm not trying to tell you that you're in the wrong, but there is just no way I can believe that, unless this guy is legitimately just talking about your breasts and not your shirts. I just... don't understand. Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. I just have to say that this is the most ridiculous bullshit ever and I'm so tired of these things happening. That is a normal t-shirt. This isn't your problem, it's the problem of the little twit who is staring at your boobs and talking about them to other people instead of doing his job. One of my ex-bosses once told me 'the way you look is distracting.' Just the way I looked in general he couldn't even tell me specifically what the issue was. Eventually I quit, but I was furious because it wasn't my fault and there was nothing I could do about it. Please don't let this situation bring down your self confidence because it really is not your fault AT ALL.  Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. Yup. I normally wear regular tee's to work. From the shoulders/armpit region of the picture you posted, it looks like the shirt might be super tight (it's hard to tell of course since that's about all I can see). 

Is it possible the issue is wearing too *tight* of clothing, rather than too low-cut? Tight clothes in a professional situation are a no-go.

I also have large boobs, and those babydoll tees (which it looks like you're wearing) nearly always fit very tight across the chest. You probably have to wear a bigger size than you think you do.

Believe it or not, V necks can actually make big boobs look *smaller* and thus less provocative, even though it's technically showing more skin. Wrap tops like [this](http://www.thelimited.com/Knit-Wrap-Top/3232039,default,pd.html?dwvar_3232039_colorCode=646&amp;amp;start=42&amp;amp;ppid=c42&amp;amp;cgid=womens-tops) are pretty universally considered professional, especially if you wear a cami underneath like the model does, and are very flattering for people shaped like you and me. From the shoulders/armpit region of the picture you posted, it looks like the shirt might be super tight (it's hard to tell of course since that's about all I can see). 

Is it possible the issue is wearing too *tight* of clothing, rather than too low-cut? Tight clothes in a professional situation are a no-go.

I also have large boobs, and those babydoll tees (which it looks like you're wearing) nearly always fit very tight across the chest. You probably have to wear a bigger size than you think you do.

Believe it or not, V necks can actually make big boobs look *smaller* and thus less provocative, even though it's technically showing more skin. Wrap tops like [this](http://www.thelimited.com/Knit-Wrap-Top/3232039,default,pd.html?dwvar_3232039_colorCode=646&amp;amp;start=42&amp;amp;ppid=c42&amp;amp;cgid=womens-tops) are pretty universally considered professional, especially if you wear a cami underneath like the model does, and are very flattering for people shaped like you and me.  So, wait, a coworker makes an unsolicited comment about your body to your boss, and your boss's solution is to have someone else berate *you*? Christ. The idea that women's bodies are distracting/unprofessional is heinous. It would be one thing if you were wearing clothes that were clearly ill-fitting or more appropriate for a nightclub, but it really seems like you're being criticized for being in possession of a body part that is excessively sexualized. 

I definitely think you should ask for clarification from your boss. If this dictum is coming from him, he should be able to explain his reasoning. 
 So, wait, a coworker makes an unsolicited comment about your body to your boss, and your boss's solution is to have someone else berate *you*? Christ. The idea that women's bodies are distracting/unprofessional is heinous. It would be one thing if you were wearing clothes that were clearly ill-fitting or more appropriate for a nightclub, but it really seems like you're being criticized for being in possession of a body part that is excessively sexualized. 

I definitely think you should ask for clarification from your boss. If this dictum is coming from him, he should be able to explain his reasoning. 
  I suggest crossposting this to /r/bigboobproblems.  Your situation is more common than you'd think, and a lot of the ladies who post there have been in similar positions. All the time. I have been told to wear extra large shirts to hide my boobs because they are too distracting for male employees. It's bull shit and it sucks. Even in school. Even at church when I went. Big breasted girls can't win. They're there. They're big. And yet the person who has them gets reduced to a pair of walking sex toys and made feel ashamed and slutty for not being born differently. Fml. You should let them know that you find the bulging genitalia of your male coworkers distracting and they should all wear kilts. With underwear. You should let them know that you find the bulging genitalia of your male coworkers distracting and they should all wear kilts. With underwear. I suggest crossposting this to /r/bigboobproblems.  Your situation is more common than you'd think, and a lot of the ladies who post there have been in similar positions.  This sounds potentially illegal . . . particularly if he's only applying this to you and not any of your colleagues and when you're not breaking any dress codes.

If you can, maybe seek out some cheap or free consultations with an attorney in your state (universities with affiliated law schools often have them). This sounds potentially illegal . . . particularly if he's only applying this to you and not any of your colleagues and when you're not breaking any dress codes.

If you can, maybe seek out some cheap or free consultations with an attorney in your state (universities with affiliated law schools often have them). This sounds potentially illegal . . . particularly if he's only applying this to you and not any of your colleagues and when you're not breaking any dress codes.

If you can, maybe seek out some cheap or free consultations with an attorney in your state (universities with affiliated law schools often have them).  You didn't mention it, but did anyone think to talk to the guy commenting on your breasts? I don't know who it was. There's about 16 people here throughout the week. I was thinking more along the lines of your *boss* having a talk with that guy, instead of having a talk with you. I don't know who it was. There's about 16 people here throughout the week. OP, just letting to know I really feel for you and I completely support your decision to speak to a legal rep and see HR! 

I also think [you might get a laugh out of this](http://i.imgur.com/g6zgSfj.png)- god knows you deserve one after all this

The ladies (and gents!) of 2x are behind you - Good luck and keep us updated! You didn't mention it, but did anyone think to talk to the guy commenting on your breasts? You didn't mention it, but did anyone think to talk to the guy commenting on your breasts?   Do you have an employee handbook?  If so, read it.  Become familiar with the code of conduct with your office before seeking legal advice.  Even if you choose to seek legal advice, I would suggest you talk to HR about this situation.  Get it in writing that you're not happy.  Maybe even try to arrange a meeting between yourself, your boss and an HR rep to discuss it calmly and supervised by a 3rd party.

If you don't have an HR department, ask for a meeting between yourself, your boss and the lady who spoke to you.  If you have concerns about what is happening, you have the right to voice your concerns.

To me (a former HR worker), it seems unreasonable for them to make this request.   However, workplaces differ from one to another.  

And I hate to be this person, but *accident, not axedent. There is no employee hand book. And that's a good idea to go to HR and see that they have to say.


And thank you for correcting me :p I typed up everything in a huff and that word didn't look right to me after I posted Be careful with HR. They are department put in place to protect the company. Your best interests are not their ultimate goal, and they are sometimes willing to throw employees under the bus if they think it will save their company a buck. Be careful with HR. They are department put in place to protect the company. Your best interests are not their ultimate goal, and they are sometimes willing to throw employees under the bus if they think it will save their company a buck. yeah, but this is a dispute easily resolved by them saying "hey, there's not really anything we can do about you wearing fitted shirts. we can't exactly make you wear loose t shirts to work, sorry not an appropriate request, her clothes are fine" Hopefully they're reasonable and it will go that route, though I have heard horror stories of retaliatory firing or punishment for employees making any type of complaint about discrimination. I'm sure those are much rarer than HR just saying, "Whoops, our bad!" Be careful with HR. They are department put in place to protect the company. Your best interests are not their ultimate goal, and they are sometimes willing to throw employees under the bus if they think it will save their company a buck. Be careful with HR. They are department put in place to protect the company. Your best interests are not their ultimate goal, and they are sometimes willing to throw employees under the bus if they think it will save their company a buck. There is no employee hand book. And that's a good idea to go to HR and see that they have to say.


And thank you for correcting me :p I typed up everything in a huff and that word didn't look right to me after I posted There is no employee hand book. And that's a good idea to go to HR and see that they have to say.


And thank you for correcting me :p I typed up everything in a huff and that word didn't look right to me after I posted Yeah, it's best to get things in writing.  Above all else, maintain professionalism.  Keep things by the book.  Keep a paper trail wherever you can.  I know you're probably really upset right now, so schedule your appointment with HR for tomorrow so you can have time to digest what happened and think of what you want to say and what you want to achieve from the meeting. Also, it would be a good idea to get a voice memo of the meeting if you have an iphone or a smartphone that can record it. Maintain your professionalism above all else! There is no employee hand book. And that's a good idea to go to HR and see that they have to say.


And thank you for correcting me :p I typed up everything in a huff and that word didn't look right to me after I posted There is no employee hand book. And that's a good idea to go to HR and see that they have to say.


And thank you for correcting me :p I typed up everything in a huff and that word didn't look right to me after I posted  My first childish knee jerk response would be to come to work in a burqa. Not sure what I would actually do,  but I'd be pissed off.  My first childish knee jerk response would be to come to work in a burqa. Not sure what I would actually do,  but I'd be pissed off.  Then do no work because your clothes are not conducive to a wide range of motion (or so I'd expect, can't say I've ever worn a burqa).  At first I was going to relay a story of three girls I know who have come to me after receiving similAr complaints at work.  And I was going to tell you that all three of these women frequently spotted a fist full of cleavage in a professional work environment.  And I was going to advise you to consult a close girlfriend before taking your next steps because sometimes we just don't realize. 

Then I saw your picture.  If you are being honest, and your shirt doesn't have some secret cleavage slit we can't see, then that is discrimination. Make sure you are within the appropriate company dress code policy and call your boss and this woman in to a meeting to discuss this.  You sound pretty comfortable with confrontation so I suggest you skip hr and go that route.   I disagree.  The boss is clearly too uncomfortable with the situation to discuss it himself (he sent a junior associate to do his dirty work for him) and the woman is new in her position and unlikely to rock the boat.  Go to HR, this is their wheelhouse and they can help fix this immediately. At first I was going to relay a story of three girls I know who have come to me after receiving similAr complaints at work.  And I was going to tell you that all three of these women frequently spotted a fist full of cleavage in a professional work environment.  And I was going to advise you to consult a close girlfriend before taking your next steps because sometimes we just don't realize. 

Then I saw your picture.  If you are being honest, and your shirt doesn't have some secret cleavage slit we can't see, then that is discrimination. Make sure you are within the appropriate company dress code policy and call your boss and this woman in to a meeting to discuss this.  You sound pretty comfortable with confrontation so I suggest you skip hr and go that route.   &amp;gt;Then I saw your picture.

The OP said "When I notice my shirt has been pulled down a little bit, I just tug it back up into place."  She also said she wears flattering shirts.  There's no way in hell she's being honest in the picture. &amp;gt;Then I saw your picture.

The OP said "When I notice my shirt has been pulled down a little bit, I just tug it back up into place."  She also said she wears flattering shirts.  There's no way in hell she's being honest in the picture. A t-shirt can't be flattering? That's not really the point he's making. For what reason would a t-shirt need to be tugged back UP into place? I can understand down, but up?  Given what I can assume about your body shape from the picture you provided, I highly doubt you need a 38" band. 

You should come over to /r/abrathatfits. Wearing improperly fitting bras can cause a lot of back problems for girls with larger breasts. Not sure who downvoted you.  You are correct.  A woman whose rib cage is actually 38" around would be plus sized, which OP does not seem to be.  

I guess somebody thought it was unrelated to the post, but that doesn't mean you're wrong.  Resizing herself would help OP's clothes to fit better and help her look more proportional, as well as making her * immensely* more comfortable.  I consider 4 downvotes a relatively small penalty for spreading the bravelution. Not sure who downvoted you.  You are correct.  A woman whose rib cage is actually 38" around would be plus sized, which OP does not seem to be.  

I guess somebody thought it was unrelated to the post, but that doesn't mean you're wrong.  Resizing herself would help OP's clothes to fit better and help her look more proportional, as well as making her * immensely* more comfortable.  Not sure who downvoted you.  You are correct.  A woman whose rib cage is actually 38" around would be plus sized, which OP does not seem to be.  

I guess somebody thought it was unrelated to the post, but that doesn't mean you're wrong.  Resizing herself would help OP's clothes to fit better and help her look more proportional, as well as making her * immensely* more comfortable.  I wear a 38B and am not a plus size.  OP doesn't look much smaller than I do (And yes, I have been sized multiple times).  You can't really assume she needs a smaller band.  You don't have to subscribe to the subreddit, but please consider [sizing yourself](http://www.reddit.com/r/ABraThatFits/comments/rh26h/is_getting_fitted_for_a_bra_as_humiliating_as_it/c469bi0), just once. You might be surprised at the results! Just because a 38B fits doesn't mean it's the right size for you. I did, and I'm still a 38B.  SHOCK, a girl who knows how to find bras that fit all on her own without guidance! I wear a 38B and am not a plus size.  OP doesn't look much smaller than I do (And yes, I have been sized multiple times).  You can't really assume she needs a smaller band.  I wear a 38B and am not a plus size.  OP doesn't look much smaller than I do (And yes, I have been sized multiple times).  You can't really assume she needs a smaller band.  Given what I can assume about your body shape from the picture you provided, I highly doubt you need a 38" band. 

You should come over to /r/abrathatfits. Wearing improperly fitting bras can cause a lot of back problems for girls with larger breasts. Given what I can assume about your body shape from the picture you provided, I highly doubt you need a 38" band. 

You should come over to /r/abrathatfits. Wearing improperly fitting bras can cause a lot of back problems for girls with larger breasts. Given what I can assume about your body shape from the picture you provided, I highly doubt you need a 38" band. 

You should come over to /r/abrathatfits. Wearing improperly fitting bras can cause a lot of back problems for girls with larger breasts. Agreed! OP you are so slender and cute :) Don't make yourself sound bigger than you are by telling people you are a 38 if you are really less.  /r/abrathatfits will change your life (in a super good way) And people with a 38 band aren't cute, huh?    It sucks that you're having to put up with kind of crap: I would definitely talk to HR about being called out for your body type, and follow up with the boss.  If the complaint was not specific to a particular occasion and there is no formal dress code, it is (even more) ridiculous and unreasonable to expect you to know based off one generic comment what your coworker or boss would consider appropriate.

On a side note, you look pretty small to be a 38 band.  If you are not familiar with /r/ABraThatFits, take a look around and check out the fitting guide on the sidebar.  I used to wear a 36DD (because that's the only thing that I could even pretend fit me), but now am in love with my 32FF girls.  You can even get advice on how to find well-fitting bras to fit a students budget! At the very least, your boobs will be more comfortable in your new bra! 30E to 26GG here. It sucks that you're having to put up with kind of crap: I would definitely talk to HR about being called out for your body type, and follow up with the boss.  If the complaint was not specific to a particular occasion and there is no formal dress code, it is (even more) ridiculous and unreasonable to expect you to know based off one generic comment what your coworker or boss would consider appropriate.

On a side note, you look pretty small to be a 38 band.  If you are not familiar with /r/ABraThatFits, take a look around and check out the fitting guide on the sidebar.  I used to wear a 36DD (because that's the only thing that I could even pretend fit me), but now am in love with my 32FF girls.  You can even get advice on how to find well-fitting bras to fit a students budget! It sucks that you're having to put up with kind of crap: I would definitely talk to HR about being called out for your body type, and follow up with the boss.  If the complaint was not specific to a particular occasion and there is no formal dress code, it is (even more) ridiculous and unreasonable to expect you to know based off one generic comment what your coworker or boss would consider appropriate.

On a side note, you look pretty small to be a 38 band.  If you are not familiar with /r/ABraThatFits, take a look around and check out the fitting guide on the sidebar.  I used to wear a 36DD (because that's the only thing that I could even pretend fit me), but now am in love with my 32FF girls.  You can even get advice on how to find well-fitting bras to fit a students budget! It sucks that you're having to put up with kind of crap: I would definitely talk to HR about being called out for your body type, and follow up with the boss.  If the complaint was not specific to a particular occasion and there is no formal dress code, it is (even more) ridiculous and unreasonable to expect you to know based off one generic comment what your coworker or boss would consider appropriate.

On a side note, you look pretty small to be a 38 band.  If you are not familiar with /r/ABraThatFits, take a look around and check out the fitting guide on the sidebar.  I used to wear a 36DD (because that's the only thing that I could even pretend fit me), but now am in love with my 32FF girls.  You can even get advice on how to find well-fitting bras to fit a students budget!      Report her (or your boss) for sexual harassment. Seriously. You're wearing a fucking crew neck, they can suck tennis balls. 

Either that or step up your troll game and wear more revealing shirts or go into your bosses office crying about not being able to afford a reduction. Well, if you are playing troll I would go the other way. If she comes in wearing revealing clothes she might get in trouble, after all she has already been told off for it.  

They want her to cover up more, so I would come to work in a burqa. :D 

 Report her (or your boss) for sexual harassment. Seriously. You're wearing a fucking crew neck, they can suck tennis balls. 

Either that or step up your troll game and wear more revealing shirts or go into your bosses office crying about not being able to afford a reduction. While I'll probably be downvoted for this, please don't report *her* for sexual harassment. I feel this is much more an issue with the original employee who made the comment. While my time working in an office is limited, I would assume both the female employee and boss were just acting within protocol for their company. I would say this is especially true for your recently-promoted friend who may not want to lose her new position at work (especially when working with such charming gentlemen around/above her).**    Yeah... My MALE boss dropped a highlighted copy of the dress code on my desk. The highlighted section was about ill-fitting clothing (specifically wearing pants that are "too tight"). I was wearing black khaki style pants that are a size too big (recently lost some weight - I am a Canadian size 2). Apparently someone "raised an issue regarding my wardrobe" and this was the solution. Frustrating! Wear a potato sack. Well-fitted clothes are for sluts.       You definitely need to go over this ladies he's and talk straight to your boss. Unless you start wearing turtle neck sweaters there's no way that shirt should be considered inappropriate. I think the co-worker who said something about you chest is at fault because you'd have to be straining really hard to look down that shirt.       If your boss has a problem, HE should be the one to come and talk to you. I don't see why you should be punished for being well endowed when you don't flaunt it in the work environment. It sounds incredibly rude for them to draw attention to you like that just because of your boobs.  If your boss has a problem, HE should be the one to come and talk to you. I don't see why you should be punished for being well endowed when you don't flaunt it in the work environment. It sounds incredibly rude for them to draw attention to you like that just because of your boobs.    This is totally unrelated to your boob situation, I have nothing more to add to that.  But you're super cute.         It's not like the guy was complaining about what you wear. You can't see anything with that shirt. You obviously can't see cleavage, but I imagine that from the side, it is quite obvious you have boobs, which one should expect from a woman so I don't know why this is a problem. It's not like you can make them look smaller.     Oh god I had a situation like this, same thing - big boobs, involuntary cleavage...the holier-than-thou bitch in the office across the hall complained and by the end of the day, everyone in the office was giving me looks and whispering behind my back.  The holier-than-thou bitch from accounting made up some pathetically transparent excuse to come back to my room (to check out my cleavage).  I have never been so angry and embarrassed! And these were ALL women. It was awful.  Thank jeebus I don't live in the midwest anymore!  I'm sorry you're having this problem, and it sounds like total bullshit, but I can't get past "axedent."                                                </snippet></document><document><title>A Tiny Village Where Women Chose to Be Single Mothers.</title><url>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/15/world/asia/in-vietnam-some-chose-to-be-single-mothers.html?hp&amp;amp;pagewanted=all</url><snippet /></document><document><title>[IFF] Just some Valentine's day post cards I sent to a few of my friends</title><url>http://imgur.com/urujOZ6</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>A Billion Rising: A Movement of Spirit</title><url>http://www.tikkun.org/tikkundaily/2013/02/14/a-billion-rising-a-movement-of-spirit/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>[IFF] All single, we had a 'Gal'entine's Day complete with picnic and Degrassi marathon!</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/CuGa3</url><snippet>  Uteruses before duderuses! Absolutely! And we wore our onesies and drank booze! Old Degrassi! Have another upvote!

Love, your pal Canada  I didn't read the full title and when I got to the end of the pictures I thought this was some sort of new "Surprise Spike" thing. I would be on board for that.

You look like you are definitely some place warm... How do you come by Degrassi!? I thought it was pure Canada, are you Canada? Spike rolling could be the new Rick rolling!

We're in Melbourne - but Degrassi was huge here as well. It was on everyday after school up until the late 90's. I learnt everything I know about teen pregnancy/drug addiction/domestic violence/HIV/abortion from Spike, Joey Jeremiah et al. I didn't read the full title and when I got to the end of the pictures I thought this was some sort of new "Surprise Spike" thing. I would be on board for that.

You look like you are definitely some place warm... How do you come by Degrassi!? I thought it was pure Canada, are you Canada? </snippet></document><document><title>Rant: Audrey Kitching (of Myspace fame) says rape victims may have done something in a previous life to attract rape, then blames the backlash she receives on "internet bullying".</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18l5mq/rant_audrey_kitching_of_myspace_fame_says_rape/</url><snippet>Audrey Kitching, self-proclaimed designer (who you probably wont  remember from 2006 as being Myspace famous for having pink hair), thinks that people who get raped have "maybe done something of the sort to another person in a previous life". 

She responded to a [formspring](http://www.formspring.me/audreykitching) question asking her about her stance on rape. After offending a bunch of people, she posted [this](http://audrey.buzznet.com/user/journal/17310601/gossip-people-already-made-up/) blog post which says she is a victim to internet bullying and gossip regarding the reaction she experienced after answering the question.


She has since deleted the question, but everything she wrote about the incident, including the original formspring response, can be found [here](http://audreykitchingisinsane.tumblr.com/).


Her fans are asking her to apologize, but she claims her words were misinterpreted. Is there really any other way to interpret what she said, though? She even says in her response on her blog that she believes that we "attract situations and circumstances due to past life experiences and lessons to be learned as well as our current vibrational factors". I don't understand how she can state that she isn't saying that rape victims are raped because of their own actions.


Why does this person have fans?!     Honestly, I don't think she intended her answer to have that actual meaning. It seemed like she was following some super shitty formula for how to adress subjects in a new age/crystal/5dwhatevershit-type way, and it ended up sounding really fucking bad. 

I am in no way a fan of Fraudrey; I'm a member of a livejournal group that snarks her (Are you too?) so I know way too much about her bullshit, and I'm not defending her at all. I just think she is so unintelligent that she doesn't even realize how insane and horrible she sounds, and uses up all her mind-power trying to project some deluded image of herself. I think what she said is disgusting, but I don't think she has any idea why we could think that. I don't think the girl has a clue. I'm not part of a livejournal group, but can I join?! I just discovered that she still has a following on the internet and couldn't believe it.    To play devil's advocate, this is something many Buddhists popularly (whether accurately or not) and honestly believe, particularly those who believe in karma and reincarnation. And there are two explanations.

1) They want to believe in a just world. Every good deed is rewarded eventually, every bad deed is punished eventually.


2) Or, if you want to be charitable, it's another way of saying, "so-and-so in "your" (although the concept of 'soul' is different in Eastern cultures) previous life caused cosmic forces to occur in such a way that it was the cause (not well-deserved reason) of rape."

Which is slightly different from saying that s/he deserved being raped.

Does that make sense? It does make sense to me. But it's always a tricky thing to talk about reincarnation in this way and always seems to come out overlapping with victim blaming. I find it's better to save those conversations for one-on-one with friends, where you can tease out the distinctions and make your meaning clear.</snippet></document><document><title>Hating other women is toxic</title><url>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/hating-other-women-is-toxic/</url><snippet>  There's a big difference between not liking a woman that's actively hitting on your boyfriend and hating women in general. I think the author shouldn't beat herself up - but I do agree we need to try and be friendlier and more welcoming to other women in general.  This is an article about how the author realized that even if a woman was actively hitting on her boyfriend, she still shouldn't be so quick to hate because under all the competitive bullshit, we're all still painfully, vulnerably human and sisters. 

And honestly, once you understand that, it's really hard to hate on another woman even if she's trying to rub her crotch all over your boyfriend. Although, I think in the context of the article, the boyfriend cozying was more of a perception the author had rather than a true attempt to horn in on her man.   </snippet></document><document><title>Back in the workforce after a 5 year hiatus. </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18lak8/back_in_the_workforce_after_a_5_year_hiatus/</url><snippet>I have always wanted to be able to stay at home during my child's formative years. She turns 5 in a couple weeks and I am so glad we were able to live on a single income. Now its my time to return to work. I decided on a part time job so I could still be there for my family but also make a little extra scratch. My best friend also was interested in a part time job. We were lamenting on how great it would be if we could share a part time job, and then that job actually found us. An acquaintance thought we would be perfect for this one job and let us know. We could make our own schedule and split the hours however we wanted. We could watch each others child if our husband was working. It was perfect. Plus we could support each other in returning to work, because after 5 years its a scary thing to do. 

So we were supposed to start in 2 weeks. We were both excited to start, talking about how awesome this would be, and the yesterday my friend drops this bomb on me that after talking with her husband she decided to back out. Now she already talked to the employer and accepted the job, so this wasnt like she said she would maybe do it. She committed and then she backed out, because her husband said no. Her portion would have been 12 measly hours a week. She was so excited and positive about working. I cant believe that she needed permission for that, and I dont even know that I can respect my friend for being like that, and what she did to me. 

I dont think she expected me to say what I said after that. I am normally a quiet person, but I told her flat out how I felt. "I cant believe you quit before you even started. I had a gut feeling that this would happen. I am SUPER pissed at you right now." We were walking together, and she walked away from me.

I lost respect for her. I dont know that our friendship will ever recover. She left me high and dry. I have 2 choices. Work full time, or wait for a different job. I have been having issues because I am a little overqualified for most jobs, and chemistry gigs in this small isolated town are rare, and I dont want to be married to my job either. Many employers look at me like I have 2 heads when I am applying to work at a hotel or liquor store or whatever. This lady didnt require a resume so she has no clue about my education. Anyhow I TOOK THE JOB. I am freaking terrified. I havent been in the workforce for 5 years. I found childcare for my daughter, which I wont need long because she starts kindergarten. I am so excited for all the fun stuff we will do with her because we have a little more disposable income. I am also proud of myself. I may fail, but at least I am trying. I am scared, but I am moving forward. 

tl;dr I may have lost a friend, but I gained employment. This mama is back in the workforce after a 5 year hiatus.   Well, my opinion isn't going to be popular, but: I think what your friend did was shitty (to you, and possibly to the employer), not to mention incredibly short-sighted. It's not exactly easy for many women to get back into the workforce after an extended hiatus, unless they happen to have skills that are incredibly in-demand and have kept up those skills. Another job may not come along for her, in the event that her controlling husband changes his mind...or dumps her, or loses his own job, or becomes seriously disabled, or dies. 

In any case, I think your friend owes you an apology, and I hope you get it eventually. And in the mean time, congrats on your new job, and I hope it goes well! Its not so much about the apology. She doesnt have integrity. She offered to provide childcare today and I had to decline, because I cant even trust her for that. If you dont have trust, you dont have a friend. You have an acquaintance at best. I do plan to be civil, because our children are friends. But in light of this, and this not being the first time she has flaked on me, I just dont think we can be friends. Not like we were, anyway.   Congrats. 

And don't judge your friend too harshly. She's doing what she thinks is best for her and her family as well. Your name is misleading. lol.   &amp;gt; I lost respect for her. I dont know that our friendship will ever recover. She left me high and dry.

And you, her best friend, just slammed her after what was undoubtedly a really difficult experience for her.  I would imagine she's feeling pretty fucked by something over which she currently has no control.

I'm feeling pretty hard for her right now. It's not like she cancelled a lunch date here.  She made a commitment to two different people.  She should have never offered to participate unless she was 100% all in and had discussed all aspects of this with her husband.

There are, of course, exceptions to this rule but in this case it sounds like she really dropped the ball - I mean, how do you make a decision to return to the workforce without discussing it with your partner?   I understand that.  That's not what I'm addressing.

OP is posting solely about her own angst over the situation.  I commented on her friend's situation.  Both situations exist.  Neither one invalidates the other. I am not responsible for the situation she is in. She however is responsible for mine.  You are certainly responsible for part of her situation - you chose to drop her as a best friend.

She is furthermore not solely responsible for the situation you are in; her husband plays a large part in that. People lose friends when they break trust. Oh I dont like him either right now.  Your sense of empathy is truly inspiring. Always been one to keep people at arms length when they hurt me. She will never get a chance to hurt me like that again. She knows that about me, so this should not be a surprise to her.  Yet elsewhere you admit that the reversal was her husband's decision, and, returning to my original comment, she has just been doubly fucked; she has a controlling husband and has just lost her best friend.  It's not clear to me from the information provided that she could have done anything differently to change the outcome. Yet elsewhere you admit that the reversal was her husband's decision, and, returning to my original comment, she has just been doubly fucked; she has a controlling husband and has just lost her best friend.  It's not clear to me from the information provided that she could have done anything differently to change the outcome. It's not like she cancelled a lunch date here.  She made a commitment to two different people.  She should have never offered to participate unless she was 100% all in and had discussed all aspects of this with her husband.

There are, of course, exceptions to this rule but in this case it sounds like she really dropped the ball - I mean, how do you make a decision to return to the workforce without discussing it with your partner?   They did discuss it. It was all good at first, and then he changed his mind.  In that case, what were your expectations of her? Were you already aware that her family and marital stability were her priorities over work? While you might not like it, it sounds like you already knew that she regularly defers to her husband and in light of that, that she was NOT completely in control of the situation.  That is frustrating!
I hope with some time and sober reflection you and your friend (ex-friend?) can discuss this situation and gain a better understanding of each others perspective.

On the other hand, how exciting to be starting a new job. Now you and your daughter will have stories to swap at dinner time. :) I am looking forward to the shifting family dynamic, and my husband thinks it will be good too. We are on the waiting list for adoption, so this will help us trim down our debt faster too. I may not even quit when the baby comes, I may just find another person in the community to split the job with.   Keep on the lookout for another person who could potentially split the work with you--you don't have to give up that option.  Big deal? Most people are on their own when it comes to sorting out their employment. You treated her horribly.   I'm so glad you didn't let her backing out keep *you* from taking the job. I hope it works out! As an aside, is it possible your friend's husband is abusive and/or controlling? To play the devil's advocate, make sure you don't punish her for being in a difficult situation even though she put you in one as well. He isnt abusive. He is a bit older, and she always defers to his judgement, because he is "older and he knows best". Its not that I want to punish her. Its that when I think of hanging out, or talking, or planning anything with her, I just dont want to. Like it would be really fake for me at this point, even if she is sorry. I would have never done that to her. If she was still going to do this, and if tomorrow my husband brought the hammer down and said no, I would still do it, because I made a commitment. I am a woman of my word. Integrity is important.  Well that all makes perfect sense! I can't imagine that I'd want to spend time with or still be friends with someone who'd let me down this majorly either. I've been on the side of letting people down though due to my own issues/disabilities and it always feels terrible. I hope she's at least tried to make amends or apologize? Yes, and we briefly talked today and we were civil. She did text me a very passive apology. I will always be respectful toward her. Our children are friends, I dont see why we cant be civil and make small talk. Will I plan hiking and camping trips with her? Probably not. Will I rely on her or lean on her as I would my other friends or allow her to do the same? Will I pop in for scrabble games? Probably not. Not anytime soon anyways. </snippet></document><document><title>Reclaiming Wife: The Tyranny of the Grand Romantic Gesture. Great post about questioning a destructive cultural narrative.</title><url>http://apracticalwedding.com/2013/02/big-romantic-gestures/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>shout out for how awesome tubby time is!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18m4ic/shout_out_for_how_awesome_tubby_time_is/</url><snippet>after a stressful week and shitty commutes, sometimes a girl just needs some tubby time. warm water, bubbles that smell awesome, maybe some wine and avideo on computer/ipod/phone and just reeeeeelaaaaaaaxing. i feel so much better now.

no shame in grown up bubble baths!!

happy friday, 2x!!!</snippet></document><document><title>I Find Your Lack of Women Disturbing. Or, Leia Is Not Enough.</title><url>http://www.wired.com/underwire/2013/02/opinion-star-wars-females-media/</url><snippet>  </snippet></document></searchresult>