<searchresult><uiuc /><document><title>Fight at firehaus</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17d0wm/fight_at_firehaus/</url><snippet>what happend?     Seemed to me they unleashed pepper spray on the place, me and a couple of friends started coughing on the top floor and had to leave very quickly  Wtf does Firehaus unleash the pepper spray? That happened to me there towards the end of last semester. If so that's really not cool.  I'm not sure if it was Haus itself, the police, or the individuals fighting using it on one another, but it was enough for upstairs and the fight was downstairs... It wasn't Haus and the police were not there yet when it happened so it was the individuals fighting using it on one another. At the time when one of the bartenders said "there was pepper spray used" I assumed they were just making it up to get everyone to leave, but I guess not.  In fact it was the police who sprayed it. Apparently there have been too many cases of the police getting assaulted, so now they just go straight for the pepper spray without giving thought to surroundings or consequences I.e. wide open door to a bar packed with people

Source: haus employee

Now who's got video?
 So do you work at Haus? If so wouldn't whoever owns Firehaus be super pissed at the cops? I'm pretty sure using pepper spray in a bar is illegal, and someone could get injured by the stampede of people leaving the bar which could leave to a big lawsuit.  Indeed I do. And the manager isn't particularly happy... but the spraying occurred outside the bar, though the police did say this is now their standard response to a fight, so who knows if they'd have sprayed inside had they gotten a chance.  Wtf does Firehaus unleash the pepper spray? That happened to me there towards the end of last semester. If so that's really not cool.   I thought it was SUPER illegal to have pepper spray in a bar? It is. It can cause stampedes and people get trampled, it's happened before. </snippet></document><document><title>Looking for good hair salon</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17d3oe/looking_for_good_hair_salon/</url><snippet>My hair is long, curly, and thick. Any idea where I can get a good hair cut?   ippatsu hair salon. everyone there is super nice and at least 3 of the stylists have been specially trained to cut curly hair from deva curl. they know what they are doing (i've been going there for years). if you make an appointment with them you should make sure to tell them you have curly hair so they can set you up with the right person - good luck! I'm trying to think of the name of the stylist I really didn't like. I think it was Lindsey. She gave me an awful cut. I have thick straight/wavy hair, so it's not too difficult to cut, but she really butchered it. And my bangs ended up uneven and a little ragged looking. My appointment was right before her lunch break, and it was hot in the salon. She turned on a fan, and one of the other stylists said, "don't you want that fan off to cut her hair, especially her bangs?" My hairdresser thought it would be fine, but midcut she said, "Oh, maybe I do want that fan off..."

Not words you want to hear during a hair cut. oh... that is odd how long ago was this? only stylists i really know and have cut my hair are rebecca, jake, and doug. they always did an amazing job sucks to hear that she fucked your hair up...     I like Terra at Kane &amp;amp; Co. She used to be at H2O and she can do a lot of different styles. Might be a bit expensive though.   Landon's, ask for Jesssica.  33$ cut, blow and style for women.  21$ for guys.

Edit: almost 4 years with her as my stylist. What are their hours?

Why are they so much more expensive? Shampoo+cut costs ~$17 for women at MasterCuts at the mall.</snippet></document><document><title>Roommate needed for Fall 2013/Spring 2014</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17cpnt/roommate_needed_for_fall_2013spring_2014/</url><snippet>I'm a girl (currently a sophomore) who's looking for a roommate next year, male or female. I'm not the type to throw wild parties in the apartment but I do go out occasionally. I'm hoping for a place in Urbana but I'm flexible. Nothing too far away though, I don't like depending on buses. I'm clean but I won't snap on you for being messy, I tend to sleep in late and stay up until 2ish. I'm looking for my half of the rent to be from $400-$650. If anyone's up for finding an apartment with me send me a message.  </snippet></document><document><title>Headed to the NW Suburbs 1/31</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ckd7/headed_to_the_nw_suburbs_131/</url><snippet>Hey all,

I'm headed to the NW suburbs on 1/31. I would like to leave around 5 pm, but I'm flexible with time. Ideal suburbs: Palatine, Arlington Heights, Mount Prospect, Buffalo Grove, Schaumburg, Hoffman Estates, etc. I would be asking for $15 gas, perhaps less depending on the number of travelers.
</snippet></document><document><title>....and this is why I love Campus Liquors.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/MwmFNbT.jpg</url><snippet>  $2 per condom? This is why I hate campus liquors.  You know they're **FREE** at McKinley right? They're also free in the basement of the Union by the computer lab. They're also free in the basement of the Union by the computer lab. Whaa? Really, where exactly? All I remember is there being a water fountain there. Will definitely check this out   </snippet></document><document><title>Guy Fierrrrri at Maize</title><url>https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=555954884415731&amp;amp;set=pb.281516325192923.-2207520000.1359160079&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater</url><snippet>  he was there with Jimmy John he was there with Jimmy John he was there with Jimmy John     Aaaaaaaaand there goes eating there ever again.  Frankly, I just do take out if I can.   Aaaaaaaaand there goes eating there ever again.  Frankly, I just do take out if I can.   If you don't mind me asking, why? Does Guy Fieri's very presence at a restaurant make the place unappealing? Not at all, it's that the place will most likely become another venue to the hordes of people who travel across the nation to eat everywhere he has been.  I have a friend who has been on DDD and his place is swamped which is awesome.  But maize is already swamped and rightly so. He wasn't shooting DDD there so this won't happen. Aaaaaaaaand there goes eating there ever again.  Frankly, I just do take out if I can.   Oh, whatever. You're reading it wrong.  The restaurant rocks but think of how impossible it will be to get in there now. Oh, no more impossible than it already was. It's worse than Black Dog at mealtimes. It'll be bad for a little while, maybe, if he actually was shooting a show. But it doesn't look like that was what was happening. Black Dog usually has a minimum of a 45 minute wait to get a table at mealtime... You're telling me Maize is that bad? Black Dog usually has a minimum of a 45 minute wait to get a table at mealtime... You're telling me Maize is that bad? Oh, no more impossible than it already was. It's worse than Black Dog at mealtimes. It'll be bad for a little while, maybe, if he actually was shooting a show. But it doesn't look like that was what was happening. Why don't you just do the smart thing and call ahead to have your food ready when you're there?</snippet></document><document /><document><title>I saw a TED uiuc Sign outside the union on wednesday, Anyone know if they are holding a event here?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17a74b/i_saw_a_ted_uiuc_sign_outside_the_union_on/</url><snippet>  http://www.ted.com/tedx/events/6885 :) Awesome! Found the (**EDIT:** old 2011) lineup here: http://tedxuillinois.com/ (**EDIT:** I can't read. Hopefully they will update the site soon.)

Do you think we should try to have one of them on here for an AMA? That would be really cool. That is the lineup for the 2011 one?  they let people hold unofficial ones if they want. I'm guessing someone organized it? yeah i know that, any idea when and where?  </snippet></document><document /><document /><document /><document><title>Job Search</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ar4r/job_search/</url><snippet>Anyone know of any places around campus that are hiring?

  Potbelly As someone who works at potbelly I can confirm we are currently hiring.  As someone who recently applied to potbelly but has not heard back, I must say, pick me! Seriously though, is there anything I can do to increase my chances? Don't call in asking about the status of your application, we will call you. Also, if we do call you and you are calling back...have the common sense to not call during a rush, call when you think it won't be busy.  Alright thanks! Hoping for a call.    The new Einstein Bros. bagels in the union food court There's a new Einstein? Is it open yet?

The one on University did a promotion where the first hundred customers got free bagels. It was kinda awesome.   </snippet></document><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document /><document><title>When Racism is a University Tradition: An Open Letter to the UIUC Community</title><url>http://criticalspontaneity.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/when-racism-is-a-university-tradition/</url><snippet>    </snippet></document><document><title>Is anyone in ANTH 103 (second 8-week) </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/198g7a/is_anyone_in_anth_103_second_8week/</url><snippet>I really need to take this course. If anyone is in it and plans on dropping it, let me know.  </snippet></document><document><title>ECE 206 question, if you're in that could you please help me for a minute?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/198hz4/ece_206_question_if_youre_in_that_could_you/</url><snippet>What is the graph in part A3 supposed to look like? I forgot to plot that. This is Vt and Vc vs T. 

Thanks  [This is what I got.](http://i.imgur.com/BZT9G4X.jpg)</snippet></document></searchresult>