<searchresult><twoxchromosomes /><document><title>[UPDATE] Ladies, can someone help me with my not-feeling-too-good cooch?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18hyed/update_ladies_can_someone_help_me_with_my/</url><snippet>Hello!  Saw the doctor about [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ecfj/ladies_can_someone_help_me_with_my/) problem, and it does indeed seem like I have a raging yeast infection.  So bad there might even be something else too, she couldn't tell because the yeast situation was pretty bad.

The update is for two reasons: I read the advice and decided to stick with ice packs and tepid showers and it did help.  The doc I saw today was glad I did not self-medicate, and I wanted to add that here so others know to go to the doc and don't start spreading creams around if you don't know what you have for sure.

The other questions is: where did this come from?  Could it be from my boyfriend fingering me without washing his hands first? I remember a particularly good session of that two days before I started to feel like something was up.  I've never had a yeast infection before and this feels awful, and I would like to avoid this happening again at any price.  I wasn't taking antibiotics.  For what it's worth I eat about 1 cup of yogurt a day, I love the stuff, but maybe eating it doesn't help.  Any info on future prevention would be appreciated!

I got two of those pills and a tube of nycostatin and things are feeling better already.

Thanks for all your advice and commiseration!  </snippet></document><document><title>I received not very good news from my doctor, and it kind of concerns my ex-bf. Should I talk to him?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gxpr/i_received_not_very_good_news_from_my_doctor_and/</url><snippet>Hello Ladies! 

I've been reading this subreddit for a little while now, but this is my first post in here. So be patient with me, and if this doesn't belong here please let me know.

So, a few weeks ago, I received the results of my tests and it turns out that I have HPV and low-level dysplasia. I felt terrible for a couple of days, but then I read some of your stories and you girls gave me hope! I felt so much better after reading that some of you are free of precancerous cells. I already went for treatment and now I'm waiting for the next pap in 3 months and hopefully it'll be gone (let's cross fingers!!)

My problem here is that I'm wondering if I should tell my ex-bf about this. Even though I know I can't be sure that he gave it to me, he was my only boyfriend for 4 years until we broke up last year. However, I don't want to tell him so I can blame him or something like that, I just want him to be aware of this, and maybe advice his sexual partners to go to the gyno and check if everything is ok.

What makes hesitant about telling him, is that I'm in a relationship with someone else now, and even though we've been together for a couple of months (I believe that HPV doesn't turn in dysplasia in such a short period of time, but correct me if I'm wrong), I can't be 100% sure. Also, my current boyfriend freaked out so much, he didn't took it very well. He started asking a million doctors and his parents (yes, his parents) about what could possibly happen to him. After his doctors reassured him that his chances to develop something from HPV like penis cancer was very very low, he calmed down. And I'm not really looking forward for another reaction like this.

On the top of it, my ex avoids me like the plague since we broke up. He even blocked me from fb and whatsapp (it's been a year and this is still going on). So, should I tell him? I feel like it is the responsible thing to do, but maybe I'm wrong. It's really not a big deal for guys, and I'm not sure of how he would react. Also, if he eliminated any type of contact with me is because he doesn't want to know anything about me. I really don't know what to do.

What do you girls think? Should I tell him or not? 

**tl;dr** **Have HPV and I'm not sure if I should tell my ex about it, because we don't have any contact anymore and he blocked me from everywhere possible. I feel like is the responsible thing to do, but maybe I'm wrong. What do you think? Should I tell him or not?**

  Find a way to contact him and tell him.  Yes. You owe it to his future girlfriends.  And also him, I guess?   While issues caused by HPV in men are more rare compared to issues caused by HPV in women Teklicon has a point in that [men can experience significant health problems (specifically types of cancer and genital warts) from the virus](http://www.cdc.gov/std/hpv/stdfact-hpv-and-men.htm) - men being "lower at risk" for complications is no excuse to not inform him. It's important that you inform *all* parties involved; there is no way of telling where you contracted the virus - for all you know your ex is the one that gave it to you and it's just now acting up. But, is there a way for men to find out for sure if they HPV? I keep reading there is no way for them to know.  Yes. You owe it to his future girlfriends.  Yes, I believe this is the main reason. I guess you are right, I need to tell him. Any ideas on how? I wouldn't want him to freak out on me before I finish explaining the whole thing. Yes, I believe this is the main reason. I guess you are right, I need to tell him. Any ideas on how? I wouldn't want him to freak out on me before I finish explaining the whole thing. Find a way to contact him and tell him.    What exactly is the point of telling him? You can't treat HPV, and it's extremely unlikely to cause any problems. Same for other girls he's been with - they can't be treated either. They'll be getting Pap smear and if one comes back abnormal it will be investigated. HPV is not a normal STI. Almost everyone has it or will have it at some point, it can't be treated, and it almost never causes an illness. The **only** reason they even test for it is if someone has abnormal cells on a Pap smear, be quad statistically they think it helps determine whether the changes may be more likely to progress than if there's no HPV. It's not something that needs contact tracing like normal STIs. We don't even test people for it in my country. We just do Pap smears.

TL:DR -there's nothing to be gained by telling him. I'd just leave it alone. If I were one of his future girlfriends, I would want to know. why not just get vaccinated</snippet></document><document><title>ESA Report: Women aren't the minority in gaming?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fsb8/esa_report_women_arent_the_minority_in_gaming/</url><snippet>**Disclaimer:** ***This is not an affirmative claim*** as to the demographic statics of women in gaming, i am attempting to find *data* on the topic to create a more complete picture.

This started off as a different thread on a different topic, but while researching i found some shocking data.

According to [The Entertainment Software Association](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entertainment_Software_Association) women make up [47% of the gaming population (google pdf)](http://www.pdfdownload.org/pdf2html/pdf2html.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theesa.com%2Ffacts%2Fpdfs%2FESA_EF_2012.pdf&amp;amp;images=yes).

I'm not sure why i hadn't considered this to be a possibility but now I have a few questions.

1. Was I alone in **assuming women were a minority** in gaming?

2. If not, what do you think creates this perception?

3. If women are actually a plurality, why do we see so many mostly male gaming environments? How did we end up with so many 'boy's clubs' and seemingly so few 'girls clubs'?

4. **Is this data/analysis accurate?** 

What might be another way of looking at the information to form a more complete picture? Can you find a flaw in the methodology or my interpretation?

I've posted this after having a great conversation with a friend of mine on the treatment of women in gaming communities and ways both sexes can unify to ensure an equal community for all of our fellow gamers. 

Much to my shock the first bit of information i find is that women are supposedly nowhere near a minority share of gaming! Perhaps it is my own biases, but i almost can't believe it.

I guess my main question is that if women gamers are 47% of the population, **how is it that I, and many other gamers end up in almost exclusively male organizations** so often after years of gaming?

Does my breath stink or something?

                                                         Edit Notes: 
- *5:13AM EST* formatting/grammar
- *1:38PM EST* formatting/link repair (ty redacteddude!)
- *2:01 EST added [link](http://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/18gkst/the_super_mario_generation_and_casual_gaming/) to avoid derail.
- *2:13 EST* added [link](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXtSOsoEOC8) (ty Starpire)

                                                            Links:

[On Eve Online (95 percent male)](http://virtual-economy.org/2006/10/02/interview_with_ccp_eve_currenc/),   
[Nick Yees work on MMORPGs](http://www.nickyee.com/index-daedalus.html) 

[Well formatted presentation of concerns of some female gamers](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXtSOsoEOC8) (ty Tamashii Hiroka)
                                                    

                                                    Personal Notes:
**Interesting Personal [Epiphany](http://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/18gkst/the_super_mario_generation_and_casual_gaming/):** A generation of people who revered Super Mario Brothers have grown up to revile modern examples of the same "casual" style gaming genre/style that introduced our generation to gaming. 

The dissonance is so entrenched that we can speak highly of the simple scroller Mario *in the same sentence* as belittling modern examples of simple gameplay designed for ease of entry and casual enjoyment.  I've mentioned this before, but I was an officer in a raiding WoW guild that was actually in the top 1% of raid progression, top guild on our server.  It was a very serious, competitive atmosphere where you were expected to pull your weight.  As it happened, the officers were all friends from a previous MMO, and we'd bonded over the fact we were all couples who played.

Like any other guild, we were open to recruiting, and with our focus, we had some very high standards.  But unlike other guilds, it seems word had got out that we had a zero tolerance for harassment.  And soon we noticed a very interesting trend in the people trying to join our guild... By far the majority were women.  (By the last year, I'd say it was 75% women)

Up until that point, if you had asked me, I would've said gamers were overwhelmingly male.  But now I realize a lot of women gamers hide their gender and there are a lot more out there than you realize.  &amp;gt;I guess my main question is that if women gamers are 47% of the population, how is it that I, and many other gamers end up in almost exclusively male organizations so often after years of gaming?

I'm guessing you're not a fan of casual, mobile or facebook games? I found that *women gamers make up 60% of farmville users* a golden standard among those considered "casual" games. I found this because i'd initially made the assumption "oh yeah, older women playing facebook games". 60% female doesn't account for the vast perception in the split of male/female gamers. If the thought is "it's all women playing casual games" and we discover "as many men play casually as women" what does that mean about the possibility of a **silent concentration of women in other genres?**

Perhaps other games have more skewed demographics but in tandem with the knowledge that many female gamers are silent in games to avoid harassment and that the social MMOs genre has a high woman gamer contingent that is sometimes hesitant to interact, i begin to wonder how many women gamers might be unaccounted for through silence in other genres? 

Perhaps i'm completely misreading this, but it's interesting to think that there is actually a closer vision to equality waiting for people to realize that they're not the only woman in the room. That could be completely incorrect by the data, which is why i'm so interested in finding out more.

Unfortunately i have to do many tasks today and i'm hoping that people with an interest will show up and add statistics they have, or at least people **ask their friends who might be experts in the topic** so that I can get the statistics to form a more complete picture.

6:10AM: extensively edited for clarity.

 I still think you're over-thinking it, finding things you want to find.

Just to look at the market , 290 million people are &#8220;active users&#8221; of only Zynga games (60% fem, 40% male).




Now compare it to lets say RTS genre, I'm taking a huge leap here and assuming that most currently playing RTS fans (at least 70%) have bought Starcraft 2. And if you look at those sales they would be much much lower when compared to free social games.  

So what I'm saying it's higly possible that you are playing the *"wrong"* games and *"cool"* games that fall under FPS/RTS/MMORPG are not the only games out there (and i forgot about wii).  As has been mentioned, the definition comes down to 'gamers' and the style of games played.  Co-operative gaming such as the predominant amount of social games tend to have a large amount of female gamers, indeed much in the majority of the type of game played, alongside mobile gamers - both of those styles are not conducive to 'clubs' as you describe them, yet are considered "gamers" none-the-less.

Social media itself has a greater number of active female users and those companies have a great deal of associated 'games' to help aid with social bonding, indeed the game developer Zynga grew exponentially by exploiting this market in tandem with facebook.  

If you look at Google's Ad reveue statistics [here](http://gigaom.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/4138193854_289d814ae6_2o.png?w=338&amp;amp;h=473) perhaps this social media dominance and the attempts to monetize this through 'fun interactions' by content holders is where these 'gamers' might be, though perhaps are incidental gamers.  

Reportedly SecondLife had/has 60% of its subscribers as female, though due to the propensity of harassment from males it'd seem sensible to keep this information quiet, as has been stated.  I have not played this game, though my initial assumption was that it is/was "male dominated" precisely because that is how most MMOs have been to-date.  

This schism between perception and reality is certainly interesting  - I'd suggest it may be a worthy area of further research to see how this population of gamers is distributed between combative or confrontational genres versus those which promote collaboration; and whether this stereotype could be distilled further to try and understand whether a difference in bonding behaviour may partly explain these admittedly quite significant differences in populations versus perceptions.    I have a video on this subject actually, if anyone is interested.

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXtSOsoEOC8 I have a video on this subject actually, if anyone is interested.

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXtSOsoEOC8     I think that the female gamer community isn't as discussed is because the games most women prefer are not played at a professional level. That isn't to say that there are no female professional gamers, there are, but most of the professionally played games are male dominated. Games like Call of Duty, Star Craft, DOTA 2 and League of Legends are played primarily by guys with a smaller female community. League of Legends put out some statistics (it is the most played online game in the world numbers wise) and women were a small percentage of their customer base. 

Gender demographic for different game platforms would be interesting to see. I would speculate that males dominate the traditional console platforms, then computer gaming starts to see an increase in female gamers, and then when you hit android/iOS based games you see a large increase in the female demographic, potentially a majority.  It might be interesting to examine those professional gaming levels in context of toxic online communities.  League of Legends and CoD are among those infamous for abusive communities and you could not *pay* me to self-identify as a woman in those circumstances.  Attitude drives desire and then demand.  It's a complicated ball and I'm not going to say the abuse in the community is the *only* factor in competitive play, but it does figure in.    Anecdotal story: I work in an office full of great people. We have half a dozen girls and several guys. Two of the guys play call of duty, another has his snes set up and I play pretty much everything. Only one of the women I work with even know who Mario is. I'm not saying this is a bad thing. I just think that's part of where the perception comes from. I don't know where all of these ladies are, but every guy I know plays games. Only a very small handful of my lady friends play any type of game. How old is the woman though? A lot of younger people aren't familiar with Mario. People my age think he's a cultural icon (and I guess he kind of is, because Super Mario Bros was the first game I ever played) but he's not exactly a big deal out there anymore. My 10 year old nephew could care less about who Mario is, for instance.  Mario was a poor choice. I just mean that most of them don't do any gaming, at all. Their ages range from 24 to 29.  Ah, okay. My boyfriend and I were talking about classic gaming the other day, and how most of the hardcore gamers seem to be mainly of our generation because we were "the first", so that's what made me question it.  Understandable. I doubt many teens really know much about the icons from our childhood. </snippet></document><document><title>Birth control question?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gcw8/birth_control_question/</url><snippet>Hey Reddit, I started birth control two years ago when I was 19. I always had long and heavy periods, so I was looking for birth control to make it a little easier on me. My doctor told me she'd prescribe me a "mid-dose" pill, Reclipsen. Initially, it helped a lot. My period lightened up a bit and went from 7 days to 4-5 days long.

However, my period's returned to its old, miserable state in the past 6 months. It's back to a week long, and ridiculously heavy the first 3 days. 

I have an appointment with my doctor tomorrow. Should I tell her I'm looking for a new birth control? If so, what? I'd like to find one that qualifies under my insurance, since they cover my co-pay each month.  [deleted]     It's pretty normal to have to try a few different things before you find the BC that works for you. By any chance have you gained some weight recently? Could be a dose issue. 

Just FYI- there's absolutely no reason why you need to have a period at all. In fact, there are health benefits of not getting a period. If it's financially feasible you might want to consider a pill that will stop your periods, or let you have only a few per year. Also, while it only totally stops periods in a subset of women, nearly all women who get the Mirena IUD experience drastically lighter periods with fewer cramps, so that might be a good option for you (not to mention that lovely 99.9% effective pregnancy prevention).  I have actually lost about 15 lbs in the past 6 months or so. But it was gradual and I'd be surprised if it affected my period.

I'll ask my doctor about those kind of pills! They sound amazing, but pregnancy scares would be my only issue (I get paranoid so easily). Thanks for the advice!    [Lybrel](http://contraception.about.com/od/prescriptionoptions/a/Lybrel.htm) eliminates periods. It comes in at least one generic brand, Amethyst. I would definitely recommend looking into it and asking your doctor about it. Feel free to ask me any questions as well, it's been working really great for me.  I've always wondered about these types of pills. The only reason I'm hesitant to ask about it is because I'm sexually active with my boyfriend. Even though I'm very good about taking my pills everyday, I still freak out if my period is a day late. Don't you ever get nervous?! </snippet></document><document><title>Sometimes I wish I was born a guy (Disjointed rant)</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18grwt/sometimes_i_wish_i_was_born_a_guy_disjointed_rant/</url><snippet>Let me first preface this by saying I am not transgender. I feel completely like a girl but sometimes would like to be treated like guys are usually treated. I am a bit of  what many would consider a "tom-boy" in many ways. I have no interest in fashion or shopping and I feel like many of my peers and even my own grandmother think of me as some sort of weirdo for it. Because of my hobbies I also tend to be friends with guys because I can't find many girls off of the internet who share my geeky interests (anime/manga/video games/etc.). I mentioned earlier that my grandmother doesn't appreciate who I am. Whenever she gets me presents, she buys me clothes. I know that I should be grateful that she even gets me presents so I feel bad thinking that. However, she also always  subtly criticizes my lack of fashion sense. I constantly hear "Why don't you wear earrings?" or "Why don't you go shopping more often". I constantly tell her that it isn't my interest but she never listens. I feel like everyone around me, to some degree, also feels that way and I don't know what to do other than change fundamental parts of who I am.  I'm sorry others are making you feel ostracized because of what you wear and what you are interested in. It's not right and it's not nice. :( Have you thought about connecting with some other people where you live that have similar interests as you do? Sometimes you have to branch out more to find people who will appreciate you and your interests :) Meetup.com is a pretty nice site to do that. Just make sure to be safe about it.

If I may ask, are you in high school?  Thank you for the reply and the suggestions! I'm in my first year of college right now and I'm trying to make friends here and join some clubs I'm interested in but I've always found it hard to make friends. I'll definitely try meetup.com so thank you for the suggestion!    </snippet></document><document><title>Welcome to the Breast Cancer Prevention Era?</title><url>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jeanne-rizzo/beyond-treatment-beyond-c_b_2666858.html</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Happy 37th Birthday to Leslie Feist. Bring it on, Gatekeeper</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3xYNTVaSAYI&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded</url><snippet /></document><document><title>NYC TwoXers: Anyone in search of clothes or shoes? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18grn0/nyc_twoxers_anyone_in_search_of_clothes_or_shoes/</url><snippet>I think we need a trading post. I have been generously passed along items here before, and I wanted to do the same. Local pick ups in Brooklyn are ideal because it might cost worth than it's worth to ship. 

I have a [whole, ongoing post in NYList](http://www.reddit.com/r/NYList/comments/181e0b/free_womens_clothes_dishes_lsat_mcat_textbooks/) if you are interested in other items like dishes, home items, yarn, textbooks, etc. I will try to add more clothes as well.

**Clothes**

* I have a bag or 2 of women's clothing. All approximately XS/S/4 sizes. Basics&#8212;sweaters, shirts, a pair of jeans or 2, etc. All in good, wearable condition. I'd prefer if you took the lot, but let me know if you are looking for something in particular, like a coat.

* Brown women's riding style boots. Almost new but in gently used condition. Size 8

* American Eagle Wedges: Brown canvas strappy with a peep toe. Super cute. Look to be brand new. Size 8

Let me know if you have questions or are interested in snagging something. </snippet></document><document><title>Newbie Hair Removal Advice?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18hhjk/newbie_hair_removal_advice/</url><snippet>Hello!

Long story short, I'm a guy who is considering getting a sex change. Before I do that, I'm trying to get an idea of what it's like to be a woman - that involves not having any, or much, body hair!

I looked into getting a full body wax, but it's over 200$(!) and I just can't afford that. So I decided I'd look into doing it myself. I currently shave myself, including downtown, pretty regularly, but I understand for a whole-body thing that may not be ideal. 

I looked into waxing at home, but there seems to be a lot of negative press for that. I've had it done before professionally, on my back, and am familiar with the technique, so I think I could do it, if you guys think it's a good idea. Do you? If so, what should I buy?

There's also, of course, depilatory cream - I can't do my naughty bits with it, but it sure sounds like a great idea. What do you ladies think?

And, finally, I heard about these new Epilator things. I've never heard of them before. What do you all think about them? Barring other advice, I was considering giving this a go, but I think it'll be painful. 

Anyways, I'm just looking for some advice, so hopefully this is the appropriate place for it. Thanks again!  No lies, epilators are pretty painful. They do the job *really* well, though, and unless you have a really low tolerance for pain, it's certainly a pain you can get used to.

I use mine on my armpits all the time and when I'm done, holy crap smoothness, Batman. I kind of love it for that since I've got dark hair and no matter how close my shave is, it'll never get close enough to make my armpits look totally smooth. And it works better on shorter hairs than wax does, in my experience. It works really well grabbing thick hairs, but I've never had much luck using it on my legs. Apparently my leg hair is thin enough that it'll get most of it, but a lot of it will just snap off and grow back weird. One thing going for it is after the initial investment of buying one, that's pretty much all you have to worry about price-wise.

At-home waxing... I've tried it, and I just ended up making an unholy mess except for the times I used a hardish sugar wax that comes in a tub and you work it in your hands to warm it up. Then you put it on your skin and YANK! Wax kits are inexpensive enough that you can grab one and try it out. It's kind of a pain getting all the little hairs, so you might want to get some tweezers for the hairs the wax misses.

I've never really been a fan of Nair and the like, but a big part of that is that when I first started growing hair, my mom wouldn't let me shave and made me use Nair and it smelled awful. I have some that I use in the shower for when I don't have the time or energy to shave. The fact that it chemically eats the hair away and turns it into this spaghetti paste that you have to scrape away weirds me out.

My combo that works for me (after years of getting frustrated and trying to figure it out) is epilating my armpits and shaving everything else, but try things out! A different combination might be what works for you. Awesome, thanks!

I couldn't find an epilator at the store today... where did you get yours?   Waxing your legs is a lot less painful than epilating, can't speak for any other body parts. I recommend Marzena wax strips, really easy to use, not too expensive and smell nice too. Not sure if they're available overseas though - I live in N.Z. </snippet></document><document><title>The girls are not alright: Single female immigrants to Australia</title><url>http://crookedtimber.org/2013/02/12/the-girls-are-not-alright/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>How can I tell him I love him...? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gbx1/how_can_i_tell_him_i_love_him/</url><snippet>I'm partly venting/frustrated. I'm dating a wonderful and amazing guy, I've told him my feelings in many many beautiful words and he's told me his in the same way. He doesn't really say "I love you" to anyone outside of family, he just feels that family is an unbreakable bond and worthy of the words. And, honestly, seeing him with his family I completely understand. I've never seen a family so close and loving. He feels that people tend to overuse the word and it loses meaning. "I love this sweater!" or saying "I love you man!" to friends, etc. 

I don't doubt he knows how I feel about him and how deeply I love him, and I don't doubt his feelings for me. But I still have the urge to tell him in plain, simple, words. 

I've been trying to muster the courage for two weeks now. We were on a wonderful vacation and got to see a brilliant light and fireworks show, and afterwords I looked deeply into his eyes and couldn't manage to say anything. Laying in bed that night he was already asleep when I got the courage to whisper it. After a game on Sunday I tried again and it didn't feel like the right moment. Last night I wussed out again.

I'm so afraid of his reaction. I know he doesn't like the word so I wouldn't get an "I love you" in return, which is ok, I don't see "I love you" as a command to hear the same thing repeated back to me. But I'm scared he's just going to stare at me blankly and it's going to really hurt me. Or worse, he'll get uncomfortable.

What can I do? Should I just give up and stick to articulating my feelings as best I can? 

I can't even fully explain why I *need* to say "I love you" instead of sharing my feelings. I guess I just want him to know beyond the shadow of a doubt. [Edit] I think I'm most concerned about saying it and him feeling that it's just casual or I don't really mean it and I'm just saying it because I'm in a relationship with him.    </snippet></document><document><title>I want some lady perspectives on online dating</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18g9yu/i_want_some_lady_perspectives_on_online_dating/</url><snippet>Reddit has its OKCupid community for things like this but it's hard to find a female perspective. Furthermore, I'm looking more for responses relating to match.com. Just browsing both, I am more drawn to men on match, the site seems overall more geared towards finding something serious. Of course I could be completely off base. 

So to the ladies who have tried both, did you have success in finding relationships? If so how long did it take? How long do you usually talk to someone before meeting in person? I'm wondering in general how the whole process of finding someone online progresses. Thanks!  I just have experience with okcupid. I sent out a lot of messages, had some great conversations but ended up only meeting with two guys while I was in the site. 

I've been with the second guy met up with for 7 months (as of today!). We messaged for a couple of days, exchanged numbers and then went on a date about a week after he first contacted me. 

One thing I learned is that you have to be willing to take chances even if someone doesn't seem perfect for you from their profile. There's only so much you can put in a profile and (for me) it's best to take a chance. Otherwise, I would have missed the great boyfriend I have today.  Happy anniversary!     Ive tried both okcupid and match.com. I'll keep this short.

The guy I met and started a relationship with from okcupid said he wanted a relationship with me, but as soon as we became official, he backed off and wanted to be fuck buddies. I turned him down for this and after numerous times of turning him down for hookups, he threatened me and my family. 


After that experience I was hesitant to try online dating again, but a coworker assured me that match was more relationship oriented. Six months later im with an amazing man I couldnt be happier with. We have so much in common and our views on relationships, what makes them work, and what we want for the future are perfectly in sync. I definitely recommend match.com if youre looking for something more meaningful than just a hookup.


Sorry for the spelling, I'm on my phone and rushing to type this before my lunch break is up lol.     I met my boyfriend on okcupid two years ago, we've lived together for a year, travelled lots together, he is absolutely awesome and we're very happy together :) I was so nervous about meeting him, but it was worth it, obviously. I had a profile on match.com years ago, but I didn't like it, it cost money and it looked like most of the guys there didn't really have much in common with me (for me, match.com felt like it was mainly very outgoing party people who weren't into the slightly nerdier things I like to do/talk about, while okcupid seemed to attract a different crowd, at least in my nook of the world. I realize this is 100% subjective :).  Ahh thanks, that really helps. I'm not so sure I would be into party people. I think I'll try okcupid first now.</snippet></document><document><title>Are These the Most Offensive Feminine Hygiene Ads Ever?</title><url>http://ladyish.com/fitness/are-these-the-most-offensive-feminine-hygiene-ads-ever/</url><snippet>    </snippet></document><document><title>UTI + Yeast Infection = Miserable. Advice please?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18h7cm/uti_yeast_infection_miserable_advice_please/</url><snippet>I am currently taking Macrobid for my UTI. Does anyone know if it is safe to also administer Vandazole vaginal gel at the same time as taking this antibiotic? 

Going to the doctor is not an option. I was just wondering if anyone has ever been prescribed these two treatments together and knows that there won't be any horrible drug interactions.

If not, does anyone know how to soothe the itch with something I'll have around the house? I have no money to buy anything.

Thank you!!  Go to a drug store and talk to a pharmacist. They can give better information about how different medications react together and if there is an issue can offer suggestions.   coconut oil? google says it has been used as an antifungal...

also, I think you would do better if you stop taking fish oil. Thanks! Does fish oil increase the chances of these infections occurring? I'm not taking it, but I've considered starting to. Not anymore...? the latest research finds no benefit for cardiovascular health &amp;amp; fish oil.

iodine would probably help the infections... i would send you a bottle for a few dollars - I would like to promote it to women for these common problems, and it would help to have more feedback about how well it works. Thanks, I have no dollars, though, unfortunately :(</snippet></document><document><title>Teen Birth Rates Plunge due to Birth Control Access....duh?</title><url>http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/02/11/1568311/teen-birth-rates-plunge/</url><snippet>    </snippet></document><document><title>Skewed body image?  Type in your weight, height &amp;amp; clothing size here to find pictures of other women that are the same size as you.</title><url>http://www.mybodygallery.com/photos-16319-body-shape.htm#img</url><snippet>  I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I'm afraid this backfired on me too. I looked at the women at my height/weight and thought oh... they all carry this better, none of them have my massive tree-stump legs... so I looked ten pounds down. And another ten pounds down. And another ten pounds. Finally, I'm looking at 5'7" women who weight under 100 pounds and I'm thinking why is it that I can look at them, know that would not be a healthy weight for me (I've had ED issues and been down to ~110, which was where I started fainting...) and still I feel like that's the goal, that's the only body I could love? :\ I do the exact same thing. :( I found a girl at my height and weight (5'4") that seemed to actually look exactly like I do (like I could really judge that) and I was freaking out because she looks fat to me. So I dropped the weight down to 100 or under 100 and I decided those girls are perfect and I need to look like them in order to be pretty. 

Maybe it's helpful for some people, but for me it just helps to reinforce my ED. :/  I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! &amp;gt;Nobody looks like me on there

I think the point of this site is that maybe you DO look as good as those other women, but you're just so much more critical of yourself than of others.  When you look at your body every day in the mirror, you lose the ability to see it for what it really is - totally sexy!  

So if you're seeing a bunch of awesome-looking women with your height and weight, it could very well be that you're just as awesome. I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! You put my feelings into words exactly. I might even pull out the word hate to describe this site. First of all, completely agree that this just makes me focus on my flaws rather than accepting myself for what I am.

Secondly, why does this exist? It seems like such a back-peddling in terms of self-acceptance and self-love! The point of this site is to *compare* yourself to other women. Not only that, but upload anonymous pictures of yourself to feed this false sense of validation...

I get why people would think this is a good idea, and why it *seems* like it's pro-body acceptance, but yikes....this is not for me. Yes, yes, that's exactly it - I sit there comparing myself to everyone, and thinking "this is what I should look like". I voiced exactly that to my boyfriend this morning, as I was looking at it again. 

When I look at myself in the mirror, or see myself through my boyfriend's eyes - I like how I look. I feel sexy. I feel at peace with my body. But then I look at the pictures on this site, and I start to compare. 

I even took pictures of myself to submit, because I thought "well maybe this site needs to see women who aren't comfortable showing their bodies because of self-image issues" - and then I looked at the pictures, and I hated myself even more. It made for a rough morning today, that's for sure. 

I understand the motivation for this site; I know that it's so you can see regular women from everyday walks of life, women who look just like you. But women like me, who are self-conscious, who focus on flaws and imperfections - I feel like we aren't the ones submitting the photos. 

I submitted mine, but I'm wavering back and forth about taking them down again. On the one hand, I want people to see me, and know that they can feel sexy and beautiful even if they aren't so, objectively; on the other hand, I feel self-conscious and like I'm adding to the idea of comparing and saying "I'm better than that, I'm worse than that"... 

It's a bit of a struggle.  I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs! I know that everyone touts this site as the awesomest thing since sliced bread, and loves the hell out of it - but honestly, it makes me feel even worse about myself. Nobody looks like me on there, and all it does is make me focus even more so on my own flaws. 

I know that I can't be the only person out there who looks like me - but every time I look at the site, I feel even more alone. It reinforces my skewed sense of body image :-/ I guess that means I'm totally FUBAR. 

Also, I hate that it limits the body type to 4 general categories, none of which seem to describe me. I guess I'm a banana. And ending on a positive note, I totally do have great legs!  Sadly this didn't help, so many ladies carry my same weight so much better than I do! :( i think a lot of them are grossly underestimating or overestimating their weight, tbh. i am exactly 5'4" and exactly 117 lbs. very few ladies in the 120 category look anything similar to me, and vice versa. some of them are very waifish and some look much heavier.  I'm your exact height and weight! Can we be friends? 

I was also extremely saddened by the results. Pretty much 100% of the girls on there at 120, 124, 128 have completely flat stomachs. Mine is...not. :[ I'm your exact height and weight! Can we be friends? 

I was also extremely saddened by the results. Pretty much 100% of the girls on there at 120, 124, 128 have completely flat stomachs. Mine is...not. :[ i think a lot of them are grossly underestimating or overestimating their weight, tbh. i am exactly 5'4" and exactly 117 lbs. very few ladies in the 120 category look anything similar to me, and vice versa. some of them are very waifish and some look much heavier.  I'm 5'5 (ok like 4.75") and 130lbs..they all looked like fitness models or perfect hourglass shapes....I look like a potato sack with arms and legs... i think a lot of them are grossly underestimating or overestimating their weight, tbh. i am exactly 5'4" and exactly 117 lbs. very few ladies in the 120 category look anything similar to me, and vice versa. some of them are very waifish and some look much heavier.  Sadly this didn't help, so many ladies carry my same weight so much better than I do! :( Scumbag DNA. I don't want the fat on my arms, I want it on my butt! Oh well. I wish there was a way to just move the fat from my stomach into my boobs (nonsurgically). I need less fat in the middle and more on top. Scumbag DNA. I don't want the fat on my arms, I want it on my butt! Oh well. Having a big ass and average waist and hips makes it incredibly difficult to buy jeans. It's not the worst thing.. but I wish I had more than three pairs of jeans!  Sadly this didn't help, so many ladies carry my same weight so much better than I do! :( Sadly this didn't help, so many ladies carry my same weight so much better than I do! :(  More like: type in your weight and height, subtract twenty pounds, and feel bad because you really would look better if you lost weight. :( Try this: type in your weight and height, add twenty pounds, and see how good those women look, then feel good that people look at you and see a thinner woman.  Many of these self-reported body shapes are doubtful. While I consider [this girl](http://www.mybodygallery.com/photos-24238-body-shape.htm#img) as hourglass, [this one](http://www.mybodygallery.com/photos-27219-body-shape.htm#img) and [this one](http://www.mybodygallery.com/photos-13970-body-shape.htm#img) have me wondering. Wrongfully reporting the shape like this gives me mixed feelings.

Not to mention, there's nothing wrong with not being an hourglass    For my height and weight, most of the girls who chose to post their photos are not what I would consider the norm. They look very toned to me. Seemingly biased subset of women but it's a nice idea.. For my height and weight, most of the girls who chose to post their photos are not what I would consider the norm. They look very toned to me. Seemingly biased subset of women but it's a nice idea.. For my height and weight, most of the girls who chose to post their photos are not what I would consider the norm. They look very toned to me. Seemingly biased subset of women but it's a nice idea..  Nope, women my pant size (42), weight (73kg) and height (5'9) look dumpy, and others just my weight and height are 4 sizes smaller... so I can only conclude that I'm carrying excess fat and have absolutely no idea how to change that, since a year of dieting, cardio and lifting heavy achieved no change. It's possible you're not wearing the right size.  Its true. Once I admitted my true size to myself and bought the correct fit, damn I looked good! Your size doesn't matter, but sizing does. Nope, women my pant size (42), weight (73kg) and height (5'9) look dumpy, and others just my weight and height are 4 sizes smaller... so I can only conclude that I'm carrying excess fat and have absolutely no idea how to change that, since a year of dieting, cardio and lifting heavy achieved no change. Nope, women my pant size (42), weight (73kg) and height (5'9) look dumpy, and others just my weight and height are 4 sizes smaller... so I can only conclude that I'm carrying excess fat and have absolutely no idea how to change that, since a year of dieting, cardio and lifting heavy achieved no change.  so what happens when they say they don't have any pictures of your body type? 

i am an anomaly.  so what happens when they say they don't have any pictures of your body type? 

i am an anomaly.  Ditto....you 5'3, 130 by any chance?  noooo... 5' 9 170...  For all the people saying that the pictures don't look like them, maybe we should post our own pictures this IFF? 

I've recently realized that taking pictures of my body IN A MIRROR has a completely different effect on me than just LOOKING in a mirror. When I look in a mirror, I think, "man I look fat." When I see a picture, I tend to think, "hey, I don't look so bad... " It's weird, but that's the way it is. I'm working on it. 

[Here's one from yesterday](https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-AH_h3y6DV-I/URmwfDYGHTI/AAAAAAAAbIk/9f7BPNyk1rk/s512/IMG_20130211_215708.jpg). I'm 5'7" and last I weighed myself, I was 144.6. I wear a size 8 and wear 'curvy' cut pants to fit my butt and thighs. Most of my body-hate is around my stomach and top of my hips. 

I've tried going on /r/BodyAcceptance, but I don't have the same mindset the people on there do. I'm a normal healthy weight, I exercise regularly, I'm an active person.. but, calories. I've learned that to maintain my ideal body size, I need to consume about 1600-1700 net calories daily. That's like... depressing.

So what do you guys think about a body image IFF where we are HONEST? Maybe contained in just ONE thread to prevent it from getting out of control. It's funny, I'm the exact opposite. I love the way I look in the mirror, but when I see myself in pictures, I'm disgusted.  Haha, I wouldn't say I'm disgusted by my body, but I'm definitely surprised by how much more overweight I look in photos, and I feel like the flash just does something to ruin my face. I know I'm fat and not pretty, but I still feel like it works for me in the mirror. For me, it's less the weight and more proportions. In photos, I can see how small my head is compared to the rest of my body. I can see how my hair looks bad (I have this weird obsession with how my hair looks in comparison to my face - probably my biggest insecurity). I can see how much I slouch compared to other girls, etc. So it's not so much about my weight, but more about how my carry myself and how my head is small. For all the people saying that the pictures don't look like them, maybe we should post our own pictures this IFF? 

I've recently realized that taking pictures of my body IN A MIRROR has a completely different effect on me than just LOOKING in a mirror. When I look in a mirror, I think, "man I look fat." When I see a picture, I tend to think, "hey, I don't look so bad... " It's weird, but that's the way it is. I'm working on it. 

[Here's one from yesterday](https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-AH_h3y6DV-I/URmwfDYGHTI/AAAAAAAAbIk/9f7BPNyk1rk/s512/IMG_20130211_215708.jpg). I'm 5'7" and last I weighed myself, I was 144.6. I wear a size 8 and wear 'curvy' cut pants to fit my butt and thighs. Most of my body-hate is around my stomach and top of my hips. 

I've tried going on /r/BodyAcceptance, but I don't have the same mindset the people on there do. I'm a normal healthy weight, I exercise regularly, I'm an active person.. but, calories. I've learned that to maintain my ideal body size, I need to consume about 1600-1700 net calories daily. That's like... depressing.

So what do you guys think about a body image IFF where we are HONEST? Maybe contained in just ONE thread to prevent it from getting out of control. For all the people saying that the pictures don't look like them, maybe we should post our own pictures this IFF? 

I've recently realized that taking pictures of my body IN A MIRROR has a completely different effect on me than just LOOKING in a mirror. When I look in a mirror, I think, "man I look fat." When I see a picture, I tend to think, "hey, I don't look so bad... " It's weird, but that's the way it is. I'm working on it. 

[Here's one from yesterday](https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-AH_h3y6DV-I/URmwfDYGHTI/AAAAAAAAbIk/9f7BPNyk1rk/s512/IMG_20130211_215708.jpg). I'm 5'7" and last I weighed myself, I was 144.6. I wear a size 8 and wear 'curvy' cut pants to fit my butt and thighs. Most of my body-hate is around my stomach and top of my hips. 

I've tried going on /r/BodyAcceptance, but I don't have the same mindset the people on there do. I'm a normal healthy weight, I exercise regularly, I'm an active person.. but, calories. I've learned that to maintain my ideal body size, I need to consume about 1600-1700 net calories daily. That's like... depressing.

So what do you guys think about a body image IFF where we are HONEST? Maybe contained in just ONE thread to prevent it from getting out of control.   There was 1 match to my body type, and when I read the stats, they weren't really a match.  :\ almost everyone chooses "hourglass" as their body type on that site. i suggest looking by weight and height only. 

it has been helpful for me overall i guess. i still feel like a lot of the ladies at my height and weight look great, and while i am *mostly* happy... it does bring up some insecurities.  almost everyone chooses "hourglass" as their body type on that site. i suggest looking by weight and height only. 

it has been helpful for me overall i guess. i still feel like a lot of the ladies at my height and weight look great, and while i am *mostly* happy... it does bring up some insecurities.   The women in my weight/height/pant size don't look like me. :/ Also, some of the girls didn't even look like they belonged in my weight/height category, they were so thin. I guess it's hard to get every one to be honest/ get accurate data on a site like this. Or maybe this shows that everyone carries weight differently.  My sister is shorter than me and about 10 pounds lighter but sometimes we can wear the same pants. I'm not saying every one is a liar, but I'm sure a lot of guessing went on, and obviously not all these girls used the exact same scale that was set to zero. And being shorter/weighing slightly less may or may not change pant size, that doesn't really relate to what I was saying, I'm making a point for all these girls who are supposedly the same weight/height/pant size. And yes, you can look radically different even with in these diameters, because every one is different. But I'm pretty sure from some of the pictures I was looking at, a lot of guessing went on. That doesn't make people liars per say, but it makes for bad data. The only one that didn't fit into my weight category was, surprisingly, a girl who was far too skinny. I can imagine that some girls might round down, but I can't imagine someone rounding up. I thought maybe she just carried weight differently, but a good portion of her body was in the shot so I couldn't imagine where else she'd be carrying it.   there are 4 photos matching my search criteria. 4. this is supposed to make me feel better about myself?   There are NO matches that fit my criteria. 

Um...yay? I'm unique?               I thought I looked thinner than the women that were my height/weight :-/   The results looked exactly like my body type, really cool.      I put a picture up on this website, and I later found the same picture in /r/gonewild. It was me with a bra and underwear, but my head was cut off. I was literally standing there, not in any way seductive - but someone put it up on GONEWILD!! *WTF*! I had to show the admins that it was indeed my body to get them to take the post down!!! 

Be careful when you post to this site guys!     I don't understand why looking at barely clothed and/or naked women who supposedly represent me in some way is supposed to make me feel good about myself.

Why bother comparing your body to others...? If you really need to see what you look like, set up your camera and take a picture from far away. If you want to see other people who look like you, get out in the world and do stuff and eventually you'll run into someone similar. Seriously. Why is stuff like this supposed to be so profound? (Not to attack OP or anything, these are just my thoughts on the various 'body projects' that have been floating around the internet lately.)

Edit: I suppose if you had an eating disorder you could have problems seeing your own body objectively. But for the average person? Meh. Honestly if I had an eating disorder I'd probably find this site more damaging than helpful, although I can't speak from personal experience... The whole headless-body thing is a little dehumanizing, even if its meant to protect anonymity. It helped me. It helps me look at myself how others see me, not just how I see me. I can look at girls with my height and weight and they all look really pretty, so it makes me think maybe *I* look that pretty to other people. If not pretty, at least my body doesn't disgust people.</snippet></document><document><title>Ladies, break out your best break up advice!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gci9/ladies_break_out_your_best_break_up_advice/</url><snippet>So my best friend of basically my entire life was recently dumped. She's taking it especially hard considering they were pretty serious(dated 2+years, talked about marriage/kids). The break up also came as a complete shock. They had been having a few problems throughout the relationship, but after a long talk a few months ago, she was under the impression that they had worked things out. Now out of the blue right after her birthday and before Valentines day, her bf drops the bomb that he might not want to be with her. Long story short, in the span of 2-3 days he went from "not sure" in the relationship to wanting to work on things to not wanting to be with her anymore. 

Understandably she's devastated. We've talked on the phone and Skype, but as she's in Chicago and I'm in NC, there's not much I can do in terms of face-to-face help. On top of all this, I've always been sort of bad/awkward at comforting people.

So twox, I'm asking for advice on what I can do help my friend feel better or at least not so down on herself. It's not just her being sad or upset that worries me, but she's having a lot of doubts on how she can trust anyone again. She feels like she was very secure in the relationship, so to be broken up with suddenly is hitting her really hard. Also, the bulk of her social circle was based around her boyfriend and his friends, so  she really doesn't have many people directly around her that she can turn to. 

Thanks in advance!  well the way i see it is most of the time a breakups not about hurting the other person. its alot worse to string a person along then to just cut it

u can do everything right in a relationship and stuffs just not working out :/ its not like shes undesireable. it just means it wasnt meant to be  Click on my name and go to "submitted" The post about tips for those in heart ache. I hope she feels better soon!!  Click on my name and go to "submitted" The post about tips for those in heart ache. I hope she feels better soon!!   If you have the means, now would be a good time to send her a nice care package?  If it were my bff I'd probably include some bubble bath and some of those chocolate cordial cherries (because they're her favorite and they ship reasonably well), maybe a scented candle, and a nice "thinking of you" card just reminding her to take care of herself and that you love her.  And if you have even more means than that, maybe offer to have her come visit you for a bit.  Getting out of town and away from the immediacy of the situation can be super helpful in the short term.  In the long term, well, her ability to trust people will come back when she's with someone new that she can talk to about her misgivings and who'll make her feel like she doesn't need to worry.  Which (understandably) might take a while.  I feel her pain. So hard. This just happened to me. :-/ I hope you feel better soon. Although it's not me going through it,  I can really feel her pain and emphasize with you. Do you have any advice on what not to do/say?  One best friend lives with me. When my recent ex and I broke up, I got off the phone with him, knocked on her door, and told her and asked what I was supposed to do.

She sat and listened. And then she told me to take time to mourn and that is was okay to cry, but to go ahead and just keep doing whatever I was doing before/while we were together. 

I realize your friend probably is about to relearn who she is without this relationship. This is a big lesson to have to teach yourself. Be there for her while she does that, even if it seems like she is acting out. Right now, being supportive helps. Unless she is placing herself in clear danger, let her do what she needs to. 

Do you have other friends in her area that she can hang out with, since you aren't there? Maybe ask them to keep her a little close during this. </snippet></document><document><title>Ladies of reddit have you ever had a Brazilian wax? If so how was your experience? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gkul/ladies_of_reddit_have_you_ever_had_a_brazilian/</url><snippet>I've been contemplating getting one but I haven't built up the courage to actually do it.   I get one about once a month and haven't shaved once in almost 2 years (I'm actually getting one this afternoon). The first time hurts the most, but it really isn't too bad. It stings/burns for a couple of seconds, then goes away. The Brazilian is done in 4-5 sections, so you go through the burn that many times. If you go back in 3-4 weeks before the roots take hold again, it will hurt much less after that first time. If you do it consistently long term, the hair will actually get thinner. I have huge patches on my legs where hair pretty doesn't grow at this point. I have been doing it for about two years, and doing it myself for the last year.  I don't think it hurts that bad, and it is a million times better than shaving.  I have sensitive skin and shaving was just not something I was willing to do.  

I did a lot of research and found a really great esthetician who had a lot of great reviews and she did an awesome job the first time.  Definitely take Advil an hour before you go, and I always apply hydro-cortisone cream to the areas afterwards and a few times the following day.  In my opinion they're totally worth it, especially if you do them yourself.  Very smooth and soft for weeks.         Did anyone feel uncomfortable showing their vaginas to strangers?  I'm interested in the answer to thus too. My problem is that I'm a big girl and embarrassed about that. I know you have to get into some odd positions and I'm worried I'd find this humiliating in case the waxer laughed at me for being a fatty.

Am I being foolish? I'm interested in the answer to thus too. My problem is that I'm a big girl and embarrassed about that. I know you have to get into some odd positions and I'm worried I'd find this humiliating in case the waxer laughed at me for being a fatty.

Am I being foolish? I'm interested in the answer to thus too. My problem is that I'm a big girl and embarrassed about that. I know you have to get into some odd positions and I'm worried I'd find this humiliating in case the waxer laughed at me for being a fatty.

Am I being foolish? Did anyone feel uncomfortable showing their vaginas to strangers?  Did anyone feel uncomfortable showing their vaginas to strangers?  Did anyone feel uncomfortable showing their vaginas to strangers?   </snippet></document><document><title>A Visual Representation of "Fatphobia". A woman's self portraits in public. </title><url>http://www.petapixel.com/2013/02/11/woman-photographs-herself-receiving-strange-looks-in-public/</url><snippet>  I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" This was my exact same thought. I'd make a face at anyone who stood in the middle of a busy walkway and obstructed traffic... 

Also, I tend to look at what cameras are pointed at. I feel like this project is awfully judgmental of the people who are now imposed upon by this woman taking photos of them without their consent in public. I wouldn't like to be the poor sap, annoyed by the woman standing still in the middle of the road, who just happened to make a grumpy face at her. 

I mean, especially for being a project about snap-judgements towards strangers... this is more than a little self-righteous. 

Totally not trying to downplay what she must feel on a daily basis, but I just don't feel like some of these photos are valid evidence of that.  I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I agree with this. They're likely looking at her funny because not only is she doing these things, but she's being photographed.

Honestly? She looks like about half of the people I know - People I'm related to, people I worked with, people I'm friends with. I'm not going to go crazy about how "beautiful" she is - To me, she looks incredibly average. I have to say, I had the same thought about the exact circumstances of these photographs, but on the other hand, it illustrates a real phenomenon. I know because I have looked at people like that, and when I was younger I made fun of "random" people for whatever reason, but always people who looked more like her than the people giving her the looks.

Another thing that makes it easier for her to get these looks is that she's doing "dumb tourist" kinds of things (the map, fumbling with the camera, standing still where people are walking in a rush), but I think this actually HELPS her point, because there is definitely a stereotype about the stupid American tourist being a fat, stupid American tourist. 

I can't tell where these pictures were taken, but some of them look like a different country, also because there aren't any other people her size in the pictures. Europeans, at least, certainly stare when they see a person that size, because it's not that common, and it's not as taboo to stare in places like France and Germany as it is in the US.

tl;dr: sometimes I ramble I have to say, I had the same thought about the exact circumstances of these photographs, but on the other hand, it illustrates a real phenomenon. I know because I have looked at people like that, and when I was younger I made fun of "random" people for whatever reason, but always people who looked more like her than the people giving her the looks.

Another thing that makes it easier for her to get these looks is that she's doing "dumb tourist" kinds of things (the map, fumbling with the camera, standing still where people are walking in a rush), but I think this actually HELPS her point, because there is definitely a stereotype about the stupid American tourist being a fat, stupid American tourist. 

I can't tell where these pictures were taken, but some of them look like a different country, also because there aren't any other people her size in the pictures. Europeans, at least, certainly stare when they see a person that size, because it's not that common, and it's not as taboo to stare in places like France and Germany as it is in the US.

tl;dr: sometimes I ramble I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I do this all the time, screaming "It's a sidewalk not a sidestop! MOVE" in my head at strangers.  Or when people stop in the middle of a hallway/in front of a doorway/in front of my sugar and cream stand for my coffee.


I've got maaaaaajor issues with this. I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?" But here's the thing.. if she was slim... do you think people would be giving her the same looks and giggles behind her back?  I don't think so.  Not to the extent that is being shown here.  I mean one photo, she's getting the look I am all too familiar with just standing at a cross walk which others are doing.  That's hardly being weird.   Or being stared at for looking at a map?  Really?  That's a weird thing? People can't stop and look at a map anymore?   

Maybe because I am so used to getting the exact same looks and snickers that this woman gets.. even more so because I'm larger than she, I don't see this as "why is this woman standing here?" more than "Holy crap, she's fat!".  Experience just tells me a different story than what others seem to be seeing. Yes, I do think so, because she is making somewhat of a spectacle of herself. I'm not large, and I've gotten annoyed looks when I walk in someone's way, and stop to look at a map. Just like anyone would get irritated looks for rudely cutting someone off on the road. And I have given those looks as well. I know that people look down on others who are fat. But that doesn't mean that everything that happens to/around you can be attributed to being fat. Its ironic that the people who so desperately want to be defined by something *other* than their weight are the same people who attribute even the slightest actions as being in response to their weight.  How? Standing in the street, doing what others do?  Look at maps, stand at intersections, stop to talk on the phone?  Stand on a beach?  Oh.. ok.. noted.  I shall never so such things ever.  because they're apparently weird, and I am making a spectacle of myself!   How? Standing in the street, doing what others do?  Look at maps, stand at intersections, stop to talk on the phone?  Stand on a beach?  Oh.. ok.. noted.  I shall never so such things ever.  because they're apparently weird, and I am making a spectacle of myself!   OK, have you ever been to NY? You don't walk out onto a crowded, fast moving sidewalk, stop, and obliviously look at a map while a camera on a tripod takes a picture of you. It's weird. 


 There is a photograph there were she is standing *in the middle of a crowed crosswalk*, and a woman and her child are forced to go around her. Yes, that is odd, obstructive, and rude behavior. You should not do those things, I'm glad that this has been educational for you. 


I took a look at the picture you were referring to, where she is on her phone, standing at a crosswalk, my first thought was that the woman was looking for on-coming traffic. As to the rest, in my opinion most of the pictures don't have clear judgemental or disgusted (or whatever it is you're seeing) expressions. The people (that are even clearly looking at her) just seem irritated. 

Anyway, I have no way to prove that these people are not giving her dirty looks, and you have no way to prove that they are. My point is, why are you assuming, given all the abnormal circumstances surrounding these photos, that these people are making judgements about her weight? I think that speaks more to *your* judgements than it does about the people being photographed. 


Edit: grammar I'm from NY... Me too! How about that. How many insults do you get for blocking up your street corner?  OK, have you ever been to NY? You don't walk out onto a crowded, fast moving sidewalk, stop, and obliviously look at a map while a camera on a tripod takes a picture of you. It's weird. 


 There is a photograph there were she is standing *in the middle of a crowed crosswalk*, and a woman and her child are forced to go around her. Yes, that is odd, obstructive, and rude behavior. You should not do those things, I'm glad that this has been educational for you. 


I took a look at the picture you were referring to, where she is on her phone, standing at a crosswalk, my first thought was that the woman was looking for on-coming traffic. As to the rest, in my opinion most of the pictures don't have clear judgemental or disgusted (or whatever it is you're seeing) expressions. The people (that are even clearly looking at her) just seem irritated. 

Anyway, I have no way to prove that these people are not giving her dirty looks, and you have no way to prove that they are. My point is, why are you assuming, given all the abnormal circumstances surrounding these photos, that these people are making judgements about her weight? I think that speaks more to *your* judgements than it does about the people being photographed. 


Edit: grammar But here's the thing.. if she was slim... do you think people would be giving her the same looks and giggles behind her back?  I don't think so.  Not to the extent that is being shown here.  I mean one photo, she's getting the look I am all too familiar with just standing at a cross walk which others are doing.  That's hardly being weird.   Or being stared at for looking at a map?  Really?  That's a weird thing? People can't stop and look at a map anymore?   

Maybe because I am so used to getting the exact same looks and snickers that this woman gets.. even more so because I'm larger than she, I don't see this as "why is this woman standing here?" more than "Holy crap, she's fat!".  Experience just tells me a different story than what others seem to be seeing. But here's the thing.. if she was slim... do you think people would be giving her the same looks and giggles behind her back?  I don't think so.  Not to the extent that is being shown here.  I mean one photo, she's getting the look I am all too familiar with just standing at a cross walk which others are doing.  That's hardly being weird.   Or being stared at for looking at a map?  Really?  That's a weird thing? People can't stop and look at a map anymore?   

Maybe because I am so used to getting the exact same looks and snickers that this woman gets.. even more so because I'm larger than she, I don't see this as "why is this woman standing here?" more than "Holy crap, she's fat!".  Experience just tells me a different story than what others seem to be seeing. I'd probably stare in confusion if someone was looking at a map, and given my extreme case of bitchface, it'd look like I was glaring or sneering. The confusion would be at seeing someone with a map, because I haven't seen someone consult a map since cellphones with GPS became ubiquitous.  Yep, chronic bitchface coupled with my unconscious frown and furrowed brow when trying to figure out what I'm seeing would make me look as if I'm glaring at someone.

If I saw someone with a map, I'd probably glance at them, too, but I'd be wondering if the person needed help, if they would get upset if a stranger approached them, if I'd actually be able to help, if maybe I've been staring too long and frowning.

I'm sure people do sneer at her for her weight. I've seen plenty of people doing it to others. Hell, that's what drives People of Walmart. But, some of these photos really look to me as if the person looking is trying to figure out why there's a camera pointed at the lady in question. "I mean, what the heck is going on here? Is that a video camera? Did I get recorded? *What is she doing?*" But here's the thing.. if she was slim... do you think people would be giving her the same looks and giggles behind her back?  I don't think so.  Not to the extent that is being shown here.  I mean one photo, she's getting the look I am all too familiar with just standing at a cross walk which others are doing.  That's hardly being weird.   Or being stared at for looking at a map?  Really?  That's a weird thing? People can't stop and look at a map anymore?   

Maybe because I am so used to getting the exact same looks and snickers that this woman gets.. even more so because I'm larger than she, I don't see this as "why is this woman standing here?" more than "Holy crap, she's fat!".  Experience just tells me a different story than what others seem to be seeing. But here's the thing.. if she was slim... do you think people would be giving her the same looks and giggles behind her back?  I don't think so.  Not to the extent that is being shown here.  I mean one photo, she's getting the look I am all too familiar with just standing at a cross walk which others are doing.  That's hardly being weird.   Or being stared at for looking at a map?  Really?  That's a weird thing? People can't stop and look at a map anymore?   

Maybe because I am so used to getting the exact same looks and snickers that this woman gets.. even more so because I'm larger than she, I don't see this as "why is this woman standing here?" more than "Holy crap, she's fat!".  Experience just tells me a different story than what others seem to be seeing. I really like one of the comments down below where it can seriously be warped in a way that's not her being stared at because she's fat, but being stared at because she's doing something unusual.  IE sitting on a child's swing alone, you're probably gonna get looked at fat or not same as if you pull out a map and stand in the middle of the street, you're going to be looked at like, "you're standing in the middle of the street, really?"  I think this is really interesting; I particularly like the point about "reversing the gaze". However, do I like the result? No. Emotionally - and I think we have to judge art at least in part by our (subjective) emotional reactions to it - I'm uncomfortable with the aspersions that appear to be cast on the "fatphobic" viewers, and it makes me feel that the photographer portrays herself as verging on the slightly paranoid. 

Like others are saying, to me they just look like people who are thinking to themselves, "Huh. Why is this woman standing in front of a camera/in the middle of the pavement/in my damn way/making a strange face?". Caught in that single moment the camera captures, I would probably be looking askance too, but not because I was standing behind somebody whose weight I "disapproved" of (wtf?). I would be wondering what the hell was going on, what she was doing/looking at, and whether I was being caught in the same picture. 

Of course, I haven't looked at every single picture, and I wasn't there when they were taken. I am not her; I don't mean to denigrate or devalue her experience. Ultimately, I think this project is both interesting and important... but I also think we need to see past "fat" to "person", and realise that the context of the images is valid, as well as the abstracted faces of the observers.  Given I have a chronic case of bitchface, I would look like that in most background shots of me (particularly if i'm busy/thinking), and that's before the person standing in the flow of traffic with a camera set on a tripod caught my attention.



  While I'm sure some people were just thinking "Ew she's fat," she's also doing something unusual in high traffic areas. I can imagine trying to get somewhere and some stranger standing in a walkway and feeling annoyed at that person, whether they were overweight or not. I got things to do! Get outta the way! I think the same, although the first image on the steps where the guy is getting a mocking photo of her without her knowledge is pretty fucked up.   I judged most of pictures before even reading the article.

In the NYC pictures:
She's wearing a blue shirt, green shorts, red sneakers..  Well, for starters, who wears that in NY? Who stops in the middle of the sidewalk in NYC to look at a map?? Who even USES a map anymore?? Back up against the building, move out of the way of people walking, and look at your map.

The swing thing is just creepy. All around.

There's one on a busy square in Peru. 1) She's stopped to tie her shoe. 2) Using one hand (you can't tie your shoe with one hand), 3) Is still holding her phone to her ear with the other. 4) FYI, shes not even on the sidewalk, she's technically in the crosswalk where she is standing. 

Walking on the beach: She's hold her purse so awkwardly... above water... 

Then I read the article. And realized that she was setting up a camera to take these pictures of her. So, wait not only is she blocking traffic in awkward ways, shes got a tripod set up taking pictures of her ... taking pictures... looking at a map... taking random shots of her looking confused, not looking at the camera, and not smiling??

This is so far reaching that anyone is looking and judging her on her weight. 

edit: da spellings and grammars    
These pictures show typically normal responses to somebody being photographed while doing awkward things in the middle of crowds. People are looking at her and the cameraman. That is completely expected. 

It is inherently biased because the photographer and subject offer their commentary based on what they expected to find on the outset of the 'project'. 

I'm not saying this is a bad idea, but this is executed horribly. Use a hidden camera, or stop doing such awkward things for the shots. Having said that, I imagine if this was tried they wouldn't get much of a response because frankly... people really don't care. &amp;gt;These pictures show typically normal responses to somebody who is a disgusting slob

I doubt there would have been as many grimaces and frowns if she were attractive and in shape.   Photos don't look like Memphis. They look like NYC and somewhere in Europe. Both of those places you're not going to see the same proportion of obese people like you would in Tennessee, Mississippi, or Texas. In NYC you walk your ass off. You can be fat, but it's pretty hard to be obese if you live in the city. In continental Europe it is very rare to be fat or obese unless you are old [although they are growing as well.]

It's not "fatphobia" to look at something you don't see everyday, and wonder "how did this person get like that?" They are all NYC These are not all NYC; Two shots are from Peru, at least 1 in Brazil, and I think the beach may be south america as well.    </snippet></document><document><title>At what point does his 'persistence' become stalking? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fe37/at_what_point_does_his_persistence_become_stalking/</url><snippet>I'm mostly a 2XC lurker, but I have a problem I have to post about. 

I had been dating this guy (we'll call him 'M') for 14 months when I broke up with him on August 4th, 2012. He tried, repeatedly, to regain my affections, but I had fallen out of love with him months before the actual breakup (and stayed with him out of comfort more than anything else). 

For months, M threatened suicide, sent me thousands of texts I didn't respond to, called hundreds of times even when I didn't answer, and even showed up at my house while I was out on a date to deliver Christmas presents to my family. I told him not to contact me again, and things cut off abruptly.

Eventually, it seemed like he had finally accepted that I had moved forward and began dating again. The texts dwindled off, the calls stopped coming, and I got rid of the gifts. 

Things have started to come up again, though. He sent me a text on New Years, which was fine. Then three weeks ago he sent me a few texts under a different number that I responded to (general "Hi, how are you"s, etc.), but that quickly dissolved into 

"*I feel like this is a bad idea, Katherine. I don't want to upset you or anything like that. But I'll never know if I don't ask. Would you like to do something some time? I don't want it to seem like that's the only reason for me to talk to you. I mostly just feel like I would be bothering you. I get the impression I'm making things worse by rambling on like an idiot, but at least I'm being open.*"

And I refused to respond after that. I've made that a very clear limit for myself and for him. I hadn't heard from him since then... Until my mom texted me saying Valentine's Day flowers had been delivered for me, today, from M. 

It's a bouquet of pink roses, with an attached note saying "*Happy Valentine's Day. I love no one but you. I have discovered, but you are far away and I am here alone. This is my life and maybe, however unlikely, I'll find my way back there.*"

It's making me totally uncomfortable, especially since I have been seeing a new man for five months. I am at a loss and have no idea what to do anymore. At what point do I notify police? At what point does my discomfort make a restraining order reasonable? I'm not in fear of my life, but I still feel really threatened by this. 


**TL;DR**: Ex boyfriend sent thousands of texts, called, sent Christmas gifts, and now Valentine's day roses, despite my repeated efforts to cut off contact with him. I am dating someone else. Where is the 'stalking' line drawn?   Unfortunately, having someone make you uncomfortable repeatedly for long periods isn't illegal most places.

I'd say he's already crossed the stalking line, and it seems he needs therapy to learn to deal with his emotions. I'd keep a record of these things as much as possible, and other than that, do not respond at all again. 

Block him online and on your phone if you can, and ask your friends and family to not answer the door if he tries to drop stuff off for you. Completely breaking contact will probably be best for both of you, as it will hopefully discourage him from continuing to bother you and hopefully help him deal with his remaining feelings for you.

If he goes over the line and threatens or hurts you or anyone close to you, that documentation and record of his behavior will come in handy. It might even be worth trying to file a police report, even if it's very unlikely that the cops can or would do anything. I appreciate your response. I feel really threatened by his behavior, even though he hasn't said anything or even alluded to anything that would make me fear for my safety. 

I keep a record of all of his attempts at communication because I had a fear-for-my-life stalker in the past, but I can't help but feel like my efforts are futile until he tries to hurt me or my family. 

Thanks again.  Have you explicitly told him that his behaviour makes you uncomfortable, and you do NOT want him talking to you anymore? I appreciate your response. I feel really threatened by his behavior, even though he hasn't said anything or even alluded to anything that would make me fear for my safety. 

I keep a record of all of his attempts at communication because I had a fear-for-my-life stalker in the past, but I can't help but feel like my efforts are futile until he tries to hurt me or my family. 

Thanks again.   Hi, I have been in a similar situation.

I can't quite say if you feel threatened you are being threatened, I can say, if someone's not respecting your boundaries, and you fear it could go further, don't waste any time, get the Police involved because if you need to make a case for Harassment later on, you have to start now.

I live in Canada.  I had my current partner step in and explain to my ex that the emails, text messages, and phone calls were not appropriate. My ex screamed at him to put me on the phone because he had to ask me to marry him.  At this point he was parking outside my work, he was calling from fake phone numbers, he was writing three page long emails.  And it was fucked.  He was trying all kinds of manipulative bullshit to get me back.

At the point he had been told I no longer wanted to talk to him, and he said he wanted to ask me to marry him, I contacted my local Police. 

I had copies of the emails but they didn't even need those.  They gave him a call and explained that I was uncomfortable being contacted, that I no longer wished to be contacted, and that they had been informed of this.  If he continued to contact me then it would make a case for harassment and they would have to get involved beyond a phone call.

He still tried to friend me on Facebook about a month ago... but otherwise... no emails. No phonecalls. No text messages.  The line for stalking has been drawn a long time ago. M pretty much hurdled over the line and went straight into the bleachers after he threatened suicide and sent you thousands of texts. If you have any saved and more evidence of his encounters, bring yourself to the police station and ask, and for the love of all that is holy, DO NOT stay at your house.  Pack a bug-out bag and get yourself to a friend's place. 


Change your cell if you can.  The line for stalking has been drawn a long time ago. M pretty much hurdled over the line and went straight into the bleachers after he threatened suicide and sent you thousands of texts. If you have any saved and more evidence of his encounters, bring yourself to the police station and ask, and for the love of all that is holy, DO NOT stay at your house.  Pack a bug-out bag and get yourself to a friend's place. 


Change your cell if you can.  What? No.  It sounds like he was just sending ex texts.  Op should have firmly stated she was done receiving them and blocked the number, but she responded.  Just because you don't like someone, it doesn't mean they're stalking you. Op gives no indication of fear for safety of his keeping track of her whereabouts.  You are giving ridiculous, extremist advice.    These kind of stories always strike me as they remind me of the horrible way stalking and harassment is presented in media as endearing infatuation. A few twists and turns aside, the exact same scenario that you are going through would be considered the "conflict" portion of the third act of many romance films. 

The man in the relationship has wronged the women in some way and must win back her affection. The most important thing to remember is that you can remind her how much she loves you if you just persist and find the one "magical" thing to do or say that will win her back. The woman at this point is not much more than a prize to acquire, an obstacle to overcome. The climax of the film is her realizing she actually does love him and she should have never left them.

If your life were a film, by this point you would be engaged. On your wedding day he would burst into the ceremony and proclaim his love for you in a heartfelt speech, before the eyes of you, your fiance, your family and God. You would see how wrong you were to love another man and rush into his arms. 

I always point out how these actions in reality would be considered stalking and harassment but I am always treated as a negative nancy and "cold heart'ed prick" for saying so.

Just think it's interesting. Sorry about your situation by the way. These kind of stories always strike me as they remind me of the horrible way stalking and harassment is presented in media as endearing infatuation. A few twists and turns aside, the exact same scenario that you are going through would be considered the "conflict" portion of the third act of many romance films. 

The man in the relationship has wronged the women in some way and must win back her affection. The most important thing to remember is that you can remind her how much she loves you if you just persist and find the one "magical" thing to do or say that will win her back. The woman at this point is not much more than a prize to acquire, an obstacle to overcome. The climax of the film is her realizing she actually does love him and she should have never left them.

If your life were a film, by this point you would be engaged. On your wedding day he would burst into the ceremony and proclaim his love for you in a heartfelt speech, before the eyes of you, your fiance, your family and God. You would see how wrong you were to love another man and rush into his arms. 

I always point out how these actions in reality would be considered stalking and harassment but I am always treated as a negative nancy and "cold heart'ed prick" for saying so.

Just think it's interesting. Sorry about your situation by the way.  The stalking line was drawn about last September.

He obviously has dependency issues and needs to see a therapist about it; I would get a restraining order preemptively, because you really don't want this developing into something dangerous. 

You also shouldn't have responded to his texts. People like this WILL see that as an encouragement, that you're interested again, and get worse and worse. You need to set down clearly "Look, I don't want to talk to you, I'm creeped out by you, please don't ever message me again" and then IGNORE anything else he sends you. Do not respond whatsoever. The only good response in this situation is no response. &amp;gt;I would get a restraining order preemptively

This usually isn't an option. Courts will not issue such orders unless the stalker has actually done something to hurt you or has threatened to do so (sometimes not even then). 

I remember sitting in on a case in which a lady and her mother had accused this guy of coming to their house, pushing them around, and then busting up stuff on the outside of their home when they went inside to call the police. He had also made threatening phone calls, IIRC. The judge refused to issue them a restraining order.

I don't know if there was more to that story, but I was shocked at the outcome.</snippet></document><document><title>Birth control help!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18gxty/birth_control_help/</url><snippet>So I am in a committed, monogamous relationship with my boyfriend for 8 months. For about 6 of those months I have been using oral contraceptives. I started with a generic form of LoEsterin (Microgestin) and was moved to a generic form of Alesse (Lutera) after having emotional problems on that pill. I have only been on Lutera for 2.5 months but I am having the same emotional problems. I have been crying at basically nothing, starting arguments with my boyfriend and just generally paranoid about our relationship.

Now, my wokr moved to new insurance, so the new insurance will move me to a different generic form of Alesse (Orsythia) after I am done with this pack of Lutera. Right now, I have been going to my GP for birth control and she is understanding, but maybe I should find a Gyno. I am also frustrated with being moved to a new generic. I know the active ingredients are the same in both pills, but I am worried my body may have to adjust AGAIN to the different "fillers".

I have read that you should wait 3 months for your body to fully adapt to the pill, but being this emotional really blows. My boyfriend is so understanding, but he (and I!) shouldn't have to deal with this crazy bitch that pops out a few times a month. We used condoms in the beginning and I would go back to them, but I really do love sex without condoms. I am very good about taking my pill (I have never missed a pill by more than 30 minutes) so I am not worried about the risk of pregnancy on it sans the use of condoms.

So, my question is: Should I go back to my GP (or find a new Gyno) and try ANOTHER pill? Should I ride this one out for a couple more months? Should I fuck it all and just get a copper IUD? Honestly, doing the trial and error with the different pills wouldn't be half as bad if I weren't in a relationship.

I know this is technically a medical question and I will discuss it will my doctor, but I would love to get some feedback. After not being on the pill very long, I could use all the help I can get!
  </snippet></document><document><title>Why we still need feminism:</title><url>http://oxford.tab.co.uk/2013/02/06/womcam-whiteboards-hit-rad-cam-in-radical-revolution/</url><snippet>   I still need feminism because of the comments at the bottom...yeesh.     I still need feminism because of the comments at the bottom...yeesh.     I still need feminism because of the comments at the bottom...yeesh.       I still need feminism so that myself and my trans brothers and sisters are treated as equals. Unfortunately there's a chunk of feminists who think transgendered women are still just privileged men.  Unfortunately there's a chunk of feminists who think transgendered women are still just privileged men.  I'm not attacking you by any means, this is more rhetoric and musing in nature, but how on earth could people assume that being transgender, especially a transgender woman, means that one assumes privilege.

I've never experienced anything but a lack of privilege in comparison to male friends I've talked to. The only arguments that could possible assume that transgender women have male privilege would be backed by the concept that men and women are inherently different, and men are better, therefore people who were 'previously men' are still better. I don't know... 

/rant Disclaimer: I obviously don't agree with this. This is a devil's advocate argument intended to try to figure out what the other side of this conversation is.

Here's one argument. Most people who are transgender, genderqueer, etc (anyone not cisgender) come out later in life. (By which I mean, usually not before their teens.) As a result, someone who is biologically male will live as a boy and then as a man for a significant amount of time. Throughout one's early (and possibly later) education, and very likely for one's early career, this person would be treated as a man, and would gain educational and other privileges that cisgendered men get through their early lives. No, thats an interesting return argument (and I appreciate the disclaimer!), I did read a refute to that a while back on here which really stuck with me, I just had to find it.

[Link to whole comment by user trans_sisterradio](http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/1726ye/why_feminism_cant_afford_to_ignore_transgender/c81r0ok).

&amp;gt;I came out 3 months before I turned 18. I had my first legal drink, my first trip to a bar, my first time buying cigarettes, all of those were as a woman. Every interaction I've had with every place I've ever worked, the government and tax services, most of my medical 'team' and even most of my current friends has been as a woman. I've been put down, picked up, groped onto, let go, leered at, ignored, held to standards and yelled at for meeting them. I will never know male privilege for my entire adult life.


&amp;gt;If we take a step backwards, to before I came out, I was in high school. I was the depressed, introverted emo gay boy who had few friends. My social life consisted of pretending to be someone I was not, and then getting miserable that I wasn't either of the two options. My home life consisted of trying to ignore what was going on at all costs.

&amp;gt;I'm not saying that there's a universal trans experience by any means, but I'll take the wager that a lot of transgender women who've had the opportunity to transition early had a childhood in which, like me, they didn't have the time or the ability to appreciate our privilege. We spent too much time keeping our tail between our legs, being told off for not acting like men and then being told by the world that we could be anything we wanted to be - just not what we actually wanted to be. I appreciate the story, and as per the disclaimer, don't believe what I'm saying, but some people, even within the queer community, feel that gay men, even when they face discrimination, benefit from make privilege. Also, most men, even cisgender, white, financially stable men, don't appreciate that they have privilege.   We still need feminism because it is for [equality for all people](http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/feminism) not just women. 

*scrol to the bottom of the definitions. I don't get it, what's your point? All the signs relate to problems that women face. IMO feminism is focused on women's equality issues almost exclusively so it's a bit baseless to claim it's about equality for all. We still need feminism because it is for [equality for all people](http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/feminism) not just women. 

*scrol to the bottom of the definitions.  Can I just say, those women are gorgeous! Such beautiful smiles and striking confidence!  Sometimes comments like this make me uneasy.  I have a hard time parsing the difference between "These women are gorgeous! Such beautiful smiles!" and "These chicks are hot! Awesome boobs!"  

I know that they are really different in tone and in terms of respect. But they both seem to be totally ignoring the content of the article and focusing on how the women look.  Maybe it is OK because they are women-on-street who aren't prepped for a photoshoot and look more like the average (as if she exists!) woman.  

Can someone help me out?  I know no disrespect was intended, but I need some more insight.  Thanks!  All I meant was that, when I look at these pictures, I see women (and guys!) who are filled with self-confidence and sincerity. They are not made up or posed or altered to convey any sort of message besides what they truly intended. They are speaking from the heart on their white boards, which, in my mind, is beautiful.  Sometimes comments like this make me uneasy.  I have a hard time parsing the difference between "These women are gorgeous! Such beautiful smiles!" and "These chicks are hot! Awesome boobs!"  

I know that they are really different in tone and in terms of respect. But they both seem to be totally ignoring the content of the article and focusing on how the women look.  Maybe it is OK because they are women-on-street who aren't prepped for a photoshoot and look more like the average (as if she exists!) woman.  

Can someone help me out?  I know no disrespect was intended, but I need some more insight.  Thanks!  Can I just say, those women are gorgeous! Such beautiful smiles and striking confidence!  Well they did only photograph young, good-looking college students.  I think they look like pretty average looking young people, no?  Not unattractive, but not attractive.  Not that it matters :/ Well they did only photograph young, good-looking college students.  Good-looking is fairly relative, especially when it comes to the typical portrayal of the ideal. Remember the Dove ads with all the "normal" women? 
http://kingmedianow.wordpress.com/tag/campaign-for-real-beauty/

All striking, and very unique. I get the same vibe from these college kids. The Dove Campaign For Real Beauty used images that were extensively photoshopped, FYI: http://main.stylelist.com/2008/05/08/doves-campaign-for-real-beauty-was-photoshopped/ The Dove Campaign For Real Beauty used images that were extensively photoshopped, FYI: http://main.stylelist.com/2008/05/08/doves-campaign-for-real-beauty-was-photoshopped/ Well they did only photograph young, good-looking college students.   Cool stuff! I didnt like the way they phrased "What was the victim wearing" police always need to know that for reasons other than what was implied. I loved the message though! I'm pretty sure requesting information for a police report is a very different category of people than the "they" implied by the sign... and makes a big assumption that the assault or harassment actually got reported. Not that I disagree with the sentiment, but if it hadn't been reported how would anyone know to ask what the victim was wearing...? Assaults and harassment is often discussed, and not just when it gets to the authorities.  
"I got catcalled today! How offensive!"  "Well what were you wearing?"  
"I went out dancing and some guy just grabbed my boobs!"  "Well with a shirt that low cut what did you expect?" The use of "victim" implies that there was a crime committed. That implies they reported it to the police, as normal people would generally not have their first thought be "Well that's a crime".

I mean I understand where you're coming from, and I have no problem with that, but you're kind of straying from the point and the message by introducing other things.

The sign implies that someone reported a rape and they were attacked for it. That's a completely different issue from people being afraid to report rapes. I completely, 100% disagree with you.  Sexual assault and sexual harassment inherently crimes and inherently have victims, regardless of whether the victims choose to report those crimes to the police.  Things like this are so incredibly prevalent in society that it is *normal* to not report them.  They are crimes men feel *entitled* to commit, and questioning whether the victim "provoked" the crime is the norm.  *That* is the point of the sign, not recording details of the circumstances of the crime once it gets into the justice system.   ... I can see you're clearly not understanding what I'm saying at all.

Would you like to back up for a second and stop assuming I'm trying to attack you so we can actually discuss? :3 Might help a little. I don't think you're attacking me, I think we're interpreting the sign differently.  The sign says, "I need feminism because people still ask what the victim was wearing."  It is my opinion that the intent of the sign is to indicate all victims of sexual harassment or sexual assault.  I agree with you that the police still need to collect information about the circumstances of crimes, especially to identify the individuals involved.  However, that's not the controversial issue that the sign writer was trying to address.  My last comment was an attempt to explain that issue. I guess I'm kind of pickign at smaller issues

I was really just saying that the word most people use to describe it isn't "crime". I just feel that the usage of that word implies that it was reported to police.

But I also realized that really doesn't matter in any significant context and I'm just being stupidly picky xD Sorry I don't think you're attacking me, I think we're interpreting the sign differently.  The sign says, "I need feminism because people still ask what the victim was wearing."  It is my opinion that the intent of the sign is to indicate all victims of sexual harassment or sexual assault.  I agree with you that the police still need to collect information about the circumstances of crimes, especially to identify the individuals involved.  However, that's not the controversial issue that the sign writer was trying to address.  My last comment was an attempt to explain that issue.      </snippet></document><document><title>Well 2X, she's pregnant.  We probably won't keep it.  How can I support her through this? [long]</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ewz9/well_2x_shes_pregnant_we_probably_wont_keep_it/</url><snippet>My wife and I eloped last Friday. Her period was supposed to happen right around our wedding day. It didn't come. She kept thinking it would come any day now, since she'd had some spotting. She picked up a pregnancy test just to ease her mind.

She walked out of the bathroom white as a sheet. I immediately knew I couldn't freak out.

"We're pregnant?" I asked her, seriously.

"I... I didn't think it was really possible."

She walked over to the counter in our kitchen and sat there. She started to cry and tremble. She was totally unprepared for this. I tried to comfort her as best I could. I told her that I loved her no matter what, that we would get through this together, and that no matter what, it would be okay.

She wanted to use the other test in the pack (came with 2), so I got her a glass of water. Her hands were shaking so badly she could barely hold the glass. I made her something to eat since we'd just gotten home and we sat down and ate for about 10 minutes.

I came over to where she was sitting on the couch and rubbed her feet while we talked to try to keep her calm. She told me that she felt like this was the worst possible time. She's in her last semester of graduate school, and there's no way she'd ever get a job if she was pregnant. My income can't support 3. We struggle with just 2 people. She told me she wanted a family, she wanted to have children, but this didn't seem like the right time. She wanted a career too.

I told her that I agreed. She has a fantastic job, a fantastic internship, and her degree is really valuable. I told her that I wanted a family too, but maybe this was the wrong time.

My family has always disliked her, and she started crying again when she thought of when we'd tell them about the pregnancy. My father has made *horrible* comments about her (she's trying to trap you with a baby, she just wants to get married and take all your money, she's low-class trash). I can't even imagine the smug satisfaction they'd put on us if they found out we eloped and she was pregnant. It was just one more thing that upset her.

I want to stand by her, but I don't know what she's going through. She wants us to make this decision together, and she's conflicted about what she wants. She had a miscarriage a few years into our relationship. We had broken up at the time, and she never told me she was pregnant until it happened. She's scared that she's getting older (28) and won't be able to have children. Maybe it will never be a good time start a family and we should just do it?

I would deal with it if she wanted to keep it, but I think this is the worst possible timing for us. I'd get another job, find a better job, something. I'd make it okay. I don't want to tell her what to do with her body. She wants to make the decision together, and since she's of mixed mind and I think we should get an abortion, she's said that she'll probably get the abortion. She doesn't want to "force you into that situation."

I feel horrible. I feel like I've bullied her into giving up her control over her body. I don't want to make the decision for her, and I feel like that's what I'm doing.

She took the second test and it was positive as well. She's going to get an appointment with a doctor ASAP to get a blood test and confirm, then look into appointments with the local women's clinic for an abortion.

I simultaneously want to cry, punch the wall, and hug her. I love her so much, and I want to support her every step of the way. I feel like I don't understand what she's going through. What can I do to help her? What can I do to make her feel supported in this decision?

**tl;dr: Oh shit, she's pregnant. Probably going to get an abortion. How can I support her while we deal with this?**

**Edit:** Thank you everyone for the comments. I really don't think I have the strength right now to respond to everyone, but waking up to this helped a lot. We're going to get through this. I'm just freaking out in my own way.

**Edit 2:** Dropped her off at work. She cried in the car and apparently didn't sleep a wink last night. I spent ten minutes sobbing in my car outside of work once it all caught up to me. Today is off to a stellar start. I feel unimaginably terrible.   ((((hugs))))

Your parents do NOT need to know about your sexual habits, okay?  They do NOT need to know about this.  

You give her hugs.  You tell her that you love her no matter what she decides.  You take her to marriage counseling to improve your communication and so that you can learn how to give her what she needs during this difficult time.

Get the appt now, so you have the time to discuss and process before time runs out on the decision to terminate.  After a session or two, she may decide to keep it.  

Oh, and folks WILL hire women who are pregnant.  - 1 - it's illegal for them to ask if you are pregnant.  2 - some are fine with it.  When I was pregnant, and visibly showing (19 years ago, BTW), I got a job.   

Employment should not be a barrier, as long as you two have good insurance.  

Oh, and tell your dad to butt out or he doesn't get to see the grandbaby. If she is in a science field, there will be active (if illegal) discrimination. With the vast majority of funding coming from grants, many labs don't have the resources to put an employee on maternity leave and then replace them with a temp for however long the leave lasts. If your wife is in a science field, most of the potential employers will see her as a young woman who is going to start a family and not hire her. As a contrast to this,  a large busy lab just gearing up to begin work (new recruit to the University,  large construction project to get them up and running) in my facility just hired a new lab manager who was 8 months pregnant.  She just returned from maternity leave 3 weeks ago.  And they have lots of funding. I'm getting my MS in a science field with the option to turn it into a PhD; and I have been basically told that if I get pregnant, remain unmarried, and until I get past child bearing age, some labs will actively discriminate against me. With most labs short on funding, the only ones who have enough money are the only ones who won't care about me having a family. ((((hugs))))

Your parents do NOT need to know about your sexual habits, okay?  They do NOT need to know about this.  

You give her hugs.  You tell her that you love her no matter what she decides.  You take her to marriage counseling to improve your communication and so that you can learn how to give her what she needs during this difficult time.

Get the appt now, so you have the time to discuss and process before time runs out on the decision to terminate.  After a session or two, she may decide to keep it.  

Oh, and folks WILL hire women who are pregnant.  - 1 - it's illegal for them to ask if you are pregnant.  2 - some are fine with it.  When I was pregnant, and visibly showing (19 years ago, BTW), I got a job.   

Employment should not be a barrier, as long as you two have good insurance.  

Oh, and tell your dad to butt out or he doesn't get to see the grandbaby. This is all true, except it can be difficult to get hired when you're visibly pregnant if your interviewer isn't as impartial as they should be and the job market isn't in your favor.

And whatever she decides, 28 isn't very old. If she wants to wait a few years to start a family, she'll be fine. 35 is the age at which fertility generally declines pretty steeply, and she's got plenty of time to get settled in her new marriage before getting pregnant becomes urgent. 

That doesn't mean that having this baby would be a mistake, because I don't think it sounds like it would. It just means that not having it also wouldn't likely be a mistake. It sounds like from a practicality standpoint it's more or less a toss up, so it becomes a question of what they, specifically she, want to do. I was going to make the point that 28 isn't too old for kids as well. My parents got married at 28 and didn't have me (the oldest) until 32, and my mom was 36 when she had my youngest sister, so there's still time to have a family. Yeah, my mom was 36 when my parents got married, 38 when I, the oldest, was born, and 41 when my brother was born.  I would never recommend waiting that long to have kids if you know you really want biological children because risks do skyrocket around 35, but there's definitely no rush at 28. Just to dispel a bit of a myth here, risks do not 'skyrocket' at 35. 

Your risk of any trisomy(things like Downs, etc) is .2% at age 28.
That same risk goes to .4% at 35.
Most women start to have trouble trying to get pregnant at 40, and your risk then is still only 1.5%. Which means at the tail-end of your fertility, you still have a 98.5% chance of a perfectly normal pregnancy.

Yes, risks are higher the older you are, but when you are talking a half percent vs a 1-1.5%, it's not exactly the scariness people make it out to be. To put it in perspective, most people take a bigger risk with their birth control pill every day :) (1-2% failure rate.) I was going to make the point that 28 isn't too old for kids as well. My parents got married at 28 and didn't have me (the oldest) until 32, and my mom was 36 when she had my youngest sister, so there's still time to have a family.     &amp;gt;I think this is the worst possible timing for us.

That doesn't sound true. You're married, old enough to handle kids, you're employed, she's about to finish graduate school. It's never the "perfect time." If you want it, you can make it happen. She *can* get a job while pregnant, or she can get a job a few months afterwards. 

If neither of you want to continue the pregnancy, that's one thing. But if she's conflicted, then give her time, and think about options rather than problems. It's the worst time because *they don't want it.* That's all that matters.  &amp;gt;I think this is the worst possible timing for us.

That doesn't sound true. You're married, old enough to handle kids, you're employed, she's about to finish graduate school. It's never the "perfect time." If you want it, you can make it happen. She *can* get a job while pregnant, or she can get a job a few months afterwards. 

If neither of you want to continue the pregnancy, that's one thing. But if she's conflicted, then give her time, and think about options rather than problems. He specifically said his income can't support 3 people. That sounds like pretty bad timing. He specifically said his income can't support 3 people. That sounds like pretty bad timing. He specifically said his income can't support 3 people. That sounds like pretty bad timing. It doesn't have to support 3 people long term. Also, babies don't need that much -- a safe place to sleep, food, clothes. Not that much more than 2 people (except for medical care, which admittedly can get expensive). Look at US Census data. On average, a kid costs $13k/year.

However - **OP, if she's about to finish her PhD in the sciences, have her network through her lab to ask about universities/colleges that are family friendly.** As a few other people have said, there are so many babies in my department (chemistry) that it's actually kind of scary. We have *men* in our department who are working half-time to help their wives with their newborn child. If she finds the right work environment, it can be a great experience.

Even if you two decide not to maintain this pregnancy, looking for a family-friendly department is worth it if you two want kids down the road. &amp;gt;Look at US Census data. On average, a kid costs $13k/year.

However, for the first year, it is certainly possible to keep these costs down. If the wife stays home with the baby, no daycare costs (!). (If she gets a job, hey, extra income!). They don't *have* to move to a larger place -- the US Census data attribute ~30% of the kid costs to housing. Those two items eliminate the majority of the child costs, leaving food (breastfeeding is really cheap), clothing (buy second-hand), toys (same), equipment (same), health care (make sure to have insurance, or go on state insurance if possible). 

And yes, ultimately try to find job(s) that are family-friendly. &amp;gt;If the wife stays home with the baby, no daycare costs (!)

I think this has larger financial repercussions over the rest of their lifetimes.  Not a decision to be made lightly.   I got pregnant 3 months after getting married, it was scary for me and I had alot of things to think about, wasn't a good time.. we didn't have alot of money at all and my husband and I were also arguing and not having the best relationship together at that time.. but now my little boy is 3 years old.. my husband and I can't picture our life without him and things fell into place. I'm pregnant with my second now (this baby planned) And I'm so happy with my family.

I'd urge you to think over this. *hugs* for your wife! &amp;lt;3 Not sure why you got downvoted. I was in a similar situation to you. I found out I was pregnant a week after our wedding. I am currently pregnant with #2 (unplanned, but it's ok, we are better off financially now). The OP sounds better off than I was when I got pregnant with my first, and we made it work. If they want the baby, they can find a way. They're mature, employable adults. 

Congrats on your pregnancy! I think people don't like hearing advice where it worked out in the best when keeping a child sometimes.. I don't understand it.. but whatever. I wasn't being rude or bring up a pro-life or pro-choice debate.. I was giving my experiance. And I'm glad you are too. Even though things don't happen at the best time.. and might seem super scary (Which I understand) It can turn out to be a blessing in disguise! &amp;lt;3    [deleted] [deleted] Because there aren't any homeless children out there who nobody wanted to adopt. You're right we should euthanize them like the unwanted dogs and cats that can't get adopted. [deleted] Children are only your greatest contribution to the world if you are a stupid fuck with nothing to contribute. Otherwise there are plenty of better things one can do for the humanity; extinction due to lack of reproduction is right near the very bottom of the list of possible dangers or imperfections we face.</snippet></document><document><title>The president of my college wrote this article for the Huffington Post and while I don't agree with everything she says, I love that my school is run by and filled with women like her who aren't afraid to speak out about women's issues. You go Helen!</title><url>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/helen-drinan/super-bowl_b_2629292.html</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Senate approves anti-violence against women act</title><url>http://www.salon.com/2013/02/12/senate_approves_anti_violence_against_women_act/</url><snippet>   Of course. 22 "no" votes from the ass-backward senators that dislike gender equality. How long will it take a bill like this to pass with no opposition?

Those senators are telling their female constituents that no, they don't deserve to be protected from violence. It's too bad this isn't happening late in an election cycle so that they actually have to explain their regressive votes to people. Of course. 22 "no" votes from the ass-backward senators that dislike gender equality. How long will it take a bill like this to pass with no opposition?

Those senators are telling their female constituents that no, they don't deserve to be protected from violence. It's too bad this isn't happening late in an election cycle so that they actually have to explain their regressive votes to people. &amp;gt;Those senators are telling their female constituents that no, they don't deserve to be protected from violence.

And those other 78 senators are telling their male constituents that yes, women deserve to be protected from violence more than you.  &amp;gt;Those senators are telling their female constituents that no, they don't deserve to be protected from violence.

And those other 78 senators are telling their male constituents that yes, women deserve to be protected from violence more than you. </snippet></document><document><title>Been getting strange responses to telling others I don't want children, more details inside. Any others share my situation? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fkqs/been_getting_strange_responses_to_telling_others/</url><snippet>Whenever I mention to people I don't want children (I don't go around shoving this choice in people's faces, but I'm honest if someone asks me about my future or my present situation/thoughts/feelings), I always get the strangest reactions or comments. Being a woman, I feel like others expect me to want to have kids and be a mother. Nothing against children, or those who have or want them, it's just not in my genes. My SO shares the same feeling on having children, so there's nobody else I have to convince otherwise. Are there any other women who don't want children and get the standard responses of "you'll change your mind...", "but women were born to be mothers..." or my personal favorite, "I'm so sorry you two can't have children..." Does it bother anyone else? It's just been happening a lot more frequently recently, so I thought it would be interesting to get TwoX's perspective! Thanks!  "It's not in my plans right now."

"It's not a topic that interests me."

"I'm sorry, but that's a little too personal for me to feel comfortable discussing."

People who push you for an answer can be - and probably should be - shut down with one of those replies (if you want to end that conversation, that is). 

I could go on about this at length, but long story short is: if you're doing something different from the people you're interacting with, many of those people may think you're weird merely for being different. They lack perspective, empathy, and tolerance for those whose choices are as valid as their own, but at the same time not the same.

It's a waste of your time trying to get them to see your point of view, IMO. Shut down the conversation, move on. I used to get these remarks myself when I was younger. Of course, I wound up eventually having a kid (go figure) but it was certainly not as a result of some judgmental person berating me about not having had a kid yet! "It's not in my plans right now."

"It's not a topic that interests me."

"I'm sorry, but that's a little too personal for me to feel comfortable discussing."

People who push you for an answer can be - and probably should be - shut down with one of those replies (if you want to end that conversation, that is). 

I could go on about this at length, but long story short is: if you're doing something different from the people you're interacting with, many of those people may think you're weird merely for being different. They lack perspective, empathy, and tolerance for those whose choices are as valid as their own, but at the same time not the same.

It's a waste of your time trying to get them to see your point of view, IMO. Shut down the conversation, move on. I used to get these remarks myself when I was younger. Of course, I wound up eventually having a kid (go figure) but it was certainly not as a result of some judgmental person berating me about not having had a kid yet!    Come on over to r/childfree, we know your pain!

If it's happening more frequently, I'm going to guess you're probably getting closer to 30? Personally,I think I had it worst around 28-29, but now it seems it quieted down - though I still gett stupid remarks now and then.

My general strategy is not to engage. if someone tells me I'll change my mind, I just shrug. When people ask me about it, I tell them we have no plans for it at this point.

What's important to remember is that it's none of their business, and you should treat it as such. Do NOT go over to r/childfree unless you HATE children and you HATE mothers and you want to join the immature circlejerk of talking shit on children and mothers. That subreddit is disgusting.  Not everyone there HATES children - there''s a vocal minority that does, and there's a lot of people with a dark sense of humor in regards to kids. There's also a lot of people venting, but thanks for generalizing!  You could check out r/truechildfree . Its a whole little community of people who have decided to not have children.
I think trying to politely change the subject might work if its someone you dont know well. If its family or friends, you might have to do some convincing, but i things will work out if they really trust you and respect your decisions. what's the difference between that one and /r/childfree? You could check out r/truechildfree . Its a whole little community of people who have decided to not have children.
I think trying to politely change the subject might work if its someone you dont know well. If its family or friends, you might have to do some convincing, but i things will work out if they really trust you and respect your decisions.   This is an especially common topic of conversation at my office right now, since half the people I work with are currently pregnant. 

I just state my opinions, and if they give me the "what the hell why not" routine... I just don't care. I'm the one who's in control of whether or not I'm going to have children, not them. They can be as incredulous as they like, but my SO and I are clear on what we want, and that's what's most important.   If I feel like it's a person I can reasonably be snarky to, I do it. "Oh, like (insert parent who murdered their child in a fit of frustration) changed theirs?" Or, as some people have had the audacity to suggest, "but if you got pregnant, then you'd change your mind!" Um, no, and since you've just made me *very* uncomfortable, I'm returning the favor, "Sure is a good thing abortion is legal, because I'm *still* not having kids if I get knocked up." 

As for the I'm sorry one, I generally go with, "We could, but it's just not in the cards right now." Because usually they are trying to be very nice and sympathetic and it just never occurs to parental types that some of us aren't.   I know this situation well. For over half my life now I've been getting that smug smirk and the, "Oh you'll change your mind when you're older" and all that crap. Drives me batshit crazy. My best response is to straight up say, "No, I've felt this way since I was 12 and I'm even more sure about it now (at 27) than I was then. What you're saying is really not applicable."  

Or here's a good one I get occasionally that makes me laugh -  
Them: "But what about your mom, doesn't she want to be a grandma?"  
Me: "Nah, my mom doesn't really like kids." *trying hard to hold a straight face*  

Or the weirdest one yet, coming from a **nurse practitioner at Planned Parenthood** -   
NP: "Something something when you have babies..."  
Me: "I'm not going to ever have children."  
NP: "But...what if you meet the right guy and he wants kids?"  
Me: "Then he's obviously not the right guy."  

It's weird shit I tell you.  Alot of women DO end up changing their minds about wanting children.. I know plenty who have, so I think that's why it's a common response.. I don't think people are trying to be mean or rude with that comment right there.
The other 2 comments though are a bit weird.

I honestly LOVE being a mother. I got married at 21.. got pregnant with my first 3 months after.. and I was scared. But it was the best thing that happend honestly. This little guy who is now 3 changed our life for the better! 
But just because I LOVE being a mother doesn't mean everyone has to.. if you don't want children don't have one. Although, If you end up pregnant ... I'd urge you to choose adoption if you don't want to keep the baby. I don't understand the downvotes you got. A lot of women DO change their mind. There's nothing wrong with that. Just as there is nothing wrong with always knowing you want children or always having known you don't. 
And maybe it just seems novel or interesting to other women? If you don't want to talk about it obviously you shouldn't feel pressured, but maybe these women are genuinely interested in hearing your take on life.  I don't understand the downvotes you got. A lot of women DO change their mind. There's nothing wrong with that. Just as there is nothing wrong with always knowing you want children or always having known you don't. 
And maybe it just seems novel or interesting to other women? If you don't want to talk about it obviously you shouldn't feel pressured, but maybe these women are genuinely interested in hearing your take on life.  Alot of women DO end up changing their minds about wanting children.. I know plenty who have, so I think that's why it's a common response.. I don't think people are trying to be mean or rude with that comment right there.
The other 2 comments though are a bit weird.

I honestly LOVE being a mother. I got married at 21.. got pregnant with my first 3 months after.. and I was scared. But it was the best thing that happend honestly. This little guy who is now 3 changed our life for the better! 
But just because I LOVE being a mother doesn't mean everyone has to.. if you don't want children don't have one. Although, If you end up pregnant ... I'd urge you to choose adoption if you don't want to keep the baby.</snippet></document><document><title>'Lena Dunham, "Girls", Fat-Shaming, and an Honest Male Perspective'</title><url>http://www.pajiba.com/think_pieces/lena-dunham-girls-fatshaming-and-an-honest-male-perspective.php</url><snippet>  As someone who is shaped almost exactly like Lena Dunham (though with bigger boobs, I *think*), I'm so tired of hearing about how shocking/transgressive/disgusting/empowering/sexy/repulsive Lena Dunham's nudity may or may not be.

It's a naked body. It's a naked body that looks a lot like a lot of other bodies, but they're not bodies that are normally seen on TV. That's great. I've had sex with some good-looking guys who were somehow still able to maintain an erection in spite of my non-pilates-toned body. Seeing a fictional character with roughly my same body type pull hot guys onscreen is cool. Seeing Lena Dunham with that cute guy from Fun. in real life is cool. But it's not indicative of a larger cultural shift beyond, like, *Girls* and *The Mindy Project*, because you still have men and women alike saying that Kate Upton is a disgusting fattie.

Medium-sized chick representation is cool, especially because there's very little of it in the medium. But the cultural conversation surrounding it is still gross. Critics love to comment on Dunham's "sloppy" body in a way that they don't talk about, say, Chris Pratt's lack of abs in a *Parks and Rec* review. Does anyone think it's super unrealistic that Chris Pratt has been with both Aubrey Plaza and Rashida Jones in the context of that show? No? Then what makes *Girls* any different?

Ugh, this comment is all over the place. I'm just so tired of this conversation in general. Medium chicks exist. We have bodies that aren't perfect despite our sometimes-best efforts. You don't have to fuck us, but stop commenting on our bodies like they're some sort of public art installation. Yeah, we probably *could* be a lot thinner, but acting as if our bodies are up for public debate and comment until we are is getting super old, regardless of what side you're on. I just find all of it so weird considering *most* of the population doesn't look like underwear models. Seriously, I would love to see the naked bodies of all the people who are upset about it. I mean, come on. Only a small percentage of the human population is "media hot", and yet the rest of us still manage to have orgasms with each other.  There's a huge middle area between underwear model hot and out of shape. Countless men and women at the gym I go to have Hollywood quality bodies, but that doesn't mean they can act. It also doesn't mean they have the facial beauty necessary to be a male or female underwear model.  As someone who is shaped almost exactly like Lena Dunham (though with bigger boobs, I *think*), I'm so tired of hearing about how shocking/transgressive/disgusting/empowering/sexy/repulsive Lena Dunham's nudity may or may not be.

It's a naked body. It's a naked body that looks a lot like a lot of other bodies, but they're not bodies that are normally seen on TV. That's great. I've had sex with some good-looking guys who were somehow still able to maintain an erection in spite of my non-pilates-toned body. Seeing a fictional character with roughly my same body type pull hot guys onscreen is cool. Seeing Lena Dunham with that cute guy from Fun. in real life is cool. But it's not indicative of a larger cultural shift beyond, like, *Girls* and *The Mindy Project*, because you still have men and women alike saying that Kate Upton is a disgusting fattie.

Medium-sized chick representation is cool, especially because there's very little of it in the medium. But the cultural conversation surrounding it is still gross. Critics love to comment on Dunham's "sloppy" body in a way that they don't talk about, say, Chris Pratt's lack of abs in a *Parks and Rec* review. Does anyone think it's super unrealistic that Chris Pratt has been with both Aubrey Plaza and Rashida Jones in the context of that show? No? Then what makes *Girls* any different?

Ugh, this comment is all over the place. I'm just so tired of this conversation in general. Medium chicks exist. We have bodies that aren't perfect despite our sometimes-best efforts. You don't have to fuck us, but stop commenting on our bodies like they're some sort of public art installation. Yeah, we probably *could* be a lot thinner, but acting as if our bodies are up for public debate and comment until we are is getting super old, regardless of what side you're on. As someone who is shaped almost exactly like Lena Dunham (though with bigger boobs, I *think*), I'm so tired of hearing about how shocking/transgressive/disgusting/empowering/sexy/repulsive Lena Dunham's nudity may or may not be.

It's a naked body. It's a naked body that looks a lot like a lot of other bodies, but they're not bodies that are normally seen on TV. That's great. I've had sex with some good-looking guys who were somehow still able to maintain an erection in spite of my non-pilates-toned body. Seeing a fictional character with roughly my same body type pull hot guys onscreen is cool. Seeing Lena Dunham with that cute guy from Fun. in real life is cool. But it's not indicative of a larger cultural shift beyond, like, *Girls* and *The Mindy Project*, because you still have men and women alike saying that Kate Upton is a disgusting fattie.

Medium-sized chick representation is cool, especially because there's very little of it in the medium. But the cultural conversation surrounding it is still gross. Critics love to comment on Dunham's "sloppy" body in a way that they don't talk about, say, Chris Pratt's lack of abs in a *Parks and Rec* review. Does anyone think it's super unrealistic that Chris Pratt has been with both Aubrey Plaza and Rashida Jones in the context of that show? No? Then what makes *Girls* any different?

Ugh, this comment is all over the place. I'm just so tired of this conversation in general. Medium chicks exist. We have bodies that aren't perfect despite our sometimes-best efforts. You don't have to fuck us, but stop commenting on our bodies like they're some sort of public art installation. Yeah, we probably *could* be a lot thinner, but acting as if our bodies are up for public debate and comment until we are is getting super old, regardless of what side you're on. As someone who is shaped almost exactly like Lena Dunham (though with bigger boobs, I *think*), I'm so tired of hearing about how shocking/transgressive/disgusting/empowering/sexy/repulsive Lena Dunham's nudity may or may not be.

It's a naked body. It's a naked body that looks a lot like a lot of other bodies, but they're not bodies that are normally seen on TV. That's great. I've had sex with some good-looking guys who were somehow still able to maintain an erection in spite of my non-pilates-toned body. Seeing a fictional character with roughly my same body type pull hot guys onscreen is cool. Seeing Lena Dunham with that cute guy from Fun. in real life is cool. But it's not indicative of a larger cultural shift beyond, like, *Girls* and *The Mindy Project*, because you still have men and women alike saying that Kate Upton is a disgusting fattie.

Medium-sized chick representation is cool, especially because there's very little of it in the medium. But the cultural conversation surrounding it is still gross. Critics love to comment on Dunham's "sloppy" body in a way that they don't talk about, say, Chris Pratt's lack of abs in a *Parks and Rec* review. Does anyone think it's super unrealistic that Chris Pratt has been with both Aubrey Plaza and Rashida Jones in the context of that show? No? Then what makes *Girls* any different?

Ugh, this comment is all over the place. I'm just so tired of this conversation in general. Medium chicks exist. We have bodies that aren't perfect despite our sometimes-best efforts. You don't have to fuck us, but stop commenting on our bodies like they're some sort of public art installation. Yeah, we probably *could* be a lot thinner, but acting as if our bodies are up for public debate and comment until we are is getting super old, regardless of what side you're on. 

This Chris Pratt? The badass Special Forces guy from Zero Dark Thirty? 

http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/chris-pratt-reveals-six-pack-abs-for-zero-dark-thirty-60-pound-weight-gain-for-starbuck-20121912

Sounds like he had to gain a bunch of weight for a different role. He had to get real flabby for some comedy movie he filmed after Zero Dark Thirty and now he's going to have to get super buff and lean for some movie where he's playing a super hero. 

Sounds a lot like the extreme body changes Christian Bale has had to go through to get his body to fit the various roles he plays. He got himself down to an extremely anorexic weight for The Machinist and back up to a ripped superhero in the span of a year. The guy is insane, but incredibly dedicated. 

http://celebrityweightloss24.com/christian-bale-weight-loss/
 He does the buff-for-one-movie thing on occasion, but [this is what he looks like](http://www.nypost.com/rw/nypost/2009/06/22/pagesix/photos_galleries/G3304_photo04.jpg) normally. He's on the upper end of average, I'd say, but in both fiction and real life, he's always got a gorgeous woman on his arm (married to Anna Faris in real life!). That was just the first example of a male correlary to Dunham - all the Jonah Hill/Kevin James comparisons aren't really that true, because she's not obese and never has been; she's just not *thin*.  The only pictures that come up on Google that make him look not so flattering are those couple pictures where he's wearing the silly American flag boxers.

Jonah Hill hasn't really been overweight for a while now, and I don't think Kevin James is quite obese. At least not currently. He's definitely overweight though. 

 As someone who is shaped almost exactly like Lena Dunham (though with bigger boobs, I *think*), I'm so tired of hearing about how shocking/transgressive/disgusting/empowering/sexy/repulsive Lena Dunham's nudity may or may not be.

It's a naked body. It's a naked body that looks a lot like a lot of other bodies, but they're not bodies that are normally seen on TV. That's great. I've had sex with some good-looking guys who were somehow still able to maintain an erection in spite of my non-pilates-toned body. Seeing a fictional character with roughly my same body type pull hot guys onscreen is cool. Seeing Lena Dunham with that cute guy from Fun. in real life is cool. But it's not indicative of a larger cultural shift beyond, like, *Girls* and *The Mindy Project*, because you still have men and women alike saying that Kate Upton is a disgusting fattie.

Medium-sized chick representation is cool, especially because there's very little of it in the medium. But the cultural conversation surrounding it is still gross. Critics love to comment on Dunham's "sloppy" body in a way that they don't talk about, say, Chris Pratt's lack of abs in a *Parks and Rec* review. Does anyone think it's super unrealistic that Chris Pratt has been with both Aubrey Plaza and Rashida Jones in the context of that show? No? Then what makes *Girls* any different?

Ugh, this comment is all over the place. I'm just so tired of this conversation in general. Medium chicks exist. We have bodies that aren't perfect despite our sometimes-best efforts. You don't have to fuck us, but stop commenting on our bodies like they're some sort of public art installation. Yeah, we probably *could* be a lot thinner, but acting as if our bodies are up for public debate and comment until we are is getting super old, regardless of what side you're on. Lena Dunham looks like a short smaller boobed version of me naked. I see her and see my self. 

The discussion around her body, naked and clothed, is the more moronic discussions society is having however it does reflect on society that we need to have it.  

I dislike Lena character on the show because I think she is a bit of a dick who wears horrible rompers or fake rompers.  Lena Dunham looks like a short smaller boobed version of me naked. I see her and see my self. 

The discussion around her body, naked and clothed, is the more moronic discussions society is having however it does reflect on society that we need to have it.  

I dislike Lena character on the show because I think she is a bit of a dick who wears horrible rompers or fake rompers.   I have to say that I love when I see women on TV who aren't a certain 'type' of woman. There's nothing wrong with looking beautiful in the 'traditional' way, and it doesn't mean you aren't a real woman, but when that's all you see it can be really depressing (not to mention that those women are generally hopelessly touched up, so they look nothing like they do in real life.) When I watch a show like Girls and see women who look different, it just feels... good. It's like "Hey. Hey wait. Oh. You look familiar." It's not even that she looks like me, so much as... she looks real. She's not been 'fixed' or altered, she just looks the way she looks, and she's alright with that. It makes me feel like I could do something like that, that I could be successful, even if I don't look a certain way. It gives me hope that, even if other people don't like the way I look, I can, and I don't have to make excuses. I can just be me. 

It's kind of like this. Let's say blue eyes were favored on TV, and almost every actor and actress you see has them. They're seen as incredibly beautiful, and you begin to wish you were born with them. And then you see this one actor with brown eyes, up there with the rest, doing the same thing as everyone else. They're just as successful, just as talented... and they look like you. It doesn't mean you think blue eyes are unnatural, or ugly; it just means that seeing someone who's like you gives you some validation, and makes you feel just a little better about the way you look. When all you see is women shaped a certain way, who act a certain way, who are pretty in a certain way- it messes with your head. 

No, this sort of thing shouldn't have to be an issue. But it is, and this is a win for our culture, even if it's a very small one.  You make a fine point and remind me of a conversation that i've had not too long ago on the subject. The general idea we got to was that actors not being genetic freaks of nature styled to within an inch of their lives helps realism. 

Just look at a show like Switched at Birth. I think it's a decent show, but there are times when the fact that even the extras are well above average in beauty takes me out of the moment. It comes off very unreal and unnatural. 

and while i'm rambling...do none of these people ever have a sweat pants day!?!? geesh. You make a fine point and remind me of a conversation that i've had not too long ago on the subject. The general idea we got to was that actors not being genetic freaks of nature styled to within an inch of their lives helps realism. 

Just look at a show like Switched at Birth. I think it's a decent show, but there are times when the fact that even the extras are well above average in beauty takes me out of the moment. It comes off very unreal and unnatural. 

and while i'm rambling...do none of these people ever have a sweat pants day!?!? geesh. An ever better question- why do they never have a sweatpants day that isn't runway-ready?  I have to say that I love when I see women on TV who aren't a certain 'type' of woman. There's nothing wrong with looking beautiful in the 'traditional' way, and it doesn't mean you aren't a real woman, but when that's all you see it can be really depressing (not to mention that those women are generally hopelessly touched up, so they look nothing like they do in real life.) When I watch a show like Girls and see women who look different, it just feels... good. It's like "Hey. Hey wait. Oh. You look familiar." It's not even that she looks like me, so much as... she looks real. She's not been 'fixed' or altered, she just looks the way she looks, and she's alright with that. It makes me feel like I could do something like that, that I could be successful, even if I don't look a certain way. It gives me hope that, even if other people don't like the way I look, I can, and I don't have to make excuses. I can just be me. 

It's kind of like this. Let's say blue eyes were favored on TV, and almost every actor and actress you see has them. They're seen as incredibly beautiful, and you begin to wish you were born with them. And then you see this one actor with brown eyes, up there with the rest, doing the same thing as everyone else. They're just as successful, just as talented... and they look like you. It doesn't mean you think blue eyes are unnatural, or ugly; it just means that seeing someone who's like you gives you some validation, and makes you feel just a little better about the way you look. When all you see is women shaped a certain way, who act a certain way, who are pretty in a certain way- it messes with your head. 

No, this sort of thing shouldn't have to be an issue. But it is, and this is a win for our culture, even if it's a very small one.  I have to say that I love when I see women on TV who aren't a certain 'type' of woman. There's nothing wrong with looking beautiful in the 'traditional' way, and it doesn't mean you aren't a real woman, but when that's all you see it can be really depressing (not to mention that those women are generally hopelessly touched up, so they look nothing like they do in real life.) When I watch a show like Girls and see women who look different, it just feels... good. It's like "Hey. Hey wait. Oh. You look familiar." It's not even that she looks like me, so much as... she looks real. She's not been 'fixed' or altered, she just looks the way she looks, and she's alright with that. It makes me feel like I could do something like that, that I could be successful, even if I don't look a certain way. It gives me hope that, even if other people don't like the way I look, I can, and I don't have to make excuses. I can just be me. 

It's kind of like this. Let's say blue eyes were favored on TV, and almost every actor and actress you see has them. They're seen as incredibly beautiful, and you begin to wish you were born with them. And then you see this one actor with brown eyes, up there with the rest, doing the same thing as everyone else. They're just as successful, just as talented... and they look like you. It doesn't mean you think blue eyes are unnatural, or ugly; it just means that seeing someone who's like you gives you some validation, and makes you feel just a little better about the way you look. When all you see is women shaped a certain way, who act a certain way, who are pretty in a certain way- it messes with your head. 

No, this sort of thing shouldn't have to be an issue. But it is, and this is a win for our culture, even if it's a very small one.   Just the other day I saw [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/18a3d0/the_official_grammy_discussion/c8d2phx?context=3) response made at the very *mention* of Lena Dunham. Its just unimaginable to me how so many people can just absolutely despise a woman who directs, writes, produces, and stars in her own show, just because she fails to measure up to the absolutely insane body standards that Hollywood sets on women. This article is refreshing to read. For once, someone decided to take a look as to *why* they feel uncomfortable by Dunham's nudity as opposed to just pushing it aside and shouting "EWWWW GROSS." The body shaming toward Lena Dunham is disgusting, but that isn't the only reason she's criticized. Mostly she's attacked for basically ignoring WoC/LGBTQ women in her show that is being hailed as some sort of feminist beacon. Which is a very valid and necessary critique, seeing as she has all this creative control over the show. If she's writing about her own thoughts, experiences and ideas why is she responsible for writing on certain topics at all especially topics she may not have any concrete feelings or ideas about? I don't quite understand why we shoulder her with these duties to try and represent every type of woman out there; it seems terribly unfair. 

I can understand why some are frustrated, but if a guy her age wrote about his life experiences and friends I don't believe we would berate him for not covering all bases. As an artist, it simply is not her responsibility to write about what we want her to write about. She is her own person.   If she's writing about her own thoughts, experiences and ideas why is she responsible for writing on certain topics at all especially topics she may not have any concrete feelings or ideas about? I don't quite understand why we shoulder her with these duties to try and represent every type of woman out there; it seems terribly unfair. 

I can understand why some are frustrated, but if a guy her age wrote about his life experiences and friends I don't believe we would berate him for not covering all bases. As an artist, it simply is not her responsibility to write about what we want her to write about. She is her own person.   The body shaming toward Lena Dunham is disgusting, but that isn't the only reason she's criticized. Mostly she's attacked for basically ignoring WoC/LGBTQ women in her show that is being hailed as some sort of feminist beacon. Which is a very valid and necessary critique, seeing as she has all this creative control over the show. The body shaming toward Lena Dunham is disgusting, but that isn't the only reason she's criticized. Mostly she's attacked for basically ignoring WoC/LGBTQ women in her show that is being hailed as some sort of feminist beacon. Which is a very valid and necessary critique, seeing as she has all this creative control over the show. Just the other day I saw [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/18a3d0/the_official_grammy_discussion/c8d2phx?context=3) response made at the very *mention* of Lena Dunham. Its just unimaginable to me how so many people can just absolutely despise a woman who directs, writes, produces, and stars in her own show, just because she fails to measure up to the absolutely insane body standards that Hollywood sets on women. This article is refreshing to read. For once, someone decided to take a look as to *why* they feel uncomfortable by Dunham's nudity as opposed to just pushing it aside and shouting "EWWWW GROSS."  I love GIRLS and I look forward to watching the show every week. But you know what? I find Hannah to be an absolutely repulsive character. And I got to admit, I'm little bit irked (though not necessarily with Dunham) that the first "average" bodied female character, whose sexuality *and* nudity (not mutually exclusive) is regularly exposed to a regular cable audience, is such and unbelievably dislikable "person"!!! 

You want folks to stop associating body mass with quality of character? Don't produce more and more mediums that fosters and reinforces those cognitive associations that are already *constantly* drilled into our brains. Now, one of my friends asked me, "Well, do you really think it's Dunham's responsibility to make Hannah be likable all because people have skewed body-type prejudices?" And to that I say this: No, I don't think she has a duty to make Hannah likable. In reality, Dunham is doing no worse and no better for the average woman *as far as social perceptions* are concerned than any other show/movie. At the most, she's giving exposure to a body type that isn't often seen (which is good) and bringing attention to the fact that all sorts of guys are into all sorts of girls (which is also good/true). And at the worst, she is reinforcing some folks' notions that average bodied women are disgusting slobs with questionable morals and ethics. To me the show ultimately balances itself out, but this line of questioning misses the point: people may be critical of Hannah for whatever reason, but the numbers don't lie: GIRLS is a hit. 

What that tells me is that people can and WILL watch shows here in America that don't only cast etherial beauties. *Roseanne* was another major hit (#1 show in all of America for 1989 and 1990; and repeated top 5 show for the remaining seasons) , though the characters are a little less average (body type wise) and a bit more robust; but it has been nearly two decades between *Roseanne* and GIRLS, with only movies like *My Big Fat Greek Wedding* and *Bridget Jones Diary* giving major screen time to the average sized body. I'll save my critique of using comedy in ALL of those aforementioned examples, but I just think that the paucity of media depicting "average" bodied women, despite obvious succe$$ in ratings and box-office sales in the my examples, is inexplicable.

Woah, this rant was all over the board...But I guess the **Tl;dr** is this: I hate Hannah because of her character; and I'm a little bit worried about having this seemingly seminal but really dislikable character associated with the average body type; but I am even MORE worried about the strange lack of additional media with *more* average bodied women despite the successes of films/shows that have had "average" looking women. 

Edit: I shouldn't rant so quickly; lots of typos.  you kind of touched on my general opinion of the show... I couldn't care less about Dunham's body, what I care about is how selfish and childlike her character (in both Tiny Furniture and Girls) is. That is what bothers me about the show and about all the glory going to her for the show. I just am constantly having a back and forth battle with myself over not being able to watch someone behave like that and still being interested in the show. My two cents will probably be either ignored or called out but regardless it's off my chest now.  Super fast edit: I honestly only read your tldr :/  you kind of touched on my general opinion of the show... I couldn't care less about Dunham's body, what I care about is how selfish and childlike her character (in both Tiny Furniture and Girls) is. That is what bothers me about the show and about all the glory going to her for the show. I just am constantly having a back and forth battle with myself over not being able to watch someone behave like that and still being interested in the show. My two cents will probably be either ignored or called out but regardless it's off my chest now.  Super fast edit: I honestly only read your tldr :/  you kind of touched on my general opinion of the show... I couldn't care less about Dunham's body, what I care about is how selfish and childlike her character (in both Tiny Furniture and Girls) is. That is what bothers me about the show and about all the glory going to her for the show. I just am constantly having a back and forth battle with myself over not being able to watch someone behave like that and still being interested in the show. My two cents will probably be either ignored or called out but regardless it's off my chest now.  Super fast edit: I honestly only read your tldr :/  I love GIRLS and I look forward to watching the show every week. But you know what? I find Hannah to be an absolutely repulsive character. And I got to admit, I'm little bit irked (though not necessarily with Dunham) that the first "average" bodied female character, whose sexuality *and* nudity (not mutually exclusive) is regularly exposed to a regular cable audience, is such and unbelievably dislikable "person"!!! 

You want folks to stop associating body mass with quality of character? Don't produce more and more mediums that fosters and reinforces those cognitive associations that are already *constantly* drilled into our brains. Now, one of my friends asked me, "Well, do you really think it's Dunham's responsibility to make Hannah be likable all because people have skewed body-type prejudices?" And to that I say this: No, I don't think she has a duty to make Hannah likable. In reality, Dunham is doing no worse and no better for the average woman *as far as social perceptions* are concerned than any other show/movie. At the most, she's giving exposure to a body type that isn't often seen (which is good) and bringing attention to the fact that all sorts of guys are into all sorts of girls (which is also good/true). And at the worst, she is reinforcing some folks' notions that average bodied women are disgusting slobs with questionable morals and ethics. To me the show ultimately balances itself out, but this line of questioning misses the point: people may be critical of Hannah for whatever reason, but the numbers don't lie: GIRLS is a hit. 

What that tells me is that people can and WILL watch shows here in America that don't only cast etherial beauties. *Roseanne* was another major hit (#1 show in all of America for 1989 and 1990; and repeated top 5 show for the remaining seasons) , though the characters are a little less average (body type wise) and a bit more robust; but it has been nearly two decades between *Roseanne* and GIRLS, with only movies like *My Big Fat Greek Wedding* and *Bridget Jones Diary* giving major screen time to the average sized body. I'll save my critique of using comedy in ALL of those aforementioned examples, but I just think that the paucity of media depicting "average" bodied women, despite obvious succe$$ in ratings and box-office sales in the my examples, is inexplicable.

Woah, this rant was all over the board...But I guess the **Tl;dr** is this: I hate Hannah because of her character; and I'm a little bit worried about having this seemingly seminal but really dislikable character associated with the average body type; but I am even MORE worried about the strange lack of additional media with *more* average bodied women despite the successes of films/shows that have had "average" looking women. 

Edit: I shouldn't rant so quickly; lots of typos.  &amp;gt; I find Hannah to be an absolutely repulsive character. 

I watched one episode of that show to see what all the fuss was about, and I found every character repulsive.  I suppose the show appeals the road-accident rubbernecking impulse. I love GIRLS and I look forward to watching the show every week. But you know what? I find Hannah to be an absolutely repulsive character. And I got to admit, I'm little bit irked (though not necessarily with Dunham) that the first "average" bodied female character, whose sexuality *and* nudity (not mutually exclusive) is regularly exposed to a regular cable audience, is such and unbelievably dislikable "person"!!! 

You want folks to stop associating body mass with quality of character? Don't produce more and more mediums that fosters and reinforces those cognitive associations that are already *constantly* drilled into our brains. Now, one of my friends asked me, "Well, do you really think it's Dunham's responsibility to make Hannah be likable all because people have skewed body-type prejudices?" And to that I say this: No, I don't think she has a duty to make Hannah likable. In reality, Dunham is doing no worse and no better for the average woman *as far as social perceptions* are concerned than any other show/movie. At the most, she's giving exposure to a body type that isn't often seen (which is good) and bringing attention to the fact that all sorts of guys are into all sorts of girls (which is also good/true). And at the worst, she is reinforcing some folks' notions that average bodied women are disgusting slobs with questionable morals and ethics. To me the show ultimately balances itself out, but this line of questioning misses the point: people may be critical of Hannah for whatever reason, but the numbers don't lie: GIRLS is a hit. 

What that tells me is that people can and WILL watch shows here in America that don't only cast etherial beauties. *Roseanne* was another major hit (#1 show in all of America for 1989 and 1990; and repeated top 5 show for the remaining seasons) , though the characters are a little less average (body type wise) and a bit more robust; but it has been nearly two decades between *Roseanne* and GIRLS, with only movies like *My Big Fat Greek Wedding* and *Bridget Jones Diary* giving major screen time to the average sized body. I'll save my critique of using comedy in ALL of those aforementioned examples, but I just think that the paucity of media depicting "average" bodied women, despite obvious succe$$ in ratings and box-office sales in the my examples, is inexplicable.

Woah, this rant was all over the board...But I guess the **Tl;dr** is this: I hate Hannah because of her character; and I'm a little bit worried about having this seemingly seminal but really dislikable character associated with the average body type; but I am even MORE worried about the strange lack of additional media with *more* average bodied women despite the successes of films/shows that have had "average" looking women. 

Edit: I shouldn't rant so quickly; lots of typos.  Disclaimer: I haven't exactly watched *Girls*. I've seen clips and that's all. But the general topic is one that I've considered many times.

On other shows and in other movies, average/bigger women and even women in general being portrayed as unlikeable assholes always make me go back and forth with myself. On the one hand, having all people of a certain size/shape/color/gender portrayed as awesome bad asses seems amazing, but it's just not realistic, though of course all shapes/sizes/colors/and genders should be represented in the realm of badassery. The problem is not that Lena Dunham has chose to make shows about characters who are childish and awful or even that she's chosen to portray those characters herself. The problem is that the media overall doesn't portray that size woman at all and so when the characters of that type that do exist happen to be awful people, we turn around and blame the creators.

The reality is that there is no one person to blame for that phenomenon. There's an overall industry, but we can't place all the blame on the individuals, and we certainly can't blame the Lena Dunham's for wanting to portray people who are terribly flawed which makes for great entertainment. It wouldn't be better if the awful characters were the thin Hollywood beauties. 

Edited for clarity. Well said! Though I want to be clear that I am not intending to criticize/condemn Dunham for the character she's created. I have a lot of issues regarding the topic of GIRLS haha, and it all came out in a very hasty outpouring. Someday, sometime, I'll get my shit together and organize my thoughts better. 

I do want to address this though: 

&amp;gt; having all people of a certain size/shape/color/gender portrayed as awesome bad asses seems amazing, but it's just not realistic.

I just don't know (and perhaps is the biggest source of frustration) exactly why this can't be a more realistic expectation considering how it hasn't been proven that including more variety in appearances in actors reduces ratings/sales. If anything, I'd hazard to say that it may draw in more people because it makes it more relatable. 

Maybe it's our escapist mentality regarding film? Maybe America is more fond of this concept than other places? I mean, when I first began watching BBC shows, I was stunned with how "ordinary" many of the leading actors looked regardless of the genre of show I was watching. Blemished skin, slightly crooked teeth, static-hair; the "realness" of it all made it an almost surreal experience for me! haha I've since gotten over it, but now I just look at our shows and I wonder...why? 

Is it cowardly producers? Talent agencies? Fine art schools? I don't think it's safe to generalize to "society" being the problem anymore. But I do think we can narrow it down. But I don't know where exactly since the entertainment industry is not anywhere close to me knowledge base.  I think maybe what I meant by that isn't what you read. I meant that it seems like it would be awesome if every single black character on TV was some amazing stereotype-busting badass. But how realistic is it to have no black "bad guys"? If every female character was an amazing scientist or businesswoman who kicked ass and took names on a daily basis, how well would that reflect our diverse reality where women, like all other groups of people, range from petty and selfish and manipulative to deep and generous and honest, and boxing female characters into a narrow moral box is no more realistic than boxing them into a narrow physical box.

I didn't mean that bad asses of all genders and races shouldn't exist, just that not everyone of any given gender or race should be represented as a bad ass. I think we keep missing each other here. 

I think I get what you are saying now, and I agree that boxing people into a moral/physical box is unrealistic. And that's certainly not what I'd propose. Rather, I generally I simply want to see *more* variety in body types represented in TV shows/Movies in America. Hence, why I'm not annoyed with Dunham for the character she created. The qualities Hannah has are very real and there is no reason an average sized woman can't be unlikeable and self-centered. I am mere confused/baffled by general absence of average body types in media. 

To pull this all together, my issue with Hannah and whatever part that character's existence may play in reinforcing negative stereotype is *really*, *really* minimal. My bigger issue is the general lack of variety in appearance in TV/movie actors in America, and I can't put my finger as *why* that's the case.    I love the article, and 'Girls' is great, but I as a queer woman of color, all I can think when I watch the show is, "White girls... white girls everywhere..."

The show needs to do a better job of representing queer women and women of color, if it wants to be taken seriously as a well-rounded show about women. I agree with you that people of color are *so* underrepresented on TV (especially in TV shows set in New York, in my experience--*Friends*, *Seinfeld*, and *Sex and the City* all come to mind), but I sympathize with Lena when she says in [this interview](http://www.npr.org/2012/05/07/152183865/lena-dunham-addresses-criticism-aimed-at-girls) that she wanted to avoid tokenism and it's hard/risky for her to write to the experience of what she doesn't know (being a woman of color or queer). 

Also, what do you mean by "well-rounded"? *Girls* seems so far from a "well-rounded representation of women" to me. All the characters lead very privileged lives compared to the average, even though they aren't living in the glamorized fantasy of *Sex and the City.* Every female lead on the show is the product of an elite education (Shosh attends NYU, the others went to Oberlin); there's no diversity in age (all young to mid-20s); they're all living in New York... seems like a very narrow representation of a small subset of women to me, and one that a large percentage of the female population can't relate to. My mom watched the show with me over break, and while I could relate to a lot of the situations shown (especially the romantic entanglements), she was like, "*This* is what your generation's dating culture is like? Totally different from when I was young!" and really couldn't connect with the characters at all. Also, even in a place as diverse as New York, I'm sure there are plenty of privileged white women who don't have any non-white friends, especially when (like the characters of *Girls*) they don't seem to have worked to expand their social circle much since college.

Also, since the show gets compared to *Sex and the City* all the time, I have to say that *Girls*' characters aren't as universally sympathetic as Carrie and company. My friends have spent hours analyzing which *Sex and the City* character each person in the group is ("I'm Charlotte!" "I *am* Miranda" etc.), but they don't really do this with *Girls* because Hannah, Marnie, and Jessa aren't nearly as easy to project yourself onto (Shosh is the most relatable for most people I've talked to, but she doesn't get as many scenes as the others). Their behavior is sometimes (frequently?) alienating to the audience. I think the way the lead characters are all kind of train wrecks also prevents the show from being "well-rounded" in my view, because it's so one-note on this score: all the girls of the group are messes! Of course, that's deliberate. Lena has talked about how she wants to show how people are frequently just trying to figure things out in their twenties. I love the article, and 'Girls' is great, but I as a queer woman of color, all I can think when I watch the show is, "White girls... white girls everywhere..."

The show needs to do a better job of representing queer women and women of color, if it wants to be taken seriously as a well-rounded show about women. I love the article, and 'Girls' is great, but I as a queer woman of color, all I can think when I watch the show is, "White girls... white girls everywhere..."

The show needs to do a better job of representing queer women and women of color, if it wants to be taken seriously as a well-rounded show about women. I think that that is actually the point of the show.   Its not supposed to be a well-rounded show about women.  Its a show about a small niche of terrible, young people.

I was born and raised in New York, my sister has lived in Brooklyn for about 10 years.  There are many, many self-involved, MidWestern transplants who love Rent and Sex and the City and think theyre SO cosmopolitan and worldly and dont and wouldnt know a single person of color.  I don't like her and wish she'd stop talking about herself already. We get it you're a bigger girl on tv and you just gotta be naked. 

The show sucks. The acting is awful. The writing is a joke and the the humor is so forced its painful. IMHO it's fun to watch like Jerry Springer or other train wrecks, on a meta-level. I watched the first season hoping it was going to get better, it didn't. Probably doesn't help that her character is the most insufferable and annoying on that show. She doesn't make me feel anything but the need to punch her in the face.  Have you ever watched the show Enlightenment? It's a bit similar.  *Girls* is good at portraying realistic body types if you are white, I guess. Still bothers me that there are no women of color in the show. That's a major flaw. There also aren't any women amputees, blind women, or women with dwarfism on the show. Are those major flaws? Not every show has to speak to every person's experiences; it's not Lena Dunham's fault that there aren't enough shows out there with protagonists who are women of colour. Why are so many people so quick to make excuses for this? Yes, the fact that there is not a single non-white woman in a show that is supposed to be for women, that is a major flaw. Keep justifying Lena Dunham's (be it unintentional or not) racism, if you want. Why are you dodging the question? Why is it not a problem that she has no female little people on the show? I'm not "dodging the question" I just don't think it's worth wasting my time explaining this to someone who obviously doesn't give a shit about portrayal of women of color in the media.

It would be better if Girls had more diverse body types of women in other ways. If there was a woman with Dwarfism in the show, that would be awesome.

Your argument was literally, "Well, no other TV shows care about having women of color in them, so why should Lena Dunham?" That bears no resemblance to my argument at all; you need to work on your reading comprehension. I said that, while women of colour do not get enough representation in the media, that isn't Lena Dunham's fault, and she isn't obligated to have a character for every underrepresented group on the planet. Again, you're just saying, because no one else has done it, Dunham has no obligation to do it. That's essentially what your "it's not her fault argument" boils down to. Is it any one individual person's fault that women of color and other minority groups are underrepresented on the whole? Of course not, but every individual working in the field that refuses to acknowledge the existence of minorities within their work bears some of the burden for contributing to the status quo, so yes, even though it is obviously not ALL Dunham's fault, she is at fault for contributing to the culture.      </snippet></document><document><title>Chivalry is NOT dead! I met two Knights while trying to clear off my car!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fnzl/chivalry_is_not_dead_i_met_two_knights_while/</url><snippet>I live in the Northeast and I attend a small university that got hit pretty hard with snow during Nemo. During the weekend, I had dug out my little Beetle with the help of a friend and lo and behold, by Monday it was covered again. I had to move the car in order for the school plows to be able to clear out all of the snow in the parking lot. I was pretty upset because my friend was gone and I couldn't borrow his shovel. Then I hear a yell from across the parking lot, asking if I need help. I said yes gratefully and a guy cut across the lot to help, yelling back to his friend to come over when he was done. I asked him where he lived and he told me that he was from another area on campus. The girls in his building were sick and he and his friend decided to move their cars for them. Then, seeing that so many people were stuck in the lot without shovels, they went back to their rooms and got all the necessary tools to help dig out all of the cars. Honestly TwoX, I couldn't believe it. Their building was at least half a mile away from the lot and by the time they got to move the girls cars, the lots we had to move our cars to were full. They must have had to walk at least 3 miles to get all of the cars moved safely. Not only did this guy dig me out, but he made sure that I could get out of my spot safely and kept cars from coming down the unplowed lane so they wouldn't hit me. 

The best part? When I said "Wow, I guess chivalry really isn't dead." He replied, "No it's not. And I'm going to make sure it doesn't die."


tl;dr Two guardian angels helped me, and at least 10 cars escape from a wintry trap. In the process, warmed my heart and restored some faith in humanity.

edit: I feel like some of you are taking this the wrong way. These men were sweet and offered to help people of both sexes, it just caught my attention that they were so quick to help the girls on their floor that they didn't know that well. Maybe I could have scrapped the label of "chivalry", but I thought these guys deserved some recognition for it.  It is my opinion that chivalry should die and be replaced with common human decency. But in this story, I guess that's just semantics. I agree the semantics should change. The idea behind chivalry is benevolent sexism where its the idea you have to help a woman out because she needs that help.  Yes. Would they have offered to help any guy's cars? Yes. Would they have offered to help any guy's cars? It is my opinion that chivalry should die and be replaced with common human decency. But in this story, I guess that's just semantics.   </snippet></document><document><title>Hair removal advice for a hairy breasts/butt girl</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fin0/hair_removal_advice_for_a_hairy_breastsbutt_girl/</url><snippet>Anyone here willing to share their tips? I dont think I have hirutism , I have fine black hairs (alot of them) on my entire breast, some trapped under the skin I am assuming because of my KP.

I also have KP on my butt and sometimes get ingrown hairs there which suck.

The hairs are fine, and I am a light-medium complexion naturally so I am not sure if laser would work on my breasts and dont want to spend money I dont have just in case.

So if your feeling brave to admit if you have my problems too and how you fixed it, it would be great!  i have heard good things about sugaring. hoping to try it soon. you can go to a salon or get a h i have heard good things about sugaring. hoping to try it soon. you can go to a salon or get a h Be careful of sugar waxing.  I had heard it was the best for hair removal.  Unfortunately I chose to get a brazillian sugar wax.  Worst mistake of my life.  SO much more painful and unsuccessful than a typical hot wax, and that was from a professional who had definitely been doing this for 5-10+ years.  I'm sure it's NBD on eyebrows and other small areas but I found sugar waxing to be 1000x more painful than hot wax.  :( thanks for the tip. do u live in LA by any chance? i researched &amp;amp; found a lady in Santa Monica, i hope it wasn't her! i don't get to do brazilians as my skin is uber fucking sensitive :( so i am hoping to just try it on my upper lip lmao nah I am not in LA.  And I think the lady that did my sugar waxing did a great job it was just that doing it all over my kitty was the worst idea everrrrrrrrrrr. </snippet></document><document><title>This is my body</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=z2ME8sR-bnY#!</url><snippet /></document><document><title>The Typical Day Of A Teenage Girl In The Late '90s</title><url>http://www.buzzfeed.com/amandamarsh/the-typical-day-of-a-teenage-girl-in-the-late-90s-96ht</url><snippet>  Don't forget wearing out my Savage Garden CD. They were my first concert! We had fourth row seats. And by we, I mean me, my mom, my best friend, and her mom. Good times. They were my first concert! We had fourth row seats. And by we, I mean me, my mom, my best friend, and her mom. Good times. [deleted] I don't recall feeling like I had to be super sexy (sexy in the most stereotypical way possible) when I was a teen.  I can't describe it . . . but I clearly recall wearing a little kids' tee shirt and "Bjork knobs" in my hair, no make up, and feeling superfly.  I can also remember a short period when my goal was to dress exactly like the Beastie Boys, and no one called me homophobic slurs or said anything at all . . . I was a dork in general and ok with it.  I have an 18 year old niece and it seems like she is under way more pressure to look/dress a certain way. [deleted] Don't forget wearing out my Savage Garden CD. YESSSS!!!
 
And having competitions with your friends to see who could sing all the words to "I Want You" most accurately. We can't be the only ones who did that, right?? Thank God you called it by it's actual name. I don't know how many times I had to correct people as a teen who called it "Chicca Cherry cola" and would get pissed off when I told them it wasn't called that.  YESSSS!!!
 
And having competitions with your friends to see who could sing all the words to "I Want You" most accurately. We can't be the only ones who did that, right?? YESSSS!!!
 
And having competitions with your friends to see who could sing all the words to "I Want You" most accurately. We can't be the only ones who did that, right?? And now this song is on my iPod. Beautiful. :)

I remember watching them do that song at the kids choice awards on nick. Don't forget wearing out my Savage Garden CD. Don't forget wearing out my Savage Garden CD.  I was just transported. So much nostalgia...

Except where was the No Doubt? 

And obsessively changing your AOL profile. Also being upset you got warned then warning them back, spent a lot of time scanning pics too Also being upset you got warned then warning them back, spent a lot of time scanning pics too I was just transported. So much nostalgia...

Except where was the No Doubt? 

And obsessively changing your AOL profile. I was just transported. So much nostalgia...

Except where was the No Doubt? 

And obsessively changing your AOL profile. Tragic Kingdom was my first CD. I listened to that thing every day....  I may or may not still have those glowing stars on my bedroom ceiling.

(One is actually a snowflake.) My mother is finally planning on repainting my old room and she tried to take down all the stars. I noticed on a recent visit that there are a few still stuck up there. My mother is finally planning on repainting my old room and she tried to take down all the stars. I noticed on a recent visit that there are a few still stuck up there. I may or may not still have those glowing stars on my bedroom ceiling.

(One is actually a snowflake.) My sister and I had so many (they might still be there). We put them on the ceiling fan so they would be like shooting stars - literally shooting when they would fall off.  I may or may not still have those glowing stars on my bedroom ceiling.

(One is actually a snowflake.) I may or may not still have those glowing stars on my bedroom ceiling.

(One is actually a snowflake.) I may or may not still have those glowing stars on my bedroom ceiling.

(One is actually a snowflake.)  I had forgotten about Fruitopia! I had one every day at lunch x.x They still sell it in Canada. It's actually everywhere there. It's still the 90s in Canada. They'll catch up in a few years. It's still the 90s in Canada. They'll catch up in a few years. I had forgotten about Fruitopia! I had one every day at lunch x.x There was a Frutopia machine at the flower shop across the street, and I would always get one after school with my sister until it disappeared in about 2004. We had one in my school. Because you know...it is juice right?  I had forgotten about Fruitopia! I had one every day at lunch x.x Do they even sell that anymore? O.o
That was the stuff right there!! I had forgotten about Fruitopia! I had one every day at lunch x.x  All of this. I was a walking stereotype. So ashamed yet glittery. My tattoo necklace was so hot All of my sexy baby doll tees from Wet Seal... Do you remember when the spaghetti tanks with Hawaiian shirts were in? Oh god the horror.  Now it's "boybeaters" and flannel. Wait, are we going back in time? My tattoo necklace was so hot My tattoo necklace was so hot  Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Or the Bonne Belle perfumes. http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-f9y6WD1hMPQ/TedgL9Cr0qI/AAAAAAAABKM/uxe81XDiRec/s1600/haul+of+bottled+emotion+bonne+bell.jpg  Or the Bonne Belle perfumes. http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-f9y6WD1hMPQ/TedgL9Cr0qI/AAAAAAAABKM/uxe81XDiRec/s1600/haul+of+bottled+emotion+bonne+bell.jpg  Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Nah, it was all about cKone, the fragrance for a man or a woman. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Over here in the UK it was all Impulse body spray. I had one in vanilla. It was so sickly sweet. Over here in the UK it was all Impulse body spray. I had one in vanilla. It was so sickly sweet. Over here in the UK it was all Impulse body spray. I had one in vanilla. It was so sickly sweet. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Umm... whatever that one was that was the black and white exclaimation point. That one. Exclamation! (with diacritical marks that I don't remember)

That one reminds me of 1989, because one of our fourth-grade teachers wore it.

I had a bottle of Emeraude; I didn't wear it much but I sprayed it around my room after cleaning to make it smell grown-up. You smelled so grown-up you smelled elderly.  (Sorry--as an adult now it just made me laugh that you chose that scent.) Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Cool Water Woman here.  Still such a unique scent.  And I still have half a bottle. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995. Gap Perfume? It was all about Vanilla Fields. Or Bath and Body Works' raspberry scent. It's discontinued now, but that smell will always remind me of 1995.  Pretty much all of that is spot on except the pager. I had subscriptions to YM and Seventeen for years. This makes me feel incredibly old. I remember if you signed up for a new account on Neopets you would get a one year subscription to YM for free (no credit card needed or anything)! My young self felt like she hit the jackpot when she found that out!  Pretty much all of that is spot on except the pager. I had subscriptions to YM and Seventeen for years. This makes me feel incredibly old. Pretty much all of that is spot on except the pager. I had subscriptions to YM and Seventeen for years. This makes me feel incredibly old. Pretty much all of that is spot on except the pager. I had subscriptions to YM and Seventeen for years. This makes me feel incredibly old.  No one said "OMG" in real-life conversations in the late 90s.  THOSE SURVEYS! I thought I was the only one. They were huge on livejournal, so much passive aggressive answers. I remember people getting so upset over that shit. Massive fallouts between friends over/involving insults on your blogs, and thinking it was fine because you were just expresing your feelings in a diary. THOSE SURVEYS! I thought I was the only one.  Knocked off AOL when my *brother* picked up the phone? Try sister... she was MTV generation, I was AOL. She didn't get how important it was that I was in the Red Dragon Inn by 5PM... oh my god I forgot about all the RP I used to do! This just reminded me.  Knocked off AOL when my *brother* picked up the phone? Try sister... she was MTV generation, I was AOL. She didn't get how important it was that I was in the Red Dragon Inn by 5PM...  Except for the tv shows, that's scarily accurate.  I'd forgotten about stuff like glitter and those stretchy plastic chokers.  We wore SO much surfer gear from PacSun, but none of us had ever been on a surfboard.  *cringe* What about those weird plastic hair things that hooked, made a circle then pulled ur hair back, what were they called? Are you taking about [these things?](http://www.amazon.com/Topsy-Tail-Jr-Style-Braidmaker/dp/B003GRN3OO) that made your hair look like [this](https://www.google.com/search?q=inside+out+ponytail&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;client=safari&amp;amp;tbo=u&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=univ&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=xhUaUd76D-TG0QGwuoHQCg&amp;amp;ved=0CDgQsAQ&amp;amp;biw=1024&amp;amp;bih=672#)? No these things http://www.fashionaddict.com.au/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/assorted-plastic-zig-zag-hair-clips-4-pack.jpg Omg THOSE! I had so many of those. It was not a good look for me. Except for the tv shows, that's scarily accurate.  I'd forgotten about stuff like glitter and those stretchy plastic chokers.  We wore SO much surfer gear from PacSun, but none of us had ever been on a surfboard.  *cringe*  I coveted Delia's clothes so much but we were super poor so the only time I ever got to wear any was when my more well to do friend would give me her hand-me-downs.  I coveted Delia's clothes so much but we were super poor so the only time I ever got to wear any was when my more well to do friend would give me her hand-me-downs.  I coveted Delia's clothes so much but we were super poor so the only time I ever got to wear any was when my more well to do friend would give me her hand-me-downs.  I coveted Delia's clothes so much but we were super poor so the only time I ever got to wear any was when my more well to do friend would give me her hand-me-downs.  I hope this isn't a really stupid question, but are you guys talking about the same teen clothing store Delia's that's popular these days? I used to work there but I never knew it was that popular in the 90's because we didn't have one in our area until a few years ago.  I coveted Delia's clothes so much but we were super poor so the only time I ever got to wear any was when my more well to do friend would give me her hand-me-downs.   Wow, this was pretty spot on. Except I did snowboard so it was okay to wear those shirts from PacSun. I also spent 90% of my AOL time reading a lot, A LOT, of N'Sync and Harry Potter fanfiction.  Most of my AOL time was downloading Sailor Moon manga and saving it to 3.5" floppy disks lol I would spend hours collecting sailor moon pictures to print and hang on my bedroom walls. By the time my teenage obsession had ended I had at least half my walls covered. Wow, this was pretty spot on. Except I did snowboard so it was okay to wear those shirts from PacSun. I also spent 90% of my AOL time reading a lot, A LOT, of N'Sync and Harry Potter fanfiction.  Oh god yes hp fanfiction. I used to read these. They are still up!!

http://menarasin.tripod.com/hermionesworld.html Wow, this was pretty spot on. Except I did snowboard so it was okay to wear those shirts from PacSun. I also spent 90% of my AOL time reading a lot, A LOT, of N'Sync and Harry Potter fanfiction.    Well, that was painfully accurate... Except for every part that involved having friends... 


And what about Magic the Gathering cards?? ...remember that thing about friends? Yea.  Well, that was painfully accurate... Except for every part that involved having friends... 


And what about Magic the Gathering cards?? ...remember that thing about friends? Yea.  Well, that was painfully accurate... Except for every part that involved having friends... 


And what about Magic the Gathering cards?? ...remember that thing about friends? Yea.  Well, that was painfully accurate... Except for every part that involved having friends... 


And what about Magic the Gathering cards?? ...remember that thing about friends? Yea.  Well, that was painfully accurate... Except for every part that involved having friends... 


And what about Magic the Gathering cards?? ...remember that thing about friends? Yea.   I fucking loved glitter. One time I had so much on my liberal mother didn't even want to let me out of the house.  I fucking loved glitter. One time I had so much on my liberal mother didn't even want to let me out of the house.  Glitter needs to come back. I love glitter Glitter needs to come back. I love glitter  &amp;gt; If "Heathers" were made a decade later, it would've been named "Jessicas"

We had four or five in my grade four class. WHAT THE HELL.

Also, so many of these applied to me... It wasn't Jessica at my school.  It was JENNIFER (me being one of them).  We had to all be called by our last names, there were so many. I was (well, still am) one of the 3+ Jennifers! &amp;gt; If "Heathers" were made a decade later, it would've been named "Jessicas"

We had four or five in my grade four class. WHAT THE HELL.

Also, so many of these applied to me... &amp;gt; If "Heathers" were made a decade later, it would've been named "Jessicas"

We had four or five in my grade four class. WHAT THE HELL.

Also, so many of these applied to me...   I actually remember reading that exact issue of ym! Me too! I actually forgot about that magazine until I saw this. It was one of my favorites back then.     Way.too.accurate. HE shampoo, check. Glow in the dark stars on the ceiling, check. Delia's magazines, check. Dial-up internet and a geocities website, double-check. Only exception, I was listening to music like Garbage, NIN, Tori Amos, No Doubt, Bush, Live, the Toadies, and other 90s alt rock, industrial music, or electronica.. I thoroughly loathed both BSB and N'Sync (but now I like a lot of pop music). How things change. I was mostly watching the X-Files (sometimes Buffy and Charmed) and I wore most anything found at HotTopic and/or PacSun in addition to Delia's/Girlfriends. (A random mix.) Some days I felt quite goth..other days..let's pretend to be a skater. All the other days? Candy raver. 
Side note: The Heather's or Jessica's or Jennifer's of today might be Katie/Katelynn/Kaitlin's. Just an FYI, in case you want some really nostalgic showers, they re-released that [Herbal Essences shampoo](http://www.drugstore.com/products/prod.asp?pid=454337&amp;amp;catid=186696).  As far as I can tell, it's exactly the same as it used to be, they just changed the label a little.  It's even in the same bottle.    

Lucky for me, I happened to just run out of shampoo, so I bought myself some last night.  


Edit: Don't let their "0% silicone" and "0% sulfate" labels confuse you.  The *shampoo* is silicone free, which is usually the case, and the *conditioner* is sulfate free, which is also the norm.  It's actually really deceptive if you ask me.  People will see "0% silicone" and "0% sulfate" and think there isn't either of those things between the two, when in fact there's both of them.  I'm glad they didn't change the formula, but I think this sneaky packaging is just unnecessary.  I have to assume people are gonna buy it for nostalgic reasons alone.  That's what I did.   Way.too.accurate. HE shampoo, check. Glow in the dark stars on the ceiling, check. Delia's magazines, check. Dial-up internet and a geocities website, double-check. Only exception, I was listening to music like Garbage, NIN, Tori Amos, No Doubt, Bush, Live, the Toadies, and other 90s alt rock, industrial music, or electronica.. I thoroughly loathed both BSB and N'Sync (but now I like a lot of pop music). How things change. I was mostly watching the X-Files (sometimes Buffy and Charmed) and I wore most anything found at HotTopic and/or PacSun in addition to Delia's/Girlfriends. (A random mix.) Some days I felt quite goth..other days..let's pretend to be a skater. All the other days? Candy raver. 
Side note: The Heather's or Jessica's or Jennifer's of today might be Katie/Katelynn/Kaitlin's. Are you me?! No, she's *me*!!

EDIT: David Duchovny from the X-files was my first TV crush. Rawr.  Please tell me I'm not the only one here that still remembers the sound of dial-up and can tell you my old ICQ number.  Didn't have AOL, but had a Geocities page and eventually had a LiveJournal.  Had the soundtracks to Clueless and Empire Records on constantly.  I would drink Frutopia, Josta, and Clearly Canadian water whenever I could buy it.  Kind of bummed they didn't mention all the amazing 90s alternative bands - Gin Blossoms, Better Than Ezra, Toad the Wet Sprocket, No Doubt...so many great memories!    What I took from this was that I am old because I still watch Buffy every night before bed and I just got rid of AOL two years ago.    I'm actually in the process of getting rid of my old babydoll band shirts.. that I've had since 98.  I'm actually in the process of getting rid of my old babydoll band shirts.. that I've had since 98.  Send to me! Seriously!    I'm pretty sure the only thing I lacked was the glitter. 

 Bath and Body Works had some pretty sweet roll on glitter, I would adorn my cheeks with it every day.    Yes to practically all of those. And I thought I was a nonconformist...     How is there no mention of Sakura Gel Pens!? I lived for those things in the 90's! A glaring omission on my part, I agree. I perhaps pushed them out of my mind because they never seemed to work for me past the second time I used them.     I'm just slightly too young to have been a teenager in the 90s (born '87) and I'm also British so some of these things were the same but some were different.

* We were up to NOW 41 by the time your NOW 1 came out... Probably the same songs though
* My mother chose my clothes until I was 13 and I mostly wore tracksuits... I even wore them to school discos... the shame.
* Dawson's Creek wasn't on at night, it was on Sunday mornings. I loved it but I have to say I had no idea what it was about most of the time. I think Buffy was on too late for me to watch.
* NSync didn't really reach the UK until after the Backstreet Boys fad was over. I never liked either of them.
* Jessica was fairly popular but there were probably more Lauras, Emmas and Sarahs
* The fuck is a beeper?
* We did not have calculators with games on! I pretty much thought Nokia invented Snake. My first friend to get a mobile phone did so in 99. I would beg to play Snake on it at lunchtimes.
* I first typed an essay in 2000. I did it in Comic Sans. (In my defence, it was about Puck and I thought it suited his character.) That was also the first year I used the internet, in school. I didn't have internet at home until 2002. But yes I did the surveys and wrote "ASL?" a lot anyway. I didn't realise I was out of touch at the time.
* I got my first cassette Walkman in 2000. I didn't get a Discman until 2003. I was way behind all my friends though.
* I never had any, but I would now kill for some glow in the dark stars in my room. &amp;gt; I think Buffy was on too late for me to watch.

Nope!  It was on about 1830 or 1845 on a weekday evening, just after tea for me.

&amp;gt; I first typed an essay in 2000. I did it in Comic Sans.

I think my school made me do it in Times New Roman, but I outlined all of mine with those silly picture borders that Word would let you do.  I spent ages trying to find the one that suited the essay/subject best...    Those all are the things I looked forward to when I was little.... But I was born in 1992. I never got to have a beeper, and I wasn't allowed to watch Buffy back then. I wanted to have an AOL account. I also never had the glow in the dark stars, I should at least go do that.  I wasn't allowed to watch Buffy either. (Religious parents, meh) and you know what? I've decided that I'm going to watch it now. In fact, *right now*; I just found it on Netflix!    I had to listen to Green Day after reading that      I remember doing these things in 99-2002 as 7-10 year old ;)          </snippet></document><document><title>Thinking of proposing to my boyfriend</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18estz/thinking_of_proposing_to_my_boyfriend/</url><snippet>So, as the title suggests, I am thinking of proposing to my boyfriend. I know we are on the same page as far as everything is concerned - we talk about marriage and buying a house as inevitabilities. We already live together, our families are very close, etc etc. We are going there. About two months ago, I was looking for a pen in his bag while he was in the shower. I found a ring. I felt awful, I didn't mention anything. So far, some key dates have passed (Christmas, New Years, an anniversary, etc) and no proposal. I am not complaining at all, as he is one for grand romantic gestures and I'm sure has something planned. However, something that I am more than aware of is that he has issues with feeling inadequate. I know full well that nothing I do will make those feelings go away aside from emotional support and living my own life without feeling responsible for him...but I want to propose as a token of how equally I wish to spend the rest of my life with him. I have a band (just as a sort of token/indicator of the proposal) and am totally set to do this. I know hes got something planned, I know that this is the "it" we are working towards, all of those are certainties, but... Am I stealing his thunder? Is this a terrible idea? Is the idea behind it too cutesy? I know it doesn't change how he feels, I know I can't change him, but I see this as a chance to further express my support for him and for us, as a lifelong couple. TwoX, help me!  Oh... if he already has a ring I would say don't do it. I know my boyfriend has everything planned out and it would absolutely crush him if I did anything like that. 

You could probably give him the ring after he proposes (not immediately after) to show your own devotion to him.   I was thinkin' something like this...I was actually thinking, if I don't go through with it, about keeping his band in my pocket at all times, so when he does, I can pull out the ring I got him and say yes!  I was just going to suggest that!  It would be a nice counter-surprise.     I think it's a very sweet thought! I have an idea that might be a little silly - leap day is traditionally the day that women propose to men. You could jokingly mention something Feb 28th. If he is feeling self-conscious this might loosen the mood a bit while showing that you're ready to commit to marriage. Either way, I hope everything all works out soon for you guys! =) But there won't be a leap day until 2016! I reckon he'll propose before then! Yup I know there's no leap year this year, that's why I said Feb 28th. She could turn it into a joke, "Damn it's  a shame I missed the chance last year to propose to you on leap year!" Something like that. =) Haha sorry! I'm with you :) I understand the confusion, my idea didn't really make much sense, lol! I thought it might be a jokey way to lighten the mood. =)  Honestly a complete stranger could propose to me and I would happily say yes. That gesture alone would be more meaningful then anything a girlfriend has ever done for me. The act of making the first move is often an unappreciated gesture, and when men are generally expected to make all the first moves it can be a heavy weight and leave you feeling inadequate. "Did she want ME or just someone", making that that blind leap says a lot more then simply reacting to his actions. I wouldn't feel like you were stealing my thunder, you can even have him propose as planned but with more confidence because you've removed the burden of making that blind step alone. Honestly I think a lot of social interactions would change if women took over the first move, or at least shared in them. Honestly a complete stranger could propose to me and I would happily say yes. That gesture alone would be more meaningful then anything a girlfriend has ever done for me. The act of making the first move is often an unappreciated gesture, and when men are generally expected to make all the first moves it can be a heavy weight and leave you feeling inadequate. "Did she want ME or just someone", making that that blind leap says a lot more then simply reacting to his actions. I wouldn't feel like you were stealing my thunder, you can even have him propose as planned but with more confidence because you've removed the burden of making that blind step alone. Honestly I think a lot of social interactions would change if women took over the first move, or at least shared in them. This is a little confusing... you say "a complete stranger could propose to me and I would happily say yes," but then you speculate that a man that proposes may feel like his new fiance just wanted to be proposed to and didn't care by whom ("Did she want ME or just someone")......?? And that you are male? And I'm lost now.. Ya I've always struggled with how I phrase my thoughts. I am a man, I may have exaggerated the comment of marrying a stranger for effect, but if a girl were to propose that gesture alone would be over powering. Simply I would feel more valued by a girl asking me out on a date, then her saying yes to all the times I've asked her out on dates. Personally all my relationship success was measured simply by her reactions to my gestures, and that's never as meaningful as her making the gesture.</snippet></document><document><title>Fox News Wastes Four And A Half Minutes Criticizing Adele&#8217;s Weight</title><url>http://thinkprogress.org/media/2013/02/11/1573871/adele-kelly-clarkson-fox-weight/</url><snippet>   She never said anything about health really. It was all about how they look. I am "over weight" on the BMI scale but my doc said who cares, I am totally healthy and happy. I think the whole BMI thing it kinda BS. You can't really say "we all have a different profile" and then site a standard like the BMI scale. That's a little contradictory, isn't it?  BMI is a lie anyways.  My dad used to be a body builder and went into the military.  He was considered over-weight because his muscle mass was so high, he weighed a lot more than he looked, but he was just super-fit.  So according to BMI he was "fat", but if you looked at him there was barely any fat on him at all. Right but if you have no muscle mass or very little muscle mass, BMI would be a pretty decent indicator. People always bring up the muscle mass thing but it's pretty clear when someone is very build VS someone who has more of fat on them.

It's not a perfect system but it's a decent way of giving you an idea when it comes to lots of people.  Right but if you have no muscle mass or very little muscle mass, BMI would be a pretty decent indicator. People always bring up the muscle mass thing but it's pretty clear when someone is very build VS someone who has more of fat on them.

It's not a perfect system but it's a decent way of giving you an idea when it comes to lots of people.  BMI is a lie anyways.  My dad used to be a body builder and went into the military.  He was considered over-weight because his muscle mass was so high, he weighed a lot more than he looked, but he was just super-fit.  So according to BMI he was "fat", but if you looked at him there was barely any fat on him at all. Why would they keep a system that is so obviously flawed.  Why would they keep a system that is so obviously flawed.  Why would they keep a system that is so obviously flawed.   This womans argument had nothing to do with health, and only about physical appearance and that is why her argument failed. 


A lot of young women adapt this idea that women like this imbeds in their brains that the only acceptable presence in society is being skinny, and that is the ONLY reason why so many women struggle with weight issues like yoyo dieting, starvation and bulimia and the end result is anorexia or obesity, and the ones that find their "ideal" weight through these means, develop incredibly unhealthy organs. 


Putting this much pressure on women to look a certain way will never have a positive outcome. The body is rebellious and the more you fight it the more you will fall victim to it. The body wants only one thing, and that is to be healthy. It could care less about being skinny in order to look "good" in that outfit. And if the body interprets the process you're taking to get from point A(fat) to point B(skinny) as unhealthy it will have adverse effects and cause you to fail, in order to survive. 


The best thing to do when you have weight issues is to completely ignore what people think about you. Don't lose weight because this woman in the video tells you you need to lose weight, because if you don't society wont accept you. Ignore her completely, shes an idiot. 


Simply do whats healthy for your body, and do it at the pace your body is comfortable with. Don't deprive yourself, but don't indulge either. Find the equilibrium that satisfies your mind and your body nutritionally. And you will find a long term, healthy and happy outcome.   Cavuto is dismissing her argument... I don't like Fox News but the sentiment gets a little old on Reddit.        </snippet></document><document><title>Questions about self stimulation...</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fl9l/questions_about_self_stimulation/</url><snippet>I'm not sure if this is the right place to post but I am not sure if I did it right and I just have some questions. I am nineteen years old and I have always felt really self conscious about my body and scared of anything sex related for a long time. My mom was really really good about sex ed-- she always made sure my sister and I were knowledgable about what would happen to our bodies during puberty, how to have sex responsibly, etc., but I was (and still am) very embarassed about sex related things. It's taken a good two years of going on TwoX every day and talking to people online about sex and watching Laci Green videos to make me feel more comfortable with myself. I identified as asexual for a long time because I barely had any sexual desire, and only recently have had any even vague stirrings of what could be thought of as arousal. I am not sure if I am just a late bloomer or if it is years of anxiety and nervousness about sex finally starting to wear away. 

Tonight I tried masturbating again. I have tried a few times before but was never able to feel much of anything. But I did what Laci Green suggested and just kept going when I felt something and eventually it actually did start to feel really good. I hit a sort of plateau for a while and it took a long time but I think I might have orgasmed-- my thighs were clenched up and my heart was racing and it felt really really good. I didn't get any sort of release like I had heard described, but tonight I did way better than I have ever done before. 

. I can't really talk about this with anyone in real life-- I am just too self conscious to bring the subject of sex or masturbation up with anyone, even my mom or therapist. I know it's not a healthy attitude to have but I am working on it. Watching the Laci Green sex+ videos and
 seeing the sex-positive views of TwoX has helped me immensely. So 
I guess what I am looking for now is reassurance: is it okay that even though I don't really want to have sex or masturbate? Is it normal that it took so long for me to orgasm-- and was that even an orgasm?! Do other people with perfectly decent parents still have a hard time talking about sex?

Sorry for the ramble, I am just a little lost and confused. Thank you for your support regardless!     </snippet></document><document><title>Ladies, I need to ask you a question about something I did for my wife that didn't turn *quite* as we planned.....</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ekte/ladies_i_need_to_ask_you_a_question_about/</url><snippet>Okay, bare bones, straight out.

My wife asked me to shave her vaginal area and mons.  I was more than happy to.  We used a fresh razor and a bikini area specific shaving cream.  I took my time and got her as bare as she wanted to be.  Afterwards we had happy adult time.  

However,

The next day she discovered that her mons area was nearly covered in small whiteheads.  Nearly every pore seemed to have one.  Now, 2 days later, she is in mild discomfort, major annoyance and the white heads are being exfoliated to death.

My questions:

* Where did I go wrong?
* How do I prevent this from happening again?

Please help husband who meant well but mucked up somewhere.....

EDIT:  Thank you for all the input.  My wife has been reading your comments over my shoulder and I'm going to let her pick how/if we do this again in the future.  Some women cannot handle being shaved down there.  She'll heal up, good luck.    To help with this next time, exfoliate a bunch before you shave her. For me, it helps to take a washcloth and do little circles, as well as scrub against the grain a bit. Pubic hair has a strongly defined grain, so I feel like it ends up with the roots getting kind of matted down by the skin around the hair follicle, so it grows sideways a bit instead of up. Exfoliating so it is standing up a bit more helps. I think that may have been part of the problem.  I shave my face against the grain.  But everything I've read here and other places says I should have shaved her *with* the grain.... Unless you want blood everywhere, shave with the grain, then exfoliate against. How does this work? If I try to shave with the grain, I end up with stubble. Do I need to use a sharper razor? How does this work? If I try to shave with the grain, I end up with stubble. Do I need to use a sharper razor? How does this work? If I try to shave with the grain, I end up with stubble. Do I need to use a sharper razor? How does this work? If I try to shave with the grain, I end up with stubble. Do I need to use a sharper razor? To help with this next time, exfoliate a bunch before you shave her. For me, it helps to take a washcloth and do little circles, as well as scrub against the grain a bit. Pubic hair has a strongly defined grain, so I feel like it ends up with the roots getting kind of matted down by the skin around the hair follicle, so it grows sideways a bit instead of up. Exfoliating so it is standing up a bit more helps.   Shaving just WILL NOT WORK for some of us ladies. Our skin doesnt like it, and no method or fancy product will prevent that awful reaction. It might be a few days or even a week or two before her crotch feels normal again. Ive had my fair share of bad razor burns.

[Use a bikini trimmer!](http://www.remingtonproducts.com/womens/hairremoval/personalgroomers/bikini-and-detail-trimmer-kit.aspx) &amp;lt;--that's the one I use. It comes with multiple heads, but I mainly use the regular one (as shown in the picture) to get the job done. It isn't quite the same as shaved-bald, but I can get pretty darn close to totally bare. It's very easy to use, and thus far I've never gotten any kind of razorburn/rash/ingrown hairs/whiteheads/anything since I've been using it. It feels very smooth after you give yourself a good trim down. And like I said, it will be very smooth. And ive tried for years to make shaving the hoo-ha area work for me, and it just doesn't. I dont know why I didnt look into trimmers earlier (I didnt even know they existed, actually..) but I wish I'd known that before!   Are they whiteheads? Or are they just tons of little slightly inflamed bumps? 

Next time you shave use HOT, water, soak in it for 15 minutes. Use a fresh razor and shaving cream. Shave with the grain (not against it, this prevents razor burn) and apply baby oil after shaving to keep in moisture. Use lotion daily. Shower after sex (freshly opened pores + sticky sweat and juices does not a happy vag make) then apply moisturizing lotion. Shower after a particularly hot day (sweat+chafing is hell on freshly shaved skin) apply lotion. Wear breathable cotton underwear.

Just moisturize a lot and keep it clean

 Whiteheads.

I think that what you've written makes a lot of sense.  Will definitely incorporate this.   DO NOT use lotion. It will only make her more likely to break out again. Use a gentle astringent to prevent breakouts afterwards. Apply and then let it dry before putting on undies. DO NOT use lotion. It will only make her more likely to break out again. Use a gentle astringent to prevent breakouts afterwards. Apply and then let it dry before putting on undies. Also, hot water can increase inflammation, as can some baby oils and lotions, particularly if they're perfumed or if you have sensitive skin. Many moisturizers also tend to be comedogenic, meaning they can clog pores and causes pimples.

Much of this top-voted comment isn't very good advice for many people. Whiteheads.

I think that what you've written makes a lot of sense.  Will definitely incorporate this.   They could also be ingrown hairs from not having shaved before. I get them too sometimes if I go too long between shaves. Either way, just be gentle and you two will be ok. Maybe just keeping it trimmed is what should happen instead of shaving in future.  These are all great suggestions. One thing I'd add is buying the bikini zone anti-bump gel. It's got lidocaine in it (or you could just buy lidocaine) and that will help with any irritation. I've also found that using a non-disposable men's razor works best. I use a razor specifically designed for African-American hair, and the razors are ultra cheap ($4 for 10 blades) and it works really well on coarser hair. I'm a dancer, so non-bumpy or irritated vag area is super important. Unless she has very sensitive skin, it should toughen up if she keeps up with the shaving.   She may have had a mild allergic reaction OR she has an infection. I'm assuming you two probably had sex soon afterwards, but local infections can be caused by many things (we all have lots of nasty bacteria hanging out on our skin 24/7). Have her see her GP, and for the love of god, tell her to stop exfoliating. If it's an infection, she's spreading it. If it's an allergy, she's spreading histamine (cause/part of allergen-induced inflammation). Also, heavy exfoliating can lead to scarring. Additional tissue trauma is NOT the way to go about it! 

Best thing to remember? **These things happen.** Likely not your fault, nor hers. Seriously, have a doctor take a quick check to see if she just needs some hydrocortisone and diphenhydramine or if she's needs a topical antibiotic. 

*If it was an allergy: note the ingredients of the shaving lotion used and metal type of the razor and avoid.*

Best of luck! She may have had a mild allergic reaction OR she has an infection. I'm assuming you two probably had sex soon afterwards, but local infections can be caused by many things (we all have lots of nasty bacteria hanging out on our skin 24/7). Have her see her GP, and for the love of god, tell her to stop exfoliating. If it's an infection, she's spreading it. If it's an allergy, she's spreading histamine (cause/part of allergen-induced inflammation). Also, heavy exfoliating can lead to scarring. Additional tissue trauma is NOT the way to go about it! 

Best thing to remember? **These things happen.** Likely not your fault, nor hers. Seriously, have a doctor take a quick check to see if she just needs some hydrocortisone and diphenhydramine or if she's needs a topical antibiotic. 

*If it was an allergy: note the ingredients of the shaving lotion used and metal type of the razor and avoid.*

Best of luck! I really don't think it's that serious. This type of thing happens all the time and will clear up on its own. Unless the infection seems to be getting pus-sy (hehehe) or something. Seriously, don't panic.      1. you used a razor
2. use wax


You're welcome! Razors work fine for plenty of women. Obviously not all of them though. Right, but that is what the tone of your comment insinuated :)

Not to mention, the OP said he shaved not only her mons but also the rest of her "vaginal area" which leads me to believe they wanted the results similar to a Brazilian wax, but this is not recommended to be done at home. Nice passive aggressive remark.

 My sentence was not passive aggressive. I added a smiley face because I did not want it to seem like such a serious matter. Your first comment insinuated that waxing is the answer for all women, and that if the OP would have used wax instead of a razor, she wouldn't have had problems. A more constructive response would have been "Try using wax next time, that can work better for some women."</snippet></document><document><title>I think I'm still in love with a man I despise... </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18foxt/i_think_im_still_in_love_with_a_man_i_despise/</url><snippet>Using a throwaway because reasons and I'm not sure where else to go... also, sorry for the block of text I'm just really at a loss and need to vent. We were together for almost three years, he was my everything. He was my first serious relationship, lost my virginity to him, planned a future, wedding, kids, etc. We didn't have the greatest relationship to begin with and we kept trying to make it work. Our emotions were always at extremes. When things were good, they were absolutely spectacular and I was on cloud nine. When things were bad, they were knock down, drag outs. I know you're probably going to tell me what everyone else has already said but hear me out. There were a few incidents of physical abuse, on both halves, along with a ton of emotional abuse. The first year we were together we kept it hidden and he even denied me to his family, in front of me. So when he wouldn't commit to me, I started seeing someone else, but still going back to him at the same time. I know I was wrong and I shouldn't have done it, but I loved him and wanted him to come around. But while I was waiting for it to happen, I found someone that was giving me what I wanted, it just wasn't from the right person. Regardless, I ended it with the other guy and kept hoping for more to happen with MY guy. He ended up finding out about the other guy but we worked past it and things got better. He helped me through some medical issues, stood by me when I had to leave school, took care of me when I had no place to go. He was my saint, my everything. I gave up my entire life for him and I had no problem doing it. I was ready and willing to dedicate my life to taking care of him. Unfortunately we still had our ups and downs, on and off again's. I knew I couldn't be with him forever because of how bad we would get. But every time we broke up, he'd pull me right back in because well, I was in love with him and didn't want to give him up. But I finally made things so bad he left me. Which didn't work very well because he still wanted me back. But I didn't fall for it. At least not entirely. The past few months we've gotten together, his house, my house, hotel room, just to be with each other, to be next to each other again. I kept trying to stay away but I've never had such strong feelings for another living thing in my life. I still didn't want to lose him completely. Well, I recently found out while he was still telling me he wanted to marry me, he's still in love with me, he wants us to work, he was hooking up and sleeping with 4 other women. I was crushed. Then after I pried the truth from him, he went on to say how they were all better looking than me, more successful than me, better women than me. And that no one cares about me and he hates me and he hopes my medical condition that he helped me through kills me and just a bunch of other horrible things. Mind you, this is all through a TEXT message. I never replied because I was just numb. After it all set in, I bawled and bawled until I was throwing up. I couldn't eat, the whole cliche heartache thing. Now, this was a few weeks ago and I haven't heard from him since, nor have I replied. Until last night that it. While I was leaving work I got a text from a number. I thought it was a friend I had met a few nights ago until I took a second look at it, it was his. My heart sank and I started having a mini panic attack and started hypo-ventilating(I have anxiety and such). I was able to get myself together and calm down but I still couldn't read it. About a half hour later I read it..."Maybe you can give me some insight. Why after all that do I still think about you, everyday. What the fuck. You hate me. And I still think about you." I do, I hate him. I absolutely despise him. But I know I'm still in love with him. I've put on this facade and everyone thinks I'm doing fine but I am miserable. I don't want to go back to him, I will never be able to forgive him. It still makes me sick to the point I want to vomit to even think about him and 4 other women, while he was sleeping with me and telling me he wants to marry me one day. I'm sick of having these thoughts pulling me both ways. I feel betrayed, used, played...I never thought he would pull a stunt like this. And..I just don't know how or what I'm supposed to feel anymore. I'm trying to get over it, I even went on a date this past weekend. But I just can't keep my mind off of the man that completely crushed me.       </snippet></document><document><title>Men aren't from Mars and Women aren't from Venus</title><url>http://www.theage.com.au/lifestyle/life/men-arent-from-mars-and-women-arent-from-venus-20130212-2eaje.html</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Meet Latifa Nabizada, Afghanistan's first woman military helicopter pilot</title><url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2013-02-12/latifa-nabizada-mama-asia-afghanistan/4489756</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Can't figure out tampons. Unbearably frustrated. Help?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ej8u/cant_figure_out_tampons_unbearably_frustrated_help/</url><snippet>EDIT: I did it!!!! Thanks to everyone who helped. Reddit comes through yet again :)

Hey!

So like the title says, I'm 20 years old and I've never used a tampon. I'm a virgin (I feel like that's obvious). I've tried a bunch of times. My roommate gave me one of her tampons and a little mirror and the damn directions from the tampon box and everything and I still can't do it.

I don't know if I'm too tense or if I just don't understand my own body or what... But this makes me nervous about the future too... What if I can't figure out sex? When the time comes, what am I gonna do? "Sorry, I can't fit anything up there." Cool.

I'm upset. I've tried so many times. I'm feeling like less of a woman weirdly. Any ideas?  UPDATE!

I did some exploring like a few of you were saying and I DID IT!

I'm so, so happy that I was finally able to do this. Thanks everyone so much for the help. It seems like a small thing to accomplish, but this is really a huge deal for me. Thanks so much!!! Can you explain what you were doing wrong before? Just curious. I wasn't following the path of my vagina correctly. I had to point it in a different direction. 

For the record, getting it OUT was terrifying. I thought it was stuck forever. It was for the same reason, it wasn't following the path. But it hurt and it sucked and I don't think I'm ging to be using tampons after all.

Lol. I still feel better.  Some people's vaginas have it so it's either the hymen or a large piece of skin (sorry I don't remember exactly what it was, it's been a while since I researched it) covers the majority of the vaginal opening so even if you are still bleeding on your period it may be more closed than it should be. This often requires surgery (easy, outpatient). It prevents the usage of things like tampons and penetrative sex. It can also cause issues because period blood can get blocked up because the opening is too small for it all to leave. I'd go see a doctor or a gyno and have them check it out. Geeeeezzz I hope that's not it... Thanks, though. I'll try again and see if I can get any farther by just relaxing and going slow. I have a very sporatic menstrual cycle and my periods are usually very light or don't come at all. Hopefully it's not getting all backed up like you mentioned. Some people's vaginas have it so it's either the hymen or a large piece of skin (sorry I don't remember exactly what it was, it's been a while since I researched it) covers the majority of the vaginal opening so even if you are still bleeding on your period it may be more closed than it should be. This often requires surgery (easy, outpatient). It prevents the usage of things like tampons and penetrative sex. It can also cause issues because period blood can get blocked up because the opening is too small for it all to leave. I'd go see a doctor or a gyno and have them check it out. A normal hymen doesn't cover the majority of the vaginal opening. Just a bit. Some people have larger and thicker hymens, but it's not as common.  What issue are you having with the tampons exactly? Are you just not getting them in correctly? Are they uncomfortable?  Are you getting them in at all?  I can't even get the whole plastic thing in -_- Let alone then push the actual tampon up and in any farther. Can you get a finger in there? I don't know, I haven't really tried. I don't know, I haven't really tried. I can't even get the whole plastic thing in -_- Let alone then push the actual tampon up and in any farther.  Most likely you have an intact hymen and quite probably, you are going in at the wrong angle.

As has been suggested above, try with the smallest tampon available.  For sake of practicing, try inserting your finger first and see if that works.  If you can get a finger in you should be able to do so with a tampon.  Try putting some lube or Valvoline around the tip of the tampon and see if that helps. 

You aren't alone so don't feel silly...I couldn't use a tampon when I first tried and I had my Aunt yelling at me through the bathroom door...how embarrassing!

Have you ever been to the OB/GYN?  If not you are well past time where you should, and if you have and have had a pelvic exam, you should be able to insert a tampon...

Relax...=)

As for the sex part and not being able to "fit anything", I don't think that is really a problem BUT know that it sounds like your fist time my be rather uncomfortable (yes first times can hurt) this is why finding the right partner is very important.

&amp;lt;Mom Card out&amp;gt;

AND I want to emphasize that there is NO WAY not using a tampon makes you any LESS OF A WOMAN...so stop that thinking RIGHT NOW young Lady!!! I think you meant vasoline,  Valvoline is a motor oil. I got a giggle out of this!  Oops...auto correct for the win.

Let this be a lesson...do not try to post on your iphone at stop lights Maybe your car is using your phone to communicate with you! She's thirsty!  Most likely you have an intact hymen and quite probably, you are going in at the wrong angle.

As has been suggested above, try with the smallest tampon available.  For sake of practicing, try inserting your finger first and see if that works.  If you can get a finger in you should be able to do so with a tampon.  Try putting some lube or Valvoline around the tip of the tampon and see if that helps. 

You aren't alone so don't feel silly...I couldn't use a tampon when I first tried and I had my Aunt yelling at me through the bathroom door...how embarrassing!

Have you ever been to the OB/GYN?  If not you are well past time where you should, and if you have and have had a pelvic exam, you should be able to insert a tampon...

Relax...=)

As for the sex part and not being able to "fit anything", I don't think that is really a problem BUT know that it sounds like your fist time my be rather uncomfortable (yes first times can hurt) this is why finding the right partner is very important.

&amp;lt;Mom Card out&amp;gt;

AND I want to emphasize that there is NO WAY not using a tampon makes you any LESS OF A WOMAN...so stop that thinking RIGHT NOW young Lady!!! Most likely you have an intact hymen and quite probably, you are going in at the wrong angle.

As has been suggested above, try with the smallest tampon available.  For sake of practicing, try inserting your finger first and see if that works.  If you can get a finger in you should be able to do so with a tampon.  Try putting some lube or Valvoline around the tip of the tampon and see if that helps. 

You aren't alone so don't feel silly...I couldn't use a tampon when I first tried and I had my Aunt yelling at me through the bathroom door...how embarrassing!

Have you ever been to the OB/GYN?  If not you are well past time where you should, and if you have and have had a pelvic exam, you should be able to insert a tampon...

Relax...=)

As for the sex part and not being able to "fit anything", I don't think that is really a problem BUT know that it sounds like your fist time my be rather uncomfortable (yes first times can hurt) this is why finding the right partner is very important.

&amp;lt;Mom Card out&amp;gt;

AND I want to emphasize that there is NO WAY not using a tampon makes you any LESS OF A WOMAN...so stop that thinking RIGHT NOW young Lady!!! &amp;gt;your fist time my be rather uncomfortable

Well yeah, you probably shouldn't try fisting the first time you have sex!   I'm assuming you can't get them to go in? If not, could you explain the problem a bit more.

Okay, so if you're stressed, that's going to make everything tense up down there. So take your time, no pressure, it doesn't matter if you give up the first few times. Choose the smallest tampon in the range to start with, and do it when your flow is heaviest so there is a lot of lubrication. Push gently so you can feel what direction your vagina goes in; it probably points roughly towards the small of your back. Then ease it in gently.  Ok...someone needs to explain something to me here.

HOW/WHY could this thread possible be down voted??

We have a Sister here who is asking for advice/help with something that I am SURE was hard for her to ask and someone DOWN VOTES HER???

WOW I am shocked. Reddit automatically adds downvotes, and balances them out with upvotes -- just because there is "one downvote" doesn't mean someone downvoted her.  So you are saying that Reddit automatically gives a thread a down vote .... Yup. You can read about in in the FAQ. Hmmm...I'm going to have to disagree with your explination. I have seen many threads where there are no down votes whatsoever.

IF as you say, Reddit automatically casts a down vote; these should also have an auto down vote. The FAQ doesn't mention giving an shyly down vote, it just talks about how the actual numbers might be different than those that have been actually cast BUT the up yo down ratio will be correct.

But thank you for answering me =) It automatically casts some number of downvotes; sometimes one, sometimes zero, sometimes many. 

As stated in the reddiquette:

"Some up/downvotes are by reddit to fuzz the votes in order to confuse spammers and cheaters." The up/down ratio is not correct; the difference (up minus down) is correct.

http://www.reddit.com/wiki/reddiquette

Next time that you post: "someone needs to explain something to me here", please don't automatically assume that the explanation is bogus. I didn't assume or imply it was/is bogus. I just disagree with your analysis of the FAQ explination Ok...someone needs to explain something to me here.

HOW/WHY could this thread possible be down voted??

We have a Sister here who is asking for advice/help with something that I am SURE was hard for her to ask and someone DOWN VOTES HER???

WOW I am shocked.</snippet></document><document><title>So Dominatrix is banned and /r/dom has a weird man. Where dom girl go to discuss our lifestyle on Reddit</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18fsow/so_dominatrix_is_banned_and_rdom_has_a_weird_man/</url><snippet>I don't find men to be less than women but I enjoy that sort of role playing. There doesn't seem to be a subreddit set up for this. Any ideas? Sorry if this offends anyone. I see there is a big community for BDSM, I just assumed, wrong ladies would have their own version? Yea? No? Ok I'm going to worm my way out of this somehow.   Why do you think this would offend anyone?

/r/BDSM_community There's no underscore in /r/bdsmcommunity. Damn it. Thanks!  I hadn't even heard of /r/dominatrix, but I suspect that it turned into a classified ad section.  Unfortunately. /r/femdom is porn.  (Even more unfortunately, there's only one Bitchy Jones.)

There might be a more subtly named one hiding somewhere.  /r/bdsmcommunity would probably know.  It's hard to have a public space that's actually female-dominated.  As you are no doubt aware, straight dominant women epitomize "the goods are odd, but the odds are very, very good".

Offend?  Trust me, lots of us wish we were better at making men grovel while we whip their asses... :-)  </snippet></document><document><title>I stopped ovulating and I will probably need fertility drugs to get pregnant. Any words of encouragement?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ez9w/i_stopped_ovulating_and_i_will_probably_need/</url><snippet>I am a 22 year-old graduate student. I am currently single. This has hit me pretty hard. I haven't had my period in 7 months. I had some tests done and it seems that for no good reason my period has stopped. I really want babies at some point and it sucks I might not be able to conceive naturally.  Has anyone been through something similar? I just feel very hit by this news and it's consuming me.

td;lr no eggs= infertile= sad   24, and at a bit over 6 months. I've had hormone and thyroid tests, and they all seem to be pretty much normal.

Also no clue, but I kind of like not bleeding.     </snippet></document><document><title>I (24f) think I am being stalked, but I'm not sure if I'm just freaking myself out.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18dz5b/i_24f_think_i_am_being_stalked_but_im_not_sure_if/</url><snippet>Story: I live in New York City and the following instances happened in three separate boroughs of the city. 

This all started rather innocuously while at the grocery store in early January of this year. This guy, in this early to mid-20s, came up to me while I was shopping and engaged me in some friendly banter, which I immediately recognized as a segue into him hitting on me. He asked me some rather specific questions about myself, which I answered nicely but rather vaguely. The conversation went on for a minute or two, and ended with him asking if we could hang out/if he could have my number. 

As a general rule, I do not give my number out, to anyone, ever; someone I don't know having my cell phone number absolutely creeps me out. I told the guy that I don't give my number out to people I don't know, and he seemed to take it fine. We parted ways, and I continued shopping. 

About five minutes later I notice that he is following me around the store, just standing at the end of every aisle I'm in watching me from the corner of his eye. I think to myself that I'm lucky I didn't give him my number because he definitely seems like a creep, and pay for my items and go home.

Two weeks go by and I quite honestly forget about the entire encounter. Then I am playing tennis one day after work with my brother and some friends at a public park, and I see a guy sitting on a park bench facing the tennis courts. I think nothing of it, it's a nice day, and he seems to be sketching/writing. However, my brother hits a ball over the fence and I volunteer to go get it since I am out for the time being. 

The balls lands about fifteen feet to the right of the park bench, and as I bend down to pick it up I hear the person on the bench say, "Hello there." I say hi back just being friendly, and as I stand back up I make eye contact with the person on the bench and it's the guy from the grocery store. He smiles at me and says, "Change your mind about giving me your number?" I literally have no idea what to say, and I mumble something, and jog back to the tennis courts.

Several days later I'm at the same grocery store where the first encounter happened, and he's there again. We pass each other, and I literally sprint to the checkout because I'm kind of freaked out. I pay, and exit the store. I get outside, and he's standing by the exit. I throw my items in my car as fast as I can and drive off. 

Finally, I'm out with my friends this past weekend at a bar not near the grocery store or the park where our previous encounters had taken place. I'm sitting at a booth with all my friends, and I see him walk in by himself and sit at the bar. He turns around, looks at me, and then turns back to the bar. I sit for about five minutes while this guy keeps turning around to look at me. I've had enough, and I tell one of my friends that I want to leave, so he leaves with me.

Extra info: I was stalked when I was a junior in high school by a man in his late 20s/early 30s, and I think I might just be freaking myself out due to this prior incident. I'm trying to convince myself that these are all just coincidences, but I believe that they're not. After writing this story out I'm basically convinced that I'm being stalked.

I don't know what I can do about this situation. He hasn't done anything to threaten me, but he does make me uncomfortable and uneasy. I know that stalking laws are sometimes hard to prove so I don't know if I should contact police or not. I have a fear of confronting him because I'm afraid that will only escalate his behavior. I feel like acknowledging him is exactly what he wants from me; if he can't get positive attention from me, he'll settle for negative attention.

Basically this boils down to: A) I am overreacting about this guy's behavior? B) If not, what can I do about it? C) I just need some support on this matter.

Thanks.

Edit: Added locations.  Never doubt your fear.  I honestly believe that one of the most damaging things in our society is the idea of "you're just being paranoid."  The far majority of people do not fear for no reason.

If someone freaks you out, avoid them.  If someone who freaks you out randomly shows up where you are in one of the biggest cities in the world, get as much evidence as you can, and call the police.

I would recommend setting up a system where if you see him again, you text or call a friend with your location and that you saw him again.  They will call or text you back in 15-30 minutes, and if you don't respond, they call the police.

Your fear is legitimate, and don't let anyone tell you otherwise.  Keep your support system in the know.  Do not fear taking pictures of him, or calling the police. Never doubt your fear.  I honestly believe that one of the most damaging things in our society is the idea of "you're just being paranoid."  The far majority of people do not fear for no reason.

If someone freaks you out, avoid them.  If someone who freaks you out randomly shows up where you are in one of the biggest cities in the world, get as much evidence as you can, and call the police.

I would recommend setting up a system where if you see him again, you text or call a friend with your location and that you saw him again.  They will call or text you back in 15-30 minutes, and if you don't respond, they call the police.

Your fear is legitimate, and don't let anyone tell you otherwise.  Keep your support system in the know.  Do not fear taking pictures of him, or calling the police.  No contact. Even negative contact will promote more of this. Next time he shows up someplace call the cops.  That's what I was telling my friends. When he showed up at the bar my one guy friend wanted to confront him, but I told him that I think that would only cause more problems. I don't want this to get more intense than it already is for me. I would probably talk to the police first just for advice but I would think that blatantly photographing him then texting it to someone or even yourself might put him off. He might assume there is an investigation. I wouldn't just let this slide. That's actually a really good point. My cousin's husband is a cop in my state so I might ask him the best way to go about this situation and the documentation. No contact. Even negative contact will promote more of this. Next time he shows up someplace call the cops.  I'm not sure how practical this advice is.  She didn't mention where she is  from, so I'm just imagining her in my town.  If it were my town, it would not be that surprising to run into someone in the store or bar, and you can't make someone else leave a place they also have a right to be (of course I don't know if he has followed her to these places or if it is a coincidence).  In my mind if he tries to make contact after being told no contact is wanted, that is when the police should be called.

Edit:  I see below this is NYC.....I have no idea what the frequency would be to run into a person 4 times over the course of week or so, so it may warrant further action. Pretty sure she said she was in NYC which would make this very unlikely and totally creepy.    Seeing as you live in NYC I would definitely be cautious about this. Are you opposed to carrying any kind of personal protection?? (Taser, mace, gun etc)  Sometimes people run into each other. It really depends on how big your town is. In a smaller town, people can run into each other a lot without intending to. 

However, that said, if he attempts to contact you in any way, contact the authorities.

I was stalked myself and I have a lot of sympathy for how scared you must feel right now. It'll be ok.  Honestly, the worst part is constant uneasiness. I've told all of my friends about it, in case anything happens.  I understand, it's hard to break free of the wariness and fear that kind of experience instills in you. I'm glad you have friends to watch out for you. Stay safe. {{ hugs }}   The freakiest thing about this is that the guy somehow manages to know where you are all the time! It seems like he would only be able to do this if he was following you from some set point where he knows he'll see you - like either the grocery store or your house or your work. Maybe I watch too much Dexter but at this point I would definitely a) call the police and b) buy a taser or mace. I know some people would never buy a taser, blah blah blah, but it'll probably make you feel a lot safer and if something horrible does happen you'll be able to defend yourself.   how big of a city do you live in? in a place with only a few grocery stores, parks, and bars, it could be coincidental that he's showed up at the same places you do. however, his behavior is a bit sketchy, especially if you live in a large city where he has no reason to keep ending up at the same places you do. i'd suggest keeping track of where he shows up, possibly even taking pictures, and talk to the police about it if he starts being creepier or showing up in more and more places? I live in NYC. The grocery store, the park, and the bar have been in separate boroughs of the city, which is why it's really unsettling for me. 

Pictures is a really good idea. I'm probably going to start writing everything down in a log just in case. I was skeptical at first, but the fact that you live in NYC changes things a lot. You can meet someone who lives in the building next to yours and never see them again, so the fact that you saw him in entirely different parts of the city is a bit too much to be a coincidence. 
 
The fact that he's also by himself when he runs into you is another sign that things are fishy. Yeah, and I wish I could accurately illustrate the smile that he always flashes me when we make eye contact. It's, quite honestly, the most unnerving part of this whole situation. He smiles at me like he knows what he's doing to me, like he knows how it's affecting me, and he enjoys it.  Yikes, so he doesn't even act surprised to see you? His name isn't "Tommy" is it (I ask this because I know of this very creepy guy who several other people, completely unrelated to how I've met him, have "run into")? I live in NYC. The grocery store, the park, and the bar have been in separate boroughs of the city, which is why it's really unsettling for me. 

Pictures is a really good idea. I'm probably going to start writing everything down in a log just in case. I live in NYC. The grocery store, the park, and the bar have been in separate boroughs of the city, which is why it's really unsettling for me. 

Pictures is a really good idea. I'm probably going to start writing everything down in a log just in case.   Please be careful and try not to get home at night by yourself! 
This guy sounds like a weirdo. I live in an apartment with four of my good friends, and I immediately told them about this guy when I first started to become concerned. They've been really supportive and have walked with me everywhere since. Thank goodness for good friends!   </snippet></document><document><title>I just got told I am positive for syphilis and I don't know what or how.... I'm lost. No symptoms. Please help</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18dzfx/i_just_got_told_i_am_positive_for_syphilis_and_i/</url><snippet>I was taking part of an egg donor program. Everything was fine, until I got tested for std's. It came up positive for syphilis. There is no way I feel like I could have gotten this. I've never had a bump or anything that health class told me was associated with syphilis. They retested me. It came up negative. They tested me again to make sure, it came up positive again. I'm freaking out. I have only had sex with one person, and I've been with him for 2 years now. He has no idea, he's freaking out. My mom just told me she did get herpes when she was 15 or 16. Can that make syphilis come up positive in a test? I was told my body had the antibodies to fight syphilis. They said it's possible my mom passed it to me from when she was pregnant, she says she has never had syphilis and herpes was the only thing that's ever happened to her. I can't stop crying. I feel disgusted, humiliated, embarrassed, and I just want to crawl in a hole and die. I've never slept around. I don't get how this could have happened. I'm trying to find my medical information now to schedule an appointment but I just need someone to talk to me. I can't believe this happened. Please if you know anything please reply. I am so broken right now. Please. I'm 18 years old. I'm cross posting this here because you all have been so helpful in the past and I just need to hear from someone. I can't wait. I am hysterical  Get tested again? Maybe it was a false positive. It's rare, but it happens. 

And... if it's not a false positive, it's very possible you contracted it from your boyfriend. This doesn't mean he cheated on you, it could mean he contracted it from a previous partner and never displayed any symptoms. 

Don't be embarrassed. Would you be embarrassed if you got a cold? Or the flu? Disease doesn't know its victims personally. You've gotten sick, that's all. Now all you have to do is get better. There's no reason for shame or humiliation.  I was told by my GP that the rate of false positives for certain diseases is actually higher than the rate of real positives. I think they're mostly concerned with eliminating false negatives. I was told by my GP that the rate of false positives for certain diseases is actually higher than the rate of real positives. I think they're mostly concerned with eliminating false negatives. I would consider this as that's what we all originally thought with the first test. But after the third test came up for it again, they sounded extremely positive that I have it I would consider this as that's what we all originally thought with the first test. But after the third test came up for it again, they sounded extremely positive that I have it I would consider this as that's what we all originally thought with the first test. But after the third test came up for it again, they sounded extremely positive that I have it Get tested again? Maybe it was a false positive. It's rare, but it happens. 

And... if it's not a false positive, it's very possible you contracted it from your boyfriend. This doesn't mean he cheated on you, it could mean he contracted it from a previous partner and never displayed any symptoms. 

Don't be embarrassed. Would you be embarrassed if you got a cold? Or the flu? Disease doesn't know its victims personally. You've gotten sick, that's all. Now all you have to do is get better. There's no reason for shame or humiliation.     Even if you have it (although this sounds really weird, but then again I'm no doctor), isn't syphilis treatable with antibiotics?


Edit: I know lab results can get messed up sometimes. I know people who were told they had hep C by one lab, when they didn't actually have it. Try getting tested at another lab. I have no idea. I feel so stupid. I think it's only treatable in the first 2 years? I don't know. I don't know if it's possible for me to pass it. Edit: I was tested at 2 different labs I have no idea. I feel so stupid. I think it's only treatable in the first 2 years? I don't know. I don't know if it's possible for me to pass it. Edit: I was tested at 2 different labs I have no idea. I feel so stupid. I think it's only treatable in the first 2 years? I don't know. I don't know if it's possible for me to pass it. Edit: I was tested at 2 different labs    Syphilis is easily treatable with antibiotics, and can be asymptomatic. It can be transferred even with condom use.

...All that with a simple google search. I mean really.

(Regarding herpes: there are many types of herpes, most of which aren't related to sex. Measles are a type of herpes. So get tested for that while you're at it.)  &amp;gt; Measles are a type of herpes. 

No.  Herpes is caused by a herpesvirus; measles is caused by a paramyxovirus.  They are both viruses but that's about it.

Perhaps you were thinking of the fact that Varicella zoster, which causes chicken pox and shingles, is a herpesvirus?  &amp;gt; Measles are a type of herpes. 

No.  Herpes is caused by a herpesvirus; measles is caused by a paramyxovirus.  They are both viruses but that's about it.

Perhaps you were thinking of the fact that Varicella zoster, which causes chicken pox and shingles, is a herpesvirus?  FYI my parents couldn't get married in the 60's because my dad tested positive for syphillis. Apparently it's not uncommon to test false positive.  So... What happened?  Hey, it'll be okay. Even if you do have syphilis, you'll be fine. STDs aren't some horrible, dirty thing. It is [estimated](http://womenshealth.gov/publications/our-publications/fact-sheet/sexually-transmitted-infections.cfm) that 19 million people contract an STD every year in the USA. It's like getting the flu or a cold. Getting bronchitis isn't a big deal, you get antibiotics and go on your way. Most STDs (including syphilis) are the same, you take some medication and it clears up.

The only reason people think STDs are some awful shameful thing is because you (usually) get them from having sex. But sex isn't something to be ashamed of and so STDs shouldn't be something to be ashamed of. I'm not trying to invalidate your feelings, there is a lot of stigma attached to STDs so of course you are going to feel awful, I am just trying to show that they aren't some big bad scary thing. &amp;lt;3


Good luck! Seriously, there is such a stigma attached to STD's even though many are as curable as taking a z-pack. 

Don't feel ashamed or guilty, just take the antibiotics, have a conversation with your boyfriend (not an accusatory one) and consider it a lesson learned.  For sure! And a lot of people have STDs and just don't know it, since they can often be asymptomatic in a significant population. I mean, it is estimated that at least 50% of sexually active people in the US get HPV at some point in their lives, and that is just one type of many STD/STIs you can get. I think the problems is that it is considered shameful so people don't talk about it so we assume only "dirty" people get it so it is considered shameful and the sad cycle continues. It is just SO easy to get an STD. Your partner could have been tested in the window where the infection doesn't show up on the test, or gotten a false negative, or wasn't tested for every STD (which seems to happen a lot), or any number of things. And of course there is a stigma over even getting TESTED which makes people lie or avoid getting one and it just makes things spread that much more easily.  Some STDs can't really be tested for. A lot of people have this false notion that they are completely STI free if they have clean blood work from a STD screen, but in reality things like Herpes and HPV can't be tested for that way. The only way you find out you have HPV or Herpes is if you show symptoms, but many people don't show symptoms. Especially with HPV symptoms in otherwise healthy people (especially men) are somewhat rare. There is really no test for HPV for men, and the only way HPV is diagnosed in women is through a Pap. Herpes is only diagnosed if you have Herpes sores. 

Tl;dr You can have a "clean STD test", but actually have HPV and Herpes.            False positives are common in syphilis testing. Also, you can get it from sharing a drink with someone or sitting on a dirty toilet seat. It has a terribly negative connotation as connected with risky sex but do not feel embarrassed. There is nothing wrong with you and you have no irritating symptoms. All you have are three inconclusive tests - see where that takes you. Keep your health updated. Talk to your boyfriend. He needs to know and you need to share. Absolutely true that false positives are very common.  However, you can't get it from [sharing a drink or from a toilet seat](http://www.niaid.nih.gov/topics/syphilis/understanding/Pages/transmission.aspx).  Well shucks. I had a pretty crappy education. I just repeated what my school nurse told me during sex ed day. Thanks for correcting me. Trust me... you are not the only one who learned less-than-correct information in sex ed :-)  Now you can confidently sit on public toilet seats free of worry. Well shucks. I had a pretty crappy education. I just repeated what my school nurse told me during sex ed day. Thanks for correcting me. That woman should be fired. I didn't know anyone actually still believed that nonsense. </snippet></document><document><title>This is MY body! Amazing and empowering video... </title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=z2ME8sR-bnY</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Volunteering with a local abortion and sexual health clinic</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18e7zo/volunteering_with_a_local_abortion_and_sexual/</url><snippet>I've decided to volunteer with a local abortion clinic, because I really believe in a woman's access to safe and low cost abortions and sexual education. My dream is to do presentations about sexual health and safe sex and relationships. Have any of you had experience volunteering in a women's clinic or center? I want to get some idea of what I will be getting into, since I've never done anything like that before.  It really depends on the clinic. At our local sexual health clinic, they don't perform abortions in the clinic itself but they do provide referrals. Volunteers are trained to answer phones, check in patients, organize lab specimens, set up exam rooms, etc. They are vital to running the clinic smoothly. If you're interested in sexual health, volunteering is definitely a great way to learn a lot about it!</snippet></document><document><title>Romance on a budget? Is it possible?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ekmi/romance_on_a_budget_is_it_possible/</url><snippet>I frequently equate romantic evenings with nice dinners and expensive gifts. My girlfriend of 4 years has told me the entire time we have been dating that "expensive" does not always mean romantic. I am honestly at a loss. How do I show her this valentines day?           You can do things like: 

* make her a card (I make them for my boyfriend in mspaint)
* do something around the house that she hates
* make her dinner or make her a type of sweet or cake
* take her to the beach/for a walk somewhere nice/go look at stars (you can look up online when things will be visible and point them out to her)
* make her a playlist of romantic songs that make you think of her
* write a poem
* give her a massage or have a bath together
* have lots of sex
* watch a movie on the couch together under a doona (unless it's summer or something :P then be naked)
 Watch tv naked? I am ALWAYS trying to get you to watch tv naked!  :c
 It's always freezing!         </snippet></document><document><title>Government experts say research should focus more on breast cancer prevention than diagnosis and cure.</title><url>http://www.medpagetoday.com/HematologyOncology/BreastCancer/37334</url><snippet>  Prevention?  Don't those officials know that cancer is a problem with your genes?  Don't they know that cancer 'just happens'? 

Next they'll try and tell me that major industry is to blame for the ever-increasing instances of cancer throughout our country. I bought my pink buckets of KFC to support breast cancer, so whose to say there isn't enough being done for this disease already. The article went into your argument. It said most cases are in people who have no family history. I'm not sure how accurate it is, though. But don't you think that if we find environmental factors that are consistent that  it would be more feasible to prevent more cases?  Not really, we know so much about what causes cancer.  in fact, it seems as though there is no other disease out there that we know MORE about for why people get it and what causes it. given that our food, air, and water is continuously getting more toxic, thanks to governments that turn a blind, bribed eye to major industry, does it really matter what causes cancer anymore?  Everyone is toxic...that's why cancer happens.  Modern medicine can't address any of the CAUSES of cancer with any of the treatments it offers, so why spend money finding out that almost everything around us causes it? It's not just discussing chemical factors, though.  I don't think it can hurt to look at breast cancer from a different angle.  It is the most highly funded cancer anyway, so I don't think it would hurt.  If we know what the causes are, we can treat the root of the problem instead of cherry-picking symptoms.  Just a thought.</snippet></document><document><title>How Etsy Grew Its Female Engineers By 500% In 1 Year</title><url>http://www.sfgate.com/technology/businessinsider/article/How-Etsy-Grew-Its-Female-Engineers-By-500-In-1-4270079.php</url><snippet>    Why does the gender of your company's engineers matter? It is usually a sign of gender bias.  If two qualified people are interviewed, most firms will hire the male candidate more often because male engineers prefer working with men.  

There are many tech companies that intentionally hire only men.  SW developers are notorious at underestimating female candidates.  They think most women are not as good as male developers, so they toss out resumes with female sounding names more often.

I used to work for a company that was bought by Microsoft.  I used to work from 9am to 11pm most days of the week.  If I can't commit to the long hours because other obligations (doc appointment, sick, surgery), I have to make it up on the weekend. So when female candidates say they have kids, they automatically don't get considered for the job.  If a male candidate say he has kids, it is assumed that his wife or partner will take care of the childcare.  When Microsoft took over, that shitty hiring practice stopped and actually hired more people so there is a night shift.  Most of the night shift developers were women with kids. What the hell are you talking about?

Do you have any idea how in demand female engineers are?  I know from personal experience that companies will pay top dollar to recruit from the limited pool of qualified female engineers.  Female hires at my company typically receive a starting pay that is, at least, 30% in excess of the starting pay that male hires would receive.  They're also promoted more frequently and they get excused for not doing any real work.

Most tech companies want to present themselves as companies that value diversity, and they will pay through the nose to do so.  </snippet></document><document><title>Need advice on how to break up with live-in SO</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/TwoXChromosomes/comments/18ded5/need_advice_on_how_to_break_up_with_livein_so/</url><snippet>Hi TwoX, if this is the wrong sub I will get rid of it, but I'm here because I took stock of my relationships and I have not a single person that I can discuss this with. 

It's a very long, painful, complicated story so the basics are:

Meet guy when I am 12, date on/off for high school, get back together immediately out of high school, he buys a house and we move in together immediately after college. He has severe emotional disturbances due to a very abusive childhood. Mommy issues, abandonment issues, control issues. He beats me sporadically. He sees therapists *very* sporadically. Okay, that's the gory stuff. 

I want to move out. We've lived here almost a year and I want to cut my losses and run away. He works regular hours and I work the night shift so we don't see each other much, but when we do it's confusing. He is constantly making me dinner, doing chores and errands for me, buying me presents, et cetera. This would be much appreciated if he hadn't beat the shit out of me for years. I am emotionally numb and sometimes I contemplate suicide. Not any real plans, just the easiest and least messy way to do it.  

So I realize I need to leave. The thing is, I've been with this guy for like ten years, since I was basically a child. Our lives are hopelessly intertwined. I take night courses, getting my degree bit by bit, so I have a shit paying job. I've been looking at apartments, even just studio ones, and the prices make me want to cry. I've saved up a nest egg that's around $3,000 right now and just paid off my car. 

So I'm emotionally and financially glued to this guy, who is constantly alternating between trying to drown me in good deeds to "make up for it" to show how much he loves me, or spitting in my face and choking me till my vision gets dim. I keep typing excuses, like "I could be nicer" or "I shouldn't nag him so much" and then erasing them- I really, really need to escape.

I would give almost anything to not have to be nervous all the goddamn time- he is constantly berating me about my need for therapy because I'm so anxious and depressed. I can't afford it right now. I walk on eggshells and flinch when he moves quickly and when I'm forced to be in the same bed as him I literally lay awake and seethe and dream of being free from him- I haven't had sex that I enjoyed in four years. Our sex life is nil. I just freeze up when we try, usually once every month or so, I let him go till he gets off , and sometimes I cry. That's my love life. 


Will a domestic abuse victim shelter help me find a place to live? I will have to move out of my house to the scary slums of a very big city nearby because I have no money and make very little, and that scares me. My family, who has no idea obviously, can't house me or help me financially. I have no friends, except a very nice roommate who I won't ask to move out with me (she also has no idea and is really enjoying our house and her low rent, she needs it.)


I guess I'm just ashamed. Who can I ask for help that won't judge me? Because I really, really need some help :(

I'm sorry this is so long and I will remove if out of place.  First of all, I'm sorry that you've had to endure this treatment from this abusive asswipe. You do not deserve it; you deserve to be treated with love and respect and kindness. I am glad to hear that you are at the point where you are ready to leave. Congratulations, this is a really hard thing to decide. Making plans and preparations like you've been doing is great- it is just what you should be doing to get ready to GO.

You are in the type of situation domestic violence shelters exist to help. Shelters vary from locality to locality in specifics, but in general they are all safe buildings where you can go to rest, heal, and make plans for a safe, secure future away from your abuser, with the help of a team of advocates. 

Different shelters have different resources; it depends on where you live. However, each shelter works with you to make an individualized plan for you, determining where you are going to go next and helping you get there. Many shelters have their own transitional housing, which is low-cost housing for women to live in while they are still healing and figuring out longer term plans. Even if the shelter doesn't have its own transitional housing, it can help you find trans housing in your area, or other low-cost housing options.

You can search for shelters in your area online, or you can call the national DV hotline at 1-800-799-7233, explain your situation and they will transfer you to a shelter in your area while you wait on the line. 

When you speak to the person on the hotline, they will go through safety planning with you, coming up with a plan with you how to safely gather your things and get out of the situation and into the shelter. 

I encourage you to make the call and take another step forward towards your new, independent, safe and stable life!

Source: DV Shelter manager for 5 years (in VA) Thank you for your information. I have the local DV hotline number saved in my phone. I know I can call them for help, I just haven't quite gotten the nerve yet. I feel better knowing they sometimes have their own safe housing, I might try to research our area online to find out more. Now I just have to work on getting the cojones   Thank you for your information. I have the local DV hotline number saved in my phone. I know I can call them for help, I just haven't quite gotten the nerve yet. I feel better knowing they sometimes have their own safe housing, I might try to research our area online to find out more. Now I just have to work on getting the cojones   Thank you for your information. I have the local DV hotline number saved in my phone. I know I can call them for help, I just haven't quite gotten the nerve yet. I feel better knowing they sometimes have their own safe housing, I might try to research our area online to find out more. Now I just have to work on getting the cojones   First of all, I'm sorry that you've had to endure this treatment from this abusive asswipe. You do not deserve it; you deserve to be treated with love and respect and kindness. I am glad to hear that you are at the point where you are ready to leave. Congratulations, this is a really hard thing to decide. Making plans and preparations like you've been doing is great- it is just what you should be doing to get ready to GO.

You are in the type of situation domestic violence shelters exist to help. Shelters vary from locality to locality in specifics, but in general they are all safe buildings where you can go to rest, heal, and make plans for a safe, secure future away from your abuser, with the help of a team of advocates. 

Different shelters have different resources; it depends on where you live. However, each shelter works with you to make an individualized plan for you, determining where you are going to go next and helping you get there. Many shelters have their own transitional housing, which is low-cost housing for women to live in while they are still healing and figuring out longer term plans. Even if the shelter doesn't have its own transitional housing, it can help you find trans housing in your area, or other low-cost housing options.

You can search for shelters in your area online, or you can call the national DV hotline at 1-800-799-7233, explain your situation and they will transfer you to a shelter in your area while you wait on the line. 

When you speak to the person on the hotline, they will go through safety planning with you, coming up with a plan with you how to safely gather your things and get out of the situation and into the shelter. 

I encourage you to make the call and take another step forward towards your new, independent, safe and stable life!

Source: DV Shelter manager for 5 years (in VA)  &amp;gt; I have no friends, except a very nice roommate who I won't ask to move out with me (she also has no idea and is really enjoying our house and her low rent, she needs it.)

Please please tell this person something before you go, so that they're not stuck/become your abuser's next victim. Take her with you.   Call around the local domestic violence shelters, and make sure you have somewhere to go when you leave.  You need to get yourself a decent holdall, put everything that you need to survive in it (things like your bank paperwork, your passport, and a decent chunk of clothing) and then take it and go.  Get in your car and go.   I get that far in my mental planning and then then the other fears swarm in- I think okay, stay at a hotel for a few nights. I can't afford any longer than that. But then what? The only thing I've come up with is a shelter or throwing myself on the mercy of his adoptive parents (very nice but intimidating people)I don't think I can afford to live alone and I don't have any friends anymore, so no possible roommates or couches to crash on either. What next? I know it's up to me to figure it out, that's why I posted here for advice  &amp;gt;I don't think I can afford to live alone and I don't have any friends anymore, so no possible roommates or couches to crash on either.

Can you find people on Craigslist who need a roommate? Often if you go meet them before agreeing to take the room, you can vet them a bit to see if they're easy to live with. I've lived with a couple of Craigslist randos in my time, and they've both been really nice women. I get that far in my mental planning and then then the other fears swarm in- I think okay, stay at a hotel for a few nights. I can't afford any longer than that. But then what? The only thing I've come up with is a shelter or throwing myself on the mercy of his adoptive parents (very nice but intimidating people)I don't think I can afford to live alone and I don't have any friends anymore, so no possible roommates or couches to crash on either. What next? I know it's up to me to figure it out, that's why I posted here for advice  I get that far in my mental planning and then then the other fears swarm in- I think okay, stay at a hotel for a few nights. I can't afford any longer than that. But then what? The only thing I've come up with is a shelter or throwing myself on the mercy of his adoptive parents (very nice but intimidating people)I don't think I can afford to live alone and I don't have any friends anymore, so no possible roommates or couches to crash on either. What next? I know it's up to me to figure it out, that's why I posted here for advice     Your life is in danger. Please, please get to a shelter as soon as possible. Why can't your family help you? My family is well meaning but, to be blunt, poor. I have been financially independent of them since I was 15, they just dont have enough. i think that's why I am so afraid of striking out alone. No support system whatsoever. They filled my bedroom the same month I moved out- my grandfather needed somewhere to stay. So that's not an option. They're so proud of me I can't imagine telling them, :( Why would they be less proud of you? You are in a horrible situation. It is not your fault. If your family cares about you, they will help you. My family is well meaning but, to be blunt, poor. I have been financially independent of them since I was 15, they just dont have enough. i think that's why I am so afraid of striking out alone. No support system whatsoever. They filled my bedroom the same month I moved out- my grandfather needed somewhere to stay. So that's not an option. They're so proud of me I can't imagine telling them, :( My family is well meaning but, to be blunt, poor. I have been financially independent of them since I was 15, they just dont have enough. i think that's why I am so afraid of striking out alone. No support system whatsoever. They filled my bedroom the same month I moved out- my grandfather needed somewhere to stay. So that's not an option. They're so proud of me I can't imagine telling them, :(  Hi. Not sure where you live, but you have a job and a car and three grand in the bank. That is more than enough to leave him. I left mine with no money in the bank and a brand new job in a city I had just moved to. I found a place for $800 a month in the most sought after area of Seattle. My best friend lived around the corner from me in a studio apartment for $600. I promise you, these places are out there. You don't have to go to a shelter...and at this point it's possible that going to a shelter might make you feel even more like a victim. Take your three grand and put a deposit on an apartment or rent a room!         </snippet></document><document><title>A guy who gets it's rant on rape culture</title><url>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/when-a-drunk-girl-passes-out-and-a-group-of-boys-rape-her-this-is-who-to-blame/</url><snippet>  I should tag this with a trigger warning but I don't know how :/ It's stated at the top of the article that it could be triggering and has rape in the title, but still. You can't do it, only a mod can.   They're pretty good about that though.</snippet></document></searchresult>