<searchresult><uiuc /><document><title>Question for CS students</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16f0qq/question_for_cs_students/</url><snippet>Why is the class registration system so bad? Would it actually be hard to implement a feature like say, automatically suggesting different sections if there is a time conflict?

I know the CS department is not in charge of the website. Im only asking because im mean to CS and i might be missing some security or technical limitations, that you guys might know about.

TL;DR. Is the student self service a result of bad design choices, or is it more complicated than im thinking it is.        My adviser said something alone the lines that I better get used to it because the university actually buys Banner from a 3rd party and the university requires it I be FERPA-complient  Banner isn't actually that old. It's just a really junky system that the university paid millions upon millions of dollars for- the same reason that we use a lot of the online learning portals.   it pretty much comes down to the fact that higher-ups making these decisions could care less what they pay for. they go out to dinner with the salesman and buy the product. they don't ever use it, therefore, they could give a shit

if professors or students or anyone who had to use this shitty software made the decisions, it'd be different</snippet></document><document><title>Is there a list of the companies attending the engineering career fair?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16dr77/is_there_a_list_of_the_companies_attending_the/</url><snippet>I've looked everywhere and can't seem to find one. This is so I can get an idea which companies to read up on.   A [list](http://expo.web.cs.illinois.edu/students_complist.php) for the Expo. Thanks, I've seen that list. I was wondering if there was a similar list for the career fair in january.  You have to be signed up for simplicity through the Engineering Career Services. I'd link but I'm on my phone. Happy hunting! You have to be signed up for simplicity through the Engineering Career Services. I'd link but I'm on my phone. Happy hunting! I tried to sign up for that a month ago, but it told me that a staff member had to approve my account, and it has been a month, and I still can't sign in. Does it usually take this long? Have you paid ecs $40 yet? After I paid them they approved my account. I believe OP can have access to the same services through [I-Link](https://tcc-illinois-csm.symplicity.com/students/index.php?s=jobs&amp;amp;ss=applied&amp;amp;mode=list). Is there any advantage of signing up through ECS? There are 142 companies attending the ECS career fair, according to I-Link. Tried this, but it says my email is already in the system so I can't sign up again.  Try to log in then. If that doesn't work, try changing your password. Have you paid ecs $40 yet? After I paid them they approved my account. haven't done that, I'm guessing there's no way to do this online, so I'll have to wait till I'm back on campus. </snippet></document><document><title>Any open mic nights around town?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16e3wl/any_open_mic_nights_around_town/</url><snippet>I was wondering if there were any open mic events at bars/coffee shops around town? I'm trying to get out there and play as much music as I can!  tuesday nights (i think 10 pm) at cowboy monkey Thanks! I'll have to check it out!  Green street cafe Do you know what day/time they usually have it?  </snippet></document><document><title>Oh, so we're submitting new mascots now?</title><url>http://imgur.com/6vJXr</url><snippet>  "Chef Illiniwok" Real original Sean... 

Edit: please refer to my post from 2 years ago. 
http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/eo32x/my_submission_for_the_new_university_of_illinois/ I've been caught! "Chef Illiniwok"  Really? No one's posted the [good version?](http://murph.cc/pictures/uiuchef.jpg) xD Really? No one's posted the [good version?](http://murph.cc/pictures/uiuchef.jpg) xD I'm so glad you posted this - I have the shirt but couldn't find a good picture of the logo to post!

As a side note, the shirt is hilarious to wear on game days (like a Chief shirt, it has that logo on the back, and CHEF in big letters on the front).  People can't really figure out what to think about it.  It's great. Really? No one's posted the [good version?](http://murph.cc/pictures/uiuchef.jpg) xD       </snippet></document><document><title>Warhol inspired painting I did my freshman year, 4 years ago! Save the Chief!</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/JzX4H.jpg</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>Checking my Illinois email</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16dub1/checking_my_illinois_email/</url><snippet>Hey guys, I have my Illinois account set up so that emails sent to that account get forwarded to my Gmail account. I recently bought a bus ticket using my Illinois account, but the email didn't reach my Gmail. When I tried logging on to Google Apps @ Illinois, it wasn't able to process my request. Is there a way to fix this or get around it? Thanks in advance!  Ugh this sounds like a mess. Just use one email! I wish I did lol How long ago did you buy the ticket? Maybe it just hasnt been sent yet.
 At least 6 hours ago, so I'm pretty sure the ticket has been sent. Check the spam filters of both your Illinois and main Gmail accounts.

Edit* Nvm I re-read what you said and you can't even get into your account.    Did you buy through Suburban Express? This happened to me once. I used Google Chrome's autofill feature to fill out my info. I'd go to the form, and arrow down to see all the possible emails it could've been, and check all of them.   Are you sure the ticket got charged? First check your credit card to make sure it went through. If it did, the next question is how you set up the forwarding. Did you set it up through the actual email account? Or did you set it up through the CITES portal where you physically say any email that gets sent to your @illinois automatically gets forwarded to gmail? 

Those are two pretty big distinctions. If the former, you should be able to login, if the latter then I suspect it was an issue on the bus company. Yes, I checked my bank account and it definitely got charged. I set up the forwarding through CITES when I first came here. It was a while ago, so I don't remember all the details. Also, I wasn't able to login to Google Apps @ Illinois so I'm pretty sure it was through CITES.</snippet></document><document><title>My band will be in town on Feb 15th. What bar/venue could we play?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16d4ef/my_band_will_be_in_town_on_feb_15th_what_barvenue/</url><snippet>My band, The Howl, will potentially be in town on Feb 15th if we can find a place to play. We may have a house show lined up but were looking for a bar/venue we could play earlier in the evening to help earn some gas money. We're an indie/punk band from Chicago.

Facebook.com/TheHowlChicago

the-howl.bandcamp.com  [deleted]   Hey!

Off topic but I'm a photographer and have heard you guys before and would totally be down to shoot you if you end up playing a venue around here.

My portfolio is at: www.dalzellphoto.com

That said, check out Mike N Mollys, Canopy Club, or Highdive. I'd try to avoid the majority of campus bars, the off campus bars/venues are known more for their music.   </snippet></document><document><title>Anyone play instruments wanna jam</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16deze/anyone_play_instruments_wanna_jam/</url><snippet>Hey im sophmore studying CS, would like to find some people on campus to jam with. Looking for people that just wanna have fun hanging out and playing music, nothing to serious. Ive been playing maybe 5 years but im not that great, due to not practicing as much as i used to. 

Anyway some influences include Metallica, The Strokes, RATM, RHCP... but im down to play anything   you should probably mention what instrument you play - i'm assuming guitar </snippet></document><document><title>Engineering career fair advice?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16d366/engineering_career_fair_advice/</url><snippet>The career fair on Jan 29-30 will be the first one I'll be attending. Is there any advice some more experienced people can offer? I'm a sophomore in CS trying to get an internship for this summer. For example, are there certain questions I should memorize responses for?   1. You should most definitely wear a suit or at least a dress shirt and nice pants/shoes.

2. Print out a professional name tag from the ECS office in DCL beforehand. You can skip the line to enter the fair that way.

3. RESEARCH THE COMPANIES BEFORE YOU ENTER THE FAIR. Check out the attendees on symplicity and google every company that seems even mildly interesting to you. Convey the knowledge you learn from your search in your conversation with the reps on the floor. It DEFINITELY shows interest and initiative.

4. Prepare/update your resume with all of your latest classes, projects, skills, GPA, etc. Bring multiple copies (I usually bring 10-15) in a nice folder.

5. Have a 20-30 second opening statement in mind when you approach company reps, e.g. "Hi my name is ____ and I'm a ____ in ______ interested in ______. I'm very interested in _____ , which I understand your company does as well." or something like that

6. Quite a few of the reps coming will be UIUC alumni, so don't be afraid to engage them on a more personal/friendly level. Don't be uptight! Be somebody that they would be interested in talking to. Smile!

7. Always prepare questions about the company/work/etc to ask them to keep the conversation going. They'll remember you better later on.

8. Not totally sure about CS companies since I'm in EE, but in the past I've gotten a few easy questions relating to some circuit stuff. I would imagine the questions wouldn't be too hard, but more used as a way to see how you think on your feet (literally) in such an environment. Just breathe, and talk through your answers. I don't actually think many companies even ask tech questions at the career fairs...
        </snippet></document><document><title>Any apartments on or very near campus that are unfurnished?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16dgug/any_apartments_on_or_very_near_campus_that_are/</url><snippet>I searched the subreddit and I've asked a bunch of people if these places exist. So far it is a negative. I figured I would ask you guys as my last resort and see if there were any place that rent out, but DON'T have furniture with the apartment. Thanks for the input!

Etch  According to Bankier's website, it seems like you can get most of their apartments unfurnished if you want.  I also know that Cassel Properties has some unfurnished units just to the east of Lincoln Ave.   Are you looking for a one bedroom?  [deleted]  Look up The Weiner Companies. They have a lot of unfurnished apartments.  Joe Allan properties, the building on white and wright. My friend stays there and its pretty amazing. condo-ish for 600. 
the property isnt showing on their website, but you can walk around see it there.
Also here is another one i pulled off their website: 
http://joeallanproperties.com/or/index.php?action=listingview&amp;amp;listingID=40

You should call them and find out about the property on wright and white</snippet></document><document><title>Parking at UIUC</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16bykw/parking_at_uiuc/</url><snippet>Hey guys,

I am bringing a car next semester, but my apartment complex is full. Besides lot E-14, does anyone know where I can park my car for the semester?  You can park for free on most streets in Urbana if you move your vehicle every 72 hours.

Also, if you look on craigslist there are lots of people selling parking space or garage space. I checked on craigslist. Thank you for all the help. 
 You can park for free on most streets in Urbana if you move your vehicle every 72 hours.

Also, if you look on craigslist there are lots of people selling parking space or garage space.     If any apartment complexes around yours have unused parking spaces, you could see if you could pay to park there. Or if you were really desperate, you could chance it and park in an unused spot. I can't speak for every property management group on campus, but mine (Advantage) was very relaxed about their unused spaces. My roommate and several other people utilized a number of the extra spaces for several months. None of them were towed.  Hey, someone ambitious should make a sidebar item about parking!  It's a question I get asked a lot, but since I don't have a car down here it's not something I usually know the answer to.  If you're ever down for just a weekend, there's a lot on sixth and (I think) daniels that's free over weekends. This is already in the sidebar. This is already in the sidebar.  Champaign-Urbana has some of the best public transit in the world and it is 100% FREE to students and University employees.

Take the fucking bus. Ever have to carry a full load of groceries on the bus? Probably not, because its not fun. Also booze runs, dry cleaning, and many other conveniences....
  Basement of many CPM buildings. You can rent from them or not. It would be almost impossible to tow out of there, especially if you turned and locked the wheel and pulled the e brake. If you have a SUV theres no way in hell they could tow you. Basement of many CPM buildings. You can rent from them or not. It would be almost impossible to tow out of there, especially if you turned and locked the wheel and pulled the e brake. If you have a SUV theres no way in hell they could tow you. Basement of many CPM buildings. You can rent from them or not. It would be almost impossible to tow out of there, especially if you turned and locked the wheel and pulled the e brake. If you have a SUV theres no way in hell they could tow you. They tow people all the time. CPM towed my room-mate a couple years ago, and we even lived at the building and he had the parking permit in his windshield. They've also towed one of my friends who wasn't parked longer than 20 minutes. What wound up happening with your roommate? Did they refund the tow, like a decent company should, or did they act like CPM? </snippet></document><document><title>My submission to the new mascot contest</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/c8W0q.jpg</url><snippet>    Whoever did this is brilliant.    Pardon my ignorance, but what is that supposed to mean? Whose face is it? With the nearly 100 upvotes this post has got, I must be the only one who missed something obvious. http://www.pri.org/stories/arts-entertainment/arts/amateur-restoration-botches-jesus-painting-in-spain-11245.html

It's been swirling around the internet here and there. It sold for $1400 on ebay recently too. http://www.pri.org/stories/arts-entertainment/arts/amateur-restoration-botches-jesus-painting-in-spain-11245.html

It's been swirling around the internet here and there. It sold for $1400 on ebay recently too.     </snippet></document><document><title>Can I get a ride back on Sunday the 13th from O'Hare?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16c6vf/can_i_get_a_ride_back_on_sunday_the_13th_from/</url><snippet>If you're going back anytime before 3 pm I would be so grateful if you could give me a ride back. I'd pay all gas expenses. Thanks!

EDIT: I found a ride.   If you're okay with riding on the roof of a station wagon, then yes. I'll finally understand how it is to be Mitt Romney's dog.  I'm thinking of heading down around then. What time does your flight get in and how much shit do you have?</snippet></document><document><title>yeah, we lost tonight, but here's BP3 posterizing mbakwe</title><url>http://imgur.com/jlxeV</url><snippet>    boss. Post this to /r/CollegeBasketball/. They will love it. beaten to it by a husker...  basket shouldn't have counted - mbakwe takes a charge before brandon releases the ball, but i'll take the points anyway   </snippet></document><document><title>DAE Jeff Mangum 1/15?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16cbm2/dae_jeff_mangum_115/</url><snippet>Just wondering if anyone else here was planning on going to the Jeff Mangum show in Bloomington, IN on the 15th and if they had a vehicle.  I'm not looking forward to an 8 hour bus ride if no one can drive me ;__;  Wish I knew about this earlier.   Does anybody else Jeff Mangum 1/15?   Of course, it's completely sold out :( Sorry they sold out a few hours after they went on sale:\ </snippet></document><document><title>Can you help me get home? sunday 13th</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16b4fs/can_you_help_me_get_home_sunday_13th/</url><snippet>I have a flight that arrives to midway at 8pm on sunday. If you could give me a ride back to champaign you'd be my hero, and i would happily pay for all the gas.   http://www.peoriacharter.com/ - There's a 9:55pm bus on sunday... I am on it.</snippet></document><document><title>Demolition of Garcia's Pizza and White Horse Today (Album)</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/F04mk</url><snippet>  I wish they'd improve the streetscape of Green from 4th to at least 1st (preferably Neil). It's nice walking from Wright to 4th but then all of a sudden it becomes kind of dumpy looking. I'd be with you if you could guarantee that it wouldn't be filled with more chain restaurants.  Walking from Wright to 4th makes me feel like I'm in a commercial break. the street improvements are exactly what led to this -- but I'll take it over what it used to look like The old white ho was the only view I had from my balcony, RIP. That stretch of green if kinda bleh, hopefully things change. White Ho was the first bar I went to as a Freshman. I'd be with you if you could guarantee that it wouldn't be filled with more chain restaurants.  Walking from Wright to 4th makes me feel like I'm in a commercial break.   /cry for a time when Garcia's was good. I miss their hot air balloon *nostalgia* one of my earliest memories is flipping the fuck as a toddler out because my mom won some contest and got to ride in it.

edit - for a double dose, anybody here remember land of mexico? Sounds familiar... remind me? mexican restaurant in the white ho building. i remember jello cups. run out of business when cancun / margaritas / whatever it is called now opened in 96 at sunnycrest Ha yeah I was 8 in 96 so I don't remember that I was 6 but I fucking loved land of mexico one of my earliest memories is flipping the fuck as a toddler out because my mom won some contest and got to ride in it.

edit - for a double dose, anybody here remember land of mexico? one of my earliest memories is flipping the fuck as a toddler out because my mom won some contest and got to ride in it.

edit - for a double dose, anybody here remember land of mexico? I miss their hot air balloon  /cry for a time when Garcia's was good.  /cry for a time when Garcia's was good. My parents met at the location that is now coco mero.  Wish it was still around. Moonstruck? How long was Moonstruck there before it closed? It was definitely THE place for a first date. Those artisan truffles ... and tiramisu cheesecake ... places on Green Streen come and go, but I have never felt sadder than when Moonstruck closed.   Moonstruck? That was a Garcia's location in the 80s, Moonstruck was the 2000s.   whoa... some crazy good karaoke @ WH... idk how to feel It moved at the beginning of the year to where firestation used to be. Wait wait wait. White Horse is where Fire Station used to be? I'm not sure what to think of that. Wait wait wait. White Horse is where Fire Station used to be? I'm not sure what to think of that. Wait wait wait. White Horse is where Fire Station used to be? I'm not sure what to think of that. Wait wait wait. White Horse is where Fire Station used to be? I'm not sure what to think of that. And Fire Station was* where Bar Louie used to be. It moved at the beginning of the year to where firestation used to be. RIP station.  not station, but firestation.  i just had to have this explained to me.  feeling old. Station is gone too.  They turned it into a Medieval themed bar called "The Red Lion".  No more cheap pitchers of rum and coke or whiskey and coke.  I miss White Ho Wednesdays even more now. White Ho still exists - its on John street just east of Imsomnia. Its where Firestation used to be. What's the atmosphere like in the new one? What's the atmosphere like in the new one? What's the atmosphere like in the new one?    Do we know what's going in their place?  Another apartment building, I assume? I would assume. I saw a sign that said Tartan Realty when I would walk past there - same sign is in front of the lot at the corner of Green &amp;amp; 4th where that new Roland building is supposed to be. Not sure if that means that a Roland building would be built in that spot, but I wouldn't be surprised at all if that were the case. From the Tartan Realty website:

&amp;gt;This new campustown project is the second phase to the existing building at 308. This new phase will have retail on the ground level providing a highly visible location to tenants and a quality build. Located on the Green St. shopping corridor with food, bars, shops and more this project adds another option for campustown retail tenants looking to be in the heart of the action just North of campus. Located 1 mile from the stadium and just minutes walking distance from the union and library. 

However, I'm confused because the "existing building at 308" is IHOP. From the Tartan Realty website:

&amp;gt;This new campustown project is the second phase to the existing building at 308. This new phase will have retail on the ground level providing a highly visible location to tenants and a quality build. Located on the Green St. shopping corridor with food, bars, shops and more this project adds another option for campustown retail tenants looking to be in the heart of the action just North of campus. Located 1 mile from the stadium and just minutes walking distance from the union and library. 

However, I'm confused because the "existing building at 308" is IHOP. Do we know what's going in their place?  Another apartment building, I assume?  Holy shit, finally. Curious to see what will go up there. More apartments probably , just what Green Street needs. let's put in another wendy's! I love wendy's! fuck all these independent restaurants I haven't heard of! Make it a combo restaurant, Wendy's and Jimmy's. We don't have a Jimmy's in at least 500ft.  So many ft to travel for a sandwich. ehh, JJs isn't even worth it anymore since they jacked up prices last month Make it a combo restaurant, Wendy's and Jimmy's. We don't have a Jimmy's in at least 500ft.  So many ft to travel for a sandwich. Green and locust dude. Just enough feet away. let's put in another wendy's! I love wendy's! fuck all these independent restaurants I haven't heard of! According to /u/thexcguy, there's going to be an apartment building there soon with the 1st floor open for retail space. Hopefully Maize moves there so I can actually eat there for a change. Maize is like three feet from White Ho, what? I mean more space. Maize is great, but you can barely even wait in line without being outside. Id just like to sit at a table. Ah, I agree. The location's just too small for the quality of food. let's put in another wendy's! I love wendy's! fuck all these independent restaurants I haven't heard of! Dude! Wendy's is going in on 6th street, accross from Flat Top where there used to be a liquor store.  I actually worked on the drawings for it. Holy shit, finally. Curious to see what will go up there. Apartments, according to the [News-Gazette](http://www.news-gazette.com/news/business/restaurants/2013-01-10/old-garcias-white-horse-inn-making-room-apartments.html)  Does anyone know what is going in the spot just west of Gio's? (Or for that matter, what was there before it was demolished in the first place?  I didn't start school till 2008). You mean on the other side of 4th street? There used to be a crepes place there (is it gone now?). Before that, Cafe Luna used to be there. If we're talking about the same spot, it's just a fenced off hole in the ground right now. Yeah I think we're talking about the same spot, just checked on Google Street view. It seemed to have quite a few establishments there - at least a hair salon and the crepes place and some more that I can't recall. There used to be a Burger King there at some point, too (co-existed with Luna, I believe, in different parts of the same building).  Burger King was where 309 is now. You mean on the other side of 4th street? There used to be a crepes place there (is it gone now?). Before that, Cafe Luna used to be there. You mean on the other side of 4th street? There used to be a crepes place there (is it gone now?). Before that, Cafe Luna used to be there. Does anyone know what is going in the spot just west of Gio's? (Or for that matter, what was there before it was demolished in the first place?  I didn't start school till 2008).  There used to be a ban on commercial restaurants on campus. 
 Interesting. When was the ban active?     Where am I gonna get shitty heart shaped pizza on Valentines Day? FUCK  </snippet></document><document><title>Incoming Freshman Looking for an Art &amp;amp; Design Student to Shadow</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16ao8f/incoming_freshman_looking_for_an_art_design/</url><snippet>Hi, 
I'm looking for a uiuc student who is majoring in painting, graphic design, or even a freshman in foundations to shadow on Friday, January 18th (I will be arriving at 11:30 am). I was recently accepted into the school of a + d, but I have no idea what the art program at uiuc is like.
I was accepted into other art schools etc. and I'm still trying to make the decision to go to a state school or traditional art school. Please help ._.
EDIT: 
Even if you are not an a+d student, what are the perks and downsides of going to u of i?
Also, what should I do during my visit?

PM me if you can help, and we shall chat. 
   talk to mark avery he can give you a tour of the building and tell you what you wanna know about the school   Friday may actually be the worst day because a lot of studio courses are Monday to Thursday. Heck a lot of students simply don't have any art related classes. And of course it's the first week as well. Of course you probably wouldn't even be allowed in.  I'm going to try contacting a program advisor to se if I can sit in on any classes or possibly get a run down of the school, since i'm staying over the weekend. 

What would you suggest I do instead if I can't get in? Probably still find to fine someone to talk to and they can at least show you around. Probably want a junior or senior to shadow. Foundations honestly doesn't really tell you much(really for the students since not everyone is actually interest in "art" or has the background). The real workload starts junior year. And of course Senior year you got students who are on their last semester. 

Again a Friday is where most A&amp;amp;D students don't even have a class. Maybe one or two. Some of those art related course may not even be related to their major(just electives). But at least a Junior or Senior has taken enough courses to give you a rundown.

</snippet></document><document><title>CS 125 Question</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16aue7/cs_125_question/</url><snippet>So I know stuff like this is posted on this subreddit all the time so feel free to downvote me into oblivion but I have a couple questions and considering the population of CS majors on /r/uiuc I figured you guys would know. Anyway, I'm a freshman without a major and have started thinking about taking CS 125 next semester. I have no experience with coding, will that put me at a large disadvantage? Just how tough is the class? Also both lectures are full right now. Will it be tough to get a spot or will a ton of people drop after the first couple of lectures? Thanks for the help guys!  I was in the same position last semester, however I talked to someone in the department and many people dropped the first week. 

As for difficulty, it will be much harder if you have no programming experience. You will have to do the readings and the TuringsCraft assignments (That is important they will teach you the semantics or programming which is not covered in class). However Angrave is one of the best teachers on campus he gives you weeks of extra time to complete MPs, and then regrades them all at the end of the semester. Also pretty much everyone gets 10% boosts on all the exams. I think it's important to note that it will be much harder with no experience because it's an intro class. If you already know Java, it'll be super easy because it's just basic Java. Kind of like how Calc 1 will be super easy if you have already taken calculus classes. It will be easier if you know how to code, but the class is run assuming you have never written any code in your life. OP should certainly not be discouraged by having no coding experience.   If you're willing to put in the effort, you'll do fine.  It's a great class and a ton of people enjoy it.

I'd imagine people will drop after the first week or so.  Just show up to the class and keep checking over the next few weeks because a spot will inevitably open up. That's what I figured, I just wanted to make sure I wasn't getting in over my head. Thanks a bunch! Just wanted to add, make sure you have enough free time. Programming can take up a lot of time; I didn't take CS 125, but ECE 190 MPs (machine programs) were tough to get through at that moment. Don't overload yourself because you may end up involuntarily hating programming.

Also, if after the few days no spot opens up, try emailing the teacher saying how you're a Freshie Undeclared and you're extremely interested in the CS curriculum and are really looking forward to getting an early taste of what that career path can offer. BS a little and I believe you'll get in.

Good Luck!  I am a course assistant for CS125 this semester, and having taken it last semester, if you are willing to put in the effort, do the readings and practice writing code you will do fine. That being said, I highly recommend it, I am undecided as well but taking this course really helped me to find out what I am interested in.  If you have any more questions feel free to ask! (Or pm me!)  I'm in the same position as you with waiting for it to open up again. My bf was a course assistant last semester and said that the class opened up after like a week. So hopefully I'll see you in lecture! And the coding isn't that bad from what I've heard. Source: Friend took it last semester.    </snippet></document><document><title>Does anyone know if UIUC has equipment sales?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16aeq9/does_anyone_know_if_uiuc_has_equipment_sales/</url><snippet>I just read [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/1697to/why_do_printers_and_printer_software_still_suck/c7u58am) on AskReddit and I was wondering if anyone knows if UIUC offers this service. It'd be awesome to get some free/cheap shit!!

Also, happy new year!  Nope, too risky because machines might have FERPA-protected data on them.  The university is under a legal obligation to responsibly dispose of old technology, plus it's just not worth the risk of having private information be released.

We get rid of our obsolete equipment through EngrIT.  They remove all of the hard drives and process those separately (probably destroy the drives), and then the actual equipment goes to die in the technology graveyard in the penthouse of Siebel until there's enough of it to be cost effective to recycle.  It's all asset tagged, too, so they know what's there and what's not. The hard drives are removed and then wiped. Hard drives unable to be wiped are sent to be destroyed. The wiped hard drives(and equipment) becomes re purposed. The penthouse really isn't the technology graveyard, it's just that it's a lot of crap to move out and it takes them months to get the a shipment all sorted out. There's a crap ton of inventory and changing of hands for this crap. "Engrit" only handles the the engineering equipment. DIA and other departments handle their own stuff. 

Overall the issue isn't really the private info but that the state owns all this damn equipment and they aren't too interested in putting it to better use. 

But yeah, nope never going to get sold unless a professor/rso paid for the stuff out of their own pocket.

 Hard drives that aren't able to be wiped are not destroyed.  They're actually placed by this awesome magnet that wipes it.  It's all pretty cool.  And there is no real "shipment."  You drive it over to this place next to Orchard Downs and drop it off at surplus.  Then, other depts can go to surplus and "purchase" old items.  

Source:  I used to work for College of Fine and Applied Arts IT Hard drives that aren't able to be wiped are not destroyed.  They're actually placed by this awesome magnet that wipes it.  It's all pretty cool.  And there is no real "shipment."  You drive it over to this place next to Orchard Downs and drop it off at surplus.  Then, other depts can go to surplus and "purchase" old items.  

Source:  I used to work for College of Fine and Applied Arts IT Nope, too risky because machines might have FERPA-protected data on them.  The university is under a legal obligation to responsibly dispose of old technology, plus it's just not worth the risk of having private information be released.

We get rid of our obsolete equipment through EngrIT.  They remove all of the hard drives and process those separately (probably destroy the drives), and then the actual equipment goes to die in the technology graveyard in the penthouse of Siebel until there's enough of it to be cost effective to recycle.  It's all asset tagged, too, so they know what's there and what's not.   The U of I does-in a very indirect way that first involves all the good stuff being removed. I believe that items that are gotten rid of by campus departments that are not wanted by campus surplus are sent to the state which then may have auctions/sales. There is some site that these are hosted on, but I'm not sure of it.  I believe old stuff is auctioned off at https://ibid.illinois.gov/index.php</snippet></document><document><title>MASSMAIL - Mascot Idea Contest</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/169768/massmail_mascot_idea_contest/</url><snippet>https://www.facebook.com/CampusSpiritRevival/info

So, how many times do you think we can submit the chief before they block us all?

Actual discussion as to the new mascot is also allowed.   Robot Lincoln.  Failing that, vampire hunter Lincoln.  Who knows, maybe the Illinois Bootleggers. Dudes who distributed liquor during prohibition. Theres big history in that in Illinois and since its alcohol related I'm sure the college kids won't have a problem accepting it.

Dartmouth made Keggy the Keg when their administration ended their Native American Chief 

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keggy_the_Keg Who knows, maybe the Illinois Bootleggers. Dudes who distributed liquor during prohibition. Theres big history in that in Illinois and since its alcohol related I'm sure the college kids won't have a problem accepting it.

Dartmouth made Keggy the Keg when their administration ended their Native American Chief 

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keggy_the_Keg   I honestly dont think a new mascot would be welcomed by the school, too much history. Agreed. I've been chanting ILLINI way too long to simply switch to "Let's go Bluebirds!!" or some shit. I don't know about everyone else, but I'd rather have us be one of the few schools without a mascot then to end up with some horseshit substitute.

Actually, not having a mascot is kinda cool. We're unique like that.      What a joke. 
"I'm on the student senate! Hey guise, we should have a mascot because other schools have a mascot and it would look GREAT on our resumes!"       Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it. Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it. Mostly white?  We are clearly on different sides of Green St. Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it. Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it. I disagree. I just complete my first semester at the U of I and it barely took any time to notice how much love our student body still has for the Chief. It didn't take me long to catch on, and it would be difficult, even awkward, to have a different mascot.  Racial sensitivity, especially given the gruesome history of treatment of Native Americans, is more important than awkwardness over a new mascot. 

New mascot being awkward, and difficulty adjusting to it: First world problem. Oh fuck off nobody means it to be insenstive to the mistreatment of Native Americans. 
If we really care about the Native Americans why dont we give their land back?
 Because they are, kind of, dead? A mascot shouldn't be a mascot even if *some* people have a problem with it, especially if they find it offensive (as opposed to merely lame/dumb/uninteresting). It is meant to unite all students, not divide them. It divides even people who aren't Native Americans, because they either take a stand against it, for it, or are indifferent - thus dividing them into three distinct groups. I dont think all Native Americans are dead. Also, it seems that even though the chief may not longer be our mascot he is till uniting the student body, i.e chanting his name at games, this thread, etc.

I feel that there are more over politically correct white kids offended by this, than actual natives.  Still uniting the student body? Whenever the 'chief' comes up, a massive emotional argument seems to break out. Some unity. How is it offensive to native Americans even? I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. I have seen the Chief dance at a game. The Chief is dressed in traditional gear and performs a war dance, which is essentially cavorting around on the field during half-time, as a source of amusement and entertainment for the audience, in the same way as cheerleaders.

If you are white, how would you feel if a caricature of a respected figure of your race, say Abraham Lincoln, was made to cavort around on a football field for the amusement of college students, with the audience loudly cheering? If you are black, how would you feel if  a caricature of Martin Luther King Jr. were to be used the same way? And bear in mind that since there aren't many Native Americans around, as compared to whites or blacks, for many people the Chief is probably their only image/idea/impression of Native American tribes - these weirdly dressed people who dance funny. And these are comparisons without even going into the genocide issue, which makes it all the more disrespectful. First kill them, then use a caricature of a respected figure of their tribe for your own amusement. Still uniting the student body? Whenever the 'chief' comes up, a massive emotional argument seems to break out. Some unity. Most of us are united.  If you ass holes would shut the fuck up and leave our heritage alone, we could go on with our business.

The Chief Forever. Most of us are united.  If you ass holes would shut the fuck up and leave our heritage alone, we could go on with our business.

The Chief Forever. Yeah, that looks like unity to me. 

The mascot is already gone and it's not coming back -- the NCAA saw to that. Time to move on. Because they are, kind of, dead? A mascot shouldn't be a mascot even if *some* people have a problem with it, especially if they find it offensive (as opposed to merely lame/dumb/uninteresting). It is meant to unite all students, not divide them. It divides even people who aren't Native Americans, because they either take a stand against it, for it, or are indifferent - thus dividing them into three distinct groups. Because they are, kind of, dead? A mascot shouldn't be a mascot even if *some* people have a problem with it, especially if they find it offensive (as opposed to merely lame/dumb/uninteresting). It is meant to unite all students, not divide them. It divides even people who aren't Native Americans, because they either take a stand against it, for it, or are indifferent - thus dividing them into three distinct groups. There are 32 native american students out of 42,000 people.  Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it. Well first off a mostly white school using a native american as a mascot is not exactly the wisest thing to do. 

As to people not accepting a new mascot. The majority of students right now have never had the chief as a mascot. The new students would accept it.          Bet you whoever is behind this has probably never even been to a game or cares about athletics at all. Yeah because a University is just about athletics right?  [deleted] I don't recall any other school making this silly semantic distinction. It seems to be little more than a lame attempt to deflect criticism as far as I can tell.  [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>1st illini game tonight, where to park??</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16a001/1st_illini_game_tonight_where_to_park/</url><snippet>ILL!  Going to my first illini basketball game tonight! Any suggestions on where to park? Any secret (or not secret) lots out there? I am coming from off campus, but don't mind walking a a bit.   Park in the ARC parking lot and walk over to assembly hall Park in the ARC parking lot and walk over to assembly hall Park in the ARC parking lot and walk over to assembly hall </snippet></document><document><title>TIL the streak in Brandon Paul's hair is a birthmark.</title><url>https://twitter.com/BP3/status/284148958547292160</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>Space-Western-Musical Director Cory McAbee, who's premiered two films at Sundance, is coming to town</title><url>http://www.facebook.com/events/402229276526422/</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Food vendors physically on campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1694ic/food_vendors_physically_on_campus/</url><snippet>Does anyone know of a listing of vendors and locations for drink and food vendors on campus? I'm thinking of things like the Beckman Cafe &amp;amp; Espresso in Undergrad Library and not all the stuff in campus town.   [Bevier Cafe](http://beviercafe.illinois.edu/) is operated by students in Bevier Hall. [Bevier Cafe](http://beviercafe.illinois.edu/) is operated by students in Bevier Hall.  Hmmmm... don't know if there's a list, but I'll list what I can.

**Food trucks**    
* Deralds: makes different type of burgers and the like (Fish Friday is great!): on Matthews (on east side of Noyes)    
* Cracked: egg sandwiches and do other dishes, heard its really good: on Matthews near Springfield (on east side of Grainger, typically)    
* Shanghai: Chinese and other Asian foods: on Matthews near Green (west side of Mechanical Engineering Building (MEB))

**Bevande Cafe**    
* Front of ~~MEB~~ Mechanical Engineering Laboratory (MEL) west side    
* Siebel (East side of 1st floor lobby)

**Intermezzo:** cafe and entrees: in Krannert (North end of 1st floor lobby) If you follow the cracked truck on twitter, they usually tweet where they're going to be set up since they move around a lot.  If you follow the cracked truck on twitter, they usually tweet where they're going to be set up since they move around a lot.  Hmmmm... don't know if there's a list, but I'll list what I can.

**Food trucks**    
* Deralds: makes different type of burgers and the like (Fish Friday is great!): on Matthews (on east side of Noyes)    
* Cracked: egg sandwiches and do other dishes, heard its really good: on Matthews near Springfield (on east side of Grainger, typically)    
* Shanghai: Chinese and other Asian foods: on Matthews near Green (west side of Mechanical Engineering Building (MEB))

**Bevande Cafe**    
* Front of ~~MEB~~ Mechanical Engineering Laboratory (MEL) west side    
* Siebel (East side of 1st floor lobby)

**Intermezzo:** cafe and entrees: in Krannert (North end of 1st floor lobby) Front of MEL not MEB for Bevande Cafe OOPS. Thanks for the correction. East side of MEL too You mean there's a station on both sides of MEL or just the east side? Actually you are 100% correct. I was mistaken :(  In the basement of the Institute for Genomic Biology building is the Array Cafe. Reasonably cheap food (the veggie hummus box is $3 &amp;amp; pretty filling), good teas, nice people. Good place, although I don't think too many people know about it. In the basement of the Institute for Genomic Biology building is the Array Cafe. Reasonably cheap food (the veggie hummus box is $3 &amp;amp; pretty filling), good teas, nice people. Good place, although I don't think too many people know about it. Do they have any signature dishes? Do they have any signature dishes?      </snippet></document><document><title>TIL: Roommate dies &#8800; Straight As, getting hit by bus &#8800; free tuition</title><url>http://www.dailyillini.com/features/article_6ad67f3e-050b-5eaf-a751-d730e82953f6.html</url><snippet>    after his extremely biased greek row article, i cannot give this asshole any respect. i don't care if i get downvoted, but i want you all to remember that this is the same author. after his extremely biased greek row article, i cannot give this asshole any respect. i don't care if i get downvoted, but i want you all to remember that this is the same author. link to Greek Row article?

edit: never mind, found it. my god that's terrible.  I still don't think anything can top that "don't study abroad" DI article. Or the "Pygmalion isn't worth going to" article.   DI spam? Weak. There hasn't been anything worthwhile in the DI since I Hate Pam. Googled that and saw it was a comic that we made. We made comics? I might actually read it if we had comics.

Also, there was an anti-semitic one? what? Yup the author was constantly getting flak for offensive jokes so they made one that was incredibly offensive and I think got suspended for a while  they told us there was no super computer there and not to talk about

well, i must have been mistaken, since they told me there was no secret super-computer You know, this one is interesting. I heard this rumor from people that worked at NCSA (National Center for Supercomputer Applications). 

It seems plausible, to me at least, because I can't understand why would so many computer labs and infrastructure are in a foreign language building basement? Online education for languages doesn't seem to be that old, at least not older than the labs (although I don't know when they were made, does anyone know that?) and I have no idea if any foreign language classes make use of them. 

Also, this university is one of the pioneers in supercomputing and research; we would have had the capability to make it during the cold war era, that's for sure. 

The other reason that the rumor persists is because of the FLB itself. The architecture makes it looks really out of place compared to the other quad buildings. The central space inside the building is fully open, with the floors staggered, but that space doesn't seem to be the focal point of the building, no room to gather, no art, no features - its just a wide hallway. Most buildings that have a huge indoor space (like the Union ballrooms or BIF for example) use that space to gather - for FLB you really can't (its hard to walk in that hall between classes). 

Maybe I'm just bullshitting, but that rumor has always crossed my mind when I'm in there. Its fun to think about, that there could have been some secret computer that was doing something so awesome and dangerous it had to be hidden from everyone in the place that it would never be. A computer so powerful that that the Soviets would send a missile past the coasts, all the way to Urbana Illinois - AS AN ACT OF WAR, just to prevent US from using the data on that computer on them. Is fun to think that the US' secret weapon was lying just beneath some students trying to learn verb conjugation. I guess that's what I'll need to motivate me to go to class there in the mornings. If you like that thought, then know that university scientists helped do work on the manhattan project in the basement of MSEB. Also a cool looking, really old place if you ever get the chance to go down into it. It's mostly storage/makeshift lab space and easily accessible, but I don't believe students are 'allowed' down there  I've always heard free tuition comes from getting hit by a university employee (which CUMTD is not). </snippet></document><document><title>Spring Quad day?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/168h5h/spring_quad_day/</url><snippet>I was wondering, will there be a quad-day-like event when this semester starts? I really want to join more RSOs and meet more people, but I'm sort of lost as to where to go. I tried joining a few clubs last semester but wasn't able to really give away much of my time. This semester, I'm going to try to change things.

Some things I'm interested in: entrepreneurship, cs-stuff, and anything fun really. A friend of mine told me that MUN is great, so I'm looking into that. Basically any club that is fun and where I can meet new people.   There's a Quad Day-like event called Activity Day in the Union on Wednesday, January 23 from 11-3.  I'm not sure what RSOs will be there but it wouldn't hurt to go.   </snippet></document><document><title>OK r/UIUC, what are your recommendations off of the Cravings-Chinese menu? </title><url>http://www.cravingscu.com/images/CravingsChineseMenu.png</url><snippet>  &#40635;&#23110;&#35910;&#33104;, &#22914;&#26524;&#20320;&#21487;&#20197;&#21507;&#36763;&#36771;&#30340;&#19996;&#35199;

&#20182;&#20204;&#30340;&#19977;&#26479;&#40481;&#20063;&#26159;&#30456;&#24403;&#19981;&#38169;&#30340; For the lazy, 

&#40635;&#23110;&#35910;&#33104;, &#22914;&#26524;&#20320;&#21487;&#20197;&#21507;&#36763;&#36771;&#30340;&#19996;&#35199;
&#20182;&#20204;&#30340;&#19977;&#26479;&#40481;&#20063;&#26159;&#30456;&#24403;&#19981;&#38169;&#30340;

translates as

Mapo tofu, if you can eat spicy things
Their cups chicken is quite good

Also, Mapo tofu is amazing on a cold day. I had the mapo tofu. It is really really good. I hope you are right. It is one of my favorite dishes and every Chinese place has a bastardized version of it. Always trying to find the real thing and so far Golden Harbor is the only place I've found that has it. For the lazy, 

&#40635;&#23110;&#35910;&#33104;, &#22914;&#26524;&#20320;&#21487;&#20197;&#21507;&#36763;&#36771;&#30340;&#19996;&#35199;
&#20182;&#20204;&#30340;&#19977;&#26479;&#40481;&#20063;&#26159;&#30456;&#24403;&#19981;&#38169;&#30340;

translates as

Mapo tofu, if you can eat spicy things
Their cups chicken is quite good

Also, Mapo tofu is amazing on a cold day.  Jakarta Fried Rice is really popular as well as the hot and spicy diced chicken. By the way, there's other things on the menu in store up on the wall. [deleted]  I'm white, so... hot &amp;amp; spicy chicken. I'm white, so... hot &amp;amp; spicy chicken.  GatoGato. Vegetarian dish. Spicy. So good [4] Veg tree lover? I think I've found a friend
 Is it too late to join this friend circle?  I would like to join this friend circle. Haha if you guys are in champaign this week you should stop by and blaze! Always good meeting new ents on campus   As much as I love the Jakarta Fried Rice and agree that it is as good as everyone else says, keep in mind it is also the easiest dish for them to make and costs them virtually nothing. At the same time, you're paying relatively the same amount of money for it as any other dish that has meat.
 I have taught you well. I already knew all of that but I just wanted some damn JFR!
  * Beef Ho Fun
* Jakarta Fried Rice
* Salt and Pepper Squid (little salty for my taste for an entire meal)
* Fish with Tomato Chili Sauce
* Sizzling Chicken Pot (large stone pot full of chicken - pretty much 2 meals)
* Chicken/Fish/Tofu/Beef Gado Gado (kind of like a curry) * Beef Ho Fun
* Jakarta Fried Rice
* Salt and Pepper Squid (little salty for my taste for an entire meal)
* Fish with Tomato Chili Sauce
* Sizzling Chicken Pot (large stone pot full of chicken - pretty much 2 meals)
* Chicken/Fish/Tofu/Beef Gado Gado (kind of like a curry) * Beef Ho Fun
* Jakarta Fried Rice
* Salt and Pepper Squid (little salty for my taste for an entire meal)
* Fish with Tomato Chili Sauce
* Sizzling Chicken Pot (large stone pot full of chicken - pretty much 2 meals)
* Chicken/Fish/Tofu/Beef Gado Gado (kind of like a curry)     The red curry dishes are good.  It's not nearly as good as going to the Thai restaurant on Green Street, though, but it's a bit cheaper. There is a Thai restaurant on Green Street?    You should order the Soup of Sum Yung Gai.                     </snippet></document><document><title>Do you write good notes? You can literally make money by uploading notes for others to see. There's no submissions from UIUC yet, but it would be awesome if we did! (Originally posted in /r/beermoney)</title><url>https://notesolution.com/</url><snippet>  How against school rules is this? A lot of the professors copyright their slides, so the notes that you take you are allowed to have and to download to your computer, but you aren't allowed to repost the information for profit. I think that is how that works. 

One of my professors was telling my class how she scared the shit out of two students by having her lawyers contact them because they posted her slides and notes online to a website like this.  </snippet></document><document><title>Rock Climbing Meetup 4PM Wednesday, Jan 9th</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/168qil/rock_climbing_meetup_4pm_wednesday_jan_9th/</url><snippet>Looking for something fun to do?  Look no further.  I'll be hosting a Reddit meet-up at the ARC at 4PM Wednesday, Jan 9th.  I will be wearing one of [these](http://i.imgur.com/AvBZg.jpg) shirts!

Come and introduce yourself and climb some rocks.  Its fine if you don't know what you are doing/aren't in shape/etc.  The wall is quite beginner friendly and the regulars are great.

Gear rental is $2 for students and not, but non-students will have to pay $10 for an ARC day pass.  You will need a student to get you in as well (call me at 77-55-kevlar and I can help with this).  Are you part of the climbing club? If so, when's the first meeting? Yes, but I'm not sure.  It will probably be one of the first few Wednesdays this semester.  Wish I could go but got other things going on. Just moved here from San Francisco where I was climbing for just six months but loving it. Would be interested in getting a group together to go to bloomington's gym. 

I'd be happy to drive. 

http://www.upperlimits.com/bloomington/ Wish I could go but got other things going on. Just moved here from San Francisco where I was climbing for just six months but loving it. Would be interested in getting a group together to go to bloomington's gym. 

I'd be happy to drive. 

http://www.upperlimits.com/bloomington/     Not a rockclimber myself so I will not be attending, but the real question I have for you is where do you get that wicked flair? *points at sidebar* The Beer is not one of them  Good thing I saw this now -_- idk how I missed it, I was in town!!! PM me next time kevlar00</snippet></document><document><title>Suburban Express coupons?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16809s/suburban_express_coupons/</url><snippet>Are there any out there?  </snippet></document><document><title>Anonymous STD testing in Mckinley?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/166xxp/anonymous_std_testing_in_mckinley/</url><snippet>Anyone know if Mckinley do blood testing off the record? or any order hospitals in champaign that does testing anonymously?   [Champaign's Public Health Department](http://www.c-uphd.org/std-clinic.html) is the one to go to.  Everything is confidential. Thank you for responding. Could I walk into CPHD and get tested without them asking for my identity/Social security, etc? 

I don't know what my result will come out to be, but in case things turn south, i don't want to be on my medical record Thank you for responding. Could I walk into CPHD and get tested without them asking for my identity/Social security, etc? 

I don't know what my result will come out to be, but in case things turn south, i don't want to be on my medical record Thank you for responding. Could I walk into CPHD and get tested without them asking for my identity/Social security, etc? 

I don't know what my result will come out to be, but in case things turn south, i don't want to be on my medical record I mean its kind of important for a doctor to know, shits serious.     If you're worried about it coming up on your university charges as 'std test' and your parents seeing it, it doesn't. It comes up as a 'health wellness charge' from what my parents have mentioned. I've gone to get xrays, tests, and a variety of medication and they never knew what it specifically was until I told them. I don't think it even costs any money (not sure though). Most stuff at McKinley is free (labs, x-rays, ultrasounds, etc.), except you have to pay a $5 copay for medication and I think you have to pay for immunizations. The only charges that have ever showed up on my student account are the $5 pharmacy copays. I don't think it even costs any money (not sure though). Most stuff at McKinley is free (labs, x-rays, ultrasounds, etc.), except you have to pay a $5 copay for medication and I think you have to pay for immunizations. The only charges that have ever showed up on my student account are the $5 pharmacy copays.  Do you have to make an appointment to get tested? If so, which line would you call?  Calling [Dial-A-Nurse](http://www.mckinley.illinois.edu/general/dial_a_nurse.htm) at 217-333-2700 would be the first step.    not sure if i should hope this is because you were irresponsible and had unprotected sex with a random or because your SO cheated on you and has an STD. I guess there are other possibilities too, but reddit has made me jaded not sure if i should hope this is because you were irresponsible and had unprotected sex with a random or because your SO cheated on you and has an STD. I guess there are other possibilities too, but reddit has made me jaded not sure if i should hope this is because you were irresponsible and had unprotected sex with a random or because your SO cheated on you and has an STD. I guess there are other possibilities too, but reddit has made me jaded Or, you know... Rape. OP never stated his/her gender.  Or, you know... Rape. OP never stated his/her gender. </snippet></document><document><title>Is it possible to "drop" a class grade from my GPA?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/168j3g/is_it_possible_to_drop_a_class_grade_from_my_gpa/</url><snippet>So apparently I didn't need to take Rhet 105 because of my ACT English score, but the online adviser put me in it.  I ended up getting a C+.  Is it possible to get rid of the grade and the credits?      You can retro-actively credit/no-credit the class. You will receive the credit, and it will not contribute to your GPA.

Changed an A- to CR before, and a CR to an A+. May I ask how you did this?  </snippet></document><document><title>Best Banks Near Campus? (Have car, can drive if better off campus)</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/167uf0/best_banks_near_campus_have_car_can_drive_if/</url><snippet>My work that I do pays me with checks and not direct deposit, which sucks because I end up with 9 or 10 checks sitting around my apartment before I go home to check them in. So, I'm looking for a bank on campus that offers a saving or checking account with unlimited withdrawals/tranfers...anyone have any they like/recommend? Either on campus or off campus. Is a credit union (right name?) worth while?  Honestly, go with Chase. You can put all your checks into your account with the mobile phone app (I guess assuming you have an iphone or android), or I think you can drop off checks into the ATM machines on campus (there are a few on green st). 

I finally went with Chase because I wanted a big, national bank that could easily follow me after graduation. They also have student accounts that don't have any restrictions on lowest acceptable total amount or amount added per month. The student accounts also last 5 years, even if you get an account as a senior. 

I'm pretty sure there are limits on how many transfers you can do from checking and saving, but I don't know any banks that allow unlimited transfers. Definitely unlimited withdrawals, if I'm not mistaken. 

There are a few branches in Champaign and Urbana (www.google.com) that are easily accessible by car.  Thanks! That's an issue with my current bank, it's a small town bank back near Chicago and there's no where to put my money around here. I'll definitely check out Chase. Thanks! That's an issue with my current bank, it's a small town bank back near Chicago and there's no where to put my money around here. I'll definitely check out Chase. Honestly, go with Chase. You can put all your checks into your account with the mobile phone app (I guess assuming you have an iphone or android), or I think you can drop off checks into the ATM machines on campus (there are a few on green st). 

I finally went with Chase because I wanted a big, national bank that could easily follow me after graduation. They also have student accounts that don't have any restrictions on lowest acceptable total amount or amount added per month. The student accounts also last 5 years, even if you get an account as a senior. 

I'm pretty sure there are limits on how many transfers you can do from checking and saving, but I don't know any banks that allow unlimited transfers. Definitely unlimited withdrawals, if I'm not mistaken. 

There are a few branches in Champaign and Urbana (www.google.com) that are easily accessible by car.  Honestly, go with Chase. You can put all your checks into your account with the mobile phone app (I guess assuming you have an iphone or android), or I think you can drop off checks into the ATM machines on campus (there are a few on green st). 

I finally went with Chase because I wanted a big, national bank that could easily follow me after graduation. They also have student accounts that don't have any restrictions on lowest acceptable total amount or amount added per month. The student accounts also last 5 years, even if you get an account as a senior. 

I'm pretty sure there are limits on how many transfers you can do from checking and saving, but I don't know any banks that allow unlimited transfers. Definitely unlimited withdrawals, if I'm not mistaken. 

There are a few branches in Champaign and Urbana (www.google.com) that are easily accessible by car.   Don't go with TCF, that's all I can say. Don't go with TCF, that's all I can say.  Aside from crappy interface for web banking, the UIECU has never done me wrong. Just go to the branch in the Union and sign up. There's an ATM in the Union, one each in ARC/CRCE, one by legends, and they reimburse fees for out of network ATMs like most credit unions do.    PNC is pretty good. Get the Virtual Wallet--it has a good online system and also allows for mobile check deposit. They have a bank location on Green Street by Starbucks. There is a $25 minimum to open the account, but no minimum once it is open.

You should also upgrade to Performance spend to get more benefits; there is a $10 monthly fee if you do this option but there are several ways to avoid this.  If you're OK with an online bank, I swear by Ally. No fees ever (withdraw from any ATM and all the fees will be rebated), a mobile app for check deposit, and interest on your checking (it isn't much but it's better than nothing).</snippet></document><document><title>Best way to travel back and forth from DePaul to Champaign?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/167od5/best_way_to_travel_back_and_forth_from_depaul_to/</url><snippet>I'm going to be going to DePaul University a lot to see my gf over the next semester - what is the best way to get there and back for a weekend for a reasonable price (~$20)? Are there any passes I can get for a set price? I'm looking at Amtrak and Greyhound right now, any other options?  If you get the student pass AND get the tickets a few weeks ahead of time, you can get Amtrak for only a bit over $10 (as of a couple years ago, prices might have gone up a bit).  Megabus is another option, but you want to book even further ahead of time than Amtrak.  Greyhound is like 13 dollar one way as long as you get your ticket at least 24 hours before leaving. Plus it takes you right in the middle of downtown, walkng distance from depaul [deleted] Depaul has a campus downtown also [deleted] </snippet></document><document><title>Anyone want to split a lease?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1683u5/anyone_want_to_split_a_lease/</url><snippet>I've got a 1 bedroom I'm living at now that I really love (great location and super cheap for a 1br), but I'm graduating December 2013 and they don't do semester leases at this location :(

Would anyone want to split a year lease with me? ie, I live there August-December 2013, you live there Jan-May 2014 (and we can figure out the summer portion later).

PM me if interested. Also if I don't get a response, I'll need a place to live for Fall 2013, so PM me if you have a place you're looking to sublet.</snippet></document><document><title>CS Foreign Language requirements?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/167mka/cs_foreign_language_requirements/</url><snippet>Hi, my brother is looking to come here for CS but he needs to know how many years of high school foreign language to take because he's deciding on classes for his senior year right now and doesn't want to take a fourth year if he doesn't have to. I looked on the CS requirements page through illinois.edu, but they weren't very clear about and there were some missing pages/broken links. Can anyone who is in CS let me know what you need?


Also, It's my understanding that there are CS programs in both the school of Engineering and the school of Liberal Arts and Sciences. If you could specify which one you are talking about that would be great.  Engineering: 3+ units of the same language
LAS: 4+ units of the same language

A 'unit' is a full year at high school level and a semester at college level. </snippet></document><document><title>Driving back on Saturday. Need a lift? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/165p92/driving_back_on_saturday_need_a_lift/</url><snippet>Hey guys
I'll be heading back to school from the northwest suburbs on Saturday late morning early afternoon if any one wants a ride. 
Send me a PM 
See ya all in the paign!    Ill come, but only if we can roast blunts and have some road beers on the way down</snippet></document><document><title>Illini tix for Wed night game vs #8 Minnesota for $16 being offered</title><url>https://twitter.com/IlliniHoops/status/288405836156526592</url><snippet>  </snippet></document><document><title>U of I ranked #12 in AP and #13 in coaches poll after loss to purdue and win over "the" osu</title><url>http://espn.go.com/mens-college-basketball/rankings</url><snippet>  Up  in one poll down in the other. I'm not really concerned with the ranking but pretty damn worried about the Big Ten season. It's going to be rough! Up  in one poll down in the other. I'm not really concerned with the ranking but pretty damn worried about the Big Ten season. It's going to be rough! </snippet></document><document><title>Is it against University Rules to use the email directory to try to sell a book?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/165x8v/is_it_against_university_rules_to_use_the_email/</url><snippet>I wouldn't be just mass mailing hundreds of people, but emailing about 45 people who I know are taking the class next semester.  I can't find anything in the student code.         </snippet></document><document><title>IB 202 Question? From a non-major</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16573s/ib_202_question_from_a_nonmajor/</url><snippet>How intensive is it in chemistry and mathematics? I'm a non-major [coming from art], so my knowledge in those two areas is laughable.

The website for IB 202 doesn't seem to help, and I emailed on of the profs and they gave somewhat of a vague response 'math shouldn't be hard'. 

I just don't want to take a class where I struggle due to not knowing things. 

   Honestly, 202 was one of the least intensive IB classes I've taken. As far as I remember, you should be fine as far as math goes (basic algebra if any) and they usually walked through any chemistry that was mentioned. The class was mostly a lot of review from biology classes that I took in high school so you should be fine. If not, it's easy to ask questions and get help from the professor, tas or other students.  Hey I'm in that class too.. What section? haha. MWF 1-1:50 </snippet></document><document><title>Are there any people have experience transferring to actuarial science major?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/164hh4/are_there_any_people_have_experience_transferring/</url><snippet>I will take Math210 and Math408 this spring semester and transfer after this semester. I just want to know what the procedure is to transfer. Because final grade will be reported on May17 and I want to know the time I can go home.  My ex gf did, I'll talk to her and pm you later   Why not ask the advisor/school? You don't really want to screw something up because they changed something big for the upcoming semester. </snippet></document><document><title>Are there any cab companies in CU that accept payment by credit card?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/164k3d/are_there_any_cab_companies_in_cu_that_accept/</url><snippet>  Black Cab does, I've used them to get to the airport a couple times

http://www.yelp.com/biz/black-cab-and-limo-champaign </snippet></document><document><title>John Groce &amp;amp; Thad Matta Pure Ecstasy</title><url>http://imgur.com/s7wtJ</url><snippet>   as a side piece of info... Thad is from a small illinois town called Hoopeston.  which is the home of the Cornjerkers.

Have fun with that, in combination with this picture. I played against the Cornjerkers in high school. At the time, their cheerleader uniforms said "Jerkers" across the chest, it was magical.   Am I the only one that doesn't give a flying fuck about U of I sports? Am I the only one that doesn't give a flying fuck about U of I sports?</snippet></document><document><title>Sorry if this has been posted before, but can anyone tell me how to set up UIUC undergrad email on my iPod?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/163zx6/sorry_if_this_has_been_posted_before_but_can/</url><snippet>What steps/settings should I go through. I haven't been able to get it and it's driving me nuts.  http://www.cites.illinois.edu/email/google/imap.html might be helpful :) </snippet></document><document><title>Illini football hires a new Offensive Coordinator. Maybe we will score next season. </title><url>http://espn.go.com/chicago/college-football/story/_/id/8818261/bill-cubit-hired-illinois-offensive-coordinator-source-says</url><snippet>    What is this "score" concept you speak of? Never heard of it Legend has it, "scoring" is when your team actually moves the ball down field and puts it in the "end zone" Sounds like new fangled crazy talk to me. Legend has it, "scoring" is when your team actually moves the ball down field and puts it in the "end zone" Legend has it, "scoring" is when your team actually moves the ball down field and puts it in the "end zone"    i'll believe it when I see it, I thought you need good players to score If Minnesota can score, we can do it too! Right...? </snippet></document><document><title>ECE 110?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/163uyu/ece_110/</url><snippet>Keepin it short: it says that non-majors can sign up for it starting january 7th 2013 but when I try to register for it, it says field of study restriction - major... maybe its too early? Since it is Jan 7th, Id expect it to work.. Any help would be really appreciated as I am pretty worried.

EDIT: Has anyone here registered for ECE 110 as a non-major?   [deleted]  I was a non-major who signed up for it. 2 years ago when I did, I had to go into the ECE advising office the semester before and sign up for what might have either been a wait list or an override queue or something of the sort. Regardless, I specifically had to talk to ECE advising to get an override.  </snippet></document><document><title>How do I get good tickets to an Illinois basketball game?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/163utd/how_do_i_get_good_tickets_to_an_illinois/</url><snippet>Preferably against Michigan or Indiana  stub hub / craigslist?

or know someone willing to sell tickets.

or go without tickets and expect to pay a lot more on the street before the game. Stubhub has a good selection. Check them out.      Join Orange Krush 5 months ago. Joking aside, find a friend or a friend of a friend that's in Krush or knows someone who is, and see if there's a game that they aren't going to attend. Then, although I'm not sure how they do things now, you should be able to fill in for them. Make sure you line up a few hours before the game because the seating is first come first served.

Otherwise, go with what another person said. Scalp a ticket or two.. doesn't have to be the greatest tix. Then, if you're feeling adventurous, spy an empty seat in the B level and mosey on down there (they usually won't check your ticket at this point). Worst case scenario - the season ticket holder shows up and you apologize and head back to your assigned seat. </snippet></document><document><title>Real analysis</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/162nvg/real_analysis/</url><snippet>I took math 447 (undergrad real analysis) last semester and it was pretty interesting so I thought about trying to take math 540 (graduate real analysis/measure theory) now during the spring. Would really appreciate comments on this course and how difficult it was compared to 400-level courses as say 447. Also, do I need a dedicated course in set theory and topology such as math 432 before taking math 540 or does math 447 suffice? Thanks

  I'm a first year math phd student. I took 540 in the fall with Erdogan and it kicked my ass.  I don't know what you should expect with Li. But compared to my undergrad analysis (not at UIUC) it moved at a much quicker pace. However, I don't think you'll need courses in set theory or topology. It definitely couldn't hurt, but the information you need as far as sets, metrics, topologies, Borel sets, and so on are covered at an introductory level in 540, albeit at a fast pace. So, based on what you've said, and assuming Li teaches similarly to Erdogan, then I think you should be fine as long as you plan on dedicating a fair amount of time to studying and doing homework for this course.  Appreciate the reply. Did your undergrad analysis cover metric spaces and metric topologies? I'm a first year math phd student. I took 540 in the fall with Erdogan and it kicked my ass.  I don't know what you should expect with Li. But compared to my undergrad analysis (not at UIUC) it moved at a much quicker pace. However, I don't think you'll need courses in set theory or topology. It definitely couldn't hurt, but the information you need as far as sets, metrics, topologies, Borel sets, and so on are covered at an introductory level in 540, albeit at a fast pace. So, based on what you've said, and assuming Li teaches similarly to Erdogan, then I think you should be fine as long as you plan on dedicating a fair amount of time to studying and doing homework for this course.  How is Erdogan, generally speaking as a teacher? I'm taking 425 (honors advanced analysis) with him in the spring. How is Erdogan, generally speaking as a teacher? I'm taking 425 (honors advanced analysis) with him in the spring.  This question is actually for you? What was 447 like? I'm considering taking it for my math minor (If I want to get a phd in Econ, Real Analysis looks pretty good). Took it with Nikolaev. Not an easy class, but the exams were not that bad since you get to pick 5 out of 8 questions and 4 questions are proofs from a list that he gives beforehand. He also puts up all lecture notes online which is awesome. The textbook used was Elementary Analysis: The Theory of Calculus by Ross but lots of the proofs given in the book were not really as detailed as the ones given in the lecture notes, so I mostly used the book for exercises. Apparently real analysis is really important for grad school in economics so I would definitely take it.  This question is actually for you? What was 447 like? I'm considering taking it for my math minor (If I want to get a phd in Econ, Real Analysis looks pretty good). This question is actually for you? What was 447 like? I'm considering taking it for my math minor (If I want to get a phd in Econ, Real Analysis looks pretty good).  My understanding is that 500 level classes in math are significantly harder than 400 level classes. Take it only if you enjoy such stuff (which you "should" - this is a beautiful topic).</snippet></document></searchresult>