<searchresult><uiuc /><document><title>Posted asking for help with an exchange application. Got accepted today. Thanks r/UIUC !</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/177f62/posted_asking_for_help_with_an_exchange/</url><snippet>  Glad our comments could help. Now you must claim your promised drink. Heh heh. Only if OP goes to a /r/UIUC meetup when he/she gets here. Aw you have those? It'd be nice to thank people in person. Occasionally. We just had one about a week ago. How was that btw?   You're going to have to wear orange and blue at the same time.  You know this, right? Oh that's gonna look hideous on me. Oh that's gonna look hideous on me. Oh that's gonna look hideous on me. This is about the only place where you can go around wearing a fluorescent orange t-shirt/sweatshirt and not look odd. I own seven (my high school was also orange and blue)  </snippet></document><document><title>ECEHacker's 4chan /g/ logs</title><url>http://archive.installgentoo.net/g?search_tripcode=%21e1337Hykks&amp;amp;task=search2&amp;amp;offset=24</url><snippet>  He uses his name on 4chan? This guy.... The size of his ego, of course he was a tripfag. Not sure if it was just plain and simple ego or (quite understandable) psychological issues. I feel like heartless, intrusive, stalking paparazzi for even posting this, but he kind of seemed to want to draw attention to himself. 

Findings from News-Gazette article, Circuit Clerk webpage, google, comments on /r/uiuc by people who knew him:

1. Mother died two years back (possibly from cancer?)
1. Older parents (mother born in 1949, ECEHacker in 1991, father currently in late 70s)
1. Only child - no siblings
1. Homeschooled
1. Socially awkward
1. Rich - possibly easy access to money for buying keyloggers, PVC pipes, etc. (I have no idea how much these cost)
1. Has run some marathons, half marathons, 10Ks, 5Ks.
1. Showing off his technical/hacking knowledge and skills seemed to be a prime source of self-esteem/self-worth for him.

So my amateur assessment of his psychological profile (I am not a psychologist or psych major):

ECEHacker being an only child and being homeschooled had no close relationships except with his mother, and must have been devastated when she died. If she was sick for some time he must have been experiencing chronic, high-level stress for some period of time. Being socially awkward he didn't make friends here and probably didn't have skills to deal with grief/loss. If he was egotistical he probably didn't want to seek counseling and believed he could handle it by himself. Running seems to have been an outlet but he probably needed more stuff to regain the attention that he missed now that his mother wasn't there to give him that anymore. He seemed to have posted the first post about the hacking himself, as /u/ECEStudent2012, to draw attention to himself. Not sure if he is evil (probably not) or just a confused, disoriented guy with poor life skills and in difficult circumstances crying out for attention.
 Most of what you said sounds accurate, but he probably had at least a few friends despite his social awkwardness. One of my friends in ECE has a favorable opinion of him and said that he was friends with ECEHacker.
 Yeah now that I think of it grief about the loss of his mother might be an oversimplification and might not be the *only* reason for his attention-seeking behavior. We don't know much of his history, like why was he homeschooled? Did he get into trouble at school and was expelled (like he has been from college)? Or was he bullied? Or could he not adjust socially, or did he have learning disabilities? (I am not knowledgeable about why children are homeschooled or how they get admitted into college without high school grades).  I have no idea about ECEHacker's situation, but keep in mind that being homeschooled does not mean you keep no records. (It also doesn't mean you're socially inept. Hooray for stereotypes.) I received grades for every class I took in high school, many of which were taken outside the home anyway.  I just wasn't enrolled in a public or private school.  I had no problem getting into accredited postsecondary institutions, and now I'm a grad student here.  

Many colleges accept self-made high school transcripts signed by parents, perhaps with documentation from the local school board certifying that the student has been enrolled in a home education program.  For me, it wasn't much of an issue because I was (1) dual-enrolled in a commmunity college part-time for 10th-12th grades and (2) scored highly on the SAT.  If I had scored badly on the SAT/ACT, no doubt my high grades on my transcript would have been called into question.   I really don't know anything about homeschooling, so sorry I made assumptions. I assumed that since conventional schooling is the norm, there must be a really good reason for someone to be homeschooled. I only know what I read on [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homeschooling):

&amp;gt; The three reasons that are selected by the majority of homeschooling parents in the United States are concern about the school environment, to provide religious or moral instruction, and dissatisfaction with academic instruction at public and private schools.
 
You say:

&amp;gt; Many colleges accept self-made high school transcripts signed by parents

Can't parents inflate grades then? 

If you don't mind sharing, why were you homeschooled? Were you homeschooled all through kindergarten to high school or just a few years? How did you make friends your own age? Not sure if it was just plain and simple ego or (quite understandable) psychological issues. I feel like heartless, intrusive, stalking paparazzi for even posting this, but he kind of seemed to want to draw attention to himself. 

Findings from News-Gazette article, Circuit Clerk webpage, google, comments on /r/uiuc by people who knew him:

1. Mother died two years back (possibly from cancer?)
1. Older parents (mother born in 1949, ECEHacker in 1991, father currently in late 70s)
1. Only child - no siblings
1. Homeschooled
1. Socially awkward
1. Rich - possibly easy access to money for buying keyloggers, PVC pipes, etc. (I have no idea how much these cost)
1. Has run some marathons, half marathons, 10Ks, 5Ks.
1. Showing off his technical/hacking knowledge and skills seemed to be a prime source of self-esteem/self-worth for him.

So my amateur assessment of his psychological profile (I am not a psychologist or psych major):

ECEHacker being an only child and being homeschooled had no close relationships except with his mother, and must have been devastated when she died. If she was sick for some time he must have been experiencing chronic, high-level stress for some period of time. Being socially awkward he didn't make friends here and probably didn't have skills to deal with grief/loss. If he was egotistical he probably didn't want to seek counseling and believed he could handle it by himself. Running seems to have been an outlet but he probably needed more stuff to regain the attention that he missed now that his mother wasn't there to give him that anymore. He seemed to have posted the first post about the hacking himself, as /u/ECEStudent2012, to draw attention to himself. Not sure if he is evil (probably not) or just a confused, disoriented guy with poor life skills and in difficult circumstances crying out for attention.
 Not sure if it was just plain and simple ego or (quite understandable) psychological issues. I feel like heartless, intrusive, stalking paparazzi for even posting this, but he kind of seemed to want to draw attention to himself. 

Findings from News-Gazette article, Circuit Clerk webpage, google, comments on /r/uiuc by people who knew him:

1. Mother died two years back (possibly from cancer?)
1. Older parents (mother born in 1949, ECEHacker in 1991, father currently in late 70s)
1. Only child - no siblings
1. Homeschooled
1. Socially awkward
1. Rich - possibly easy access to money for buying keyloggers, PVC pipes, etc. (I have no idea how much these cost)
1. Has run some marathons, half marathons, 10Ks, 5Ks.
1. Showing off his technical/hacking knowledge and skills seemed to be a prime source of self-esteem/self-worth for him.

So my amateur assessment of his psychological profile (I am not a psychologist or psych major):

ECEHacker being an only child and being homeschooled had no close relationships except with his mother, and must have been devastated when she died. If she was sick for some time he must have been experiencing chronic, high-level stress for some period of time. Being socially awkward he didn't make friends here and probably didn't have skills to deal with grief/loss. If he was egotistical he probably didn't want to seek counseling and believed he could handle it by himself. Running seems to have been an outlet but he probably needed more stuff to regain the attention that he missed now that his mother wasn't there to give him that anymore. He seemed to have posted the first post about the hacking himself, as /u/ECEStudent2012, to draw attention to himself. Not sure if he is evil (probably not) or just a confused, disoriented guy with poor life skills and in difficult circumstances crying out for attention.
   &amp;gt;  That reminds me, I should really NAIR and shower before going to signal processing class in a couple hours. This is rare for EEs.

-_-  Also, his /sci/
http://archive.installgentoo.net/sci?search_tripcode=%21e1337Hykks&amp;amp;task=search2&amp;amp;offset=0

And Youtube channel
http://www.youtube.com/user/skunkworks1337/videos?flow=grid&amp;amp;view=0

And some evidence that he damaged his dorm room
http://chanarchive.org/4chan/adv/11857/itt-weird-roomate-stories Hendrick House too. Does anyone know if he was living there this year?  
He also says he's rich, so I imagine he never expected to get caught.  
And he might have been at Defcon 2011? Out of state + Hendrick House = definitely rich. Hendrick House too. Does anyone know if he was living there this year?  
He also says he's rich, so I imagine he never expected to get caught.  
And he might have been at Defcon 2011? He spoke at Defcon, but the quality of his speech was lacking. Do you have to be invited to speak at Defcon? Is there a link to his Defcon speech? Is there a link to his Defcon speech? He spoke at Defcon, but the quality of his speech was lacking. Do you have to be invited to speak at Defcon? Also, his /sci/
http://archive.installgentoo.net/sci?search_tripcode=%21e1337Hykks&amp;amp;task=search2&amp;amp;offset=0

And Youtube channel
http://www.youtube.com/user/skunkworks1337/videos?flow=grid&amp;amp;view=0

And some evidence that he damaged his dorm room
http://chanarchive.org/4chan/adv/11857/itt-weird-roomate-stories Also, his /sci/
http://archive.installgentoo.net/sci?search_tripcode=%21e1337Hykks&amp;amp;task=search2&amp;amp;offset=0

And Youtube channel
http://www.youtube.com/user/skunkworks1337/videos?flow=grid&amp;amp;view=0

And some evidence that he damaged his dorm room
http://chanarchive.org/4chan/adv/11857/itt-weird-roomate-stories  Wait... is that an actual picture of him on the /g/ page? There are several pictures of him. Never post pics with your super secret hacker name. I'm guessing it played a part in his demise. There are several pictures of him. Never post pics with your super secret hacker name. I'm guessing it played a part in his demise.   This guy has some good quotes tied to his tripcode. [This quote is on /b/'s ED page about half-way down...](http://i.imgur.com/degGuSh.jpg)

Also:

"I'm the dude in the pic and the axe is handmade by me, so is the machete behind my head.

I've also made an ATA, coilgun, can crusher, shitton of various electronics and a few electrolytic cells. Plus a ton of shit I am forgetting.

Oh yeah and some knives, and a couple air cannons, and an experimental IPL machine, and a marx generator driven emp device (ended up not wokring very well, but a bit to well) and BLAH BLAH BLAH"[ Dat Axe.](http://chanarchive.org/content/60_g/10954390/1275635109252.jpg) What is /b/? (not familiar with 4chan)

What is ED? I know only two expansions of ED and in that weird wall of text it could mean either. What is /b/? (not familiar with 4chan)

What is ED? I know only two expansions of ED and in that weird wall of text it could mean either. What is /b/? (not familiar with 4chan)

What is ED? I know only two expansions of ED and in that weird wall of text it could mean either. /b/ is the deep dark corner of the internet. It's what most people think of when they think of "4chan", though its only the sub-board called "Random". It's basically gore, weird porn, and a bunch of "fag" name-calling. A very strange place if you've never ventured far into the internets. That creepy pedophile down the street? Yeah, he's on /b/. So is your socially awkward 12 year old brother. Imagine putting a bunch of people like that together anonymously in a chatroom. Thanks, TIL. Seems like he was into stuff beyond hacking - bombs, axes, firearms. Scary. He's also out on bail.

What is /g/ in the OP?

What's up with HH anyway? The last time I read about a [crime](http://www.news-gazette.com/news/courts-police-and-fire/2011-01-27/former-ui-student-sentenced-child-porn.html) in a dorm, it was in HH too.    OP = ECEHacker? If not, why post from a new account? This needs answered OP did reply to my comment, saying it was because this was his first post to /r/uiuc, then seems to have edited it, then deleted it, but it still shows up in his [comments history](http://www.reddit.com/user/MajorJohnCrichton/comments/):

&amp;gt;"Because this is my first post on /UIUC :)

&amp;gt;edit: Also, because this is me http://bit.ly/WXy0YY (and my brother). And if I'm in space, I can't be in jail... Unless it's space jail."

Given the way in which ECEHacker was desperately fishing for attention, doing *two* AMAs and then asking himself questions and answering his own questions when no one seemed interested, I wouldn't be surprised if it was ECEHacker posting again, after getting out of jail and getting back his electronic devices from the FBI. He almost seemed to *want* to be caught.  FYI that post you quoted wasn't deleted, it was caught in the spam queue.

As was this post.

DON'T MENTION SPACE JAIL YOU'LL GET SPAM QUEUED &amp;gt; As was this post.

this post = my post above? OP did reply to my comment, saying it was because this was his first post to /r/uiuc, then seems to have edited it, then deleted it, but it still shows up in his [comments history](http://www.reddit.com/user/MajorJohnCrichton/comments/):

&amp;gt;"Because this is my first post on /UIUC :)

&amp;gt;edit: Also, because this is me http://bit.ly/WXy0YY (and my brother). And if I'm in space, I can't be in jail... Unless it's space jail."

Given the way in which ECEHacker was desperately fishing for attention, doing *two* AMAs and then asking himself questions and answering his own questions when no one seemed interested, I wouldn't be surprised if it was ECEHacker posting again, after getting out of jail and getting back his electronic devices from the FBI. He almost seemed to *want* to be caught.  OP did reply to my comment, saying it was because this was his first post to /r/uiuc, then seems to have edited it, then deleted it, but it still shows up in his [comments history](http://www.reddit.com/user/MajorJohnCrichton/comments/):

&amp;gt;"Because this is my first post on /UIUC :)

&amp;gt;edit: Also, because this is me http://bit.ly/WXy0YY (and my brother). And if I'm in space, I can't be in jail... Unless it's space jail."

Given the way in which ECEHacker was desperately fishing for attention, doing *two* AMAs and then asking himself questions and answering his own questions when no one seemed interested, I wouldn't be surprised if it was ECEHacker posting again, after getting out of jail and getting back his electronic devices from the FBI. He almost seemed to *want* to be caught.  :( I found the links by Googling "skunkworks uiuc," then found his full 4chan name and Googled that. OP = ECEHacker? If not, why post from a new account? OP = ECEHacker? If not, why post from a new account?  Does ICANN and NAIR refer to the professors? [ICANN](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICANN)  
[NAIR](http://www.naircare.com/)</snippet></document><document><title>Trustees raise UI tuition by smallest amount since 2000-01</title><url>http://m.news-gazette.com/news/education/2013-01-24/trustees-raise-ui-tuition-smallest-amount-2000-01.html</url><snippet>   &amp;gt; The state also owes the UI $502 billion in unpaid bills, the largest backlog to date, he said.

Somehow I think that number's wrong... </snippet></document><document><title>Great Video of Champaign Local Band EASTER Live at Foellinger Auditorium in December</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=byqNBFwiPhg</url><snippet>   Was this when they opened for Wavves? </snippet></document><document><title>Local high school senior publishes book!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/178puu/local_high_school_senior_publishes_book/</url><snippet>[Looks of an Angel](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/looks-of-an-angel-lauren-elizabeth/1113775978) is the book title, and I think it's really inspiring to see someone so young get something published like this. 

There's a book signing at Barnes &amp;amp; Noble at 1pm on Saturday, and I'm planning on going out to support her. I think she'd really appreciate it if she had a crowd. I don't know her, but I did graduate from her high school several years ago, and I think it's important to encourage her, so if you guys can find the time, I'd like to see you there.   Dog Ear Publishing is a self-publisher. Literally *anyone* can do that.   what high school does she attend, might I ask? Centennial. Centennial. tigers rule, chargers drool tigers rule, chargers drool  To be honest, I have a strong feeling that OP is the books author, and is trying to hype up her own book../ To be honest, I have a strong feeling that OP is the books author, and is trying to hype up her own book../ To be honest, I have a strong feeling that OP is the books author, and is trying to hype up her own book../ Agreed. I also don't think that anyone who's out of highschool would have a screen name like "fakinarsome."  Agreed. I also don't think that anyone who's out of highschool would have a screen name like "fakinarsome." </snippet></document><document><title>Engineering Survey</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/oVxVu7F.jpg</url><snippet>   We can rebuild the team...we have the technology Put everyone in Iron Man-like pads that can shoot energy beams.  Stiff arming becomes stiff beaming.   More women! It gets lonely up in here! You ECE/CS? CS minor. I die a little bit every time I walk into Siebel and see only 2-3 girls in my class. Sounds about right for CS.  Make it not so cold outside.   Make all our sports better** A lot of them are pretty good</snippet></document><document><title>textbook returns/sell backs</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1787sd/textbook_returnssell_backs/</url><snippet>So I bought several textbooks for classes that I'm now dropping. What is the best way to get the most money out of it?
i lost my receipt so i can't return it to the bookstore    </snippet></document><document><title>Look who I found in the Private Certified Housing brochure that I received today. </title><url>http://imgur.com/jI0eU7Z</url><snippet>  Sheltered College Freshman ftw I don't recall a resurgence of that meme this past fall, which is kind of surprising since even the memes that have died out still show up once in a while.   I like your username.   What am I suppose to be seeing here. I chose IT and yeah it sucks... but is there more to the joke? Fuck everything about IT. No amount of stoves is worth how lifeless this place is.  </snippet></document><document><title>Does anyone know how I can contact the DI/WPGU/Local TV Stations for a news story? My club has a big event coming up that we're trying to publicize</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/176wu8/does_anyone_know_how_i_can_contact_the/</url><snippet>Title says it all.

I'm a part a breakdancing club on campus and we'll be having a huge event come spring. We usually get some pretty big and renown international judges, and dancers come from all over the states in order to battle. Usually we get a ton of people to show up, but we're looking to break into the Chambana community more and get more people around here interested as well.

Would anyone know how I could contact students writing for the DI or working for WPGU or even the local news stations?   Some other people to contact:

* Buzz Magazine (they might actually be better to contact than DI)
* Urbana Poppin' Champaing
* UC Hip-Hop Congress Some other people to contact:

* Buzz Magazine (they might actually be better to contact than DI)
* Urbana Poppin' Champaing
* UC Hip-Hop Congress haha yea, actually our club runs in conjunction with UCHH loll

Buzz magazine sounds good too! I just don't know how to go about contacting any of them yet, or getting them interested to do a piece on the event..

any suggestions?? or better yet, if anyone has any contacts with them?  Hey - I have an email list of the local non-campus news outlets if you are interested. I can PM you the list.
</snippet></document><document><title>Housing for an incoming pre-med?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/177t8b/housing_for_an_incoming_premed/</url><snippet>Just got accepted to U of I for the fall 2013 semester. I'm coming in as a biochemistry major and I was wondering if I could get some input on housing. I'm out of state so i'm not very familiar with the area. Which dormitories do you suggest for someone who is mainly taking science-based classes?  </snippet></document><document><title>Anyone have classes in 0216 Siebel (new classroom)?
</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/176eow/anyone_have_classes_in_0216_siebel_new_classroom/</url><snippet>Anyone else think that the chairs are ridiculously uncomfortable?  Compared to other Siebel classrooms?  Yes.  Compared to most classrooms on campus?  No. Compared to other Siebel classrooms?  Yes.  Compared to most classrooms on campus?  No. Not sure what exactly bothers me.. but I can never sit comfortably in those. I'd prefer the really old wooden ones in Noyes or anywhere else.  </snippet></document><document><title>Picketers In Front of Administration Buildings</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/176vcv/picketers_in_front_of_administration_buildings/</url><snippet>I was curious if anyone knew who was picketing in front of the administration building on Illinois and Lincoln yesterday. There were two police cars with lights on watching them. The only sign I could read was "honk if you like good food" which didn't really explain much. </snippet></document><document><title>Volition Inc, makers of Saint's Row, bought by Koch Media</title><url>http://www.news-gazette.com/news/courts-police-and-fire/2013-01-23/updated-volition-chief-sees-very-positive-future.html</url><snippet>   Koch Media GmbH is *not* the same as the Koch Brothers things, right? I am glad that Volition is staying in town since it's probably the second coolest place in CU (Wolfram is number one, obvi.) How is Wolfram as a workplace? (I'm assuming you work there?) I worked at Wolfram for five years. I started off as Help Desk and when I left my title was still Help Desk, even though I was running a decent part of their *nix infrastructure by that point.

Wolfram is far and away the *worst* place I've ever worked in an IT capacity. I'd wager that it's based on your visibility within the company, though...If you stay off the radar and Stephen never notices you, you might be fine...As long as you can handle the low pay.

They tried to make it somewhat "fun" and "relaxed." Free soda and other beverages, a foosball table, etc...But the pay sucked, working anywhere near Stephen or anyone else in his family was a total drag and telling people "no"---even if you were completely justified---would get you in real trouble.

I could go on...But I'm out of time for now. I'd avoid Wolfram at all costs. Work somewhere---anywhere---else, and you'll be doing yourself a favor. &amp;gt; I started off as Help Desk and when I left my title was still Help Desk

So you were an application support specialist?

I am also curious why they call themselves "Wolfram Research"? What research do they do? MATLAB developers call themselves only "The Mathworks".

Stephen Wolfram did an [AMA](http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/qisot/im_stephen_wolfram_mathematica_nks_wolframalpha/) a while back and there was a lot of angst against him in the comments. He says he lives in Boston, so isn't the Champaign branch free from (what seems like) his tantrums? They still seem to have a fair number of employees and seem to be one of the major employers in town after the university and the hospitals.

Thanks for your reply! Internal Help Desk, part of the IT group. I left Wolfram in 2005 so department and position names may have changed. The external support groups at Wolfram are Tech Support and Customer Service. You call Customer Service when Mathematica chokes on your license key and you call Tech Support when you can't figure out how to get something to work right in Mathematica.

Apparently you'd call Help Desk if you were an employee and you needed an Office upgrade...You'd tell us you'll be leaving your computer at your desk while you're at a meeting...But you take your laptop and leave the external monitor. I have *lots* of stories like this...

No idea about why they're called Wolfram Research, Inc.

When I worked there, Stephen was still in the process of moving to Boston from Chicago. Most of SW's time was spent in Chicago, but he would come down regularly---at least for every company meeting and usually more often---to wreak havoc, fire entire departments, call us all blithering idiots, etc. Good times.

When SW lived in Chicago and his home network stopped working, guess who he called? Us. In Champaign. So some poor sysadmin---I was never "lucky" enough to get this task---would drive up and work on his stuff, usually literally being screamed at by SW the entire time. SW got one sysadmin so worked up he ended up puking from the stress while he was there. Not cool.

I was the technical lead for a project, the goal being migrating our 3,500 mailing lists---note, at the time we only had 300 employees, so let that sink in for a minute---and all their archives from Majordomo/MHonArc to Mailman. The project was a slam dunk for me...Pretty straightforward. Of course, SW's brother Conrad was overall "in charge" of the project. I banged heads all the time with Conrad about his decisions that weakened the project from a technical or support point of view...He hated the way the Mailman footers looked in messages, so he wanted them turned off. I lobbied long and hard for why that footer should remain on---it gives you easy access to your settings for the list, easy access to the archives and a few other reasons---but was finally told by my IT supervisor to "just turn the thing off." So I did. Then forwarded all support calls for people asking how to get to the Mailman archives or list settings to Conrad's phone.

The footer got turned back on. :) "I never realized there would be *that* *many* support questions." That's just it...They make decisions about stuff like that there without listening to the tech geeks' opinions.

This project got "taken away" from me a week or so later, cause I wasn't cooperative enough. That was literally the reason the project got taken away. "Conrad feels you are not agreeing with him often enough." I said, "great! Someone else can deal with Conrad."

The gave me that project back a month later, mostly cause Conrad hated the other guy even more...I may have been opinionated, but at least I made sense.

That's how it goes there. It's an unholy combination up top of academic refugees and corporate micro-management.

I've always heard it said that "Wolfram is a great place to have worked," and that's absolutely true. It *does* look good on a resume, has a pretty low bar for entry in most cases---will work for peanuts seems to be about all that's required---and can expose you to a pretty large group of people in various fields, all of which are looking to get out as fast as they can. :)

The only real bright spot at that place is the people. I've met some of the most talented, most interesting people I've ever encountered at Wolfram, a lot of whom are still friends of mine since I---and a good number of them---left the company. Some of us still socialize and a lot of us work to hire people from Wolfram after we're gone. It's a great source of talent. Excellent post. Why do you think Wolfram turns out to be a great source of talent? I'm not involved, but I'm going to guess it's because it's in the University's backyard with a low cost of entry (You can walk to the interview from from the senior laden Champaign housing and the requirements are not too stringent) &amp;gt; low cost of entry

What do you mean by that? Can you elaborate further? Excellent post. Why do you think Wolfram turns out to be a great source of talent? Koch Media GmbH is *not* the same as the Koch Brothers things, right? I am glad that Volition is staying in town since it's probably the second coolest place in CU (Wolfram is number one, obvi.) GmbH means it was incorporated in Germany. It's not the same.  I hope they're okay with this decision, I remember hearing that they were worried about the whole THQ situation to begin with from classes. I wonder if any of them visit /r/uiuc...</snippet></document><document><title>Student veterans, do you regret joining the military?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175w32/student_veterans_do_you_regret_joining_the/</url><snippet>The GI bill looks nice, but then you are years older than everyone else, and a little off your academic game.  Would you do it again if given the choice?  Why or why not?  

Also, what branch were you in and how long did you serve?  Hi there.

I served 4 years in the Air Force, separating last spring.  I started Parkland in the fall, with plans to transfer to U of I for it's Computer Science program after two years.

I joined the military when I was 20.  I regret the two years I wasted inbetween high school and the military FAR, FAR more than my time in service.  The benefits are numerous and awesome.

Being older has only been a blessing.  During group projects, younger members often look up to me to set the pace for the work. Being older and serving years under strict authority (Well, Air Force. . . so kind of strict) means I interact very well with my teachers, who see me as professional, motivated, and capable.

I'm not saying young people cannot have those qualities, but you can bet your study habits and work ethics will be in place if you've served before.

I was very nervous at first attending school again. I graduated high school in 2006 as a smart but lazy student and was never a fan of math.  The faculty at Parkland have been nothing short of AMAZING in helping me adjust and I finished my first semester with a 4.0. Maybe after a deployment to Afghanistan Algebra doesn't seem that tough.  Who knows?

And the G.I. bill is everything you'd imagine.  It pays full tuition, $1000 a year for books/fees, and I get about $1200 a month tax free to just pay bills on.  It's too good in my opinion.  On top of that you can collect the full Pell grant.  I'm able to list being a student as my full time job, and still make more money than my employed girlfriend.  It's really let me enjoy my time in school.

If you want to know anything else just ask.  Are you in the position of deciding whether you want to join college or the military?  You should really check out somewhere like /r/veterans or even /r/military to get some more opinions. This basically echoes my feelings and situation too, except I really didn't enjoy the Army as an organization. I did love the people I worked with though. They were absolutely fantastic.

Sheep, did you sign up with the old GI Bill and convert to the new one, or did you just get the new one right off the bat? I think I might be one of the few (read: the lucky) because I signed up and kept the old GI Bill, AND I had the Army College Fund on top of that. In short, I get like ~$2600/month (tax free) and the IL Veterans Grant pays for all my tuition and fees. It's pretty hard to complain with that arrangement. I came in under the Montgomery, and chose to give it up in order to take the GI Bill.  I could have used the Montgomery for 4 years then the GI Bill for 1, but the loss of 3 years of BAH (The $1200 every month is only for the GI Bill) was a no brainer to me. Interesting. So can I assume you weren't an IL resident when you joined? Otherwise it would have been more profitable to keep the old GI Bill because it's paying ~$1600 per month right now, and the tuition would have been covered by IVG. Regardless, it would appear you're doing fine so keep up the good work! :) Hi there.

I served 4 years in the Air Force, separating last spring.  I started Parkland in the fall, with plans to transfer to U of I for it's Computer Science program after two years.

I joined the military when I was 20.  I regret the two years I wasted inbetween high school and the military FAR, FAR more than my time in service.  The benefits are numerous and awesome.

Being older has only been a blessing.  During group projects, younger members often look up to me to set the pace for the work. Being older and serving years under strict authority (Well, Air Force. . . so kind of strict) means I interact very well with my teachers, who see me as professional, motivated, and capable.

I'm not saying young people cannot have those qualities, but you can bet your study habits and work ethics will be in place if you've served before.

I was very nervous at first attending school again. I graduated high school in 2006 as a smart but lazy student and was never a fan of math.  The faculty at Parkland have been nothing short of AMAZING in helping me adjust and I finished my first semester with a 4.0. Maybe after a deployment to Afghanistan Algebra doesn't seem that tough.  Who knows?

And the G.I. bill is everything you'd imagine.  It pays full tuition, $1000 a year for books/fees, and I get about $1200 a month tax free to just pay bills on.  It's too good in my opinion.  On top of that you can collect the full Pell grant.  I'm able to list being a student as my full time job, and still make more money than my employed girlfriend.  It's really let me enjoy my time in school.

If you want to know anything else just ask.  Are you in the position of deciding whether you want to join college or the military?  You should really check out somewhere like /r/veterans or even /r/military to get some more opinions. Can I ask what were your motivations for serving in the military? I'm curious if there are people serving in the military primarily as a means of attending college via G.I. Bill or solely as a means of helping the country. I've never asked anyone before even though I have many friends and colleagues that are on active duty or ROTC. In high school, I spoke with an Air Force recruiter about serving post-graduation. Although I wanted to serve the country, I realized that the military was not for me. Fortunately, I've had internships with government organizations (national laboratory) that have allowed me work on projects for the government without actually serving in the military. Can I ask what were your motivations for serving in the military? I'm curious if there are people serving in the military primarily as a means of attending college via G.I. Bill or solely as a means of helping the country. I've never asked anyone before even though I have many friends and colleagues that are on active duty or ROTC. In high school, I spoke with an Air Force recruiter about serving post-graduation. Although I wanted to serve the country, I realized that the military was not for me. Fortunately, I've had internships with government organizations (national laboratory) that have allowed me work on projects for the government without actually serving in the military. Hi there.

I served 4 years in the Air Force, separating last spring.  I started Parkland in the fall, with plans to transfer to U of I for it's Computer Science program after two years.

I joined the military when I was 20.  I regret the two years I wasted inbetween high school and the military FAR, FAR more than my time in service.  The benefits are numerous and awesome.

Being older has only been a blessing.  During group projects, younger members often look up to me to set the pace for the work. Being older and serving years under strict authority (Well, Air Force. . . so kind of strict) means I interact very well with my teachers, who see me as professional, motivated, and capable.

I'm not saying young people cannot have those qualities, but you can bet your study habits and work ethics will be in place if you've served before.

I was very nervous at first attending school again. I graduated high school in 2006 as a smart but lazy student and was never a fan of math.  The faculty at Parkland have been nothing short of AMAZING in helping me adjust and I finished my first semester with a 4.0. Maybe after a deployment to Afghanistan Algebra doesn't seem that tough.  Who knows?

And the G.I. bill is everything you'd imagine.  It pays full tuition, $1000 a year for books/fees, and I get about $1200 a month tax free to just pay bills on.  It's too good in my opinion.  On top of that you can collect the full Pell grant.  I'm able to list being a student as my full time job, and still make more money than my employed girlfriend.  It's really let me enjoy my time in school.

If you want to know anything else just ask.  Are you in the position of deciding whether you want to join college or the military?  You should really check out somewhere like /r/veterans or even /r/military to get some more opinions. Wish I wasn't too visually-impaired to join up. I would have most certainly for these reasons alone. :'( Geez, how bad off are you?  I'm -6 in both eyes and got in no problem.  As long as your vision is correctable (glasses/contacts) there should be no issue.

Unless you want to be a pilot.  With jacked up eyes like yours?  You can shelf that dream.    </snippet></document><document><title>Boxing at UIUC?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175v69/boxing_at_uiuc/</url><snippet>Any one know where I can learn boxing? Do we have a boxing club on campus?  As it happens there was a guy starting a boxing club at the activity day yesterday. If I get an email from him I'll come back and post his info in here.  There is a martial arts room in the  ARC, and I'm pretty sure I've seen people boxing there. interesting. do you remember how many people there were?    </snippet></document><document><title>What is the stuff they're spraying on the roads and sidewalks today?</title><url>http://imgur.com/6IzzYvj</url><snippet>   Someone once told me that it was a corn based solution to prevent ice that was invented here at UIUC.

The advantage of corn based over salt was it woudn't harm the grass next to the sidewalk.

I'm having trouble backing that up with a source, though, so consider it speculation. I'd guess with Illinois, it'd be a salt brine with corn syrup to make it adhere better: http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/nation/environment/2009-12-21-snow-ice-removal_N.htm

That link talks about why you'd use sugar beets in the solution. Yup, the beets are why you see that purplish hue to the spray when it's in the tank. obviously it's diluted enough so the actual spray doesn't turn the sidewalks purple. Will the spray attract bears? Yup, the beets are why you see that purplish hue to the spray when it's in the tank. obviously it's diluted enough so the actual spray doesn't turn the sidewalks purple.   I've always thought it was beet juice i forgot how fucking delicious beets are  Probably beet juice, Oak Park uses it  </snippet></document><document><title>Reliable/Affordable dry-cleaning in CU?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1764hf/reliableaffordable_drycleaning_in_cu/</url><snippet>I know this has been touched on briefly before but I wanted some advice on where I can get my shirts laundered reliably at a reasonable price. I've heard about Concord and Starcrest - any comments or other suggestions? I have a car so transportation isn't a huge issue. Thanks!  http://www.countrysquirecleaners.com/

That is the place I use. They have coupons on the website.  They've always had my stuff done on time.    Denny's Drycleaners on Mattis is good...they're a community favorite</snippet></document><document><title>Champaign-Urbana's best-kept secret?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1758c0/champaignurbanas_bestkept_secret/</url><snippet>Okay, I've been living here 4.5 years, but 4 of those were college. I didn't get off campus as much as I should have. Now that I live in town, I'm looking for fun things to do. So, /r/UIUC, do me a solid. **What, in your opinion, is the best-kept secret in Champaign-Urbana? What are the best places to go for fun or for a date?**

*(I did a search and saw a few similar threads, but none of them had a whole lot of suggestions.)*

Edit: Restaurants, theaters (movie/play), typical "romantic" things, museums, activities, outdoor parks, anything!  /r/uiuc, the Meat Science Lab, and The I.D.E.A. Store. [deleted] It depends on the person. ;-) [deleted]  * Fab Lab! www.cucfablab.org
* Board games at the school of library science! Wednesdays at 6:30 * Fab Lab! www.cucfablab.org
* Board games at the school of library science! Wednesdays at 6:30  Restaurant wise? or fun activities? 

Restaurant wise: Milo's, Sunsinger wines, Wines by the pines - coffee place in the day and wine place by night, Bacaro

Activity wise: curtis orchard - apple picking, wine tasting - sleepy creek vineyards, glow in the dark mini golf, drive in movie theater - harvest moon. 

(And few things are escaping my mind as of this moment) The drive-in in Gibson City is quite awesome, but bring a blanket. The first time me and some friends went we ended up wrapped in bubble-wrap and shivering under a tarp. The drive-in in Gibson City is quite awesome, but bring a blanket. The first time me and some friends went we ended up wrapped in bubble-wrap and shivering under a tarp. The drive-in in Gibson City is quite awesome, but bring a blanket. The first time me and some friends went we ended up wrapped in bubble-wrap and shivering under a tarp. Restaurant wise? or fun activities? 

Restaurant wise: Milo's, Sunsinger wines, Wines by the pines - coffee place in the day and wine place by night, Bacaro

Activity wise: curtis orchard - apple picking, wine tasting - sleepy creek vineyards, glow in the dark mini golf, drive in movie theater - harvest moon. 

(And few things are escaping my mind as of this moment)  Some of these are a drive away but can be fun.

* Bayern Stube in Gibson City http://www.bayernstube.com/ (The guys who brought you Das Cafe in Urbana)
* The Apple Dumpling for comfort food https://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Apple-Dumplin/96304097538
* Alto Vinyards http://www.altovineyards.net/
* Prairie Fruits Farm http://www.prairiefruits.com/ (Try and get in on one of their dinners on the farm)
* Staerkle Planetarium (http://www2.parkland.edu/planetarium/)
* The Corkscrew Wine Emporium https://www.thecorkscrew.com/ (They often have tastings and special events)
* Allteron Park http://allerton.illinois.edu/ Which leads to downtown Monticello
- http://www.monticellomainstreet.org/ with awesome meals at places like the 3 ravens, Main Street Pub and the Brown Bag
- Monticello Railway Museum http://www.mrym.org/
* Chanute Air Museum in Rantoul http://www.aeromuseum.org/
* If you didn't know, Eberfest is held here every year. http://www.ebertfest.com/
* Rockome Gardens in Arcola http://www.rockome.com/
* Rent out Busboom Castle in Dewey for an evening http://www.busboomcastle.com
* The farmers market in Urbana http://urbanaillinois.us/market

And keep an eye on Krannert's schedule. They have awesome things come through all the time like guitar festivals, PechaKucha nights, etc. to add to this: in town: papa del's pizza, bacca cigar, the art theater, the high dive for dance music, find a band and become a groupie

outside of town: sleepy creek winery; wyldwood wines; +1 to the Stubbe, lots of stuff to do in bloomington (yay for Bruegala in September);the beef house on the otherside of the indiana border off of 74. to add to this: in town: papa del's pizza, bacca cigar, the art theater, the high dive for dance music, find a band and become a groupie

outside of town: sleepy creek winery; wyldwood wines; +1 to the Stubbe, lots of stuff to do in bloomington (yay for Bruegala in September);the beef house on the otherside of the indiana border off of 74. How could anyone ever call papa del's a "secret"?!? to add to this: in town: papa del's pizza, bacca cigar, the art theater, the high dive for dance music, find a band and become a groupie

outside of town: sleepy creek winery; wyldwood wines; +1 to the Stubbe, lots of stuff to do in bloomington (yay for Bruegala in September);the beef house on the otherside of the indiana border off of 74. this is the first time i've ever heard someone say there's lots of stuff to do in bloomington and i lived there for 12 years.  Try Bunny's. it's in Urbana right near Black Dog. It's pretty decent and somewhat historical. Hugh Hefner got his idea for playboy bunnies here.  Citation needed, but if so, wow. Awesome! You'd never know some of the incredible history here if you didn't look out for it! Just check the letter Hugh wrote to Bunny's hanging on the wall when you visit. Amazing smoked wings on Tuesdays!  Citation needed, but if so, wow. Awesome! You'd never know some of the incredible history here if you didn't look out for it! Try Bunny's. it's in Urbana right near Black Dog. It's pretty decent and somewhat historical. Hugh Hefner got his idea for playboy bunnies here.     Meadowbrook Park on Windsor is a nice place to go for a walk if you don't feel like getting off a paved path.  If you guys are into thrifting, The Habitat ReStore in Champaign (On University Ave between First and Second) is excellent. They don't have any clothes, but they have a great selection of home goods. 

They have three levels: The upstairs is books, home decor, dishes, kitchen gadgets, lamps, pillows, etc. The main floor is furniture and electronics. The basement is building materials and tools (they have used doors, appliances, garden stuff...) I just noticed they're having a 50% off furniture sale tomorrow. fyi     </snippet></document><document><title>Lex is back? </title><url>http://www.lincolnlandexpress.com</url><snippet>   </snippet></document><document><title>1 credit courses?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/176b8k/1_credit_courses/</url><snippet>Is there a list out there of one credit courses offered at the University? I know there's ice skating but what others?      </snippet></document><document><title>Activity Day</title><url>http://www.union.uiuc.edu/welcomeweek/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>I know it's cold, but Mother Nature isn't all bad...</title><url>http://imgur.com/J2ejfZc</url><snippet>  Still looks like Barad-d&#251;r. Still looks like Barad-d&#251;r.  It's cold? Haven't noticed.     It is too damn cold. I walk around thinking how if I as a settler back in the 1700s, I would totally think this land is uninhabitable. Absolutely bitter out there.

Sorry, but I kind^of^wish^I_Went_to_school_downsouth  Mother Nature is fine and all... but *fuck* that bell tower. besides being relatively useless, why the hate? I personally think it's cool.   I've always thought it looks like a giant falic symbol from the north-south direction.  I've always thought it looks like a giant falic symbol from the north-south direction.  Someone spent a bunch of money building this as a dedication to his wife. It is more or less a statue of his penis. You are [right](http://www.uofiwiki.org/wiki/McFarland_Memorial_Bell_Tower), but that doesn't seem much like a memorial dedicated to his *wife*. Also I think 1.5 million dollars could have been spent on something better. besides being relatively useless, why the hate? I personally think it's cool.      &#38463;&#22982;&#26031;&#29305;&#26391;&#22238;&#26059;&#21152;&#36895;&#21943;&#27668;&#24335;&#38463;&#22982;&#26031;&#29305;&#26391;&#28846; Nonono...that would be the Engineering Quad.

(Google Translate English to Chinese: &#36825;&#23558;&#26159;&#24037;&#31243;&#22235;&#21512;&#38498;&#12290;)    </snippet></document><document><title>Proficiency Exams</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175y03/proficiency_exams/</url><snippet>Hey has anyone taken any proficiency exams, in particular MCB 151? 

I just want to know if they are usually pretty reasonable or would you actually have studied beforehand to do well?

Ty mates.  I've taken 2 math proficiency exams, they were both significantly harder than the finals for the classes the were for. People who design proficiency exams tend to be worrying about the difference between Type I and Type II errors. :/ It's an unfortunate issue though. Can you elaborate on what is a Type I and II error? </snippet></document><document><title>Broomball Club?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175fa4/broomball_club/</url><snippet>I saw that there was a broomball RSO but I haven't been able to find any information on it anymore. They used to have intramural broomball last year, but I guess due to weird scheduling it's not offered this year. I was just wondering if anyone knows about the broomball RSO or is possibly in it. Thanks!   </snippet></document><document><title>Headed to NW Suburbs 2/1</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175ok7/headed_to_nw_suburbs_21/</url><snippet>Hey all,

I'm headed to the NW suburbs on 2/1. I'm not sure what time, but I would like to leave around noon, but I'm flexible with time. Ideal suburbs: Palatine, Arlington Heights, Mount Prospect, Buffalo Grove, Schaumburg, Hoffman Estates, etc. I would be asking for $15 gas, perhaps less depending on the number of travelers.   Only if we can listen to Age of Adz the entire drive. Only if we can listen to Age of Adz the entire drive. Just kidding. I'm not going home that weekend. LOL</snippet></document><document><title>Illinois finally crushes an opponent they're supposed to</title><url>http://scores.espn.go.com/ncb/recap?gameId=330220158</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Anyone else in ASTR 330: Extraterrestrial Life?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/174me0/anyone_else_in_astr_330_extraterrestrial_life/</url><snippet>Hey, anyone want to form a group for the project?  I am! Group 4! Or search for Zachary Dalzell, should be a girl in it too. We both just randomly joined, so feel free to join! Awesome. Will do.  Hey! I'm the girl! Very cool. Do you have any idea for the project?  How is that class? I plan to take it next year. </snippet></document><document><title>Need some help regarding General education requirements.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175c2e/need_some_help_regarding_general_education/</url><snippet>Hey, thx for reading. Im trying to plan out my course schedule until graduation and this website (https://wiki.engr.illinois.edu/display/undergradProg/Degree+Requirements#DegreeRequirements-bseng)  says i need 18 total hours. This site (https://wiki.engr.illinois.edu/display/ugadvise/Liberal+Education+Electives) says I need at least 6 hours in each "humanities &amp;amp; arts" and "Social &amp;amp; behavioral sciences" and one course of each "western" and "non-western" culture.

So is it correct to assume it's I would satisfy all general education requirements if i take 9 hours of "humanities &amp;amp; arts" and 9 hours of "Social &amp;amp; behavioral sciences" and that some of these courses give credit for "western" and "non-western"? 

thanks again. my advisor seems very busy which is understandable since semester just started.  You can always run a [degree audit](http://www.registrar.illinois.edu/dars/generate.html) to see exactly what you have and what you need.

    </snippet></document><document><title>Is anyone in CWL/MDVL/RLST/SCAN 251 (Viking Mythology) and wants to help a girl out?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/175c1c/is_anyone_in_cwlmdvlrlstscan_251_viking_mythology/</url><snippet>I had to miss today's lecture because of a family emergency. Can anyone send me notes?  pls be my gf [deleted] [deleted] pls be my gf    [deleted] [deleted] [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Someone took my jacket :(</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1740th/someone_took_my_jacket/</url><snippet>Hey reddit, 
I was leaving cly's tonight and went to grab my coat, only to notice that it is missing. It says "illini Equestrians" on the back and has my name "anderson" on the front. If anyone finds it I'm willing to pay a reward. (who doesn't love money on a college budget?) Please keep me posted. I've had the coat for less than a week and its really shitty that someone else took it (even by mistake) 

I'd really like to be reunited with my coat, so please keep me posted! 
Thanks! 
Hailey   If I had it, I wouldn't want the reward; I'd just be happy to get someone their coat back. Hope you find it!  We have an equestrian team? Fancy  Are you sure you weren't at Joe's? Yes I'm sure, haha why?   You set a jacket down at a bar and then lost it and act surprised.... Freshman mistake broski.</snippet></document><document><title>Professor in MCB has passed away?.. Anyone with additional information?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/173uu5/professor_in_mcb_has_passed_away_anyone_with/</url><snippet>One of my classmates texted me with unfortunate news that Dr. Meisami of the MCB department had passed away. Has anyone received any details about this? From what I know, Meisami served the department and campus in many ways. He will be greatly missed.          Was he still teaching the Neuro portion of 402? Easily the most useful class that I took at UIUC. Your crazy stories will be missed good sir.  Yeah, he was teaching it. I was totally looking forward to lecture today. :( </snippet></document><document><title>Alleged ECE Hacker Arrested</title><url>http://m.news-gazette.com/news/courts-police-and-fire/2013-01-22/former-ui-student-arrested-computer-incidents-building-damage</url><snippet>  Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b holy shit is he creepy Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b We always referred to him as "Swishy-Pants Dan" he refused to wear anything but those athletic pants that swish whenever you walk around. Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b Wtf? A website that displays mugshots and then charges you money to remove them? Wtf? A website that displays mugshots and then charges you money to remove them? Wtf? A website that displays mugshots and then charges you money to remove them? Yes, it's kind of shitty. I know two people who have their mugshots on there due to marijuana-related offenses. It sucks that non-violent criminals who haven't even been convicted are grouped alongside violent or potentially dangerous criminals. Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b Here's his mugshot. If you see him on campus, you're supposed to call the police! 

http://www.dupagemugshots.com/Mugshots/Daniel.lewis_beckwitt/21196-938145a83c57c9b2cb446f9e350a920b  For as much trash talking he did, he was really, really sloppy to leave so many clues. Like why keep the key logger packaging? Why use the same alias?

Maybe it just shows he wasn't looking to get away with it but was looking for notoriety? He was definitely looking for notoriety based on how much of a cunt he was being (or at least the guy on here claiming to be him). But honestly I think he just wasn't intelligent enough to not get caught. Just because you know how to do something most people don't doesn't necessarily mean you're smart.  It's sorta like those reddit accounts who spew racial slurs and other ignorant bullshit to collect negative karma.

Negative notoriety is much, much easier to obtain then positive.

Kinda sad, really. For as much trash talking he did, he was really, really sloppy to leave so many clues. Like why keep the key logger packaging? Why use the same alias?

Maybe it just shows he wasn't looking to get away with it but was looking for notoriety? For as much trash talking he did, he was really, really sloppy to leave so many clues. Like why keep the key logger packaging? Why use the same alias?

Maybe it just shows he wasn't looking to get away with it but was looking for notoriety? &amp;gt; Maybe it just shows he wasn't looking to get away with it but was looking for notoriety?

That must be it, since he did an AMA here *twice*. Can somebody link one of these AMAs? I missed them.  &amp;gt; Maybe it just shows he wasn't looking to get away with it but was looking for notoriety?

That must be it, since he did an AMA here *twice*. He was also "suspended" by the university coming into the fall, and I guess it was a really, really long one, too, so maybe he just wanted to fuck with the school? Based on his rantings, he probably got caught cheating/plagiarizing and decided he shouldn't have been punished for it. He tried to tie it back to anti-secrecy ideals but that sort of misses the point when it comes to going to school.  Sweet I was his roommate last spring, i'm only surprised that it took this long... AMA please! ha yeah, i lived with a douche, AMA. Woah at HH? I was the guy down the hall, Beckwith would always come down to talk to my roommate. He'd start bragging about hacking with iCards. Total douche. Always felt bad for ya man. Yeah but after the FBI investigation I got upgraded to an East suite for free, so it wasn't all bad. And I got all these fun stories.  &amp;gt;FBI investigation

Elaborate, please Well, it was ~1AM on a thursday night, I was trying to fall asleep when I began smelling spray paint fumes. And then I got up and the fumes were coming through my vent and filling my room. I go out into the main room and he's spray painting his PVC breathing apparatus black **and all the windows were closed**. Pissed that he didn't care to tell me he'd be filling the quad with fucking spray paint I told him to stop and let the house manager know about it the next day. 

Well, they sent up housekeeping the next afternoon to clean and look around. They saw the SCBA and a bottle of Ammonia laying around the main room and that led to the Fire Dept coming up. Yadda, yadda, yadda they found some more stuff and alerted the FBI. Then *they* came up and poked around some more. And one of the agents looked and talked like Hank Schrader from BrBa which was pretty amazing. But once they talked to Dan, it turned out to be some big misunderstanding and that was the end of it...for the time being.  Is that the same story about SCBA as mentioned in the article? Yeah but after the FBI investigation I got upgraded to an East suite for free, so it wasn't all bad. And I got all these fun stories.  FBI Investigation? Wow..... you should do an AMA Yeah but after the FBI investigation I got upgraded to an East suite for free, so it wasn't all bad. And I got all these fun stories.  Unrelated question about HH: why do I often see a fire engine on Gregory Street beside HH? Those seem to be there for some non-emergency purpose (sirens aren't blaring). Probably for the food, it's amazing. I'd see firefighters in the cafeteria a lot.  Firefighters can go to the dorms for food? HH is private housing, but they're also a catering service. Anyone can buy a meal plan or single meal.  Firefighters can go to the dorms for food? Unrelated question about HH: why do I often see a fire engine on Gregory Street beside HH? Those seem to be there for some non-emergency purpose (sirens aren't blaring). Woah at HH? I was the guy down the hall, Beckwith would always come down to talk to my roommate. He'd start bragging about hacking with iCards. Total douche. Always felt bad for ya man. ha yeah, i lived with a douche, AMA. ha yeah, i lived with a douche, AMA. How many fedoras does he own? ha yeah, i lived with a douche, AMA. Kid was a huge asshole Sweet I was his roommate last spring, i'm only surprised that it took this long... Sweet I was his roommate last spring, i'm only surprised that it took this long... Did you know it was him? Or at least have some suspicions? He was always doing weird shit at night, so when I heard about an ECE hacker, I just assumed it was him. Nothing like coming home after class and being told "...you might wanna open your windows." No real reason, just curious, but was he socially awkward or well adjusted?  No real reason, just curious, but was he socially awkward or well adjusted?  No real reason, just curious, but was he socially awkward or well adjusted?  I propose all his roommates (and/or anyone else who knew him) do a joint AMA. Or let's have a thread titled "Do you know the ECE hacker? What is he like?" Though I fear that is exactly the kind of attention he wants. He was always doing weird shit at night, so when I heard about an ECE hacker, I just assumed it was him. Nothing like coming home after class and being told "...you might wanna open your windows."   LOL "detective james carter" like in rush hour????  Haha. His "hack" involved physical keyloggers.  How embarrassing...no skill required. Perhaps CITES should start offering two-factor authentication considering everyone now has smartphones or can receive text messages.  I'd be less worried about him getting my NetID and password than my bank credentials. How embarrassing...no skill required. Perhaps CITES should start offering two-factor authentication considering everyone now has smartphones or can receive text messages.  Not everyone has a smartphone. Haha. His "hack" involved physical keyloggers.  Haha. His "hack" involved physical keyloggers.  So all those tor claims were lies? How does a keylogger work? Don't you have to have access to an account on the computer to be able to install a keylogger?  [This](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h9u7kMAFmys) might be the kid giving a talk on Youtube. It's his alias (Skunkworks), he mentions he's an undergrad in EE, and this Google+ [profile](https://plus.google.com/118117176631346586394/posts) is friends with some UIUC people and seems to be the same guy.

But seriously, what a moron. My god, if that's him he put basically every word he said on the slides. This man for sure deserves to be in prison.  [This](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h9u7kMAFmys) might be the kid giving a talk on Youtube. It's his alias (Skunkworks), he mentions he's an undergrad in EE, and this Google+ [profile](https://plus.google.com/118117176631346586394/posts) is friends with some UIUC people and seems to be the same guy.

But seriously, what a moron.  Props to the CITES dudes who ran this investigation.

Also, props to campus police for the two former incidents where they visited his apartment for suspicious behavior, determined it was legal, and let him be.

I hope his roommates get their electronic devices back soon, though :/ That's exactly what I thought! If I was one of his roommates, I'd be really fucking pissed! That's exactly what I thought! If I was one of his roommates, I'd be really fucking pissed! So would I. He definitely seems like the type of dude that would use his roommates computers to do illegal activity... so it's understandable why they were taken.     I'm always amazed what one can find out about a person via google. Apparently, in addition to being the alleged ECE hacker, this guy finished several 10ks and one marathon (at a pace of 9 to 13 minutes per mile), his mother died on December 12, 2010, and he was a former treasurer of the Rube Goldberg Society.  ECE hacker used at least two aliases on reddit, /u/ECEHacker and /u/burrito_eliteo. ECEHacker did two AMAs ([this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/142v6i/iama_ece_department_hacker_amaa/) and [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/151qqg/iama_ece_hacker_amaa/)), and I remember burrito_eliteo made a [comment](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/143b3h/meeting_with_office_for_student_conflict/c79kei0?context=3) about having to go to the Office for Student Conflict Resolution for having [PVC pipes in his room](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cn5i1?context=3), which he later deleted. Also, clearly he is [not ESL](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cjaln?context=3).  ECE hacker used at least two aliases on reddit, /u/ECEHacker and /u/burrito_eliteo. ECEHacker did two AMAs ([this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/142v6i/iama_ece_department_hacker_amaa/) and [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/151qqg/iama_ece_hacker_amaa/)), and I remember burrito_eliteo made a [comment](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/143b3h/meeting_with_office_for_student_conflict/c79kei0?context=3) about having to go to the Office for Student Conflict Resolution for having [PVC pipes in his room](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cn5i1?context=3), which he later deleted. Also, clearly he is [not ESL](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cjaln?context=3).  ECE hacker used at least two aliases on reddit, /u/ECEHacker and /u/burrito_eliteo. ECEHacker did two AMAs ([this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/142v6i/iama_ece_department_hacker_amaa/) and [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/151qqg/iama_ece_hacker_amaa/)), and I remember burrito_eliteo made a [comment](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/143b3h/meeting_with_office_for_student_conflict/c79kei0?context=3) about having to go to the Office for Student Conflict Resolution for having [PVC pipes in his room](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cn5i1?context=3), which he later deleted. Also, clearly he is [not ESL](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cjaln?context=3).  ECE hacker used at least two aliases on reddit, /u/ECEHacker and /u/burrito_eliteo. ECEHacker did two AMAs ([this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/142v6i/iama_ece_department_hacker_amaa/) and [this](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/151qqg/iama_ece_hacker_amaa/)), and I remember burrito_eliteo made a [comment](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/143b3h/meeting_with_office_for_student_conflict/c79kei0?context=3) about having to go to the Office for Student Conflict Resolution for having [PVC pipes in his room](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cn5i1?context=3), which he later deleted. Also, clearly he is [not ESL](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/14dzvk/new_hack_from_the_ece_hacker/c7cjaln?context=3).   This can't be the guy, he's not a grad student in CS! &#3232;_&#3232;

TBH if a hypothetical grad student in CS had 'hacked' anything you'd probably *never hear about it*.   Can someone link to this reddit post they speak of? the supposed ECE Hacker did an AMA here on /r/uiuc a while back. It was deleted because he basically just ended up asking himself questions and then answering them. Can someone link to this reddit post they speak of?  Why would we suspect the keyloggers and the "tampering with locks" to be the same person? &amp;gt; After the first incident, where one lock was damaged, an e-mail was sent out from a professor's account with information about the vandalism, but the professor hadn't authored the email, Geis said.

Sounds like his M.O, at least. I guess "makes the lock inoperable" to me sounds like random mischief. Maybe it was supposed to imply that he used this method to break into a locked building?   I wonder how the roommates feel?  Also why would he would not be attending UIUC yet live on campus?    Again remember the importance of innocent until proven guilty. So there are connections that do not fully prove he was responsible(Doesn't mean the cops don't have anything). We got some websites he visited and a supposed confession which may or may not have that much weight.  Yeah. I'm not seeing much to link him to the lock tampering and fraudulent email - at least not from the article. There's a post linking an alias of his with the hacking of TA accounts, but it's all kind of inconclusive without directly linking one of his machines to the post. The packaging sounds like it could be damning, but we don't really know enough yet to tell.

He definitely sounds like a douche from what others here have said, but I'd hesitate to rush to judgement. This could be an unfortunate collision of CITES finding evidence of something similar (the TA hacking), some attention seeking bragging, and the police saying "Wait, I remember this guy. He was weird...".   Why? What?

This is like a recurring thing with typically 'nerdy' majors like ECE and physics and other engineers; they had few friends in high school for various reasons and their solution to remedy this upon entering college is to try to be the 'alpha nerd'. Then everyone will be in awe of their douchitude and they will have legions of followers! Yeah! Make thermite in my dorm! Download terabytes of shit! Pretend I am making a bomb in my spare time!

Case in point: "Yeah bro, I totally hack into people's accounts in my spare time. I'm a big-ass hacker." Or; "Oh I read about string theory in my spare time and mouth off to my dumbass highschool science teacher who just couldn't understand how brilliant I was." Stupid. Why? What?

This is like a recurring thing with typically 'nerdy' majors like ECE and physics and other engineers; they had few friends in high school for various reasons and their solution to remedy this upon entering college is to try to be the 'alpha nerd'. Then everyone will be in awe of their douchitude and they will have legions of followers! Yeah! Make thermite in my dorm! Download terabytes of shit! Pretend I am making a bomb in my spare time!

Case in point: "Yeah bro, I totally hack into people's accounts in my spare time. I'm a big-ass hacker." Or; "Oh I read about string theory in my spare time and mouth off to my dumbass highschool science teacher who just couldn't understand how brilliant I was." Stupid. Why? What?

This is like a recurring thing with typically 'nerdy' majors like ECE and physics and other engineers; they had few friends in high school for various reasons and their solution to remedy this upon entering college is to try to be the 'alpha nerd'. Then everyone will be in awe of their douchitude and they will have legions of followers! Yeah! Make thermite in my dorm! Download terabytes of shit! Pretend I am making a bomb in my spare time!

Case in point: "Yeah bro, I totally hack into people's accounts in my spare time. I'm a big-ass hacker." Or; "Oh I read about string theory in my spare time and mouth off to my dumbass highschool science teacher who just couldn't understand how brilliant I was." Stupid.  Seems like poor [ECE hacker's mother passed away](http://www.legacy.com/obituaries/washingtonpost/obituary.aspx?n=linda-beckwitt&amp;amp;pid=147117633) a couple of years back, and this might have been his maladaptive way of coping. That's at least much better than the [NIU shooter](http://www.aolnews.com/2010/03/18/college-killer-had-long-history-of-mental-illness/) who was attending UIUC when he went on a shooting spree in similar circumstances.

PSA: There is counseling available on campus, seek help if you are going through difficult circumstances and find yourself unable to cope. Don't act out in a dysfunctional manner. Honestly, after reading all the stories about this kid and the shit he was making, now that he got busted I hope he doesnt freak out Yeah, one of the charges brought against him during his arraignment yesterday is:

    FIREARM W/O VALID FOID/ELIG  

The News-Gazette article doesn't mention anything about a firearm. This is the most serious of the 5 charges against him (it's a Class A felony). The details of the other charges (criminal damage to property, computer fraud, forgery) are available on the Champaign County Circuit Clerks's [webpage](https://secure.jtsmith.com/clerk/yytt331s.asp) (seach for his name in the criminal division).
 Oh fuck. I dont like that one bit... really really dont like that   What legal right did the investigators have to take his roomates computers and phones? What legal right did the investigators have to take his roomates computers and phones?  He was in my ECE 391 class last semester, interesting that the article says he wasn't a registered student. </snippet></document><document><title>My friend, a graduate in Civil Engineering, turned out to be a musician! I never knew he was a singer till now!</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LTIHeZbuTxI</url><snippet /></document><document><title>IllinoisNet Problems</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/172vy0/illinoisnet_problems/</url><snippet>Is anybody else unable to connect to IllinoisNet or UIUCnet today?
I haven't been able to connect all day.   There's currently an outage that seems to be affecting the DHCP services that serve the wireless networks (across all SSIDs).  CITES is aware of the problem and is hopefully working to fix it - they first acknowledged the issue at 11:00am.  Yeah it's frustrating that it's taking so long to be repaired, but then again look at the scale and complexity of the wireless networks on campus - I'm actually surprised that this is the first mass unplanned outage that I've experienced.

The [CITES Status Page](http://status.cites.uiuc.edu/index.cgi) has more information and will hopefully be updated soon.

 There's currently an outage that seems to be affecting the DHCP services that serve the wireless networks (across all SSIDs).  CITES is aware of the problem and is hopefully working to fix it - they first acknowledged the issue at 11:00am.  Yeah it's frustrating that it's taking so long to be repaired, but then again look at the scale and complexity of the wireless networks on campus - I'm actually surprised that this is the first mass unplanned outage that I've experienced.

The [CITES Status Page](http://status.cites.uiuc.edu/index.cgi) has more information and will hopefully be updated soon.

 I don't understand why they didn't communicate about the outage to the users.  We get emails broadcast to everyone about every assault that takes place on campus.  Why can't we get some communications about the systems we rely on?

It's unprofessional. I'm guessing you place internet at equal value with human life. I hope you enjoyed your little argument with your imaginary friend there.  I have to admit, that seems kind of pathetic.

If you'd rather talk to a real person with a nuanced position, I'll be right over here. Chill out.  Grow up. Once again, chill out. You seem to be the one who is worked up about this. Once again, chill out.  seems to be down at the moment. surprised they aren't sending out any mass emails about this. It's been acknowledged and posted on the [CITES status page](http://status.cites.uiuc.edu/index.cgi).  No need to send a massmail about it.  My phone claims it's on Illinois Net in Loomis now. This is after not being able to connect anywhere earlier today.    It was good until about 10:30 this morning. I wasn't able to connect in my 8am this morning I wasn't able to connect in my 8am this morning</snippet></document><document><title>Student arrested for making fake IDs</title><url>http://www.news-gazette.com/news/courts-police-and-fire/2013-01-22/formal-charges-expected-after-ui-student-arrested-over-fake-i</url><snippet>    Damn, at least do it in an apartment if youre going to be breaking the law like that. In the dorms is stupid. Better yet, dont do it. Amazing his common sense allowed him to get into this school. At the very least, don't smoke weed in the same room you're making fake IDs. Or if you're gonna smoke weed, remember the toilet paper rolls and dryer sheets. And pile some laundry on your safe. Really need a legal expert in here. But I think that under the circumstances, the person here could have denied the request of the officer for searching his safe. 

So basically(if I am correct) it was insanely stupid on his part. But like I said, the levels of idiot is astounding.  Or if you're gonna smoke weed, remember the toilet paper rolls and dryer sheets. Don't forget the exhaust fan. Just get a box fan, point it outside, open a window, and let it run full blast, making sure the smoke goes OUT the window. 

Source: I went to boarding school for high school. This is how kids avoided getting caught (in an environment where teachers actively went out looking for people smoking outside/in their room) for years. Still happens.  I did this on the 4th floor of Weston not but 7-8 years ago. We got busted for drinking once, but I smoked every day and never got caught.   </snippet></document><document><title>3D Printers on Campus</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/172lj4/3d_printers_on_campus/</url><snippet>Do we have access to the 3D printers? I remember using them for GE 101 but don't know if they would let people who aren't in classes that use have access to them. I would pay for all my materials, I just want to be able to use the printers themselves.
Thanks.  What size of an Item are you needing to print?
We have a 6x6x6 inch ABS printer at the CUC FabLab you can use. All you need is an STL file of your creation, and pricing is just $2 for usage + $0.10/gram of plastic it uses.  What size of an Item are you needing to print?
We have a 6x6x6 inch ABS printer at the CUC FabLab you can use. All you need is an STL file of your creation, and pricing is just $2 for usage + $0.10/gram of plastic it uses.  My parts will probably end up being about 7 inches high. They are long rectangular pieces really. Is is possible to print parts that long? Or will I have to change the design to split it into pieces? And thanks for the info. I'll check it out. What is the CUC though?  I've got a Makerbot Replicator w/ Dual extrusion nozzles in my lab in Siebel.

It's not specifically "public use" but I'm more than willing to let you use it if you're respectful of the hardware / you probably need to coordinate with me for access to the room.

I'll let you know, though, that 3d printing is pretty tough work. There's a lot of issues with adhesion and warping and stuff, at least in my experience. Will the Makerbot print things with a 7+ inch dimension? And I've been meaning to find someone with some real experience with a printer so I'll be PMing you soon with some questions if you don't mind.  https://www-s.mechse.uiuc.edu/rplab/stl_prep.php

If you can log in, just submit tickets with your parts. Links not working right now but I'll try again soon. So you just upload your files and they will print it off for you or what? Yeah, the link isn't working, but typically you make an STL file, log in, tell them what machine you want to use, the material you want to print out of, any special instructions and give them an account to charge it to. If you don't have an account you'll have to go talk to Professor King (I think) who's in charge of the lab but he's quite nice. I've done a bunch of stuff there - if you have questions feel free to ask. Yeah, the link isn't working, but typically you make an STL file, log in, tell them what machine you want to use, the material you want to print out of, any special instructions and give them an account to charge it to. If you don't have an account you'll have to go talk to Professor King (I think) who's in charge of the lab but he's quite nice. I've done a bunch of stuff there - if you have questions feel free to ask.  </snippet></document><document><title>The Moon and Jupiter over UIUC tonight.</title><url>http://www.flickr.com/photos/zdaz/8403333369/in/photostream</url><snippet>  [And here is a computer simulation](http://i.imgur.com/3y71pRL.png)  Very nice!

What camera/lens/settings did you use? Thanks, I used:

Nikon D600 with a Nikon 300mm 2.8 + a 1.4 teleconverter. I then cropped it a ton. Your name is misleading.  Gotta love ZDaz's work Thanks dude, how're you doing? It's been a while Been good just busy as ever. </snippet></document><document><title>Come be a part of Illinois Congressional Debate Society! Wednesdays at 6pm in Lincoln 1060.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/172b0w/come_be_a_part_of_illinois_congressional_debate/</url><snippet>We are having our first [official meeting of the semester](https://www.facebook.com/events/273698116090446/?ref=3) tomorrow evening and we would love to have you come out.

We debate in the form of a mock congress, in which student-written legislation is debated through speeches for or against the given bill or resolution. Following each speech is a questioning period. I promise it is more fun than I make it sound here.

This will help you overcome your fear of public speaking, think critically on your feet, and of course pad your resume.

Shoot me a message if you'd like me to add you to our e-mail list, and of course, RSVP to the event!

Thank you! </snippet></document><document><title>What Campus Safety Concerns does /r/UIUC have?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1710cr/what_campus_safety_concerns_does_ruiuc_have/</url><snippet>Hello, I've been recently appointed to the Illinois Student Senate Committee on Campus Safety and I wanted to know what concerns and suggestions /r/UIUC has to improve campus safety. Any suggestions will be considered and are greatly appreciated. Thank you guys so much. Let's make campus a safer place!  I think bike lanes need be more thoughtfully laid out in some areas so they don't abruptly end or begin. For example, when bike riders (like myself) are heading east on Armory, when they get to 4th, there is no easy way to get onto the bike path that runs by the sidewalk adjacent to the Armory. I've seen a lot of people have to continue in the street and it really makes drivers nervous to have them riding alongside them, especially if they stay off the bike path all the way to the light at 6th and Armory. Basic things like that. I think bike lanes need be more thoughtfully laid out in some areas so they don't abruptly end or begin. For example, when bike riders (like myself) are heading east on Armory, when they get to 4th, there is no easy way to get onto the bike path that runs by the sidewalk adjacent to the Armory. I've seen a lot of people have to continue in the street and it really makes drivers nervous to have them riding alongside them, especially if they stay off the bike path all the way to the light at 6th and Armory. Basic things like that.   Suggestions:

* Make security whistles and pepper sprays widely available (kind of like the cold packs and contraceptives at McKinley). Right now only those people who take the initiative to buy them possess them.
* Make SafeRides more responsive. Don't turn down requests for rides and ask the caller to take the bus because the bus stop is only 2 blocks away. A lot can happen in 2 blocks in a dark, scarcely populated neighborhood at 2 AM, or even at 9 PM. Yes, a few people will take advantage of this and end up using SafeRides as a free taxi service, but I think that is a reasonable cost to bear if more people can be safe. I feel like the saferides issue is my biggest concern. I have never been able to get saferides to cooperate with me once to take me home despite being really close to campus, so by the time I'm even on campus i just resort to a bus.  The purpose of 335 SafeRides, which is agreed upon by the University of Illinois and Illinois Student Senate, is to "provide safe transportation to individuals who are generally traveling alone when **no other means of safe transportation are available** within the designated boundaries." The [boundaries](http://www.cumtd.com/maps-and-schedules/route/335-saferides/weekday/night/map) reach just beyond the UI campus. As you can see on this map, there are five MTD routes that offer late-night fixed-route service (after midnight): 50 Green, 100 Yellow, 120 Teal, 130 Silver, and 220 Illini. These routes cover a tremendous amount of ground and operate with 10 and 20 minute frequency.

There are rules to riding SafeRides. When someone calls, they will be asked questions their origin and destination as well as how many people they are with. "There is a maximum limit of three persons per pick-up location, except at the Illini Union, ISR, and the Main Library at Armory &amp;amp; Wright. 335 SafeRides **does not duplicate fixed-route service already provided by MTD.** 335 SafeRides does not provide emergency transportation service to medical facilities. **335 SafeRides does not provide service to and from the bars.**"

To read between the lines, if there are groups greater than three people travelling together there is a fair assumption that there is safety in numbers. For students who are on campus and travelling to a densely populated area like a residence hall, the Illini Union, or a library, fixed-route service is perfectly suited and much more available. But for students who are starting and/or ending at destinations that are remote such as off-campus apartments, campus buildings or labs located in corridors not served by fixed-routes - SafeRides is a valid option.

As CJS7070 mentioned, wait times would be increased if students within a reasonable walking distance were all granted a SafeRide. Students make requests for SafeRides even when both their origin and destination are on fixed route service. Students will move themselves further from fixed-route service and call MTD again in hopes of reversing a denied SafeRide. This is unfortunate, but a regular challenge of providing the service.

In answer to simplyxsilly and AlmostGrad100, there are two SafeRides vans in operation Sunday through Wednesday and three SafeRides vans Thursday through Saturday during the UI Fall and Spring Semesters. CJS7070 was correct that MTD added to SafeRides service in the recent transportation contract renegotiation for 2012-2015. The additions included the extra van Thursday through Saturday as well as adding SafeRides service serving during the Fall, Winter, and Spring Breaks.

MTD and the University of Illinois want students to use SafeRides and fixed-route services when travelling at night. Campus crime is an unfortunate battle that MTD is helping combat. MTD launched an awareness campaign, [Bee Scene](http://www.cumtd.com/the-inside-lane/2013/01/14/bee-scene/), this Spring 2013 semester to increase awareness of safe behaviors which include night-time safety. Students must exercise safe practices which include not walking alone and making plans ahead of time. AlmostGrad100 mentioned that "a lot can happen in two blocks." [SafeWalks] (http://publicsafety.illinois.edu/universitypolice/safewalks.html) are available through the University of Illinois Police Department. If someone is uncomfortable walking to a bus stop, a SafeWalks escort can be called (217.333.1216) to walk with the individual.

Thank you for your feedback and thanks to CJS7070 for bringing this thread to our attention. The purpose of 335 SafeRides, which is agreed upon by the University of Illinois and Illinois Student Senate, is to "provide safe transportation to individuals who are generally traveling alone when **no other means of safe transportation are available** within the designated boundaries." The [boundaries](http://www.cumtd.com/maps-and-schedules/route/335-saferides/weekday/night/map) reach just beyond the UI campus. As you can see on this map, there are five MTD routes that offer late-night fixed-route service (after midnight): 50 Green, 100 Yellow, 120 Teal, 130 Silver, and 220 Illini. These routes cover a tremendous amount of ground and operate with 10 and 20 minute frequency.

There are rules to riding SafeRides. When someone calls, they will be asked questions their origin and destination as well as how many people they are with. "There is a maximum limit of three persons per pick-up location, except at the Illini Union, ISR, and the Main Library at Armory &amp;amp; Wright. 335 SafeRides **does not duplicate fixed-route service already provided by MTD.** 335 SafeRides does not provide emergency transportation service to medical facilities. **335 SafeRides does not provide service to and from the bars.**"

To read between the lines, if there are groups greater than three people travelling together there is a fair assumption that there is safety in numbers. For students who are on campus and travelling to a densely populated area like a residence hall, the Illini Union, or a library, fixed-route service is perfectly suited and much more available. But for students who are starting and/or ending at destinations that are remote such as off-campus apartments, campus buildings or labs located in corridors not served by fixed-routes - SafeRides is a valid option.

As CJS7070 mentioned, wait times would be increased if students within a reasonable walking distance were all granted a SafeRide. Students make requests for SafeRides even when both their origin and destination are on fixed route service. Students will move themselves further from fixed-route service and call MTD again in hopes of reversing a denied SafeRide. This is unfortunate, but a regular challenge of providing the service.

In answer to simplyxsilly and AlmostGrad100, there are two SafeRides vans in operation Sunday through Wednesday and three SafeRides vans Thursday through Saturday during the UI Fall and Spring Semesters. CJS7070 was correct that MTD added to SafeRides service in the recent transportation contract renegotiation for 2012-2015. The additions included the extra van Thursday through Saturday as well as adding SafeRides service serving during the Fall, Winter, and Spring Breaks.

MTD and the University of Illinois want students to use SafeRides and fixed-route services when travelling at night. Campus crime is an unfortunate battle that MTD is helping combat. MTD launched an awareness campaign, [Bee Scene](http://www.cumtd.com/the-inside-lane/2013/01/14/bee-scene/), this Spring 2013 semester to increase awareness of safe behaviors which include night-time safety. Students must exercise safe practices which include not walking alone and making plans ahead of time. AlmostGrad100 mentioned that "a lot can happen in two blocks." [SafeWalks] (http://publicsafety.illinois.edu/universitypolice/safewalks.html) are available through the University of Illinois Police Department. If someone is uncomfortable walking to a bus stop, a SafeWalks escort can be called (217.333.1216) to walk with the individual.

Thank you for your feedback and thanks to CJS7070 for bringing this thread to our attention. Safewalks. That should definitely be a thing more people remember. Is there anyway for, say, MTD to coordinate with SafeWalks so that people who call in a ride, but are, say, 2 blocks from a stop, can get safewalks called for them?  Safewalks. That should definitely be a thing more people remember. Is there anyway for, say, MTD to coordinate with SafeWalks so that people who call in a ride, but are, say, 2 blocks from a stop, can get safewalks called for them?  Even a student-based organization for safewalks would be a good idea. I transferred from a school with a paid student security team, and one of their big responsibilities was walking with people at night if they felt unsafe. Most of the time this was as simple as walking them across campus to their car. It was utilized by students and staff. I feel like the saferides issue is my biggest concern. I have never been able to get saferides to cooperate with me once to take me home despite being really close to campus, so by the time I'm even on campus i just resort to a bus.  I think that's the point - if you're within a certain distance of a bus that will get you to your destination, you need to use that service instead. 

People say SafeRides service is slow now; imagine if it also picked up everyone who requested a pickup despite their proximity to a fixed service location. I think that's the point - if you're within a certain distance of a bus that will get you to your destination, you need to use that service instead. 

People say SafeRides service is slow now; imagine if it also picked up everyone who requested a pickup despite their proximity to a fixed service location. &amp;gt; imagine if it also picked up everyone who requested a pickup despite their proximity to a fixed service location.

I don't believe they do so - SafeRides takes more time than a bus, so people request a SafeRide only when they feel unsafe. I don't think many people are so lazy that they would wait half an hour to avoid a one-block walk, and then possibly be driven all over Urbana and Champaign for half an hour more before they get home. Suggestions:

* Make security whistles and pepper sprays widely available (kind of like the cold packs and contraceptives at McKinley). Right now only those people who take the initiative to buy them possess them.
* Make SafeRides more responsive. Don't turn down requests for rides and ask the caller to take the bus because the bus stop is only 2 blocks away. A lot can happen in 2 blocks in a dark, scarcely populated neighborhood at 2 AM, or even at 9 PM. Yes, a few people will take advantage of this and end up using SafeRides as a free taxi service, but I think that is a reasonable cost to bear if more people can be safe. I was given a whistle as a freshman, do they not do that any more?  I believe the overwhelming consensus is they don't work. When I took the rape class thing as a freshman, what they said was, "You blow your whistle, then anyone around you blows theirs, then anyone around them blows theirs, and in a couple minutes the police know someone is being raped somewhere in the Champaign-Urbana area."  I believe the overwhelming consensus is they don't work. When I took the rape class thing as a freshman, what they said was, "You blow your whistle, then anyone around you blows theirs, then anyone around them blows theirs, and in a couple minutes the police know someone is being raped somewhere in the Champaign-Urbana area."  I was given a whistle as a freshman, do they not do that any more?  I was given a whistle as a freshman, do they not do that any more?  Suggestions:

* Make security whistles and pepper sprays widely available (kind of like the cold packs and contraceptives at McKinley). Right now only those people who take the initiative to buy them possess them.
* Make SafeRides more responsive. Don't turn down requests for rides and ask the caller to take the bus because the bus stop is only 2 blocks away. A lot can happen in 2 blocks in a dark, scarcely populated neighborhood at 2 AM, or even at 9 PM. Yes, a few people will take advantage of this and end up using SafeRides as a free taxi service, but I think that is a reasonable cost to bear if more people can be safe. Sounds good except for the pepper spray part.  It's not an effective tool for stopping an attacker.  Speaking from experience. Really, were you attacked and did the pepper spray further aggravate the attacker? I have wondered about this, whether pepper spray does disorient the attacker or does it aggravate them. I am sorry that you had an experience like that. Relax it was part of a non-lethal course when I was active duty.  
If you can hit someone in their open eye with your pepper spray it should (but not guaranteed) stun them for a few seconds.  But can you draw it, and spray accurately, and make sure their eye is open faster than they can grab you? If you can then do it and run like hell because after that initial shock (if you nailed an open eyeball) you can still see.  And yeah, it's aggravating, so much so that I don't care who or what you are, if I get sprayed ever again I will latch on to that person and keep hitting until they stop moving.  If someone wants to hurt you I promise pepper spray will make them want to hurt you more. It was never meant to be a tool for self defense.

The fact that you recommend it without ever having tried it on yourself is very irresponsible, feel free to try it.  Have a friend spray you, but it's painful and it lasts for hours. Sounds good except for the pepper spray part.  It's not an effective tool for stopping an attacker.  Speaking from experience. Do you have any recommendations given your experience? Suggestions:

* Make security whistles and pepper sprays widely available (kind of like the cold packs and contraceptives at McKinley). Right now only those people who take the initiative to buy them possess them.
* Make SafeRides more responsive. Don't turn down requests for rides and ask the caller to take the bus because the bus stop is only 2 blocks away. A lot can happen in 2 blocks in a dark, scarcely populated neighborhood at 2 AM, or even at 9 PM. Yes, a few people will take advantage of this and end up using SafeRides as a free taxi service, but I think that is a reasonable cost to bear if more people can be safe. isn't there only one saferides bus? it would be hard to do that without adding many more vehicles to the program. isn't there only one saferides bus? it would be hard to do that without adding many more vehicles to the program. Is it only one now? It has been quite a while since I used a SafeRide, but a driver once told me that they have 10 vans (if I remember correctly) operating at peak hours (maybe 10 PM - 4 AM). Even that is a pretty low number in my opinion. I found [this article](http://www.cumtd.com/the-inside-lane/2012/02/27/uiuc-transportation-fee/) which says that an increase in the number of SafeRides was one of the primary requests that the Illinois Student Senate made last year to MTD. 

I also think they shouldn't deny requests which sound like taxi service requests, like people wanting rides to/from parties or bars or restaurants or grocery stores. They shouldn't treat requests for rides from libraries/departments to dorms/apartments as the only legitimate requests. Denying SafeRides isn't going to stop people from going to parties or bars, and if they don't want to spend $15 on a cab they will end up having drunk people walking back who will be less alert and more vulnerable to crime. Is it only one now? It has been quite a while since I used a SafeRide, but a driver once told me that they have 10 vans (if I remember correctly) operating at peak hours (maybe 10 PM - 4 AM). Even that is a pretty low number in my opinion. I found [this article](http://www.cumtd.com/the-inside-lane/2012/02/27/uiuc-transportation-fee/) which says that an increase in the number of SafeRides was one of the primary requests that the Illinois Student Senate made last year to MTD. 

I also think they shouldn't deny requests which sound like taxi service requests, like people wanting rides to/from parties or bars or restaurants or grocery stores. They shouldn't treat requests for rides from libraries/departments to dorms/apartments as the only legitimate requests. Denying SafeRides isn't going to stop people from going to parties or bars, and if they don't want to spend $15 on a cab they will end up having drunk people walking back who will be less alert and more vulnerable to crime.  To be quite honest, I'd like to get into another discussion: How safe is the U of I to the rest of Champaign/Urbana and other college campuses? The amount of crime alerts that we get and how it fluctuates sorta skews perceptions (mine, at least) of how many crimes there actually are.

To me, it seems that a lot of the crime alerts that we are emailed are the same type of crime - someone walking out alone at night that just happens to be in the wrong place at the wrong time. On a campus this size, where many people are out during the middle of the night for various reasons and have various levels of awareness, odds are eventually someone will be unfortunately robbed. I'm not saying that nothing can be dome about the crime here - I hope there are some real improvements and that you can make some big changes - but to what extent can the university enforce safety policy in campustown, which would only be the Uni Police (please correct me if I'm wrong)? The data is out of date, but the site is still useful. Check http://campuscrime.net, which was made by a journalism class here. It explores some of the issues you brought up.  From [http://www.dps.illinois.edu/universitypolice/CurrentASR.pdf](http://www.dps.illinois.edu/universitypolice/CurrentASR.pdf) for 2011,

Arrests for rape, robbery, assault, burglary, arson, and auto theft:  93  

Arrests for liquor and "Drug abuse" (because anyone who uses drugs is an abuser, right?  Nevermind, I don't need you to read from the student handbook):  464

Judicial referrals for liquor and "drug abuse":  1028

Instead of undercover cops at bars; why not local gangs?  Instead of finding intoxicated minors;  finding burglars?  Instead of looking for people carrying open liquor;  carrying weapons?

Anyway, I feel safe on campus.  At least, I feel as safe as I do anywhere else.

Edit:  Slight change for clarity Those are some nice stats you have there, but you have to take into account the sheer number of "rape, robbery, assault, burglary, arson, and auto theft" that happen are ten folds smaller than the number of underage drinkers/ drug abusers. 

Also  cops don't give a shit if you're drunk. It's when you are drunk and doing really stupid shit, that's when you get a ticket.  &amp;gt;Those are some nice stats you have there, but you have to take into account the sheer number of "rape, robbery, assault, burglary, arson, and auto theft" that happen are ten folds smaller than the number of underage drinkers/ drug abusers. 

And the number of arrests that occur for the amount of crimes committed are vastly smaller as well.  You do know that the majority of rapes go unreported, right?  Or look at the other person who responded to my post.  Most people who are mugged/robbed don't even file a police report, because the police don't care/can't do anything about it.

Regardless, that's sort of beside my point, and was only suppposed to be used as an illustrative tool.  What's more important to the people who are paying to go to school here?  Or the kids' parents who sent them here?  That the kids don't drink or that they don't get mugged?  That their child isn't raped or that they don't smoke pot?  

I don't know what the statistics are, but I'd like to see a survey of the campus police departments or the people who are in the administration of the school.  How many of them drank underage or did illegal drugs?  Considering that teen drinking rates have dropped since the 1960s, and that we still have 80% of people under 21 having drank, I'd think it's a very safe assumption that the majority committed the same illegal acts.  IT SURE RUINED THEIR LIVES, RIGHT?  THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN MUCH SAFER IF WE GAVE THEM A TICKET.

&amp;gt;Also cops don't give a shit if you're drunk. It's when you are drunk and doing really stupid shit, that's when you get a ticket. 

Not really, just being in the wrong place at the wrong time is enough. From [http://www.dps.illinois.edu/universitypolice/CurrentASR.pdf](http://www.dps.illinois.edu/universitypolice/CurrentASR.pdf) for 2011,

Arrests for rape, robbery, assault, burglary, arson, and auto theft:  93  

Arrests for liquor and "Drug abuse" (because anyone who uses drugs is an abuser, right?  Nevermind, I don't need you to read from the student handbook):  464

Judicial referrals for liquor and "drug abuse":  1028

Instead of undercover cops at bars; why not local gangs?  Instead of finding intoxicated minors;  finding burglars?  Instead of looking for people carrying open liquor;  carrying weapons?

Anyway, I feel safe on campus.  At least, I feel as safe as I do anywhere else.

Edit:  Slight change for clarity Definitely agree about focusing more on violent crimes rather than drinking tickets, but that seems unlikely to change as the city makes a lot of money handing out drinking tickets. Something else to keep in mind is that the University doesn't report all the crime going on in the campus area. A couple years ago I was assaulted on Green St in front of Za's around 2 in the morning (many people were still out and about), and when I went to the campus safety building to report it, the cop basically told me that the University police wouldn't even report it since there was basically nothing they could do about it.  People not understanding the difference between sidewalks and bike paths. Also bikers not understanding the difference between bike paths and sidewalks. Lets all ride our bikes down the quad when it's ridiculously busy! Seems like a fantastic idea Also bikers not understanding the difference between bike paths and sidewalks.  I always ride my bike. It wasn't for a safety reason, but thinking about it now, I think it's a safer way to travel.  I may be alone in this, but I have always found the lighting on campus (esp. the main quad) to be way too dim, more like mood lighting than anything else. I'd like big bright lights around campus. 

I'd also like to see the "safety tips" in the crime alerts to go away or be revised severely. The tone of them is very victim-blaming to me. People have the right to safe travel on campus at night, and shouldn't be made to feel guilty if they can't round up a posse for safety every time they go out. 

EDIT: As the comments have descended into a debate on victim blaming, here's something I'd like to see in the safety tips: What the fuck do I do if I am getting mugged? Do I do what the guy says? Do I curl up in a ball to protect my voonerables or do I fight back? Should I carry a decoy wallet like the Europeans do in mugging areas?  I Agree with the lighting issue but those safety tips really are common sense. I may be alone in this, but I have always found the lighting on campus (esp. the main quad) to be way too dim, more like mood lighting than anything else. I'd like big bright lights around campus. 

I'd also like to see the "safety tips" in the crime alerts to go away or be revised severely. The tone of them is very victim-blaming to me. People have the right to safe travel on campus at night, and shouldn't be made to feel guilty if they can't round up a posse for safety every time they go out. 

EDIT: As the comments have descended into a debate on victim blaming, here's something I'd like to see in the safety tips: What the fuck do I do if I am getting mugged? Do I do what the guy says? Do I curl up in a ball to protect my voonerables or do I fight back? Should I carry a decoy wallet like the Europeans do in mugging areas?  IIRC there's actually a separate committee that's in charge of lighting on campus and nothing more.  [Perhaps you could try contacting them about this.](http://studentaffairs.illinois.edu/campuscommittees/lighting.html) IIRC there's actually a separate committee that's in charge of lighting on campus and nothing more.  [Perhaps you could try contacting them about this.](http://studentaffairs.illinois.edu/campuscommittees/lighting.html) I may be alone in this, but I have always found the lighting on campus (esp. the main quad) to be way too dim, more like mood lighting than anything else. I'd like big bright lights around campus. 

I'd also like to see the "safety tips" in the crime alerts to go away or be revised severely. The tone of them is very victim-blaming to me. People have the right to safe travel on campus at night, and shouldn't be made to feel guilty if they can't round up a posse for safety every time they go out. 

EDIT: As the comments have descended into a debate on victim blaming, here's something I'd like to see in the safety tips: What the fuck do I do if I am getting mugged? Do I do what the guy says? Do I curl up in a ball to protect my voonerables or do I fight back? Should I carry a decoy wallet like the Europeans do in mugging areas?  This is actually a big misconception.  Bright lights are often result in glare and result in sharp, harsh shadows where people can hide.  You might not be able to see sharp details (what someone's shirt says), but you will be able to see shapes and movement across a much larger area. That's interesting, I've never heard that before! Do you have any links/readings?  I don't specifically.  I have a friend who is really into lighting related stuff as a hobby.  I'll ask him for more info.
 I may be alone in this, but I have always found the lighting on campus (esp. the main quad) to be way too dim, more like mood lighting than anything else. I'd like big bright lights around campus. 

I'd also like to see the "safety tips" in the crime alerts to go away or be revised severely. The tone of them is very victim-blaming to me. People have the right to safe travel on campus at night, and shouldn't be made to feel guilty if they can't round up a posse for safety every time they go out. 

EDIT: As the comments have descended into a debate on victim blaming, here's something I'd like to see in the safety tips: What the fuck do I do if I am getting mugged? Do I do what the guy says? Do I curl up in a ball to protect my voonerables or do I fight back? Should I carry a decoy wallet like the Europeans do in mugging areas?  I may be alone in this, but I have always found the lighting on campus (esp. the main quad) to be way too dim, more like mood lighting than anything else. I'd like big bright lights around campus. 

I'd also like to see the "safety tips" in the crime alerts to go away or be revised severely. The tone of them is very victim-blaming to me. People have the right to safe travel on campus at night, and shouldn't be made to feel guilty if they can't round up a posse for safety every time they go out. 

EDIT: As the comments have descended into a debate on victim blaming, here's something I'd like to see in the safety tips: What the fuck do I do if I am getting mugged? Do I do what the guy says? Do I curl up in a ball to protect my voonerables or do I fight back? Should I carry a decoy wallet like the Europeans do in mugging areas?  Telling a person to take measures to protect them self from harm is not "victim blaming" 

But no, instead, let's tell criminals not to do bad things.  They always listen right? You can only control your own actions, your safety is up to you. Most rapes are by acquaintances. Usually they tend to rationalize things and not see themselves as criminals. The "common sense" tips they tend to dispense, like not walking alone in the dark doesn't help in these circumstances. Telling people what rape is and HOW not to be a rapist would help in this type of situation.
 Most rapes are by acquaintances. Usually they tend to rationalize things and not see themselves as criminals. The "common sense" tips they tend to dispense, like not walking alone in the dark doesn't help in these circumstances. Telling people what rape is and HOW not to be a rapist would help in this type of situation.
 Telling a person to take measures to protect them self from harm is not "victim blaming" 

But no, instead, let's tell criminals not to do bad things.  They always listen right? You can only control your own actions, your safety is up to you. Actually, sometimes they do.
http://freethoughtblogs.com/greta/2013/01/08/rape-prevention-aimed-at-rapists-does-work/ Telling a person to take measures to protect them self from harm is not "victim blaming" 

But no, instead, let's tell criminals not to do bad things.  They always listen right? You can only control your own actions, your safety is up to you. I'm not the first person to make this criticism:

http://www.patheos.com/blogs/lovejoyfeminism/2012/09/its-just-common-sense-versus-victim-blaming.html

http://socialistworker.org/2013/01/07/victim-blaming-system-excuses-rape I understand your criticism, but you're approaching the situation with a victim mentality, and so are the authors of your articles.  You're looking for ways to make your self more of a victim (no offense).  No one is going to say "you weren't walking in a well lit area, with a friend, and it was late at night so it's not an official assault/mugging/ect. and we aren't going to charge your attacker."  That would be victim blaming and that's wrong.  
But if I tell you you're an idiot because you got mugged after flashing tons of cash at the bar and being barely able to stand when you tried to walk home by yourself, that's not victim blaming, that's me being annoyed that you didn't even try to take care of yourself.  Your attacker is still going to jail, but if you had acted sensibly you wouldn't have gotten hurt.   


I could sit here and be indignant over all kinds of things, but I'm not, because I don't have that kind of mentality.  I choose how I feel and how I let things affect me.   I understand your criticism, but you're approaching the situation with a victim mentality, and so are the authors of your articles.  You're looking for ways to make your self more of a victim (no offense).  No one is going to say "you weren't walking in a well lit area, with a friend, and it was late at night so it's not an official assault/mugging/ect. and we aren't going to charge your attacker."  That would be victim blaming and that's wrong.  
But if I tell you you're an idiot because you got mugged after flashing tons of cash at the bar and being barely able to stand when you tried to walk home by yourself, that's not victim blaming, that's me being annoyed that you didn't even try to take care of yourself.  Your attacker is still going to jail, but if you had acted sensibly you wouldn't have gotten hurt.   


I could sit here and be indignant over all kinds of things, but I'm not, because I don't have that kind of mentality.  I choose how I feel and how I let things affect me.    I'd say increase the range of where crime alerts are reported. It's almost all student housing between University and Kirby and Neil and Lincoln (or Race?). I'd like to know when there is an uptick in criminal activity on my street or block, which is where I'll be walking to in the late night and early hours, rather than just what is happening around the quads and dorms. Well, that pretty much encompasses the entire campus.... keep in mind, the crime alerts are mainly for the university, not for CU as a whole.     Enforcement of bicycling laws - I was hit (not hard) on Green Street underneath one of many signs that say "No bikes" that are posted every 50 feet or so on Green Street yet are universally ignored and not enforced. I also dodge cyclists almost daily riding west on East John that blow the red light in front of Swanlund to cross Sixth and proceed the wrong way on East John (which turns into a one-way at this point headed east) while barely missing pedestrians crossing East John in the marked crossing with the walk signal on.  Concealed Carry. Concealed Carry. IIRC, carrying on campus is an expulsion worthy offense under the student code. Concealed Carry. **Pros:** Would, for the most part, deter attacks that we associate with crime alters.

**Cons:** In college, many people consume lots of alcohol. Guns would not be a good addition to that.

In principle, the idea makes sense - no one is going to fuck with people if there is a possibility anyone is carrying. At the same time, all the drunkness in college, and other issues like stolen guns and people who use bad judgement while the carry could make even worse problems than robbery. I understand your point well, but the difference between concealed carry and not **to me** is this - when there's no concealed carry, I have to watch out for that one person that's hiding from me at night; when there is concealed carry, I have to watch out for any bad situation or altercation or people that seem unstable any time, day or night.  That's a perfectly reasonable concern, fortunately most carry laws prohibit you from carrying while intoxicated and/or in a bar.  That doesn't mean that people won't break the law, but if people aren't carrying now because it's against the law it stands to reason that they won't carry when it's still against the law. Oh yeah, I'm sure there won't be guns allowed in bars, but you never know what will happen during those many pregames. *Anyone* carrying a gun would scare me. Mental fitness varies with time, and even the possibility that someone might be lax about their weapon would scare me.  A person who was mentally fit at the time they bought the gun might get depressed, stressed, intoxicated, drunk, high, addicted, fail out of school, have a break-up, lose a loved one, and that might affect their mental health - no one can accurately predict a person's future mental health, and unless the government keeps track of every gun owner's mental health on a daily/weekly basis, I would feel very afraid if I knew everyone was carrying guns, and walk on eggshells trying very hard not to upset anyone because who knows when they might snap.   I think people are less fragile than you give them credit for.

I suppose I could make all the standard arguments against what you're saying (but I would feel like an ass), so I'm mostly curious why you think this way. I think I just explained why I felt that way. Only one person needs to snap to kill 20 people. In a university with 40,000 students, even if the probability of that happening is 1/40,000 that would be too great a risk. A mass shooting making front-page news every month or so does nothing to dispel my fears. 

Also, it's not so much a question of fragility as emotional stability *in the moment*. A drunk person might be normally stable when not drunk, but might have poor judgment and poor impulse control while drunk. And universities have young people with less maturity and less impulse control and more testosterone and adrenaline than the general population, and they are also under stress (academic, moving away from home, etc.). I really don't think you would want to add guns to this mix. Granted, not everyone snaps, in fact the vast majority doesn't, but even if the probability is 10^-4 , it's 4 people and that's 4 people too many. I think 1 in 40000 is way over estimating. Using your example of a mass-shooting making the news every month (and assuming all of those happen in this country) that is only 12/300,000,000 (approximately 4X10^-8 percent of the population (if we use 40000 as the campus population that makes 0.0016 people violent psychopaths)).

That's not to say I think everyone should be able to carry a concealed firearm (I'm in favor of background checks and mandatory training), but I hope that gives a bit of perspective. Rough calculation: [Illinois has ~1.2 million gun owners](http://www.nwitimes.com/news/local/illinois/number-of-illinois-gun-owners-jumped-in/article_bcd7271d-28d1-54bb-b67d-87e498864b82.html), and the [intentional homicide rate is ~6 per 100,000](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_intentional_homicide_rate#United_States). The [population of Illinois is 12 million](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Illinois), so that is a rate of 6x10^-5 when 1/10 th of the population owns guns. If everyone owned a gun, the rate would be 6x10^-4 , 24 times higher than 1 in 40,000 (= 2.5x10^-5 ). *Anyone* carrying a gun would scare me. Mental fitness varies with time, and even the possibility that someone might be lax about their weapon would scare me.  A person who was mentally fit at the time they bought the gun might get depressed, stressed, intoxicated, drunk, high, addicted, fail out of school, have a break-up, lose a loved one, and that might affect their mental health - no one can accurately predict a person's future mental health, and unless the government keeps track of every gun owner's mental health on a daily/weekly basis, I would feel very afraid if I knew everyone was carrying guns, and walk on eggshells trying very hard not to upset anyone because who knows when they might snap.   I have to agree to a large extent - I know people that use guns for sport and protection in their home, and that doesn't bother me at all. Also, our attitude toward guns is dependent on culture and environment - many western states have very lax gun laws and concealed carry is common. If we lived in one of those states and were exposed to those behaviors, maybe our feelings would be less apprehensive. 

With that being said, the amount of trust that I would have to have from everyone around me if guns were concealed carry would be about the same as the amount of trust I wold have walking home in the middle of the night by myself, and that is not much. In short, I wouldn't feel safer in a situation where I or someone else has to actually use the gun; there are many more variables to consider when you can't be sure who does and who does not have a weapon. Of course, I would almost always be safe in a concealed carry environment, but the times that I'm not would outweigh the benefits in my situation.

**EDIT:** Grammar &amp;gt; Of course, I would almost always be safe in a concealed carry environment

How? In a hypothetical situation where everyone carries guns, how would you protect yourself if someone shoots you from behind? Or like the Aurora theater case, would you immediately be able to get your gun out in a dark theater and protect yourself? I think many people would be uncomfortable carrying a weapon at all times and would not do it even if it were legal. If we need to carry lethal weapons at *all* times to protect ourselves, then it means we trust our fellow men too less to be considered a civilized society. And sometimes weapons bought to protect yourself can be used against you, like the Newtown guy who used his mother's weapons against her. I don't think people can be trusted to be that meticulous and careful about their weapons, someone who lives in the same house is eventually going to figure out how to use them if they are determined to do so. My use of the phrase 'almost always be safe' was a reference to time, as in most of the time, we can trust people to not use their weapons in some sort of altercation, or worse, unprovoked. This is how I think about it - lets say there is a hypothetical situation where there is an altercation within a group of people and everyone has a concealed weapon. Most likely, no one would brandish their weapon because they would know that if they did, some one would retaliate and everyone in the room is in grave danger. Common sense would (hopefully) prevail.

The almost comes in due to cases that you just described - a situation like Aurora or Sandy Hook, which in a sense of any one person's probability of being in an incident of that nature is extremely low, but the consequences of that actually happening is so devastating that it wouldn't be reasonable to have concealed carry.

I do agree with your opinion that most people would not carry weapons if there were lax gun laws because they aren't needed. With the law enforcement that we have today, its rarely necessary or even beneficial in a densely or even moderately populated area. The hypothetical situation you describe is actually what scares me most about concealed carry laws: groups of strangers "self-defensing" each other to death.

And I say this having lived in Tennessee, where gun restrictions are absurdly loose.  The hypothetical situation you describe is actually what scares me most about concealed carry laws: groups of strangers "self-defensing" each other to death.

And I say this having lived in Tennessee, where gun restrictions are absurdly loose.  *Anyone* carrying a gun would scare me. Mental fitness varies with time, and even the possibility that someone might be lax about their weapon would scare me.  A person who was mentally fit at the time they bought the gun might get depressed, stressed, intoxicated, drunk, high, addicted, fail out of school, have a break-up, lose a loved one, and that might affect their mental health - no one can accurately predict a person's future mental health, and unless the government keeps track of every gun owner's mental health on a daily/weekly basis, I would feel very afraid if I knew everyone was carrying guns, and walk on eggshells trying very hard not to upset anyone because who knows when they might snap.   Concealed Carry. Haha, good luck trying to get that to happen in this state.   [The SCOTUS ruled that Illinois laws banning concealed carry are unconstitional.](http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2012-12-11/news/chi-us-appeals-court-strikes-down-states-concealedcarry-ban-20121211_1_court-strikes-appeals-court-david-sigale)

I don't really know how it's going to work out, though.  Chances are good that it will just be near impossible to get a license for it. It was only a federal court, it won't likely go to the supreme court for strategic reasons. 

As for the provisions themselves, they're likely going to be a middle ground. The courts gave Illinois a 180 day hiatus before all bans on conceal and carry are struck down. The republicans can block literally all progress and still essentially win. However, even the republicans don't want to see the laws just disappear as that would be chaotic and look bad for them. This means that the pro-gun side is going to have push beyond what their numbers may suggest. Also, the NRA is dedicating a lot of money to this so any for-sale politician will be in the pocket of the NRA by voting time. 

Personally I'm hoping it ends up being a shall-issue system with mandatory training. May-issue systems end up being won't-issue for anyone but the rich and powerful. I've always wondered this since the decision came out, but if Illinois doesn't write a law that has a provision for concealed carry in the time frame, what happens? Does Illinois get constitutional carry? It was only a federal court, it won't likely go to the supreme court for strategic reasons. 

As for the provisions themselves, they're likely going to be a middle ground. The courts gave Illinois a 180 day hiatus before all bans on conceal and carry are struck down. The republicans can block literally all progress and still essentially win. However, even the republicans don't want to see the laws just disappear as that would be chaotic and look bad for them. This means that the pro-gun side is going to have push beyond what their numbers may suggest. Also, the NRA is dedicating a lot of money to this so any for-sale politician will be in the pocket of the NRA by voting time. 

Personally I'm hoping it ends up being a shall-issue system with mandatory training. May-issue systems end up being won't-issue for anyone but the rich and powerful. Concealed Carry. </snippet></document><document><title>Lex buses on ebay</title><url>http://motors.shop.ebay.com/illinitours/m.html?hash=item337f36c49b&amp;amp;item=221177627803&amp;amp;pt=Buses&amp;amp;rt=nc&amp;amp;_trksid=p4340.l2562</url><snippet>  &amp;gt;Buses have been well maintained and include complete maintenance records.

Isn't the whole reason LEX got shut down because they didn't maintain the buses well? Yeah - I'd say there's some red flags if a full size charter bus is less than 20k. Well they are 17-19 year old buses, from a company trying to liquidate its assets. Having said that, I'm not exactly an expert on what a charter bus should cost. Yeah - I'd say there's some red flags if a full size charter bus is less than 20k. Fixer-uppers? Part buses? PARTY BUS /r/UIUC party bus - all 5000 subscribers pay only $4! That would be a hell of a meetup $20 gas surcharge per person. it's still a lex bus. /r/UIUC party bus - all 5000 subscribers pay only $4! That would be a hell of a meetup We could get it down to $2.40 if we get the oldest, crappiest bus they have! Fixer-uppers? Part buses?  Somebody doesn't understand how eBay works. 

They created an auction to say that there are a bunch of buses available in a fairly wide price range, and to call for more info? 

Idiots.  </snippet></document><document><title>Ex-U of I Foundation Student Caller's Thoughts on Campus Spirit Revival</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/171694/exu_of_i_foundation_student_callers_thoughts_on/</url><snippet>After seeing the progress of the Campus Spirit Revival facebook page over the last few weeks and how it is poorly managed, I feel that I must speak my thoughts. I used to work for the University of Illinois Foundation (UIF) http://www.uif.uillinois.edu/, as a student caller who phoned alumni to receive donations for our university. The donations that UIF collects from Alumni is very essentially to funding all three U of I campuses, individual colleges, academics units, libraries, scholarships etc. UIF uses a standard computer phone banking software that dials an Alumnus, shows the student caller the Alum&#8217;s current job, address, graduation year and major, previous donations, etc. and then prompts a script for the student caller to say to the Alum. If an alum does not answer or if an alum does not want to donate the student caller has to code the call and a reason for why a donation was not given to U of I.

This is the point in which Campus Spirit Revival becomes relevant. One of the most common responses, to not giving donations to the University was because of the loss of the Chief. The response is so common that it is the first reason coded in the program when a caller codes why an alumni did not donate. UIF trains all of the student callers multiples times with mock calls as to how to deal with Alumni who are upset with the loss of the Chief and has pre-scripted responses as to try to alleviate the situation, and possibly still get the Alumnus to donate.

The number of calls in which Alumni told me that U of I lost them when they lost the Chief was discouraging. Granted a good number of Alumni calls were never answered, the ones that did answer either laughed, or regrettable told me &#8220;no&#8221; because of the Chief being gone and how the University does not care about the opinion of its Alumni. If an Alumnus was ever very upset about the Chief there was even a special comment coding that would go straight to the Chancellor&#8217;s Office for them to assess input from the Alumni. All student workers at UIF know this is an issue, as otherwise we would not be trained so heavily on it. While some veteran student callers may disagree slightly it is only because they are set in their ways and with their seniority only have to call Alumni who are yearly renewal, frequent donors. 

The data of how many donations are lost to U of I due to the loss of the Chief and their relationship with Alumni in theory should be quantifiable by the UIF coding system, but a dollar amount cannot be expressed as UIF managers claim &#8220;we cannot put a value on the loss of each donation from an Alumnus not donating because of the loss of the Chief &#8211; because there is no donation&#8221;.

After working evening after evening calling Alumni and hearing them upset with the loss of Chief and how the University does not care of their input as an Alum, but only desiring their money, I eventually became sickened with my pre-scripted responses for the Alumni. Talking with the Alumni, brought light to how out of touch our University Administration was with Alumni, and I began to become sickened that I had become a part of that system. I decided I could no longer do the job UIF required of me. I no longer believed in the bullshit they told us to tell Alumni, the scripts of why to still donate with the Chief gone, if an Alum was upset with U of I, etc, so I quit my job at UIF.

I bring all of this up now, because the reality is, that every year this university loses a larger amount of donations from Alumni not only because of the loss of the Chief, but because Alumni feel disillusioned by how little the University cares about their opinion on matters, such as the Chief. The review of comments on the Campus Spirit Revival Facebook page is flooded with negative remarks from Alumni and terrible rebuttals from the admins of the Campus Spirit Revival page. If the University follows through with the input from Campus Spirit Revival - this poor representation, unworthy to be associated with U of I - will be a large insult to Alumni and will be viewed as U of I once again turning its back on Alumni opinion. I have recently been told that Chancellor Wise has appointed a Dean to oversee the outcome of Campus Spirit Revival and use their input. If this input is reviewed in the similar fashion of the smoking referendum results, then Campus Spirit Revival&#8217;s chosen mascot could be viewed by Chancellor Wise as input enough to put a motion forward. Should Campus Spirit Revival be backed by U of I or their results taken seriously by University Administration, I feel this could turn Alumni away from U of I on the same magnitude as if they removed the Chief a second time.

Please consider our U of I Alumni and how their donations fund this great university when making an opinion on Campus Spirit Revival. 
Support Stop Campus Spirit Revival http://www.facebook.com/StopCampusSpiritRevival?fref=ts

And when voting in Campus Spirit Revival&#8217;s farce of a contest, vote &#8220;No New Symbol&#8221;, as Good Alumni Relations and campus funding may just hang in the balance.
  That's really sad to hear that this leaves such a wound with all the alums. I don't have strong feelings about the issue either way, but this really saddens me - not just because of the deterioration between a university and its current *and* former students, but mostly because of what I interpret this to imply: that the Chief, our mascot, is not only vital to the function and the image of our university, but it is the MOST IMPORTANT thing about this university. The responses seem to imply that this university is not worth the time or the energy if the Chief is no longer our mascot. They imply that the university should suffer because the Chief is no longer our mascot. It really saddening to hear that, even though this university does some corrupt things, that this is a great school that does some remarkable things, and all that seems to be for naught. I understand that the heart of the issue, the underlying issue is the arrogance of the administration to disenfranchise its own alumni, but I never thought that our mascot - our Chief - would be where everyone drew the line.

So I ask one question to you OP (and to anyone else who has some experience talking to alumni and talking about this issue) - does the anger stem from the loss of the Chief, or the betrayal of the administration to remove it? **tl'dr:**Essentially a long winded version is the arrogance of the administration as you pointed out. I don't think its the Chief in particular that draws the line though, I think its everything he represented and the way the administration went about getting rid of it. 

I think you kind of missed the point or at least what I believe the point of many of these Alumni would be.

I think their disinterest is probably due to their perception that the University administration doesn't honor or respect the traditions of the University. I think tradition and legacy are naturally the things that keeps Alumni interested and obviously the University administration doesn't hold those concepts in the same regard as the Alumni do.

Obviously this isn't related to the Universities mission to educate at all, at which it does a great job. However I imagine a lot of the Alumni feel like this is no longer the institution they knew (my family had the record for the most students from one family here at one point, so there are a lot of Illini Alum in my family and I'd say thats a sentiment they would mostly agree with). I think that's the aspect of it that would make them reluctant to support the University.
 Traditions and values represented by the chief passed along from generation to generation - makes sense. I'll admit its hard for me to see things from that perspective; my second cousins and myself are the 1st generation to go to the U of I (most of my family went to Eastern). 

I'm sure there's some documentary or book or articles online, so I'll look for it later. But, if anyone would like to give their opinion, how has the chief come over the years to embody our collective values?  I think a lot of it had to do with his tenure as the mascot (Since 1926). Not only was the Chief or Mascot but he was also the logo of the University, I think he was the most visible symbol of our University.

I think (though obviously many would certainly disagree) that he was dignified in a way that not many mascots are. He would only come out to dance at major events, and wasn't cheering along the sidelines or anything, he was something of serious business.

I suspect the people wanting to remove the Chief and the controversy surrounding him had a lot to do with it. I think it is seen by many as an attack on our institutions traditions orchestrated by elements from outside the University. I suspect that aspect of it has a lot to do with the negative feelings over his departure.  And perhaps that what I was missing in all this. I see your point - the Chief isn't like most mascots where its some guy in a cartoonish animal suit, or even "human" mascots like the Fighting Irish mascot - the weird ass spastic leperchaun, or in light of recent events, Manti Te'o. There's a bit of reverence to it. 

I think what makes this such a divisive topic is that this is not just an issue of choice, it is an issue of what people identify with - an extension of the ego. This issue is a battle of pride and dignity; the adversaries are the competing perceptions of dignity between those who identify as pro-Chief, who view the Chief as an uniting embodiment of their pride and dignity as an insittution, and those who identify as anti-Chief, who view the Chief as an embodiment of the humiliation and stereotyping of native Americans. Either way will cause a loss of dignity and subsequent anger. The univeristy may have not had much of a choice about the Chief, but I wish that the aftermath was different. I hope that they try to empathize and relate to their students and alumni as much as possible, because it seems we need a way to display our pride and honor, and that there are a lot of bridges to rebuild. Indeed. It'll be interesting to see what happens with this movement for a new mascot.

I imagine for a lot of Alumni (and me personally as a recent Alumnus) I'd rather have no mascot than a new one. Even if hes not allowed to dance anymore I think the Chief is still alive and well in the hearts of many members of the University of Illinois family. 

I think in another few decades though we'll see people being more open to changes in the mascot, when most Alumni don't remember the Chief and some of the intensity and anger of the debate has been reduced.  Indeed. It'll be interesting to see what happens with this movement for a new mascot.

I imagine for a lot of Alumni (and me personally as a recent Alumnus) I'd rather have no mascot than a new one. Even if hes not allowed to dance anymore I think the Chief is still alive and well in the hearts of many members of the University of Illinois family. 

I think in another few decades though we'll see people being more open to changes in the mascot, when most Alumni don't remember the Chief and some of the intensity and anger of the debate has been reduced.  That's really sad to hear that this leaves such a wound with all the alums. I don't have strong feelings about the issue either way, but this really saddens me - not just because of the deterioration between a university and its current *and* former students, but mostly because of what I interpret this to imply: that the Chief, our mascot, is not only vital to the function and the image of our university, but it is the MOST IMPORTANT thing about this university. The responses seem to imply that this university is not worth the time or the energy if the Chief is no longer our mascot. They imply that the university should suffer because the Chief is no longer our mascot. It really saddening to hear that, even though this university does some corrupt things, that this is a great school that does some remarkable things, and all that seems to be for naught. I understand that the heart of the issue, the underlying issue is the arrogance of the administration to disenfranchise its own alumni, but I never thought that our mascot - our Chief - would be where everyone drew the line.

So I ask one question to you OP (and to anyone else who has some experience talking to alumni and talking about this issue) - does the anger stem from the loss of the Chief, or the betrayal of the administration to remove it? I would say that all universities have difficulty managing the expectations of their alumni, but ours fell extremely short when dealing with the issue of the Chief and thus left Alumni disillusioned with the University of Illinois they thought they knew. I think that by not taking into large consideration of what Alumni preferred, and what Alumni valued to be a part of ILLINOIS tradition, the administration created a group of ILLINI Alumni that were bonded much stronger than before as the group now had a large sense of connection of being for the past traditions of Illinois - what they felt made Illinois great - and against what the University administration now determines what is ILLINI tradition. The loss of the Chief was a catalyst that not only created disunity between the University and Alumni but created large unity between Alumni and the current students that do not get to experience the Chief and the values and traditions of U of I. The loss of the Chief was not a mascot to these Alumni but a symbol and logo that represented the values and traditions of what makes the University of Illinois great. Moreover, the Chief as a symbol collectively tied together the generations, that came through the university and was passed down through the students that fueled and made U of I a better place for all. When the decision came to remove the Chief, as an Alum you would expect the first person to back your tradition would be your University, but they pressured by the NCAA. This is where I feel the resentment towards U of I began, and from that point on the University should have dealt better with Alumni relations - and maybe they did - but it was not enough. Perhaps the administration underestimated the negative aftermath that could be created by Alumni relations or took Alumni for granted, but in the end not only donations, but also sporting events ticket sales have suffered largely. 

At this point, I feel that the appointment or the process of finding a new symbol or mascot will only create more division between the Alumni and the University. We hold one of the largest living Alumni bases in the country, and while there will always be those who will support U of I no matter what, there is still a huge group that could be supporting us to the extend of the loyalty and donations of Notre Dame's Alumni. There is no reason to further aggravate or possibly insult our Alumni by using the results of Campus Spirit Revival (which Chancellor Wise at present, may very well do). Campus Spirit Revival has been a trivial search process (with the probable intention of a resume addition) that is poorly managed, and inconsiderate of Alumni and their dissenting opinion, that I can only foresee this birthing a negative outcome and ripple effect among Alumni and current students alike.  I feel like this Campus Spirit Revival is just some attempt to wipe everything under the rug and pretend that the last 80 years never happened. I understand that the university has to comply to the NCAA because forfeiting playoff games would essentially destroy the sports program, but the university doesn't seem to want to have any discussion about how to proceed. After all, mascots are for fans. In the end, we either have a mascot or we don't, but the administration could acknowledge that feelings have been hurt and try to find a better solution, if there is one, to this.  We never had to forfeit games. We were told we could not host and the chief could not dance at playoff games. The first clause is the one that the university was concerned with, since the NCAA playoff games bring money in for the host University. We never had to forfeit games. We were told we could not host and the chief could not dance at playoff games. The first clause is the one that the university was concerned with, since the NCAA playoff games bring money in for the host University. On a further note, this means that the university would miss revenue for NCAA playoff games and not the actual game? I know the university has many bills to pay, but I'm starting to see the alums train of thought.  During your calls, did anyone ever want to talk about international students?</snippet></document><document><title>Gatecrash Prerelease this weekend</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/171nja/gatecrash_prerelease_this_weekend/</url><snippet>Just wondering if there was any interest in getting a group together to attend a prerelease event this weekend at either Armored Gopher or Dragon's table.  ever thought that if you explained your post better for people that have no idea what you're talking about, you might get more people interested in your event?   I was curious if there's a difference between the places.  I haven't gone to either, but is one store better than the other? Dragon's Table is on almost every bus line, Armored Gopher is on the Magenta which IIRC doesn't run often. I love Gopher it's just terribly inconvenient .  Can you explain why you love Gopher? I haven't been to Gopher yet. I was curious if there's a difference between the places.  I haven't gone to either, but is one store better than the other?  </snippet></document><document><title>Where to get Girl Scout cookies? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1708og/where_to_get_girl_scout_cookies/</url><snippet>Yeah Thin Mints and Samoas are needed.   I believe Girl Scout cookie season is in February. There are usually Girl Scouts selling cookies on the quad (from Campus Girl Scouts) and younger Girl Scouts selling them in grocery stores. 

If you can't wait, Keebler sells knockoff Thin Mints (they call them Grasshoppers) and Samoas (Coconut Dreams).  The selling season is different for each troop (as are the prices and the flavors available). If you really want them, my daughter selling them for $4/box. PM me if you want to order some. I'll pay for shipping if once she gets her supply next month. I believe Girl Scout cookie season is in February. There are usually Girl Scouts selling cookies on the quad (from Campus Girl Scouts) and younger Girl Scouts selling them in grocery stores. 

If you can't wait, Keebler sells knockoff Thin Mints (they call them Grasshoppers) and Samoas (Coconut Dreams).    Here's a general schedule for Girl Scouts of Central Illinois: http://www.girlscouts-gsci.org/cookie-activity-dates

Looks like street selling doesn't start until February 15th.  At that point, you can check here for exact selling days, times, and locations: http://www.girlscouts.org/program/gs_cookies/cookie_season.asp?t=distance

For some reason, that schedule doesn't usually get updated until right before sales start. And that is going into the calendar. He also memorised it. I was impressed right up until I checked the comments...   </snippet></document><document><title>Double Majoring in Business</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/171i1m/double_majoring_in_business/</url><snippet>Hey everyone,
I'm going to be a freshman this fall and am interested in double majoring in the school of business (I've been directly admitted). I am interested in majoring in Business Administration (Marketing) and Finance. 

Is this possible? Anyone on here have any experience in this? Will upper level finance and marketing classes kill me towards the end of my college career?

Thanks    If you can use excel, it will put you at the top of the class.  ....... Do people not know how to use excel? I have noticed it's a tough task for some  But...... But... A fifth grader could use it (rudimentarily of course but still)  Marketing is a waste of time. Go with Finance and Economics. Economics isn't even in the College of Business.</snippet></document><document><title>Wat to do on Valentine's Day?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/170n3l/wat_to_do_on_valentines_day/</url><snippet>I was just wondering if any local restaurants or places have cute valentines day things or events that me and my boyfriend could go to.  Mostly restaurants with special menus or if they have entertainment. Stuff like that.  Any suggestions would be great.  Or if you know of a particularly romantic little spot. Thanks!  take a MAT 231 exam take a MAT 231 exam take a MAT 231 exam   [deleted]     most of the restaurants will have special stuff going on so just go and ask them or call ahead.  reservations will be needed.  go somewhere you both like and just have a good time.     The Art Theater usually shows The Room.  The most romantic movie of all time.  The Art is showing "The Room" again. (It is in consideration for the worst movie of all time) I'm pretty sure that's what my girlfriend and I are doing.  [deleted] [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Jewelers around town?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/171fdv/jewelers_around_town/</url><snippet>I figured I'd ask reddit before devoting a trip to the mall sometime soon; are there any jewelers within a short bus ride or walking distance around campus(town)? I have several watches that need the batteries replaced, as well as a crystal in one of them. Thanks for any help!  I've been to Spritz Jewelers (http://www.spritzjewelers.com/spritz.htm) and had a good experince there    Several in downtown Champaign.  One at Lincoln Square Mall.  I can actually do the batteries for you, not sure about the crystal.

Beware, crystal replacement can be expensive, what kind of watch is it?</snippet></document><document><title>Last Night's Meetup Recap</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16ysuz/last_nights_meetup_recap/</url><snippet>Just wanted to say thanks to all of you that ended up coming out last night! There were about 28 that joined the group at some point in the night and we had a great time at Merry Ann's and The Blind Pig!

I hope all of you that missed us can make it out to the next one =)

Here are some pictures courtesy of mhensh01 and cooluke:

[most of group at Merry Ann's](http://i.imgur.com/fD6voHv.jpg)

[Merry Ann's again](http://i.imgur.com/r1rfC7u.jpg)

[playing Cards Against Humanity](http://i.imgur.com/TaFfvyL.jpg)

[more cards](http://i.imgur.com/GjAzsln.jpg)  the guy-girl ratio is worse than it was in my ECE classes... If you come to any kind of Internet-centered meetups expecting to meet women, you're gonna have a bad time. the guy-girl ratio is worse than it was in my ECE classes...  Seems like an appropriate (if unintended) celebration of /r/uiuc becoming the first college subreddit to have 5,000+ subscribers.    Who's got a missed connection? 
http://chambana.craigslist.org/mis/3559344237.html</snippet></document><document><title>UIUC related Postsecret this week</title><url>http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0gu9cm6VICE/UPt16pGNzQI/AAAAAAAAXNY/6SmKhvtyKro/s1600/stagesex.jpg</url><snippet>  I'll just wait here until OP delivers. http://i.imgur.com/AFhFu.jpg Well, least there was a "bone"r involved. All the people who went up to tell their secrets were women (around 20-30 of them, according to my estimate).  I attended the PostSecret event last semester and saw this on the PostSecret site, but didn't recognize it was Foellinger auditorium until I saw this post.

The most interesting thing about that event was that 97% of the audience were women. The few men that were there were with women and seemed to have been dragged there by women. 

The person who sent that postcard must have said a rather trivial secret at the event, so I'm trying to recall the secrets now.  &#3232;_&#3232; </snippet></document><document><title>Is the engineering advising open today?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16zkdl/is_the_engineering_advising_open_today/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Shlens - good landlord?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/16yl00/shlens_good_landlord/</url><snippet>I was wondering if anyone leased with Shlens.  Any thoughts?  Thanks    I had a lease with them a few years back when the husband was still around. They're not bad, but we weren't the type of tenants who ever really asked for anything. The apartments are kind of lower-end, we couldn't run the microwave at the same time as the A/C or the breaker would flip. We also had a problem with running through light-bulbs very quickly --just a terrible electrical system. We got most of our security deposit back (they made us pay for cleaning the oven, which is understandable). I wouldn't be worried that the woman's running the business by herself now, the husband rarely did anything in the first place. Just out of curiosity, which building were you in?     Currently with her now. A semester into my lease and so far I have nothing to really complain about. If anything, we regret getting an apartment with a tv included in it. At this point, you can get a better tv for the same cost and it will be yours after the lease is up. The locations she offers are pretty hard to beat for the price. 

As for the comment about the bike sticker thing, I haven't needed one at all. 

Edit:

Was reading comments below, she is quite strict with no candles and no space heaters. So far, I haven't had any huge issues with the electrical system at all (The only thing being that the bathroom fan takes a few seconds to turn on sometimes.) Found it a little that she wanted the first month's rent a month after signing, then waited a few months to cash it, but if that's my biggest complaint... not bad at all. She charged you extra for the TV? For us, it was "the rent is the same regardless, if there's a TV in the unit, then you get a TV."  Ended up with a unit with both a TV and ceiling fans.  No, she's not good. She takes forever to get anything done whether it be cashing in your rent checks, sending back your deposit, giving you a bike sticker to park your bike in the bike stands, fixing heat. My friend lived with her last year and went without heat for the whole winter and had exposed wires from his heater the whole time too. 
Avoid Shlens like the plague &amp;gt; My friend lived with her last year and went without heat for the whole winter

Yeah, I'm calling bullshit.  She's really slow at fixing things. Obscenely slow. Something has been broke in my apartment from the previous tenant. When we were looking at the apartment the tenants reminded her then and she didn't do anything. My current roommate reminded her and nothing. What is "something"?  An aesthetic fix could be forgivable (scratched/chipped/etc furniture), but if its a non-essential appliance (like a dishwasher), this would be a dealbreaker to me.</snippet></document></searchresult>