<searchresult><uiuc /><document><title>Missing friend: Have you seen her?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17uf2f/missing_friend_have_you_seen_her/</url><snippet>Hey everyone,
a friend of ours was coming down from ISU on Wednesday to visit and hasn't been heard from since then. Her roommates, family, and friends around here can't get a hold of her and no one knows where she was headed other than the University.


Thanks everyone, we're all really worried. 

Edit: Good news, everyone! They finally found her. Thanks for all the support on here, it's really appreciated.  Since Wednesday?!  I'm glad she's found safe and sound, but...you've gotta tell us what happened now that she's been found. You know, for science I haven't even heard the whole story yet, I just heard it from her sister. We're gonna talk later and if I feel I can tell the story I'll let you know. I'm glad she's found safe and sound, but...you've gotta tell us what happened now that she's been found. You know, for science      Delete the picture now that she's been found.

On a side note, this kind of shit needs to stop. If you are going to a foreign place, and planning on drinking and partying, go with friends so you don't get lost. If you and your friends are out of towners, one person gets to not drink and keep track of everyone. 

Sheesh.  really you should not post peoples' personal information on reddit regardless of the situation.  Remove all that information and tell folks to call the cops.  Remove all that information and tell folks to call the cops.   [deleted] I said the same thing to her family, but they insisted. I think finding her is more important at this point than protecting her identity (you had given only her first name anyway) or her sister's privacy (she can always change her phone number if it is misused in some way). If you want people to help, you have to give them information to work with. I hope you find her soon.  [deleted] I also sincerely hope no one would troll this post</snippet></document><document><title>Best place to do laundry? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17wh23/best_place_to_do_laundry/</url><snippet>I have a car so either Urbana or Champaign locations are fine.   Highly recommend Starcrest cleaners, in Champaign South of the CVS at Green &amp;amp; Neil.  

Lots of machines in good working order... prices aren't too bad... free wifi too.

The manager (Charlie) may seem a little strange, but he has a heart of gold, and keeps the place spotless.  There was a profile of him in the local newspaper a year ago... 

http://www.news-gazette.com/news/people/2012-05-28/still-missing-his-wife-36-years-man-keeps-himself-occupied-champaign-laundrom

 Highly recommend Starcrest cleaners, in Champaign South of the CVS at Green &amp;amp; Neil.  

Lots of machines in good working order... prices aren't too bad... free wifi too.

The manager (Charlie) may seem a little strange, but he has a heart of gold, and keeps the place spotless.  There was a profile of him in the local newspaper a year ago... 

http://www.news-gazette.com/news/people/2012-05-28/still-missing-his-wife-36-years-man-keeps-himself-occupied-champaign-laundrom

 Highly recommend Starcrest cleaners, in Champaign South of the CVS at Green &amp;amp; Neil.  

Lots of machines in good working order... prices aren't too bad... free wifi too.

The manager (Charlie) may seem a little strange, but he has a heart of gold, and keeps the place spotless.  There was a profile of him in the local newspaper a year ago... 

http://www.news-gazette.com/news/people/2012-05-28/still-missing-his-wife-36-years-man-keeps-himself-occupied-champaign-laundrom

  </snippet></document><document><title>scooter riders--please read</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17vpc6/scooter_ridersplease_read/</url><snippet>hello scooter riders--i'd like to get my M license so that i can ride a scooter over 150 cc.  is anyone on campus willing to let another student use his/her scooter for the dmv test?  of course, i'd be happy to compensate you.  I would suggest the [Motorcycle Rider Program](http://www.mrp.uiuc.edu/). It's just a few weekends and it's free. Yup, as someone who used to work at the DMV, this is your best option. Our  course for bikes can be pretty tricky for people, it usually takes you a few tries.

Also, the course costs $20 if I'm not mistaken. I took the course a few years back and highly recommend it. The fee is around $20, but it's an optional fee that you can get reimbursed. I think most people taking the course end up letting the Motorcycle Rider Program keep the fee money. And if I can make the plug, if you can afford to 'donate' the fee, please do.  They want you to learn and learn how to ride safe.   Yup, as someone who used to work at the DMV, this is your best option. Our  course for bikes can be pretty tricky for people, it usually takes you a few tries.

Also, the course costs $20 if I'm not mistaken. </snippet></document><document><title>What are some fun and/or cheap things to do around campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17uq5h/what_are_some_fun_andor_cheap_things_to_do_around/</url><snippet>I'm done with the bar scene for the most part and need things to do around campus.  you can get a loaf of bread from jimmy john's for $.50 -yea...I work at JJ...thats the last thing I want lol -yea...I work at JJ...thats the last thing I want lol  Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 GeoCaching as well.. It's like a treasure hunt of sorts! soo much fun! Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 Disney fo' lyfe. Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 Lose in a baking competition needs to be added to that list Maybe to YOUR list.  Maybe to YOUR list.  So what ended up happening with this baking contest? Lose in a baking competition needs to be added to that list Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 How do you get to the roof of Krannert? I thought they won't let you go there. 
 No, it's totally fine! You can just walk right up the stairs. If you go up the steps of that outdoor theater thing -- boom, you're there. You can also get up there with the stairs off Gregory Place. We've gone up there late at night just to sort of hang out, too. Never had any problems.  Things that I will often end up doing:

* Get some friends and play capture the flag on the roof of Krannet. I've done it at least 5 times now.

* Get some friends and play [Fugitive](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fugitive_%28game%29)

* Disney movie marathon 

* Go see a movie at the Champaign Art Theater

* Go swimming at the ARC or CRCE (waterslide!)

* Board game night. Pandemic is the greatest. 
 How do you get on the roof of Krannert?  Check out RSOs.  In my opinion, the best part of Chambana is the people, and people with common interests are great.  

Personally I like [dancing to jazz](http://illiniswing.org) (lessons start this Tues), [climbing rocks](https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/IllinoisClimbingClub), and [brewing beer](http://www.buzzbrewclub.org). Yeah, here you have to be creative and put in effort to find/create your own entertainment. It's not a big city where you can just wander into downtown and there will be a thousand things going on.  That being said, I struggle to choose between what I want to do almost every night.  There is an enormous amount of stuff to do, but you can't expect it to fall into place around you.   smoke weed smoke weed smoke weed &amp;gt;cheap     </snippet></document><document><title>I am running for ISS in the upcoming election, so as to make our student government more transparent.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ulkk/i_am_running_for_iss_in_the_upcoming_election_so/</url><snippet>**EDIT: February 4th, 2013, 15:23: Please keep asking your questions. I have updated this post because apparently an ISS Webmaster does already exist. Hopefully the new Webmaster will be able to speed up the delivery of information to the iss.illinois.edu webpage and allow the public to see information at an expedited pace.**


I would appreciate if you would take the time to read some of my ideas before you are quick to judge. I understand that public opinion is not very high right now.

I want to change that.

Hello!

My name is Ben Deese and I am campaigning for the position of Illinois Student Senator, LAS, for the academic term of 2013-2014. I am currently a junior in Economics, with concentrations in Eastern Religious Studies, Mathematics, Japanese.

I am running for the Illinois Student Senate because I am tired of the failed policies of old, and would like to bring in a fresh perspective. I will be graduating in May 2014, and therefore do not have to worry about re-election. This will allow me to be more free in my criticism of university policies, as well as fight for YOUR rights as a student. I understand that this may seem like typical campaign jargon, but I promise you will be satisfied.

As an out-of-state student, I know the financial pressures and concerns of those of you who pay the increased tuition and international fees. It is outrageous, and the bureaucracy needs to be addressed head on.

If elected, I will make sure there is a painless way to contact me regarding the issues YOU want addressed:

Don't like a new fee? Let me know!
Want to know what is happening in meetings? Feel free to ask!
Pissed off because our tuition is constantly increasing? ME TOO!

Here are a few ideas:

&#8226; Creation of ISS Inspector General: This position would be created to audit the decisions of the Illinois Student Senate, and to give political transparency for all Illini. This is specifically in response to the fiasco over Campus Spirit Revival and their backdoor approach to legislation.

&#8226; Creation of ISS Stenotype Operator: This position would entail recording all senate proceedings via written and/or oral transcripts. These records would then be available to all.

&#8226; Weekly Massmail to all students: This would explain the highlights of the weekly session, as well as provide links to the transcripts of all proceedings for public benefit.

&#8226; Creation of ISS Webmaster (Already exists. See update above): This position would entail keeping the ISS web portal up-to-date with all spending procedures and referendum announcements, as well as working with the ISS Stenotype Operator to make all sure all weekly proceedings are easily available to the student body.

There are an infinite number of questions and concerns the students of LAS have, and I assure you I will dedicate my time and energy to make sure your experience at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign is as stress free as possible. 

If you have any questions, comments, concerns, or proposals please post here; you may also send me an email, text, or tweet. I promise to reply back within 24 hours.

Email: deese2@illinois.edu
Twitter: @bendeese

With that being said, I thank you for your interest!

Here is a link to my Facebook page if you are interested or have friends that might be. If you like what you see, a share of my page can do wonders to reach the students of this fine school:

http://www.facebook.com/ben.deese.senate  A+ should be a 4.33 and more free condoms.  This was the letter I received from Robert Palinkas, Director of McKinley Health Center, regarding your question about condoms. I hope this helps:

"Ben Deese

I write to you today as a response to an inquiry you submitted through McKinley&#8217;s website.
McKinley has a long history of supporting access to birth control, reaching back several decades. Certainly McKinley&#8217;s commitment to supporting birth control issues predates the recent Affordable Care Act, which has considerably opened up access to contraception for the American public in general.
Over the years, McKinley Health Center has provided six to ten different versions of oral contraceptive for a small fee of just $5/month. This is in spite of the fact that McKinley purchases those medications for $15 to $20 per month supply through our wholesale provider.
The recent provisions of the Affordable Care Act now have moved University of Illinois students and virtually the entire American health insured public to completely free access to contraception. This is because insurance plans are now required to identify a list of no charge medications which must be supported by the licensed insurance underwriter.
As a result of those provisions, students at the University of Illinois can take their receipts for most of their contraceptive purchases to their insurance carrier and submit a claim for reimbursement. Assuming that the products are among those listed on the insurance carrier&#8217;s free formulary, students could expect to be reimbursed for their acquisition, subject to the provisions of their individual insurance plan. One should remember that students have health insurance from many different sources, and the provisions of their plan will vary in accordance to regional laws governing insurance underwriting.
McKinley also offers a number of related no charge services to students at the University of Illinois in related areas. For example, individual sessions with our sexuality health educator are no charge, and McKinley provides regular limited access to no charge condoms to all students at the Health Resource Center at the Illini Union, McKinley Health Center, and at several of the cultural houses.
Finally, McKinley Health Center has peer educators that are certified for the purpose of presenting sexual health related programs elsewhere on campus. Perhaps you might be interested in becoming involved in this project?" I did read that whole answer, and honestly it seems like a lot of bs. My main problem is as follows: talking to friends at other big 10 schools and ISU and a few other universities I have come to the conclusion that EVERY university besides ours has no limit on condoms or else the limit is much higher than 12 per 2 weeks. Most universities also had clubs handing them out on their respective quad or else just had bowls full of them in the dorms. It just seems like mckinley is cheaping out is all. It's still better than no free ones at all, but thank you for doing the research and getting an answer for me! I can see you do care about this and care about the students and that is important. A+ should be a 4.33 and more free condoms.  A+ should be a 4.33 and more free condoms.  I will write an email to McKinley today and ask what would be required to increase the distribution of free birth control to students. I will request permission to post the response to this thread. 

On the point of GPA, I agree fully with that suggestion. In terms of pure math that would make sense, but the problem is that would allow above a 4.0 on the scale. Instead, removing an A- grade would make much more sense. If one can get above a 90% in a course, one deserves a 4.0. My mathematics professor, Aldo Manfroi, does this. It seems to work well.

Thing to note: This change would undoubtedly require sweeping change to the educational policy, something that requires Board of Trustees approval.  In past semesters when people in a similar situation as yours posted on reddit these are the 2 biggest things, and yet nothing seems to change. What can you do personally to follow through on these things? Also, A- being a 4.0 would also be acceptable, seems like a good compromise. I will bring it up at the ISS meetings, and if that doesn't work I will contact the university directly. Also, I have friends in Illini Media who could run stories to get the public involved. If thousands of students started mailing the chancellor and other board members, extreme pressure to act would be put on them. If a state or national news source found out, thousands of more voices could be added to the cause. The power if social media to make democratic participation easy will act as the key to change. 

I will also have a relatively light course load next year, so if elected, this position would be my primary focus.

Basically, a "No" will not dissuade me from my goal, which is to make sure the opinions of the student body are brought to the table and then given an examination.  If this is a sincere answer then I truly respect that and hope for the best. As a senior graduating in May I would not personally benefit from this, but I hope future generations of students will. In past semesters when people in a similar situation as yours posted on reddit these are the 2 biggest things, and yet nothing seems to change. What can you do personally to follow through on these things? Also, A- being a 4.0 would also be acceptable, seems like a good compromise. I will write an email to McKinley today and ask what would be required to increase the distribution of free birth control to students. I will request permission to post the response to this thread. 

On the point of GPA, I agree fully with that suggestion. In terms of pure math that would make sense, but the problem is that would allow above a 4.0 on the scale. Instead, removing an A- grade would make much more sense. If one can get above a 90% in a course, one deserves a 4.0. My mathematics professor, Aldo Manfroi, does this. It seems to work well.

Thing to note: This change would undoubtedly require sweeping change to the educational policy, something that requires Board of Trustees approval.  If you like wonky details of GPA, here is one even within the same university:

* At UIUC, an A- scores 3.67 in your GPA.
* At UIS, an A- scores 3.70 in your GPA.

As someone who delves into student data sometimes, GPA is horrifying. :D This is atrocious. If you can provide me a link to the source &#8212; for verification &#8212; I will add it to the original post, as well as my Facebook page.  Please don't try to change it. It's really not worth trying to change. Some of your other ideas are really good and worth spending time on.

Anyway! The best verification I have for you is the top result from a google search for **site:uis.edu gpa**, but it was a word document.

Again, please just file this away under "universities are complicated" rather than under "universities have fixable problems." :) I understand that you may feel that way, but unless the idea of change is instigated, nothing will ever progress. To change GPA at the university is a daunting task. However, if the University of Illinois decided to re-evaluate its policies it could be the tipping point to others doing the same. 

Once one brick falls the rest will tumble.  Hi Ben,

As a current senator I'm excited to hear about your desire to gt involved and make positive changes. I would suggest though that you spend some time learning more about ISS before going out and campaigning. Most of the things you are campaigning for already exist or are out of the purview of the ISS. I don't want to rain on the parade, but I wouldn't want you to make any promises to your constituents that you will not be able to fulfill.

I'm more than happy to chat with you about ISS. Feel free to contact me.

Kevin Seymour
Graduate Senator Kevin,

I understand that many of these ideas are already reality. The thing is that the senate.illinois.edu portal is very confusing. Although videos exist, they are not up-to-date with current information.

I understand that some things may be out of the purview of the ISS, but that means that they can be added to the constitution. Just because something cannot work today is not an excuse to prevent change for tomorrow. Ben,

I agree that the ISS' website is very confusing (iss.illinois.edu is the one I think you are referring too? -- senate.illinois.edu is the domain for the UC Senate which every student senator is also a part of but mostly contains faculty). The ISS has recently hired a webmaster who is currently working to update the info and make it more user friendly, this should be coming out in the next week or so.

Simply changing our constitution will not suddenly give the ISS new oversight over anything we so choose. The shared governance process is very complex, and I wont try to go into here.

Again, I'm more than happy to help you better understand this in more detail if you want to meet up at some point. I think its important that candidates are armed with knowledge about how ISS works. The reason so many people are upset with the ISS these days is because of misinformation.

Kevin  These are great suggestions to change university policy and I hope they work well; I'm sure many in ISS and even students that aren't have ideas of this nature. 

On this note, I'd like to ask a few questions - as a senator, what actions will you have to take in order to complete these goals? How much agency do you have as an individual senator to change policy? Lastly, how much agency does the ISS have in creating university policy and acting as a check and/or balance for the administration?  What do you think of the $2 fee that ISS is hoping to tax its students with?   What is your take on the current budget of the ISS? Spending $3,786.42 for hand outs on quad day just to promote the ISS seems like a waste of funds. The same applies to the PSA. What is your take on this spending ? 
[budget](http://ge.tt/3yOtxnW/v/0?c)    If you want people to vote for you, give them candy. A Werther's Original stapled to a flier will do you wonders.  To address your second and third points:

 - The ISS already has a staff of interns who keep pretty decent minutes (which would be on the website if it was working). In the past, ISS kept video recordings of all it's meetings, but this stopped for reasons I'm unsure of. (Probably because no one ever asked to watch them.) I'd advise against hiring an actual stenographer, as they tend to be expensive and you'd need someone to translate all their notes anyway. Maybe a YouTube channel?
 - The University Administration limits the ISS to 3 (iirc) Massmails per year. The "Administrative Agreement" can be renegotiated, but it's a package deal. Once you start bargaining, everything ISS related goes on the table. On a related note, the current Vice-President Internal and Historian of ISS has been trying to set up an at-least-monthly newsletter to summarize passed and pending legislation. Might be worth sending him an email.

I'd also like to point out that ISS has nothing to do with setting tuition.  You say you want to "fight for YOUR rights as a student" which personally I find refreshing since it seems that most ISS members just want material to throw on their resume.  
So on that note I'm curious about your opinion on the upcoming smoking ban.  There's no reason to take away the right of someone to smoke when a compromise of making designated smoking areas protects both smokers right to smoke and nonsmokers right to not.  

Also, how willing are you to compromise and when it comes to policy you disagree with?  Will you stick to your guns not matter what, or try to find a middle ground? The smoking ban is a touchy subject, but as an elected official I do have to be neutral and represent the student body. As a non-smoker this issue does not personally effect me, but I do have friends who smoke, and I have heard their anger over the ban.

I agree with you and would attempt to propose an amendment to allow designated smoking areas, if that is what the students want. The city of Champaign-Urbana tends to have a lot of wind, which could be a potential problem for smoking areas, causing the smoke to drift to those who do not want it. However, the wind would also blow the smoke up and away, making sure that the smoking areas are relatively clean. 

You are right that smoking areas work; as a California resident, I have been to Disneyland multiple times, and to cater to all customers, there must be smoking areas in the park. The Walt Disney Company has done an excellent job in allowing their smoking customers to be as welcome as the non-smoking ones. To create smoking areas would require a monetary investment, but if it could work, the rights of all students would be honored. With that being said, the issue is that in a democracy people will still be disappointed no matter what.</snippet></document><document><title>IEEE/AES hosting a DIY Guitar Pedal Workshop!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17uoko/ieeeaes_hosting_a_diy_guitar_pedal_workshop/</url><snippet>Sign up at: http://tinyurl.com/guitarpedal

IEEE will be hosting a Guitar Pedal Workshop in 241/245 Everitt Lab at 2PM on February 17th, 2013! Are you interested in music, have a guitar that you want to make a distortion pedal for, or both? Then come to our workshop! If you're a novice at technical projects, we'll have people to properly lecture you with the design and implementation, and if you're feeling confident, then we'll give you the kit with instructions for you to implement, and we'll have people to answer any quick questions you may have!  hooray! Maybe one of you can help me finish my guitar pedal kit.

(also, tried signing up; even though it says to leave the IEEE number blank if you don't have one, it's still not letting me register without one.)  You should probably mention that this isn't free... Isn't it like $60 for non-members?  Is this the same guitar pedal as the one former ECE Alumnus David Harwath designed a couple of years ago? Where did you guys come up with the schematics for the pedal? Just curious because I don't want to build the same pedal again :) No this one is designed by Danny Klinger, a grad student here with the Audio Engineering Society</snippet></document><document><title>Nintendo 3DS and Illinoisnet?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ujly/nintendo_3ds_and_illinoisnet/</url><snippet>Does anyone know if it's possible to connect a Nintendo 3DS to Illinoisnet/UIUC net? If so, how? Thanks!   </snippet></document><document><title>Good small business layers?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17utjo/good_small_business_layers/</url><snippet>Hey guys, 

I need some recommendations for excellent lawyers in the area. Starting up a business and need some legal advice. I'm not a student, so it's a no go on SLS. 

Cheers! 

Etch </snippet></document><document><title>Alternative to EATCU</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17u59d/alternative_to_eatcu/</url><snippet>I've been using eatcu for almost 3 years and I'm getting tired of this processing fee. They need to be making money off the restaurants for advertising their restaurants there. Not off me the costumer. Does anyone know of a good site that doesn't charge a processing fee and that services the Champaign-Urbana area?      </snippet></document><document><title>Any ladies know of a good place to get a hair cut in the area?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ttyr/any_ladies_know_of_a_good_place_to_get_a_hair_cut/</url><snippet>I really just want to get my hair trimmed, without spending a fortune to do so. I have a car and can drive wherever, so feel free to suggest on or off campus locations if you know of any. Thanks!    I go to Look After on Green and Fourth. You can get a wash, cut, and blow-dry for about $18 (plus a tip).          </snippet></document><document><title>PA system needed for house show!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17twt8/pa_system_needed_for_house_show/</url><snippet>I play in a band from Chicago called The Howl. We're playing a house show down in Urbana on Friday Feb 15th. Does anybody have a PA system that we could use that night?

We're not looking to wreck your equipment. We are respectful people. We just can't fit a PA system in our van. We'll buy you beer or something that night for the generosity. :)

https://www.facebook.com/TheHowlChicago

http://the-howl.bandcamp.com  2 things you can do:

1) ask on the Champaign area shows Facebook page. http://www.facebook.com/groups/Champaignareashows/

2) rent something from Analog Outfitters.</snippet></document><document><title>Need a logo design for a club, any takers? Willing to pay.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17tvkg/need_a_logo_design_for_a_club_any_takers_willing/</url><snippet>Hey r/uiuc, I have no creative talent whatsoever, and I'd like to request some help.

I am the president of an RSO, the Illinois Debate Society (technically Illinois Congressional Debate Society but we're getting that changed)

I want a logo that we can stick on documents, team merchandise, facebook, and a team webpage, among other things.

I don't know necessarily what symbols to use, whether it's a silhouette of a person speaking, a gavel, a big I, or whatever. I don't know how to combine any such symbols, either. But whatever it is, it should be blue, orange, and white.

If anyone is interested in taking on this project, please let me know and we can talk over some details.

Thanks!  Here's a concept design I threw together.  Were you looking for something like this?

http://imgur.com/C45Lzpu   http://imgur.com/jyS4A0Y
I do not own any advance software to produce a quality image, but how about something like this?  No, sorry - it must be up to ~professionalish grade. I know! Just giving a potential idea is all  Gotcha. I'm actually trying to avoid something like this, haha. It's pretty cliched. Thanks though!        I graduated from the Creative University of North Tuvalu with an associate's in Overusing Helvetica. I can do it for $5 less than the lowest bidder. Hit me up, yo. I'll do it for free, now pay the man $5 and make him a design</snippet></document><document><title>Space Available Monday from NW suburbs to Chambana</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17tjvt/space_available_monday_from_nw_suburbs_to_chambana/</url><snippet>Hey,

I have space available from the NW suburbs (Palatine, Arlington Heights, Hoffman Estates, Buffalo Grove, Schaumburg, etc.) to Chambana. Gas would be $15.   But how much do you charge for transportation, tolls &amp;amp; taxes, and non-carry-on baggage? I bet this will add up to $50, based on my experiences with LEX. Lex was usually $25 including all that, unless you're coming from O'hare..</snippet></document><document><title>Cold case thawed: Wallet stolen at UI in 2001 found inside freezer</title><url>http://www.news-gazette.com/news/courts-police-and-fire/2013-02-02/cold-case-thawed-wallet-stolen-2001-found-inside-freezer.html</url><snippet>  &amp;gt;Mike Porter, a member of the Plumbers and Pipefitters Local 149 who works at the UI refrigeration shop, was about to drain the Freon from a freezer when he made a discovery that heated him up.
&amp;gt;


Really?  As a former B&amp;amp;N employee, I can attest that gift cards don't have an expiration date.  I worked there from 2003-2007, and I honored certs from the 90s on a fairly regular basis.  </snippet></document><document><title>Is Burrito King gone?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17sucl/is_burrito_king_gone/</url><snippet>I noticed while walking down Green Street that Burrito King had a cardboard 'For Sale' sign in their front window. This was just after I read The Black Sheep's article on the new Wendy's. Is it really gone though or is it just a hoax?  Tortica's was always run by the same guys. I think they're just focusing on one location right now, partly because Tortica's has the liquor license. Unfortunately, they're only using the Burrito King menu so food that was specific to Tortica's, like empanadas, isn't available. Tortica's was always run by the same guys. I think they're just focusing on one location right now, partly because Tortica's has the liquor license. Unfortunately, they're only using the Burrito King menu so food that was specific to Tortica's, like empanadas, isn't available. Seriously the empanadas are gone? I loved those!    Hope Maize moves in  It may have merged into Torticas. I seem to recall seeing a Burrito King section on their menu?  Sources say it is expected that [MarineKing](http://i.minus.com/i1wBBD6UuqDAE.gif) will replace Burrito King in the near future Sources say it is expected that [MarineKing](http://i.minus.com/i1wBBD6UuqDAE.gif) will replace Burrito King in the near future</snippet></document><document><title>Does anybody know anything about the "homeless vet" outside of Starbucks? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17s0nx/does_anybody_know_anything_about_the_homeless_vet/</url><snippet>I often walk into Starbucks past a couple holding a "homeless vet" sign.  They smile at people and aren't too aggressive.  I'm curious if anybody knows their story (i.e. is the guy really a vet), or are they your garden variety Green Street scammers?   Still more believable than "trying to get to Danville". Good one Matt ;)   [deleted]  I wonder how much they make in a day. If I had the time I would stand next to them and count how much they made. I wonder how much they make in a day. If I had the time I would stand next to them and count how much they made. There was a story about a woman in new york city making 6 figures by begging and pretending to be crippled. On green i bet they can rack in ~50 a day at least which is not much but hey free money! [deleted] yeah but that is standing out for 8 hours. that's six bucks a hour
  I've seen them get on the bus at the union everyday at like 5:15 ish, so my best guess is they are not homeless. and i would not be surprised if he wasn't a vet either.   Yea and the woman was sipping on a frozen starbucks drink, sorry but if you can buy a $5 drink then you arent getting my money Yea and the woman was sipping on a frozen starbucks drink, sorry but if you can buy a $5 drink then you arent getting my money I dont understand this logic. So if a homeless person wants to buy a starbucks frozen drink thats $5 dollars then shes not homeless? No it means that if they are homeless they clearly dont care to save money in order to get better lives for themselves. Poor business model on their part</snippet></document><document><title>Is there any place in the town for sledding?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17s665/is_there_any_place_in_the_town_for_sledding/</url><snippet>      Crystal Lake Park off of University in Urbana. There's a pretty big hill. that's the baby hill in town, nobody goes there after 1st grade  If you can make it to Monticello, the meadow in Allerton Park is actually super dope for sledding.  </snippet></document><document><title>Unofficial Shirts - let's seem 'em all</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17rkxd/unofficial_shirts_lets_seem_em_all/</url><snippet>Let's try to get all the shirts in one place? What are your favorites? What are designs you wish you saw? I'll post a few I've come across:

http://www.facebook.com/Unofficialshirts2013

http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013Shirts?fref=ts

www.UNOFFICIALSHIRTS.com

https://www.facebook.com/groups/159098467571559/

https://www.facebook.com/theunofficialstore
  The first link led me to a shirt with a picture of Alma Mater showing her tits? Classy.  fapfapfap The first link led me to a shirt with a picture of Alma Mater showing her tits? Classy.   I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 So...About the order form? Sorry! It's coming, just a day or two more tops! [So..about that shirt](http://i3.kym-cdn.com/entries/icons/original/000/006/595/1262055260350.jpg) Wow talk about timing! Just got the store up and running! Sorry for the delay! Quick Question: are those shirts 100% cotton, so should you order up a size? And also do you have a size chart? I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 yes!  my girlfriend would love the jameson inspired one!  count me in I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
 I sold these [Guinness/Jameson inspired Unofficial shirts](http://i.imgur.com/PIDD87r.jpg) last year, if there's enough interested, I may sell them again. Let me know what you think! If you have any suggestions to modify the design for Unofficial 2013 let me know too.

[EDIT] SORRY FOR THE WAIT! Seriously thanks for being patient, it's been a busy week. [Order here!](https://www.facebook.com/pages/Unofficial-GuinnessJameson-Shirts-Unofficial-Adidas-NBA-Jerseys/398403843582595?fref=ts)
  http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013TShirts

We just got this group up yesterday but check it out. Me and my friend designed these, hoping to do something a little bit different from the usual played out unofficial designs. Let me know what you think reddit.
 http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013TShirts

We just got this group up yesterday but check it out. Me and my friend designed these, hoping to do something a little bit different from the usual played out unofficial designs. Let me know what you think reddit.
 You realize that song is against drinking, right? http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013TShirts

We just got this group up yesterday but check it out. Me and my friend designed these, hoping to do something a little bit different from the usual played out unofficial designs. Let me know what you think reddit.
 http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013TShirts

We just got this group up yesterday but check it out. Me and my friend designed these, hoping to do something a little bit different from the usual played out unofficial designs. Let me know what you think reddit.
 http://www.facebook.com/Unofficial2013TShirts

We just got this group up yesterday but check it out. Me and my friend designed these, hoping to do something a little bit different from the usual played out unofficial designs. Let me know what you think reddit.
         I want to get a jersey for this year, but why are so many of them for D-Rose? Am I missing something here?   </snippet></document><document><title>Library Resource Survey</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ruq3/library_resource_survey/</url><snippet>Hey guys, 

I'm working on a project to improve campus library resources. It would be great if you guys could take this survey. 

https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1TdlV6VRpVF-zmlVH2ZUkhQ9j1akid2tmJ1n5nFQfj40/viewform

Thanks so much!  </snippet></document><document><title>Place to buy inexpensive computer accessories?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17rxqg/place_to_buy_inexpensive_computer_accessories/</url><snippet>Hey guys i'm looking for somewhere to buy an inexpensive miniport to hdmi adapter. I realize that amazon has them super cheap, but I was looking for somewhere on campus, since I need it for tonight. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated!! 


http://cdn-images.sewelldirect.com/products/SW-22067/SW-22067.jpg   Computer Deli up by Barnes and Noble  [ECE Store?](http://www.ece.illinois.edu/ecestores/) Closed on on Saturday's :(  </snippet></document><document><title>Superbowl take-out and delivery deals?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17rq6a/superbowl_takeout_and_delivery_deals/</url><snippet>Anyone know of any good deals from places in the champaign urbana area tomorrow?    Dominos will pretty much take any coupon you have, be it expired, or even nonexistent. A group of us used this recently to get 3 large pizzas at $5/pizza. </snippet></document><document><title>Giving away: women's sparring gear</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17rc3n/giving_away_womens_sparring_gear/</url><snippet>Have a full set of women's (or small men's, no idea really) sparring gear, made by Macho Martial Arts. Everything looks to be in pretty good shape except the footpads. If you want this stuff or are part of one of the clubs that I could donate it to, let me know.</snippet></document><document><title>Another bus company bites the dust?</title><url>http://cgi.ebay.com/ebaymotors/MCI-charter-Bus-/221184615112?pt=Buses&amp;amp;hash=item337fa162c8</url><snippet>  who wants to pitch in &amp;amp; get a reddit party bus? who wants to pitch in &amp;amp; get a reddit party bus?  It's bizarre if they're shutting down already, since they just started offering service here 2-3 months ago. Might just be that they're trying to get rid of an old bus and get some money for it. They had commercial space at Lincoln &amp;amp; University last year. They suddenly moved out, and their bus equipment (this, the karaoke party bus, and some other junk) was being stored at a house on Bloomington Road, in a bad neighborhood. Now they're running Dodge Caravans. 

Seems like a downward trend, but maybe not.   </snippet></document><document><title>The only thing I could see while voting.</title><url>http://qkme.me/3st2wk?id=229784564</url><snippet>  Why do I think this is going to become the unofficial logo of this school...     </snippet></document><document><title>Giving away my russian dwarf hamster, Luffy</title><url>http://chambana.craigslist.org/zip/3586339988.html</url><snippet>  I would like to take him if he gets along well with my Chinese dwarf hamster! Is this a communist joke? Is this a communist joke?      </snippet></document><document><title>Student loans... how deep in the hole are you? How are you planning on getting out?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ol42/student_loans_how_deep_in_the_hole_are_you_how/</url><snippet>I'm down like 30k so far... I think I should be able to dig myself out as long as I get a job. I do have a sister in FAA and I have no idea how she is going to manage her debt.  Some law students have six-figure debt numbers. I had a half-tuition scholarship and am at $171,000. o shit that much? Tuition's a hair over $40,000 at the law school, plus living expenses ($20k per year), plus books and a laptop. Then I had to take summer classes each summer because we needed the cost of living loans. That's another $30k or so for both summers. There aren't many paying jobs available for law students, and I didn't land any until after I had enrolled in summer classes and accepted loans my second year. 

So yeah, it adds up fast. Tuition's a hair over $40,000 at the law school, plus living expenses ($20k per year), plus books and a laptop. Then I had to take summer classes each summer because we needed the cost of living loans. That's another $30k or so for both summers. There aren't many paying jobs available for law students, and I didn't land any until after I had enrolled in summer classes and accepted loans my second year. 

So yeah, it adds up fast. 20k per year for living expenses? Are you accounting for a couple? That seems a little outlandish in a place with such a low cost of living like Champaign/Urbana. Even renting a large one bedroom house all for myself, my living expenses are about half of that. Some law students have six-figure debt numbers. Some law students have six-figure debt numbers.  A lot. My plan? I'm an engineer. Yeah I'm a CS major so I guess it helps. I think paying off 30k will take around 2-3 years. I don't know how many of the non-engineering majors manage to pay them off... like my sister. This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. This just in: Engineers get the wages you are talking about more frequently than most majors. The average job an engineer can find right out of college will pay more than the average job most other majors will find, and for good reason. I don't know if it is for good reason. I'm a social science major and I knew a lot of engineering students who could barely pass Calculus. (For the record, I got an A in all three semesters)

Crap engineers get stuck on the floor and I can't imagine them making more money *in the long term*. I don't know if it is for good reason. I'm a social science major and I knew a lot of engineering students who could barely pass Calculus. (For the record, I got an A in all three semesters)

Crap engineers get stuck on the floor and I can't imagine them making more money *in the long term*. In the long term we are all going to die. Not a very convincing argument... This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. Which majors make more than engineering majors after just a bachelor's degree? This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. Shut up, were on reddit, you're only asking to be downvoted This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. Sorry I should have specified FAA majors (my sis)... I don't think they start off with a 60k+ salary. Architecture majors or Euphonium Performance majors? Sorry I should have specified FAA majors (my sis)... I don't think they start off with a 60k+ salary. Sorry I should have specified FAA majors (my sis)... I don't think they start off with a 60k+ salary. Sorry I should have specified FAA majors (my sis)... I don't think they start off with a 60k+ salary. This just in: Non-engineering majors can make as much, if not more, than engineering majors. College of LAS grad. I make more as a police officer than many of the grads in engineering that don't go into consulting College of LAS grad. I make more as a police officer than many of the grads in engineering that don't go into consulting   You guys should check out /r/frugal or /r/personalfinance to help out with your finances. While in school and jobless, you can start by making a monthly budget of food, rent, shopping, bills, etc. You can get a feel of how much you're spending and areas you can save money in (ie. fast food, shopping, beer).    Business major checking in. Going to whore myself out to Corporate America while still living like a college student. You shouldn't be spending more than $20,000 a year to live comfortably. As long as you make more than that (very easy,) and don't go on any big vacations (not so easy,) you should be able to put a lot of each paycheck into your debt. 

It's all about living within your means. Hope this gives you some comfort. Dolla dolla bill, yall. Only problem is, "You shouldn't be spending more than $20,000/year to live comfortably" is a complete load of garbage.

http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/alpha-consumer/2011/10/03/the-secret-to-living-well-on-20000-a-year

You give up quite a bit of creature comforts to live on $20k a year. No car, no health insurance, no retirement savings, going to the movies is considered a splurge. If you want to live "comfortably" in this town, which is significantly cheaper than a real city, you'll need more than that. I don't know about Seattle, but I can assure you that thousands of grad students live in this town on $20k or less (before taxes), while having both a car and a health insurance.  If they do not work over the summer at all, grad students average $17,183 per person. They live, but it'll assure you none of them will say it's a comfortable life.

It occurs to me that $20k is probably doable if you've got roommates. I suppose that would make a huge difference when compared to where my expenses go. I'm a grad student and I feel very comfortable on the 1.8k-ish I get per month.  Rent+utilities+food+monthly costs is maybe 800/mo tops (I have shopped around to keep this down), and this leaves me a ton for travel, climbing gear (big money sink), eating/going out, etc.  

If you aren't lazy, supporting someone, or really materialistic, I don't know how 20k isn't reasonable to live on. Well most posts here are from people living in champaign where living cost is very low. Imagine being in Chicago or any other major city. You can't get by paying $350 rent. You are going to be paying at least $700 for rent and higher on everything else. Well most posts here are from people living in champaign where living cost is very low. Imagine being in Chicago or any other major city. You can't get by paying $350 rent. You are going to be paying at least $700 for rent and higher on everything else. I'm a grad student and I feel very comfortable on the 1.8k-ish I get per month.  Rent+utilities+food+monthly costs is maybe 800/mo tops (I have shopped around to keep this down), and this leaves me a ton for travel, climbing gear (big money sink), eating/going out, etc.  

If you aren't lazy, supporting someone, or really materialistic, I don't know how 20k isn't reasonable to live on. I'd go with the "It's expensive to be poor" type things.

Remember, if you're take home is $1,800 you're making closer to $27k.

Imagine dropping $500/month off your take home and where your quality of life would be. Sorry, I think it was about 20k for 9 months or something like that.
Sure, I would rather have the extra 500/mo, but I hardly need it.  I'm able to travel for swing dancing or climbing nearly every week, and if I had to stay home one extra time a month, I would hardly be crushed.  I could probably manage to brew more often.   Did you not take out loans for undergrad? If they do not work over the summer at all, grad students average $17,183 per person. They live, but it'll assure you none of them will say it's a comfortable life.

It occurs to me that $20k is probably doable if you've got roommates. I suppose that would make a huge difference when compared to where my expenses go. Well, I can tell you that I have lived on $21k last year, and it was enough for not worrying about what kind of food I eat, new clothes, new glasses, new gadgets, videogames, airplane tickets, etc (in no particular order). I live alone in 1BR. Are you paying internet/cell/cable/netflix? Eating free food provided by the department? Did you get a kitchen that was outfitted with gear to allow you to make decent healthy food?

$21k is
~$1487/month after tax.
~$375 for rent
~$50 for basic utilities (Just counting connection fees and minimal usage for power/water. I pay more for a house since I have to pay the entirety of the power and water connection fee, but I made that choice).
68.88/month prorated health insurance premium for the University (From http://www.si.uiuc.edu with a 4.5 month semester).
$45/month car insurance.
$40 in gas for a single fill-up a month to get groceries
Now you're down to ~$30/day after completely basic living expenses that cannot be avoided.
That's paycheck to paycheck territory to me, and a single car repair could put you into the negative for the month. Are you paying internet/cell/cable/netflix? Eating free food provided by the department? Did you get a kitchen that was outfitted with gear to allow you to make decent healthy food?

$21k is
~$1487/month after tax.
~$375 for rent
~$50 for basic utilities (Just counting connection fees and minimal usage for power/water. I pay more for a house since I have to pay the entirety of the power and water connection fee, but I made that choice).
68.88/month prorated health insurance premium for the University (From http://www.si.uiuc.edu with a 4.5 month semester).
$45/month car insurance.
$40 in gas for a single fill-up a month to get groceries
Now you're down to ~$30/day after completely basic living expenses that cannot be avoided.
That's paycheck to paycheck territory to me, and a single car repair could put you into the negative for the month. If they do not work over the summer at all, grad students average $17,183 per person. They live, but it'll assure you none of them will say it's a comfortable life.

It occurs to me that $20k is probably doable if you've got roommates. I suppose that would make a huge difference when compared to where my expenses go.     I will be 120k in debt after finishing my major. Plan? Major is cs.   UIUC is one of my top choices but I don't think I can afford to come here. From what I've heard, UIUC is extremely stingy with financial aid. My parents don't make much and have very little savings. I'd probably have to go $200,000 in debt to attend.. I'm going to major in computer science so I might be able to pay it off eventually but I'm not sure if that would be worth it. UIUC is one of my top choices but I don't think I can afford to come here. From what I've heard, UIUC is extremely stingy with financial aid. My parents don't make much and have very little savings. I'd probably have to go $200,000 in debt to attend.. I'm going to major in computer science so I might be able to pay it off eventually but I'm not sure if that would be worth it. UIUC is one of my top choices but I don't think I can afford to come here. From what I've heard, UIUC is extremely stingy with financial aid. My parents don't make much and have very little savings. I'd probably have to go $200,000 in debt to attend.. I'm going to major in computer science so I might be able to pay it off eventually but I'm not sure if that would be worth it. UIUC is one of my top choices but I don't think I can afford to come here. From what I've heard, UIUC is extremely stingy with financial aid. My parents don't make much and have very little savings. I'd probably have to go $200,000 in debt to attend.. I'm going to major in computer science so I might be able to pay it off eventually but I'm not sure if that would be worth it.    </snippet></document><document><title>The best and worst of student submissions to design Illinois&#8217; new logo</title><url>http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/ncaab-the-dagger/best-worst-student-submissions-design-illinois-logo-023212780--ncaab.html</url><snippet>  It seems like some people are overly concerned with how good some of the logos look. I thought the idea is what matters. I doubt anyone is actually expecting the university to copy and paste their submission and just roll with it. I agree. I'm pretty sure the 3 worst were drawn by kids. Thanks Yahoo, you bunch of anuses. You just shit on a bunch of kids who wanted to be involved. 
Douches.   I agree. I'm pretty sure the 3 worst were drawn by kids. Thanks Yahoo, you bunch of anuses. You just shit on a bunch of kids who wanted to be involved. 
Douches.   It seems like some people are overly concerned with how good some of the logos look. I thought the idea is what matters. I doubt anyone is actually expecting the university to copy and paste their submission and just roll with it.  I voted for Colonel Kernel, among others, which this blog post doesn't like stating, "A living, breathing musclebound corn cob mascot is probably better suited for Nebraska than Illinois." While the University of Nebraska's team name is the Cornhuskers, Illinois as a state actually [produces much more corn](http://wherefoodcomesfrom.com/article/2190/Corn-Production-By-State-Alphabetical), and it's time to represent.

 But the drawing was hideous. I would imagine that they would have somebody draw something professionally rather than just using a hand drawn picture from somebody that isn't very good at drawing. Oh....but that doesn't explain why there were three Krakens. I still voted for the krakens cus lol krakens  There was a late submission that was glossed over, the Scarecrow or "Strawman", [check it out](https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10200544125824675&amp;amp;set=o.198869786856029&amp;amp;type=1&amp;amp;theater).   Yahoo comments, let's see...did they blame liberals for the Chief being retired? Yep! Thanks a lot Obama...  http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jkQxHlr2fXM     </snippet></document><document><title>I don't know why this wasn't one of the mascot submissions...maybe it was too obvious</title><url>http://topnews.in/files/Nicholas-Cage1254.jpg</url><snippet>    </snippet></document><document><title>Girls! Looking for a new club to try out?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17nlvc/girls_looking_for_a_new_club_to_try_out/</url><snippet>Join [Illinois Women's Rugby!](http://iwrfc-com.webs.com/) We're a club sport that is open to all skill levels and athletic abilities. We've just started practice, so feel free to stop in and give it a try (we love rookies). The beginning of the spring we have night practices at the Irwin Indoor Football Facility (the building right next to the arc) on Sundays 8:30-10:30pm, Tuesdays 9:30-11:00pm, and Thursdays 10:30-12:00am. Once it warms up we go back to a normal schedule outside, but now is the best time to join! Come play with us yaaayyyyy :)    Jazmin, is that you? Aww come on you can guess better than that! Haha, I am not going to lie, I did some quick creeping and found out who you are. I don't know anyone else on the rugby team, only Jazmin because we're in another RSO together. Tell her I said hi :P</snippet></document><document><title>Win $15k: Create an app to help Champaign residents and uses at least one source from data.illinois.gov</title><url>http://illinoisopentech.org/challenge/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>THE ROOM at The Art Co-op Theater this weekend!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17msm4/the_room_at_the_art_coop_theater_this_weekend/</url><snippet>A stunning portrayal of friendship, love, and betrayal. Showing at Midnight on Friday, Saturday, and 10PM Wednesday and Thursday. A movie that encourages participation (protip: bring plenty of plastic spoons). Admission is only 5 bucks-and these shows almost always are sell outs. I'll be at the Saturday night show, if any redditors want to assemble. This is a LOT of fun!!!  Guys, just remember that the movie is funnier than whatever you're yelling. Guys, just remember that the movie is funnier than whatever you're yelling. Oh hi Mark!         Guys, just remember that the movie is funnier than whatever you're yelling. Guys, just remember that the movie is funnier than whatever you're yelling.   sounds like fun. I'd be down for the Friday showing. You buy tickets at the door?   Saw it at the Art Theater last year.  It was a blast.  They handed out spoons to everyone last time though.  Hope that's the case again. Why spoons? Is there free food? In case this is a serious question: one of the gimmicks for a viewing of *The Room* is that, for some reason, a lot of the "art" in the apartment that most of the film takes place in features images of spoons. It is traditional, whenever one of them is visible, to yell "Spoon!" and throw plastic spoons at the screen.

Here is a [viewer's guide from the Onion's A.V. Club](http://www.avclub.com/articles/a-viewers-guide-to-the-room,25721/) (some spoilers). Why spoons? Is there free food? I hope there's free Scotchka! Saw it at the Art Theater last year.  It was a blast.  They handed out spoons to everyone last time though.  Hope that's the case again. They will have spoons available!    I have never been to a viewing of the room. Is it recommended that new people stay at the back to get a feel for things?  I have never been to a viewing of the room. Is it recommended that new people stay at the back to get a feel for things? </snippet></document><document><title>Student Senate to discuss $2/semester mandatory student fee referendum this Friday (Feb 1) at 3pm at Illini Union's Pine Lounge after $9000 error exposed! Bonus: Catering is Provided (sigh)! </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17m8x0/student_senate_to_discuss_2semester_mandatory/</url><snippet>All are welcome to speak during public comment this friday at 3pm.

Daily Illini Article on the Error:http://www.dailyillini.com/news/campus/article_6fd0536e-6b68-11e2-aa17-001a4bcf6878.html
   Image of ISS $9000 Error: https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BB67Y1mCIAAHIj5.jpg:large Am I missing something here?

edit: Thanks guys. I get it now haha Am I missing something here?

edit: Thanks guys. I get it now haha Am I missing something here?

edit: Thanks guys. I get it now haha Am I missing something here?

edit: Thanks guys. I get it now haha  Just in case anyone is interested, a full report of ISS spending is linked below. 

http://ge.tt/3yOtxnW/v/0?c

source: The Treasurer Just in case anyone is interested, a full report of ISS spending is linked below. 

http://ge.tt/3yOtxnW/v/0?c

source: The Treasurer Thanks Mr. Treasurer for the comprehensive information.
Would it be in the Senate's best interest to demand a refund for this $9,000 error?  It may be. I will be meeting with the appropriate individuals to see what can be done next week. It may be. I will be meeting with the appropriate individuals to see what can be done next week. Just in case anyone is interested, a full report of ISS spending is linked below. 

http://ge.tt/3yOtxnW/v/0?c

source: The Treasurer You should put that information in your flair, like I do :P Dear Webmaster.  I was made aware that the current list of Senators on iss.illinois.edu is not correct.  When will it be updated?  As soon as the ODOS guys push out my changes to the live server (hopefully tonight)   The ISS isn't paying for the catering, just fyi. The ISS isn't paying for the catering, just fyi.</snippet></document><document><title>Anyone else hear a bigass noise just now?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17md0i/anyone_else_hear_a_bigass_noise_just_now/</url><snippet>Heard a bigass bang that made the electricity in my dorm flicker, then a few minutes later saw a bright light flicker and explode on the building by 5th and armory. the fuck?  I saw it explode. The power line. A box just blew up, twice! We're running on back up power here.  Damn roommate, stealing my karma.  HA! Nice unicorn. It suits you.    3:00 AM

Power guys seem to be checking it out. 

http://www.imgur.com/Mrz1X1a.jpeg

Edit: that pole is still giving off mad hum  Where is my Illini Alert? Where is my Illini Alert?  I saw it too. First explosion on a power pole in front of IT. Woke me up and a brown out. Saw flashing outside and it was the pole sparking until a 2nd explosion and then it was done.    </snippet></document><document><title>Car rentals around CU?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17nrhd/car_rentals_around_cu/</url><snippet>Which ones would you suggest? I know that zipcar is good, are there others? We're 3-4 people, so we might need an SUV (not sure if Zipcar provides SUV's)   You'll have to do some math to figure out if Zipcar is a better deal than a more traditional rental place like Enterprise. I used to be a Zipcar member and I think it's great for things like weekly grocery shopping. However, I found that for weekend trips and such it was cheaper to go with Enterprise (even having already paid the $25 annual fee for Zipcar). Your age will also affect the cost of renting through Enterprise. If you go that route you should arrange to have someone come pick you up when you need the car (they do it for free). Otherwise it's kind of a pain to get there. </snippet></document><document><title>For those that live in Urbana apartments and park on the curb</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17npcx/for_those_that_live_in_urbana_apartments_and_park/</url><snippet>I know there's a rule that you can't stay in a spot for more than three days, but how do they keep track of that? Do consistently move your cars every three days?  I heard from one of the guys that works at one of the apartment management companies that they "use chalk". I don't know what exactly this means or how it works nor did I ask him to elaborate, but it's a clue. Anyone care to speculate? They mark a tire with chalk. When you move your vehicle, the chalk wears off.

I imagine they either rotate through colors to tell how long it's been or just mark parked cars every three days.   </snippet></document><document><title>off-campus lease</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17nj00/offcampus_lease/</url><snippet>Hi guys,

Do you know any company or person who makes rental leases for a specified period of time like 5 months? It is not important how far away the place is.   </snippet></document><document><title>Anybody else up for that power line explosion in front of Illini Tower? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17md4b/anybody_else_up_for_that_power_line_explosion_in/</url><snippet>There were like 2 explosions. One caused a small power outage and woke me up. Then I looked out my Window to see some bright sparking and eventually a second explosion. 

Anybody else see/hear it? I'll get a picture of the pole once it gets light out.    I believe a transformer blew. Probably looked like [this](http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=hy6UXxhzYlk#t=50s).   I live right by IT and didn't see or hear anything! Dammit! Of course I would sleep through something interesting, but at least I know why my clocks were all out this morning </snippet></document><document><title>Proposed changes to the Football Stadium</title><url>http://www.illinoisloyalty.com/i/n/new-illini-scoreboard-2013.jpg</url><snippet>  They're going to add fans to the stands and a team that can get into the endzone?

Seems promising. Should have thought of that years ago.  They're going to add fans to the stands and a team that can get into the endzone?

Seems promising. Should have thought of that years ago.  They're going to add fans to the stands and a team that can get into the endzone?

Seems promising. Should have thought of that years ago.  Shut the fuck up, you ass raping donkey fucker.  I'd like to see your pussy ass out on the field, cunt.  Pathetic trash like you makes me fucking sick.  Get the fuck out of my subreddit, homo. Shut the fuck up, you ass raping donkey fucker.  I'd like to see your pussy ass out on the field, cunt.  Pathetic trash like you makes me fucking sick.  Get the fuck out of my subreddit, homo.  This is like putting new rims on a car with a blown engine. This is like putting new rims on a car with a blown engine. You couldn't have stated that better.  Totally agree.   As long as it doesn't have a blobs of messed up pixels in the middle, it's an improvement.

The old scoreboard was as wide as that ribbon board that says "wins wins wins" so that should give a good comparison as to what the improvement will be.  Looks like this would put it at 6th largest in the conference, and 20th largest in the nation.  Pretty cool.

They're also adding a scoreboard to the north endzone.  It won't have a video board, but should still be nice for those who would be sitting with their backs to the big board.  The ribbons look nice too. One game, I'm pretty sure some of our video inputs were broken, so we got BTN feed. That wouldn't surprise me.  There always seemed to be a blob of greenish/purple in the middle.

That scoreboard wasn't *that* old either, did they just go cheap last time around? That wouldn't surprise me.  There always seemed to be a blob of greenish/purple in the middle.

That scoreboard wasn't *that* old either, did they just go cheap last time around?     How about we focus on changing the football team first? Why not both? Also a better stadium would be an incentive to play here.        Can our school even afford this? The athletic department is self-sustaining through ticket and merchandise revenue, BTN money, and donations. Really, none of your tuition money will go towards this.  The athletic department is self-sustaining through ticket and merchandise revenue, BTN money, and donations. Really, none of your tuition money will go towards this.  Can our school even afford this?</snippet></document><document><title>Anyone ever tutored at Irwin Academic Center?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ky9b/anyone_ever_tutored_at_irwin_academic_center/</url><snippet>This is the building where student athletes get to go and receive free academic tutoring. I just got an email from their tutoring coordinator saying that one of my profs from last semester recommended me to tutor a student in his class.

They pay undergrad tutors $10/hr, do you guys know if this is taxed? Is it a generally good gig? How is the time commitment? Are there other benefits to being able to get into this building? Thanks!

Edit: Thanks to everyone who replied!    I do! Shoot me a pm.  My boyfriend was an athlete who had to put in 10-15 hours per week, depending on grades and course load.  Most athletes are just there because they're required to be, not because they're actively seeking out help on a subject.  They bring a book and "study" and clock out as soon as possible..... I would assume tutor wages are taxed, as I would assume it's also probably a good gig because you'll probably get a lot of your own study time too.  I would find out how much of it is really tutoring, vs. being the kid at the door who swipes them in and tells them to put away their magazines.  It's a nice facility, convenient location, and it would look good on a resume!</snippet></document><document><title>Is there a public scanner on campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17m27z/is_there_a_public_scanner_on_campus/</url><snippet>I need to scan some documents for a class. Is there a scanner somewhere on campus that students can use?   Grainger Library has two. First floor, go in through the main doors and make a right and they're right there! I'd assume UGL and ACES library probably have 'em too, but I don't usually go there... UGL has two as well.  I think you'd just need to have a flashdrive to store all of the files.   </snippet></document><document><title>Voting is live for Campus Spirit Revival - the most liked next symbols for The University of Illinois</title><url>http://vote.illinois.edu/</url><snippet>   Where the fuck is the Dragon Warrior?? There was a dragon warrior?  Someone take some screenshots of them for me just to see. I'm not a student anymore; therefore, my log-in doesn't work.  I'm curious! You can still log in if you have a current password. There's a site to reset it somewhere if you remember your security questions. 

I was able to log in and see them, but couldn't vote. damn...no even that is working. There's definitely a facebook page with all of these. Somebody who follows it might be able to link you. Or search the group  that would be awesome! If anyone could do that...that would be awesome! [Here it is.](https://www.facebook.com/CampusSpiritRevival) You can still log in if you have a current password. There's a site to reset it somewhere if you remember your security questions. 

I was able to log in and see them, but couldn't vote.      This is just depressing. He can't be replaced. There is still so much Chief memorabilia and tradition here. No matter what UIUC does, Chief will always be our mascot.   Other than the "Fighting Illini" with the soldier, they all sucked. Rather have no mascot/symbol than any of those. I would prefer that the symbol be representational of the original source of the "Fighting Illini" name as well.

I just don't want to wind up with a guy in a costume on the sidelines like most other teams have. Even when we had the Chief he was just there for the halftime Three-in-One. He was a symbol, not a mascot.  Wait what? Chef Illini is actually on the ballot!

If Chef Illini actually wins would the NCAA even allow us to have that as a mascot? lol Wait what? Chef Illini is actually on the ballot!

If Chef Illini actually wins would the NCAA even allow us to have that as a mascot? lol  I can't vote since I'm not a student, but I liked "Illini Pride" and the Lincoln I face. HEe heeeee :)   I really hope the Eagle wins. Its got a great description about it, and is visually very similar to the Chief, without looking like it was trying too hard (ie, like the wolf one, and others that tried to incorporate the headdress)   Like it or not, the day has come. Voting ends February 1st. The ballot reminds you that you should be focusing on concepts - and therefor the written portion should weigh heavily on your decision. I like the squirrel but don't like the drawing. I'm sure whatever gets picked will be redrawn professionally. This is correct. It mentions at the top that you're voting on the concepts, not the actual pictures.  Then why the hell do we have five billion lincolns?  Does anyone agree that this whole voting process is a fucking joke? Haha seriously you think any of the t shirt shops on campus or in the Illinois area are going to make orange and blue shirts with a freaking Kraken on it? Does anyone agree that this whole voting process is a fucking joke? Haha seriously you think any of the t shirt shops on campus or in the Illinois area are going to make orange and blue shirts with a freaking Kraken on it?     [deleted] We had a meeting and decided that we're going to let you down. Not alumni in general, just you.  We had a meeting and decided that we're going to let you down. Not alumni in general, just you.  [deleted] As another alumni, I'm excited for a new symbol that will do our university proud going into the future. As another alumni, I'm excited for a new symbol that will do our university proud going into the future. As another alum, meh. Never cared about the chief, and I don't really care about the replacement. I just care that the logo isn't ugly... Is there a link to an external site yet? [deleted]   Voted for all 3 krakens. No regrets. University of Illinois Krakens. Which slogan?

- We're 1,000 miles from the ocean.
- We do not sow. Hey, there's just as many krakens in Illinois as there are outside of Illinois!    </snippet></document><document><title>Spotted in Physics 212 today. Congrats on being totally gorgeous, dude.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/LQ5a7fM.jpg</url><snippet>  I saw you take this picture in Physics 212 today. Twist ending, my friend and I both took pictures, and we were sitting right next to each other. You'll never know. I know which one took it.
Source: I was right next to you. Source: The nice dream you had during lecture today touch&#233; I saw you take this picture in Physics 212 today. I saw you take this picture in Physics 212 today.    I'm in 211 right now and so far our comments have sucked. Most of them are related to how kids aren't understanding physics..  lol I'm in 211 right now and so far our comments have sucked. Most of them are related to how kids aren't understanding physics..  Ours were all terrible puns. When I say terrible I mean TERRIBLE.  Ours were all terrible puns. When I say terrible I mean TERRIBLE.   I'm pretty sure the same thing came up, in the exact same wording except for the genders switched, when I took 212 in 2009. So, uh, don't get too excited.   Ahhh Kwiat. My favorite non-engineering entity of undergrad. Ever. The suspenders. The intelligence! The slick bastard swing danced with my girlfriend and I ain't even mad. Kwiat teaches 214, not 212. And yes, he is amazing. Ahhh Kwiat. My favorite non-engineering entity of undergrad. Ever. The suspenders. The intelligence! The slick bastard swing danced with my girlfriend and I ain't even mad. Omg, that guy is still around? Does he still drive a sporty red car with license plate "PHOTON"? I saw him driving today! His license plate is still "PHOTON" but his car is black with a red symbol on the hood.  I didn't get a good look though :/ You can see his car in the uiuc physics gangam style </snippet></document><document><title>I work at the Illini Union Tech Zone and I was wondering what you think of the new store and if you have any suggestions, concerns, or questions.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17k6nw/i_work_at_the_illini_union_tech_zone_and_i_was/</url><snippet>  Do you guys price match? I understand that tech zone is about the convenience of being on campus, but with amazon prime for students products aren't too far away from students.

Otherwise, the store looks great. You guys have a better selection of computers and accessories. For some products, you have even more options than the local Best Buy.  One of the best things about the Tech Zone is the knowledgeability of the staff - they've worked there for years and often have heard of and solved the same kinds of student needs over and over. I really like that. You don't get that at brick and mortar stores - you wouldn't believe the nonsense I've heard at local chains. One of the best things about the Tech Zone is the knowledgeability of the staff - they've worked there for years and often have heard of and solved the same kinds of student needs over and over. I really like that. You don't get that at brick and mortar stores - you wouldn't believe the nonsense I've heard at local chains. What kind of repairs do they do? One of the keys on my keyboard is stiff and I need that fixed, does Tech Zone fix this kind of thing? Does it cost money, and if so, how much?   What's the best student deal you have for laptops? Are you looking for an Apple computer or a Windows computer?
We have the MacBook Pro 13" starting at $1074.  For Windows we have a few HP Elitebook Models that are new, but open box that start at $399.     Do you guys service/fix iDevices? Do you guys service/fix iDevices?   In terms of battery life and general similarity, what is the closest equivalent to the MBA you have?  Especially 13"+   I feel like the devices need to have little information plates next to them. if I'm going to drop $400+ in a purchase I want to know specs/features  [deleted]   I've been looking all over Reddit for you, Dave. I've scoured this cess pool trying to find you - and now I have!

Because you LOVE the cock!

Edit: Reddit doesn't understand. </snippet></document><document><title>T-shirt copyrights</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17kfcz/tshirt_copyrights/</url><snippet>I am trying to print some team shirts ASAP but I am using an Illinois Column "I" in the picture. Is there any place or anyone who has the rights to print it? I need small quantity but willing to pay if I can get what I need.     This should be a place to get you going: http://identitystandards.illinois.edu/graphicstandardsmanual/logodownloads/logodownloads.html

Click around on the links on the left, somewhere in there tells you what you can use and how to use them. I *believe* that you can openly use them, but look around on that website. So I just looked at it. You can use it, but it needs the tm sign. You are both wrong.
&amp;gt; Prior written approval is needed for students, campus groups, registered student organizations, or sports clubs from the Trademark and Licensing Office and the Collegiate Licensing Company (the University's licensing agent) for use of the University name or marks for anything other than official University business. This also applies to students, student groups, and organizations that wish to make use of the University name in conjunction with their group or activities, or those groups desiring use of the University's identifying marks.

[as per dylanova's link](http://identitystandards.illinois.edu/graphicstandardsmanual/universityguidelines/trademarkandlicensing.html) actually, the licensing and trademark office is pretty good with these, as long as you follow the guidelines. 
"A club team may, however, use a University mark as part of its uniform, provided the item is not issued or made available for sale to anyone other than team members. Students, student organizations and campus groups may receive permission to use a University mark for special uses, such as a commemorative item that is for members use only. No royalties are due on these items. Contact the Trademark and Licensing Office for approval of such uses."
Licensing and trademark Office phone is at the bottom of the page - (217) 333-2474 and (217) 244-0016 - there's also a list of licensed, local manufacturers that handle these often near the bottom of the page. actually, the licensing and trademark office is pretty good with these, as long as you follow the guidelines. 
"A club team may, however, use a University mark as part of its uniform, provided the item is not issued or made available for sale to anyone other than team members. Students, student organizations and campus groups may receive permission to use a University mark for special uses, such as a commemorative item that is for members use only. No royalties are due on these items. Contact the Trademark and Licensing Office for approval of such uses."
Licensing and trademark Office phone is at the bottom of the page - (217) 333-2474 and (217) 244-0016 - there's also a list of licensed, local manufacturers that handle these often near the bottom of the page.  So how would someone go about getting the chief put onto a t shirt? </snippet></document><document><title>UIUCProTip: Utilize the ECE Store</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17ikro/uiucprotip_utilize_the_ece_store/</url><snippet>A lot of people don't even know this exists and I couldn't find a post about it here (which is very aggravating and surprising). It's located in the basement of Everitt laboratory in RM 60 and I think their hours are Noon-4:30 M-F. 

I never went in there before but had to go in and get a lab manual. While in there, I was amazed at the abundant amount of electronic devices they have there at dirt cheap prices. For example, the guy in front of me in line bought an iPod cable for $1.30. I bought a 4 pack of AAA Energizer batteries for about $1.40. Comparatively, Walgreens, TIS, and other stores were charging about $7 for 4 AAAs. They also have a ton of cool things that I wanted to buy and I'm sure they were cheap too: keyboards, mice, headphones, usbs. Call ahead if you're looking for something specific obviously. They also have circuit parts but I'm sure if you needed circuit parts then you already knew that.

Basically, I never saw it pushed here before, but the ECE store is where I'll be going for all my future electronic needs.   I cannot thank you enough for posting this. The ECE store is an amazing resource and is often overlooked in favor of online resources.   Do they have a list of typical products/prices online? Do they have a list of typical products/prices online?  The only thing I find less than ideal is that you can't browse the store. You have to tell the person behind the counter exactly what you want (which they may or may not understand). But I've found good prices on things like generic DisplayPort&amp;gt;HDMI adapters and you don't have to wait weeks for shipping on that one you bought from China.


Also, you can buy 4 AAAs at walgreens for $3.50... so, it's still a savings, but you're getting ripped off if you pay $7.  Anything more than a quarter a battery is a rip off. But idk you must have seen them on sale when you were there. When I was there the generic brand was 4.99 and the Duracell were 6.99. Absurd.  more than a quarter a battery is a ripoff, and yet you paid $1.40 for 4, or 35 cents a battery?   Very true ECE store rocks! One thing from your post though, it's open from 8am to 12noon and then from 1pm to 4:30   Now I was under the impression that only ECE and engineering students could use the store. Is this just a completely false assumption? Yup! any student can use it Yup! any student can use it I'm not sure about that. I was always told that you needed to be an ECE, and I've always had my card scanned when I've bought stuff from there. ProTip:  ECE scans your iCard but its not linked to UIUC Banner according to the staff.  Its only to keep track of weird purchases so you can use ECE after you graduate until your icard exprires I'm not sure about that. I was always told that you needed to be an ECE, and I've always had my card scanned when I've bought stuff from there.    I'm not even an engineer and I went there once for an auxiliary cable for my car...$2.00 as opposed to $14 at walmart  I need new headphones, the rubber part of mine has slipped away and is exposing the wires which are getting frayed. I didn't see any headphones in the catalogue but does anyone know if they carry them anyways? I need new headphones, the rubber part of mine has slipped away and is exposing the wires which are getting frayed. I didn't see any headphones in the catalogue but does anyone know if they carry them anyways?     </snippet></document><document><title>My humble proposal for the new $100M pledge to the College of Engineering</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/E9VXhZZ.jpg</url><snippet>  Not a bad idea, but it needs ziplines from the top of each bell tower to popular destinations around campus. Not a bad idea, but it needs ziplines from the top of each bell tower to popular destinations around campus. That's So Riven    Ringing all these bells simultaneously opens the gates to hell...aka Unofficial.   I SEE YOU *Ash nazg durbatul&#251;k, ash nazg gimbatul, ash nazg thrakatul&#251;k agh burzum-ishi krimpatul.* [All Hail](http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8447/7842832986_275e4ca459_z.jpg)     For $100 million, you could have 66 of them - why limit yourself to 10? The grant was for 1.5 million, but the actual cost of the tower was much higher. Rumored up to 10 million.   Funny enough, one of our projects last year in ME 370 (Mechanical Design) was to model a bell tower that would go on the Engineering Quad... So we put ours right where that goofy sculpture is by MEL. Goofy sculpture?

Someone isn't properly letting you guys in on the secret there anymore, evidently... Explain? Funny enough, one of our projects last year in ME 370 (Mechanical Design) was to model a bell tower that would go on the Engineering Quad... So we put ours right where that goofy sculpture is by MEL.      2 much yoleaux 2 much swague 420
edit: downvotes, really? edit: downvotes, really? literally  THIS! What a waste of money that damn bell tower is. That was a donation Yeah, I'm pretty sure the donor stipulated it be a memorial to his wife or something That was a donation</snippet></document><document><title>International students: question about tax treaty</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17jh48/international_students_question_about_tax_treaty/</url><snippet>I am going to file my tax return for the first time. I am on f1 student visa and the whole tax filing system is really foreign to me. I read online that as international students, I can get about $5000 tax exemption thanks to a tax treaty between my county and the U.S. But I must do paper filing instead if I want to get the treaty benefit.
So has any international student here ever done taxes under the tax treaty? Any tips or pointers as to where I should get my taxes done (since I can't file online using softwares like Turbo Tax)? Many thanks!!   [deleted]  Are you making income? If you're not, the Form 8843 is the only form you'll need, but I am not a tax professional.

Most likely the tax exemptions will do jack all for you since I'm guessing you're not making enough for most exemptions to matter. do all F1 student need to fill the Form 8843? I am so confused as to fill it up or not :/.     What country?  Yes, they have to be done on paper.  Tax Treatys are really a cluster fuck all around as most likely if your an international student, you an dependent in your home country and have a smaller exemption if the tax treaty had that provision in there.  Have you tried r/tax? What country?  Yes, they have to be done on paper.  Tax Treatys are really a cluster fuck all around as most likely if your an international student, you an dependent in your home country and have a smaller exemption if the tax treaty had that provision in there.  Have you tried r/tax?</snippet></document><document><title>Illinoisnet down again? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/17is9z/illinoisnet_down_again/</url><snippet>Sitting in siebel, unable to connect   And yet people are confused when I suggested that CITES should be improved. &amp;gt; CITES should be improved.

Do you mean the whole damn giant-ass, IT-providing organization? Or some aspect of the services they provide? In either case, how? (Beyond just saying "the internet should always work for me and their gmail login is dumb and where did my netfiles go.")

I can see why you feel like CITES has fallen short. I felt that way before I got an IT job with ACES, but I found that many problems aren't actually as simple as some people doing their jobs poorly. It may be an issue with the school's ISP or your own computer's credentials. As one example, CITES could communicate to users about maintenance and outages on IllinoisNet.  Instructors in the CS building have been regularly losing their wireless connection in the middle of lectures!  This has been going on for weeks.  What is going on?  Why?  Why aren't they communicating about it.

IT organizations that blame their users for their own lack of communication are unprofessional. As one example, CITES could communicate to users about maintenance and outages on IllinoisNet.  Instructors in the CS building have been regularly losing their wireless connection in the middle of lectures!  This has been going on for weeks.  What is going on?  Why?  Why aren't they communicating about it.

IT organizations that blame their users for their own lack of communication are unprofessional.  I had trouble with both earlier,  but others were getting on fine, quite easily could have been on my end
     Lots of drivers have problems with IllinoisNet. Not sure exactly what it is, but I know Apple's drivers (The broadcom ones) SUCK for University WiFi. Lots of drivers have problems with IllinoisNet. Not sure exactly what it is, but I know Apple's drivers (The broadcom ones) SUCK for University WiFi. Really? Besides lately, I haven't had any issues in my four years here.</snippet></document><document><title>Looking over the quad today</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/sZviks9.jpg</url><snippet>  This makes it look endless, which is awesome. It's like a video game or dream where you just keep running but never get to the end...because...you know...it's one of those levels. The staircase in Mario 64! No no it does end but it takes about twenty minutes, go try it. No no it does end but it takes about twenty minutes, go try it. It's like a video game or dream where you just keep running but never get to the end...because...you know...it's one of those levels.        It was brought to my attention that the man who took this picture is /u/imarealboyce. I saw this shared by a mutual friend of ours on my FB feed. So thanks to him for taking this great one. I hope you don't feel offended that I upped it here realboyce.        [deleted] Kinda like how you were probably gawking like a baby at the Midwest snow? Granted, none yet this year but it could get horrible.  [deleted] So sort of like not everyone from Chicago is totally amazed by fog, I see. Would you like a ladder to help get off your high horse? [deleted] Ok bud. I called the fire station to get you down so hang in there.  [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Gallery of the Fog around campus tonight</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/ioOkt</url><snippet>       Damn, that first picture would be such tight butthole if that person wasn't there. Anyone know photoshop? Damn, that first picture would be such tight butthole if that person wasn't there. Anyone know photoshop?</snippet></document></searchresult>