<searchresult><uiuc /><document><title>Where can i get something faxed and notarized on campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18jvgy/where_can_i_get_something_faxed_and_notarized_on/</url><snippet>This is for stupid ameren.   Urbana public library has a notary if I recall. It's possible the Champaign library might too.        TCF: they'll both notarized and fax the thing for you (I assume this is for Ameren?)</snippet></document><document><title>Local computer repair?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18jhc8/local_computer_repair/</url><snippet>I was wondering if you guys had any opinions on local computer repair places.  I've got an external hard drive that won't power up.  I'm pretty sure I want to avoid Illini Tech Center, right?  I've heard good things about simplified computers.  Not sure they'll have the cable you're looking for, I suppose it's worth a shot though.

You could always dissect the enclosure and hook the drive up to a desktop.  If it spins up and works you just need to buy a new enclosure which can be found for pretty cheap on the internet. I've heard good things about simplified computers.  Not sure they'll have the cable you're looking for, I suppose it's worth a shot though.

You could always dissect the enclosure and hook the drive up to a desktop.  If it spins up and works you just need to buy a new enclosure which can be found for pretty cheap on the internet.  Is the hard drive still under warranty? The manufacturer should be able to help you out and save you some money. You *might* have to pay for shipping.  What brand is it, how old is it, and is it powering on or click,ing? If its a newer WD Passport, you're fucked since they use a proprietary ZIF connector inside. It's a Seagate FreeAgent.  It's about 3.5 years old.  And it's not powering up: no spinning disk noises, no light, not showing up on my computer.  It may just be a bad cable, but I'd like to just take it to an expert. wouldn't it make more sense to just replace the cable first? Sure, if I could find one that fits.  I bet a computer repair store might have one that they could test that with.  And if that's the problem, I bet I could buy it from them, too. If its three years old, its either USB-B, miniUSB, or microUSB. Post a pic and I can tell you which it is. All are very common.  It's not even powering up.  It's the power cable that may be bad.  [Computer Deli](http://www.computerdeli.com/) should be able to help you diagnose this problem

If they are unable to fix it and you REALLY need the data you can try [Drive Savers](http://www.drivesaversdatarecovery.com/) but this is a pretty expensive service I think. I noticed Computer Deli with a Google search, but they didn't have any reviews.  You recommend them?

Disk Savers seems like a pretty neat service.  I especially liked their Museum of Bizzare Disk-astours.  More the likely just a desktop SATA drive in there, I would try replacing the case: http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817182155

Less then $20.

Or take the drive out of the enclosure and bring it by one of the campus departmental IT offices. They should have an adapter like the one sold with this adapter: http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16812232002

That way you know if the drive is bad or the case. It will take them less then two minutes to plug it in and see if the drive powers up.  You can go to the Tech Zone at the Union, I used to work there. Theres a group of good techs there and they'll see what can be done! They do hourly work for less than all of the other computer places around. Is that the same place that used to be called The Flash Drive?</snippet></document><document><title>X-Files creator Chris Carter is the special guest for this year's Insect Fear Film Festival 2/23</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18i3cd/xfiles_creator_chris_carter_is_the_special_guest/</url><snippet>If you've never been, the [Insect Fear Film Festival](http://www.life.illinois.edu/entomology/egsa/ifff.html) is a tradition of the Entomology Department on campus. This is our 30th year and I'm really excited about our special guest this year so I hope we get a good crowd! 


**Date:** February 23, 2013

**Time:** Doors open at 6pm, see the schedule below for more info

**Theme:** The InsX-Files: The Truth (About Insects) Is Out There, with special guest [Chris Carter](http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0004810/), creator of the X-Files. 

**Location:** [Foellinger Auditorium](https://maps.google.com/maps?q=foellinger+auditorium&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;fb=1&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;hq=foellinger+auditorium)


We'll be showing the episode [The X-Files: "The War of the Coprophages,"](http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0751259/) about a wave of deaths linked to what may be alien robotic cockroaches, followed by the 1998 feature [The X-Files: Fight the Future](http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120902/), about killer bees that transmit a deadly alien virus by stinging. Fun fact: the character Bambi Berenbaum in "The War of the Coprophages" is named after UIUC Entomology faculty member [May Berenbaum](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/May_Berenbaum).


Exhibits and activities include exotic insect displays from around the world, the **insect petting zoo**, face painting, and entries from the annual insect art contest (some of them end up being super cute!). 


**Admission is free!**


6:00 pm - 7:00 pm - Exhibits, displays, &amp;amp; activities

7:00 pm - 7:30 pm - Opening remarks

7:30 pm - 8:15 pm - "War of the Coprophages"

8:15 pm - 8:45 pm - Q&amp;amp;A Chris Carter

8:45 pm - 10:45 pm - "X Files"

10:45 pm - 11:15 pm - Q&amp;amp;A Chris Carter </snippet></document><document><title>Juciy J at Foellinger this Friday???</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=woLTqW7HqqE</url><snippet>   It was for the cotton club. Its a annual black frat event on campus. Its not supposed to be a huge show. That's why it was in Foellinger. Regardless they either didn't make enough to pay him because they sold out and he was charging more or they didn't think they sell out in order to pay.

Supposedly they're offering refunds if you bought one but who knows. Everything is related with the university. If you don't get a refund contact the RSO office because fraternities are involved. But really, try and get the money first before going to the university.  I don't think Juicy J will actually be there..for some reason, I'm getting the feeling that this is a huge scam.   Yeah it seems really shady. You have to call a chicago number to buy tickets?  That and it says nothing on the Juicy J ticketmaster or official websites.  and the website for that ticket is sketch as f &amp;gt;For more information, please text 773-678-7133 or 312-450-9806.

Yeah that sounds legit. I don't think Juicy J will actually be there..for some reason, I'm getting the feeling that this is a huge scam.    http://livemusic7.com/  Got my tickets this weekend. Don't understand why someone that big is playing such a small venue. Got my tickets this weekend. Don't understand why someone that big is playing such a small venue.  So...according to his [twitter](https://twitter.com/therealjuicyj) the show was cancelled due to "lack of funds".  WTF?!?

I thought foellinger would be a weird place for juicy anyway but srsly wtf...anyone know anything?  This is what the ticket looks like. No barcode or anything. Guess I'm out $20. 

http://imgur.com/cPyVmpY This is what the ticket looks like. No barcode or anything. Guess I'm out $20. 

http://imgur.com/cPyVmpY This is what the ticket looks like. No barcode or anything. Guess I'm out $20. 

http://imgur.com/cPyVmpY   </snippet></document><document><title>Any easy half semester courses to take?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18hyrk/any_easy_half_semester_courses_to_take/</url><snippet>I might need to drop out of a course soon and it will put me at 11 hours, so suggestions would be GREAT

Edit: The course catalog search function was a pleasant surprise. Very well done and my compliments to the devs who worked on that.  If you're looking for an easy A, Phys 213. Super easy course, ask anyone.  If you're looking for an easy A, Phys 213. Super easy course, ask anyone.  Is 213 way harder than 214? Because I'm failing the shit out of 214 right now  If you're looking for an easy A, Phys 213. Super easy course, ask anyone.  How much calc-3 do we need for that class?  RST110. I took it last semester and it was super easy. It has a different teacher this time so keep that in mind but the course material was easy.   I hope you've already looked this up but theres been quite a few people that have already asked this:
[One year ago](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/pdcre/anyone_know_of_any_good_secondhalf_geneds_i_could/)

[4 months ago](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/10jo0t/are_there_any_8_week_courses_worth_taking_my/)

[Also a year ago](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/pvgju/suggestion_for_a_second_half_the_the_semester/)

[3 months ago](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/11qa58/need_help_picking_an_8week_course_self/)

[Also 4 months ago](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/10r5ul/suggestions_for_an_8week_course/)  I signed up for NRES 102 or 103 or something like that. It's the only 8 week one. I can only assume it will be really easy. I mean, it's a 100 level earth sciences course that is made for non majors. I signed up for NRES 102 or 103 or something like that. It's the only 8 week one. I can only assume it will be really easy. I mean, it's a 100 level earth sciences course that is made for non majors.     Ok, I found a course called TSM 311. Any thoughts on that? And what about courses that the course catalog says are "closed". I have heard people that can get into these courses somehow?  TSM 311 is a full-semester course. They just do the discussions differently in the first half and second half, so the discussions look like second-half courses. They are not. You can't do TSM 311. (I know because I called them to ask about it last week)

TSM should fix the course schedule so that this course does not display as a second-eight-week course, but that definitely won't happen for this semester. This is helpful, thanks.
They really should somehow group the discussion sections with lecture sections so this doesn't happen  Any QI or QII ones out there? Atms 120 is a quant II. And it is very easy.  phys 214 phys 214 phys 214 I knew that this or phys 213 would be the first answer I would get.
Now, if we can move on to the real suggestions... </snippet></document><document><title>How long do companies take to contact you after the application?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18irj4/how_long_do_companies_take_to_contact_you_after/</url><snippet>I went to the engineering career fair on the 29th and still haven't heard back from any of the companies I applied to. Does it usually take this long to hear back or is it safe to say none of them were interested?        </snippet></document><document><title>Where can we find puppies near campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18i409/where_can_we_find_puppies_near_campus/</url><snippet>It's already that time in the semester that I'm starting to get stressed out.

Where is a good place near campus that visitors may play with puppies? Is there such a magical land?   I'm not sure about the rest of the year, but the ARC is hosting snuggle time with Illini Service Dogs from 3-6 today as part of their Valentine's Day celebration! =)      ????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
You don't know how to relax? You should probably add some more question marks. I don't think you've adequately expressed your confusion yet.</snippet></document><document><title>My friend's cat is missing. It's a long shot but maybe someone has seen it?</title><url>http://chambana.craigslist.org/laf/3613489973.html</url><snippet>  He needs to call the Humane Society and report this ASAP.  They'll take some information and let him know if someone brings the cat in.  Good luck!  :'(   Yesterday (Tuesday) I saw a stray cat near Siebel Center on like springfield and goodwin. Can't exactly remember if it looked like your cat or not but just thought I'd let you know  I saw a cat that looks similar to the cat in those pictures around my house on First and Gregory   Pic? I see a lot of cats. all four pictures on that page are of the same cat.</snippet></document><document><title>LEX Express/Suburban Express Customer Experience Survey -- Vent to me about your Bus-fueled frustrations!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18h2jo/lex_expresssuburban_express_customer_experience/</url><snippet>Howdy ya'll! I'm working on a story about LEX Express's closure in December and could use some input from students on their experiences riding with LEX before they were shut down. I'm also looking into Suburban Express' use of the charter buses for another story, and could use individual feedback on their services as well. 

Will post final stories on /r/UIUC in return. Thank you for your time!   I was recently banned by Suburban Express.  Having lost my ticket at the last minute, I had to go print out another one and arrived at the bus three minutes late -- I checked.  As I neared ISR, I saw that they still had a couple people boarding the bus.  When the guy in charge of directing the passengers to the appropriate bus saw me approaching, he yelled, "If you want to catch this bus, you'd better start running!"  He then proceeded to berate and me and two other guys for arriving late, yelling at us while we stowed our luggage, "Who the hell do you think you are?  You're holding up a whole bus load of people!"  After our luggage was stowed, he continued to yell at us about how inconsiderate we were and how we were banned from every using the service again.  Once we were on the bus, turned to the driver and said, "Can you believe these fucking people?"

Honestly, I know I was late -- I'm not excusing myself.  In fact, I expected that the bus would have already left or that I would not be allowed on.  I would have understood and been okay with either of those outcomes.  However, I found it extremely unprofessional to be yelled and cursed at for being late.  The bus driver, though, was really nice about the whole thing.  Seeing how shaken I was after the whole thing, he offered me a bottle of water and tried to comfort me, saying that he "didn't believe in taking pleasure in the misfortune of others."

For what it's worth, when I asked the bus driver who the guy was, he said that he didn't know.  Given that he was wearing a Suburban Express shirt, I assumed that he was an employee of Suburban Express and unconnected with the charter company driving the bus.  

On a completely different note, another time that I rode Suburban Express, the driver missed the exit to the Northbrook Court stop.  Despite the GPS repeatedly telling him to exit, he also missed the next several exits and didn't turn around until a passenger went to tell him that he missed the exit.

On the other hand, I almost never ride LEX due to the mechanical failures of their buses.  Once, one of the tires on the bus blew out on the freeway and another time, the hood of the van started smoking during the trip.  Also, my roommate almost missed her flight due to a bus breaking down on the freeway. I was recently banned by Suburban Express.  Having lost my ticket at the last minute, I had to go print out another one and arrived at the bus three minutes late -- I checked.  As I neared ISR, I saw that they still had a couple people boarding the bus.  When the guy in charge of directing the passengers to the appropriate bus saw me approaching, he yelled, "If you want to catch this bus, you'd better start running!"  He then proceeded to berate and me and two other guys for arriving late, yelling at us while we stowed our luggage, "Who the hell do you think you are?  You're holding up a whole bus load of people!"  After our luggage was stowed, he continued to yell at us about how inconsiderate we were and how we were banned from every using the service again.  Once we were on the bus, turned to the driver and said, "Can you believe these fucking people?"

Honestly, I know I was late -- I'm not excusing myself.  In fact, I expected that the bus would have already left or that I would not be allowed on.  I would have understood and been okay with either of those outcomes.  However, I found it extremely unprofessional to be yelled and cursed at for being late.  The bus driver, though, was really nice about the whole thing.  Seeing how shaken I was after the whole thing, he offered me a bottle of water and tried to comfort me, saying that he "didn't believe in taking pleasure in the misfortune of others."

For what it's worth, when I asked the bus driver who the guy was, he said that he didn't know.  Given that he was wearing a Suburban Express shirt, I assumed that he was an employee of Suburban Express and unconnected with the charter company driving the bus.  

On a completely different note, another time that I rode Suburban Express, the driver missed the exit to the Northbrook Court stop.  Despite the GPS repeatedly telling him to exit, he also missed the next several exits and didn't turn around until a passenger went to tell him that he missed the exit.

On the other hand, I almost never ride LEX due to the mechanical failures of their buses.  Once, one of the tires on the bus blew out on the freeway and another time, the hood of the van started smoking during the trip.  Also, my roommate almost missed her flight due to a bus breaking down on the freeway. I was recently banned by Suburban Express.  Having lost my ticket at the last minute, I had to go print out another one and arrived at the bus three minutes late -- I checked.  As I neared ISR, I saw that they still had a couple people boarding the bus.  When the guy in charge of directing the passengers to the appropriate bus saw me approaching, he yelled, "If you want to catch this bus, you'd better start running!"  He then proceeded to berate and me and two other guys for arriving late, yelling at us while we stowed our luggage, "Who the hell do you think you are?  You're holding up a whole bus load of people!"  After our luggage was stowed, he continued to yell at us about how inconsiderate we were and how we were banned from every using the service again.  Once we were on the bus, turned to the driver and said, "Can you believe these fucking people?"

Honestly, I know I was late -- I'm not excusing myself.  In fact, I expected that the bus would have already left or that I would not be allowed on.  I would have understood and been okay with either of those outcomes.  However, I found it extremely unprofessional to be yelled and cursed at for being late.  The bus driver, though, was really nice about the whole thing.  Seeing how shaken I was after the whole thing, he offered me a bottle of water and tried to comfort me, saying that he "didn't believe in taking pleasure in the misfortune of others."

For what it's worth, when I asked the bus driver who the guy was, he said that he didn't know.  Given that he was wearing a Suburban Express shirt, I assumed that he was an employee of Suburban Express and unconnected with the charter company driving the bus.  

On a completely different note, another time that I rode Suburban Express, the driver missed the exit to the Northbrook Court stop.  Despite the GPS repeatedly telling him to exit, he also missed the next several exits and didn't turn around until a passenger went to tell him that he missed the exit.

On the other hand, I almost never ride LEX due to the mechanical failures of their buses.  Once, one of the tires on the bus blew out on the freeway and another time, the hood of the van started smoking during the trip.  Also, my roommate almost missed her flight due to a bus breaking down on the freeway. Why were you banned? Apparently, being late gets you banned. [deleted] I was recently banned by Suburban Express.  Having lost my ticket at the last minute, I had to go print out another one and arrived at the bus three minutes late -- I checked.  As I neared ISR, I saw that they still had a couple people boarding the bus.  When the guy in charge of directing the passengers to the appropriate bus saw me approaching, he yelled, "If you want to catch this bus, you'd better start running!"  He then proceeded to berate and me and two other guys for arriving late, yelling at us while we stowed our luggage, "Who the hell do you think you are?  You're holding up a whole bus load of people!"  After our luggage was stowed, he continued to yell at us about how inconsiderate we were and how we were banned from every using the service again.  Once we were on the bus, turned to the driver and said, "Can you believe these fucking people?"

Honestly, I know I was late -- I'm not excusing myself.  In fact, I expected that the bus would have already left or that I would not be allowed on.  I would have understood and been okay with either of those outcomes.  However, I found it extremely unprofessional to be yelled and cursed at for being late.  The bus driver, though, was really nice about the whole thing.  Seeing how shaken I was after the whole thing, he offered me a bottle of water and tried to comfort me, saying that he "didn't believe in taking pleasure in the misfortune of others."

For what it's worth, when I asked the bus driver who the guy was, he said that he didn't know.  Given that he was wearing a Suburban Express shirt, I assumed that he was an employee of Suburban Express and unconnected with the charter company driving the bus.  

On a completely different note, another time that I rode Suburban Express, the driver missed the exit to the Northbrook Court stop.  Despite the GPS repeatedly telling him to exit, he also missed the next several exits and didn't turn around until a passenger went to tell him that he missed the exit.

On the other hand, I almost never ride LEX due to the mechanical failures of their buses.  Once, one of the tires on the bus blew out on the freeway and another time, the hood of the van started smoking during the trip.  Also, my roommate almost missed her flight due to a bus breaking down on the freeway.       I'm surprised the Suburban Express account hasn't shown up to harass the people in this thread yet. What makes you think so? Any account which posts almost exclusively about Suburban Express is probably yet another Suburban Express account, like the OP and many others in this thread. You won't see posts on any other topics from many people who have posted in this thread. LEx is gone and Suburban Express is literally flogging a dead horse. They were obsessed with LEx when it was there, and they cannot let go of it even when it is gone. What makes you think so? Any account which posts almost exclusively about Suburban Express is probably yet another Suburban Express account, like the OP and many others in this thread. You won't see posts on any other topics from many people who have posted in this thread. LEx is gone and Suburban Express is literally flogging a dead horse. They were obsessed with LEx when it was there, and they cannot let go of it even when it is gone.     As much as I hate Suburban because they're assholes, I swore I would never take Lex after last year. They were almost always late, sometimes by more than an hour, which was annoying. But not too awful. But the thing that finally made me say enough was the time I took a bus back to Champaign at night, and the headlights of the bus weren't working. At all. And yet we drove all the way back to Champaign in the pitch dark. Driving at night without headlights is illegal in Illinois. I'm quite surprised they weren't pulled over by state police, because they're mainly in charge of enforcing imminent mechanical vehicle regulations, just like anyone else can get pulled over and written up for a traffic violation for driving without headlights.

Thanks for the response, please get in touch! Since you've researched the matter, which states allow one to drive at night without headlights? I'm curious. I didn't mean to imply there were any states that do allow driving without headlights at night. But if you're that curious, you could probably start [here](http://www.dmv.org/il-illinois/safety-laws.php). It really depends on the vehicle code of the state you're in. It may not be specifically illegal depending on the cop/lawyer you're dealing with, but it's an easy way to be cited for reckless and dangerous driving and grant probable cause for a traffic stop anyways.    </snippet></document><document><title>UIUC sees decline in Asian applicants primarily due to the announcement that this is a smoke free campus</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18h3kg/uiuc_sees_decline_in_asian_applicants_primarily/</url><snippet>Somebody in class claimed this but he had no factual evidence to back it up? Any truth to this?

Personally I think as long we have a top tier engineering and business program nobody will care but who knows.  [Correlation does not imply causation.](http://i.imgur.com/CMyJQTo.jpg)        [deleted] How someone can be a "science" major and vomit such unsubstantiated, intolerant bullshit is beyond me. [deleted] Sure. [deleted] How someone can be a "science" major and vomit such unsubstantiated, intolerant bullshit is beyond me.  [deleted] They don't get a free education you know. They pay alot more for tuition and other costs. They are honestly the reason U of I is where its at. Its what keeps us from being ISU, NIU, or SIU. They're usually filthy rich and what they can offer the school is unmatched. They also give the school alot of international exposure. So yea they're kinda important [deleted] American students cheat as well. Cheating is not relevant to this conversation and neither are grading curves. You sound a bit bitter? These students are what make U of I relevant as an academic institution. If you don't like it you can go to ISU [deleted] [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>New Python Users Group (Py-CU) first meeting</title><url>http://py-cu.org/events.html</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>"I don't do Eeyores. I do Tiggers." --Coach Groce</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fGNBX2xEVSg&amp;amp;t=8m27s</url><snippet>   Watched this 3 times. Still don't know what he is talking about. People on the team need to have a good attitude like tigger, not be pessimistic like eeyore. He said he only had to send someone to the locker room once for being an eeyore.  Indeed. Someone asked him what Tyler Griffey's attitude had been like when he was struggling from 3. Said that he always has a great attitude. Griff sounds like a great kid - really glad to see him turn it around in such a huge way.  It's probably a reference to [Randy Pausch's Last Lecture](http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=ji5_MqicxSo#t=3719s)  </snippet></document><document><title>Looking for 1 Umphrey's @ Canopy Ticket!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18gwbt/looking_for_1_umphreys_canopy_ticket/</url><snippet>Waited too long to buy tickets but would love to make it to the show on Sunday.  Any help would be much appreciated.  </snippet></document><document><title>Anyone here play Heroes of Newerth? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18gocl/anyone_here_play_heroes_of_newerth/</url><snippet>I know alot of people play LOL and dota 2 here. I just started playing hon and was looking for any uiuc people that played that wanted to queue up!  You don't like LoL? LoL master race checking in. AHAHHAHAHAHAH LoL master race that's a good one. LoL: for the gamer who doesn't really want to think too hard abotu his MOBA. Seriously, DOTA was the most infuriating experience of my life. Speak for yourself; I think very hard about my LoL. :) Academic Adviser... one of us?!? Speak for yourself; I think very hard about my LoL. :) LoL: for the gamer who doesn't really want to think too hard abotu his MOBA. Seriously, DOTA was the most infuriating experience of my life. LoL: for the gamer who doesn't really want to think too hard abotu his MOBA. Seriously, DOTA was the most infuriating experience of my life.    whats your mmr? I sit around 1500. Still learning I haven't played in a while but are there still a significant amount of smurfs in that MMR range?  (I am a pre-compression 1900, right now sitting at 1750)    Cmon man y dont u play dota 2 it so god cuz its beter han lol and its hardr so ir a hety rt in man aojbuy http://i.imgur.com/VIFvW.gif I don't understand why that doesn't hurt. Cmon man y dont u play dota 2 it so god cuz its beter han lol and its hardr so ir a hety rt in man aojbuy</snippet></document><document><title>In response to the thread yesterday, here's all the documents for the Illinois Student Senate referenda questions</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18g2sm/in_response_to_the_thread_yesterday_heres_all_the/</url><snippet>The documents associated with the proposed constitutional changes are provided here: http://iss.illinois.edu/documents.asp</snippet></document><document><title>Anybody have basketball tickets to tonight's game? I'm looking for 2.</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18h6ui/anybody_have_basketball_tickets_to_tonights_game/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>my friend snapped this picture outside of the union the other day.  I'm not sure how to feel about this.</title><url>http://i.imgur.com/OCfWWuC.jpg</url><snippet>  I can't think of anything but how terrible Tobias in animorphs felt about himself when he finally accepted that he had to kill to live as the red-tailed hawk he had been trapped as.

But then he accepted himself for who he was. I think we can accept this hawk for who it is:
an awesome hawk. I can't think of anything but how terrible Tobias in animorphs felt about himself when he finally accepted that he had to kill to live as the red-tailed hawk he had been trapped as.

But then he accepted himself for who he was. I think we can accept this hawk for who it is:
an awesome hawk. Thank you, just spent 5 minutes reliving that wonderful series in my head instead of studying. 

Jake - The Tiger
Marco - The Gorilla
Ax - himself
Rachel - the Bear
...can't remember anymore I can't think of anything but how terrible Tobias in animorphs felt about himself when he finally accepted that he had to kill to live as the red-tailed hawk he had been trapped as.

But then he accepted himself for who he was. I think we can accept this hawk for who it is:
an awesome hawk.     Nobody treats our future mascot like that! Our future mascot is the Kraken!      It took me a couple minutes to realize this, but the squirrel's head is hanging about six inches below its body.   Eww. Could've warned about the contents... You're at least 18 years old and you're on the internet,
seriously? Eww. Could've warned about the contents...  Majestic bird of prey eating a rodent that over populates our campus? Why dont know you know to feel? Its nature. This is an awesome picture. the squirrels are all little bastards anyway Fun fact: the squirrels were actually introduced to campus in the early 1900s to give a little more character to the quad. And now one lives in my ceiling.  Thanks early 1900s UofI! You're lucky you only have one. I'm pretty sure there's a whole family of the fuckers living in ours... If time travel is invented, I'm stopping the introduction of squirrels to uiuc.  Those things running around on a drop ceiling is unnerving.  Especially once you know they'll eat meat. Forget Hitler, we're gonna go fight squirrel introduction   Put this on R/WTF I freaked out a bit when I saw the squirrel head hanging there...    And marking it NSFW though really it's not that bad. I don't know why at least 18 year old college students on the internet are complaining about this picture being too graphic
  NSFW NSFL NSFLOL NSFLOL NSFL  [deleted] [deleted] [deleted] ASSHAT! Once again, no names, kids. thank you murph :) See, now I know who I am.

And now I'm off to PM myself very creepy things.               [deleted] How do you find a vegetarian on reddit? oh, **all** my posts are about vegetarianism. How do you find a vegetarian on reddit? How do you find a vegetarian on reddit?  This is awkward. The original photographer is my room mate and showed me this picture a couple days ago. I could of posted it and received an abundant load of karma. :( Rats.  are you ben</snippet></document><document><title>Yet another Harlem Shake video - this time in Grainger (study room)! Give us some likes for E-Week!</title><url>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j5bCRDbue-M&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be</url><snippet>  Would I get points for dancing naked in the Lincoln Hall auditorium, with my wiener flopping everywhere, and a paper bag on my head?  Huge fan of the alien headed guy wearing an American flag cape. Huge fan of the alien headed guy wearing an American flag cape.   Why?  Combines everything I love. EWeek, Harlem shake, and grainger. What team? Theta-Taurus Rex!   Have you submitted to /r/Harlemshake ? This one is definitely better than the ugl one, probably because this lacks dude ass.   stop  Why is it that every E-Week video has been a Harlem Shake? Coincidence and timing
 Coincidence and timing
 Sup kief Why is it that every E-Week video has been a Harlem Shake? Yeah, it's just too perfect timing. We had the idea this weekend, but SHPE got theirs posted a day before ours. Is there a third one? there's a few general ones from the university as well. SHPE had the idea this weekend too.

Source: I'm in SHPE Is SHPE's Harlem Shake video their submission for their E-Week video? Our president said it was. Tell him he still has to tweet it at E-Week and post it on the facebook page for it to count.  Was right outside the door when you guys did this. Took me a while to figure out what was going on in the room.    Is this in the legendary Theta Tau study room? Haha I didn't know the Theta Tau study room was "legendary". I mean, it is now I guess. 100 LIKES ON YOUTUBE :) *watermelon* **kate**... 
gee I wonder who this is.     [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Launch an Illinois alum into space!! - In 54th place right now...</title><url>https://www.facebook.com/pages/Send-an-Illini-Alum-to-Space/206329999509183</url><snippet>  Short Description: Vote for me to go up into space. You can only vote once but you can invite others to vote! My goal is to get 1000 votes by 2/18/13. I should be in the top 20 that way and convincing strangers on the street should be much easier then. Thank you! :D

https://www2.axeapollo.com/en_US/28525/kamil-stelmach

Long Description:

Hi everyone,

So I kind of dreamed of going up to space ever since I was a youngling (pictures to be released in March when I return to la casa de mi padres). My interests in space have only grown since then: I interned at NASA twice, once each at NASA Ames and at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory; I flew (a hastily constructed) experiment in zero gravity; and am now a Master's graduate student at George Mason University studying planetary ice chemistry.

Never for a second I would have thought that I could go up to space in my 20s, but recent developments have changed that. AXE - the deodorant company and not the chemistry fraternity - is hosting a competition to send a few people into a space through the developing Lynx Mark I suborbital spacecraft. Naturally, I decided to enter this competition: if I am in the top two portion in the US leaderboard then I will move on to the next level of selection. 

How can you help? By voting for me by April 30th! Also, I guess it would help if you shared this event with your friends...but then you'd be going above and beyond my request so I would have to enter into your servitude forever.

Thanks everyone! And sorry for inviting you if you voted already &amp;gt;.&amp;lt;

-Kamil 

Here is a video of some cats in zero gravity:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O9XtK6R1QAkShort Description: Vote for me to go up into space. You can only vote once but you can invite others to vote! My goal is to get 1000 votes by 2/18/13. I should be in the top 20 that way and convincing strangers on the street should be much easier then. Thank you! :D

https://www2.axeapollo.com/en_US/28525/kamil-stelmach

Long Description:

Hi everyone,

So I kind of dreamed of going up to space ever since I was a youngling (pictures to be released in March when I return to la casa de mi padres). My interests in space have only grown since then: I interned at NASA twice, once each at NASA Ames and at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory; I flew (a hastily constructed) experiment in zero gravity; and am now a Master's graduate student at George Mason University studying planetary ice chemistry.

Never for a second I would have thought that I could go up to space in my 20s, but recent developments have changed that. AXE - the deodorant company and not the chemistry fraternity - is hosting a competition to send a few people into a space through the developing Lynx Mark I suborbital spacecraft. Naturally, I decided to enter this competition: if I am in the top two portion in the US leaderboard then I will move on to the next level of selection. 

How can you help? By voting for me by April 30th! Also, I guess it would help if you shared this event with your friends...but then you'd be going above and beyond my request so I would have to enter into your servitude forever.

Thanks everyone! And sorry for inviting you if you voted already &amp;gt;.&amp;lt;

-Kamil 

Here is a video of some cats in zero gravity:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O9XtK6R1QAk  http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_University_of_Illinois_at_Urbana%E2%80%93Champaign_people#Astronauts  Alumnus, damnit!

Pedantry done now...</snippet></document><document><title>Why..UIUC..? Why?</title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=6HqaYYrCfKs</url><snippet>  wellllllllllll.... that was weird    Literally and figuratively the ballsiest one I've seen so far. There are several of these? There are several of these?    I've never been to UGL. After seeing this video, I don't think I'll ever go. Grainger is closer to where I live anyways. The bottom floor is better. It's quiet. I prefer Grainger, though. Grainger has gotten busy as fuck this year though.   This video describes the UGL perfectly.     [deleted] [deleted]    ...Might as well capitalize off of this for some attention to our university. [Crossposted to r/harlemshake](http://www.reddit.com/r/harlemshake/comments/18e2bq/harlem_shake_university_of_illinois_edition/)!      This why UGL is UGL. Never happening in Grainger.   [deleted]  Harlem Shake Protip: If you don't have cool costumes, it's best to just not make a video at all rather than wearing nothing.       this is literally ...literally what? 

I think you accidentally a word.  [deleted] [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Lincoln Hall will be rededicated today at 4, catch the livestream of the event here. Governor Quinn, among others, will be speaking. </title><url>http://www.lincolnhall.illinois.edu/events/</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Coach Beckman handing out vouchers for free food at Union 2/12 from 12-1</title><url>https://twitter.com/coachbeckman/status/301360487503892482</url><snippet>      Coach Beckman really cares about the students and wants to get them and the community involved, lot more active with the student body than Zook was. He seems like a great guy and I really hope that he can turn this program around. He's a great guy in public and to the fans/students... Unfortunately, that's about all I can say for his character.   Really? Thats a shame, Everyone I know that has interacted with him said he was really nice. So you're saying he's a jerk otherwise?
     [deleted]</snippet></document><document><title>Petition to Add Referenda Questions (Current Students Only)</title><url>https://illinois.edu/fb/sec/632204</url><snippet>   &amp;gt;  Do you approve of the Student Government as the Official Voice of the Student Body (Illinois Student Senate) through a new Constitution and Transition Document as proposed by the Commission on Constitutional Reform and adopted by the Illinois Student Senate?

What does that even mean?

&amp;gt; Should each student contribute $1.00 per semester to the Student Government to keep the Student Government financially independent from the University and Campus Administrations?

I thought we did already. Are you asking for more? 1. The Illinois Student Senate created a special commission in the Fall to look into ways of improving the ISS Constitution (e.g. to make the student government more effective and representative). This question asks the Student Body to approve the commission's draft as adopted by ISS - as a referendum vote is the only way to change the student government Constitution. (I agree that the wording is terrible, but a number of senators were dead set that it appear this way.)
2. The ISS is currently funded by the University's Office of Student Affairs, from general student fee money. The second question aims to replace this money with a direct student fee. This is intended to make the student government directly accountable to students and open up it's funding to review by the Student Fee Advisory Committee in the same way fees for McKinley, Krannert, and Assembly Hall are reviewed and require renewal periodically by referenda vote. At $1.00/semester, this would account for slightly less than a doubling of the ISS's funding, iirc. While this seems a bit extreme, the fee would require approval by SFAC, who have a history of severely cutting fees post-referendum. For example, Illini Media was granted $3.00/semester in last Spring's vote, but SFAC cut that to $1.85/semester.

TLDR; 1) Approve the new, reformed Constitution for the student government, 2) move the student government to a funding system subject to review and periodic renewal by the students. a number of senators are idiots then. The original amendment was going to be "Do you approve of the reorganization and existence of the student government through...".  They wanted a direct mandate from the students (Since the current form of ISS sucks...)  One senator was worried that if it was rejected it would mean a dismantling of the senate and gutted the language.   I stand by my statement. Nothing personal against them though; they are probably good at other things. The original amendment was going to be "Do you approve of the reorganization and existence of the student government through...".  They wanted a direct mandate from the students (Since the current form of ISS sucks...)  One senator was worried that if it was rejected it would mean a dismantling of the senate and gutted the language.   For reference, the original question was:

"Should the Constitution and Transition Document of the Student Government of the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign be ratified  as unanimously recommended by Commission on Constitutional Reform and as approved by two-thirds vote of the Illinois Student Senate?" The ORIGINAL question doesn't matter, burntglass. The only thing that matters is the final version of the referendum question. Why are you confusing people?  1. The Illinois Student Senate created a special commission in the Fall to look into ways of improving the ISS Constitution (e.g. to make the student government more effective and representative). This question asks the Student Body to approve the commission's draft as adopted by ISS - as a referendum vote is the only way to change the student government Constitution. (I agree that the wording is terrible, but a number of senators were dead set that it appear this way.)
2. The ISS is currently funded by the University's Office of Student Affairs, from general student fee money. The second question aims to replace this money with a direct student fee. This is intended to make the student government directly accountable to students and open up it's funding to review by the Student Fee Advisory Committee in the same way fees for McKinley, Krannert, and Assembly Hall are reviewed and require renewal periodically by referenda vote. At $1.00/semester, this would account for slightly less than a doubling of the ISS's funding, iirc. While this seems a bit extreme, the fee would require approval by SFAC, who have a history of severely cutting fees post-referendum. For example, Illini Media was granted $3.00/semester in last Spring's vote, but SFAC cut that to $1.85/semester.

TLDR; 1) Approve the new, reformed Constitution for the student government, 2) move the student government to a funding system subject to review and periodic renewal by the students. This still doesn't answer NV's question on item 1: "What does that even mean?"
How ~~do~~ will we know what's in that new constitution? </snippet></document><document><title>Wendy's Is Open!</title><url>http://www.facebook.com/events/108287612686395/</url><snippet>  Okay, Wendy's is a pretty good fast food restaurant. Much better than McDonald's or Burger King. But I don't understand. It's not a place that I'd wait in line out the door for.  Seriously, Mor, I don't understand it either. It's my go-to when I'm running low on the budget at the end of the month, but otherwise... what's the big deal? Most students on campus are constantly in that "low budget at the end of the month" range Seriously, Mor, I don't understand it either. It's my go-to when I'm running low on the budget at the end of the month, but otherwise... what's the big deal? Its more the fact that we finally have a good fast food place within walking distance. That and Wendys is fucking delicious. I went for the experience and my first fast food in over 2 months. 

Also, due to some cashier error, they gave me my meal for free so it was worth it (yes, I did tell them I didn't pay yet and they told me to just go ahead anyway, I didn't just steal food.)   Any free food for opening day/week? Any free food for opening day/week? for those standing in line the manager was doing a guess a number between 1-100. the first person to guess won whatever she was holding. mostly frosties and those ice coffee things  Can anyone explain what's the big deal? Never tried it. Can anyone explain what's the big deal? Never tried it. Can anyone explain what's the big deal? Never tried it. For me at least, it's b/c this one is the first wendys/mcdonalds/burger king/five guys/steak and shake to open in campustown Oh wow. Back in my dad we had McDonald's, Burger King, and Wendy's. Can anyone explain what's the big deal? Never tried it. [deleted]   Got a frosty and a double stack x crispy chicken ("McGangBang"), waited in line from about 11:10 to 11:25, once I orded I got my food pretty quick.

Asked for dine in, but they gave me a takeout bag with no napkins in it. God damn burger got mustard and ketchup all over my hands and frosty.
Pretty nice wendys, itll be better in a week once the staff is more used to the work. Theyve also got one of those Coke machines that let you choose from 100s of different flavor combinations which is pretty  cool Yup, I had the same problem, no napkins. The manager was looking over the shoulder of some of the ordering staff, so I guess most of them are still being trained. Definitely potential though.  Yup, I had the same problem, no napkins. The manager was looking over the shoulder of some of the ordering staff, so I guess most of them are still being trained. Definitely potential though.  You guys realize there were napkin dispensers right by the straws and drink covers, right? Yup, I had the same problem, no napkins. The manager was looking over the shoulder of some of the ordering staff, so I guess most of them are still being trained. Definitely potential though.  &amp;gt; I guess most of them are still being trained. 

Considering the restaurant just opened, that's a fairly safe bet.  I thought fast food chains were banned from campus/campustown? You're getting downvoted, but maybe the younger posters here don't remember when there used to be two McDonalds, a Wendys, and a Burger King on campus until the University forced them out during that anti-fast food craze in the late 90s/early 2000s. You're getting downvoted, but maybe the younger posters here don't remember when there used to be two McDonalds, a Wendys, and a Burger King on campus until the University forced them out during that anti-fast food craze in the late 90s/early 2000s. seriously we just got rid of the fast food and now it came back You're getting downvoted, but maybe the younger posters here don't remember when there used to be two McDonalds, a Wendys, and a Burger King on campus until the University forced them out during that anti-fast food craze in the late 90s/early 2000s. &amp;gt;Reports that McDonald's Corp. is planning to open two restaurant outlets on the University of Illinois campus in Chicago, Illinois.

 Oops. Well, regardless, there was one in the Union basement and one on Green Street. Oops. Well, regardless, there was one in the Union basement and one on Green Street. &amp;gt;Reports that McDonald's Corp. is planning to open two restaurant outlets on the University of Illinois campus in Chicago, Illinois.

 I thought fast food chains were banned from campus/campustown? subway, jummy john's, chipotle... In combo with thatoneguy's post, they certainly have a different menu and far less locations(well JJ and Chipotle) then the burger joints. Subway is currently ranked with the most locations in the world. subway, jummy john's, chipotle...     I might get down voted for this but I don't care... Wendy's.</snippet></document><document><title>Saddened by the loss of the Guiness toucan in the Murphys basement, my friend decided to improvise.</title><url>http://imgur.com/a/kfeW9</url><snippet /></document><document><title>Anyone selling or know of anyone selling a Loaded Vanguard longboard on campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18dbqc/anyone_selling_or_know_of_anyone_selling_a_loaded/</url><snippet>I need a longboard (preferably a Vanguard) for a project I'll be doing soon, and wanted to see what my options were for buying.  Thanks all!</snippet></document><document><title>After a good week, we managed to get a few Top 25 votes, and are 26th in the RPI</title><url>http://espn.go.com/mens-college-basketball/rankings</url><snippet>   Our RPI is helped by the [5th hardest schedule](http://espn.go.com/mens-college-basketball/rpi/_/sort/sos).</snippet></document><document><title>Quick question: If anyone is in ECE 206 could you please help me out because I'm an idiot?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18busf/quick_question_if_anyone_is_in_ece_206_could_you/</url><snippet>I forgot to write down the correct answers for pre-lab 2 that were given in lab after we turned the pre-lab in. I need those answers to do the post-lab and want to make sure I use the correct values. If you have the answers for Pre-Lab 2 (the one we turned in last week involving the thevenin and norton circuits) could you please share?  Va0  7.5
Vb0  4.44
Vc0 4.59
Vd0 .417
i1 .0756
i33 .882
i3 -.465
i8 .541
i11 .417
 Cleaned it up for clarity's sake (space twice then enter to create a new line):  
Va0  7.5  
Vb0  4.44  
Vc0 4.59  
Vd0 .417  
i1 .0756  
i33 .882  
i3 -.465  
i8 .541  
i11 .417   Cleaned it up for clarity's sake (space twice then enter to create a new line):  
Va0  7.5  
Vb0  4.44  
Vc0 4.59  
Vd0 .417  
i1 .0756  
i33 .882  
i3 -.465  
i8 .541  
i11 .417   I'm looking at my lab data right now, and shouldn't all those current values be in some SI form of amps, milli or micro? I'm looking at my data now, and it looks like all of the voltages are in Volts (V), and all of the currents are in milliAmps (mA). Va0  7.5
Vb0  4.44
Vc0 4.59
Vd0 .417
i1 .0756
i33 .882
i3 -.465
i8 .541
i11 .417
</snippet></document><document><title>Illinois men's basketball beats Minnesota (ranked 18th) 57-54, and improves to 4-7 in the Big 10!</title><url>http://scores.espn.go.com/ncb/boxscore?gameId=330410135</url><snippet>  Abrams 3 at the end was so nasty I felt defiled all the way in Champaign  "ugh why did you shoot that"  "OMG YES!"  "I still cant believe you shot that"  We now have the most wins against ranked teams in the country. Whered you figure that from?    Next 3 games are pretty manageable too.  Hopefully there won't be a letdown. We'd better beat Purdue -.- Or Notherwestern.  Tyler and Tracy are my new favorite people ever.   </snippet></document><document><title>Should the ISS Consider the Nuclear-Capable Iran Resolution? </title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18b7ye/should_the_iss_consider_the_nuclearcapable_iran/</url><snippet>The Illinois Student Senate decided not to take up a resolution at its meeting on a nuclear-capable Iran because it felt it was not a pertinent student/campus issue. Others feel that the Senate should field any topic brought to them by students. What should the Senate do?

[daily illini](http://www.dailyillini.com/opinion/letters_to_editor/article_4838626e-7401-11e2-a010-0019bb30f31a.html)  It isn't a pertinent student/campus issue. They should ignore this crap and focus on relevant issues. It isn't a pertinent student/campus issue. They should ignore this crap and focus on relevant issues. It isn't a pertinent student/campus issue. They should ignore this crap and focus on relevant issues. Well obviously it's not an issue relating to the University of Illinois specifically. But there are Israeli students on campus along with students who have Israeli relatives (such as myself) who consider this to be a serious issue. If the ISS passes a resolution against a nuclear Iran, it WILL be brought to the Illinois State Senate, because we are the flagship university in this state. So, you admit it has nothing to do with the University and it's students, and in reality, is just a PR stunt to get the attention of the Illinois Senate.  :) Well obviously it's not an issue relating to the University of Illinois specifically. But there are Israeli students on campus along with students who have Israeli relatives (such as myself) who consider this to be a serious issue. If the ISS passes a resolution against a nuclear Iran, it WILL be brought to the Illinois State Senate, because we are the flagship university in this state. Well obviously it's not an issue relating to the University of Illinois specifically. But there are Israeli students on campus along with students who have Israeli relatives (such as myself) who consider this to be a serious issue. If the ISS passes a resolution against a nuclear Iran, it WILL be brought to the Illinois State Senate, because we are the flagship university in this state.  We have United States senators we elect to concern themselves with these issues. We have the ISS to deal with campus issues.  That depends, how many hundreds of dollars worth of cupcakes will this cost us all?    ~~What confuses me is how the sponsors chose to introduce this resolution. Had they submitted it the Sunday before the meeting, it would have been placed on the agenda **automatically** and would have been referred to a committee like any other resolution. Instead they decided to amend the agenda after the meeting began, forcing this awkward confrontation and the failed vote. I don't understand their thinking...~~

That being said, I have to side with the Treasurer on this one. If a student group wants the ISS's help to lobby their Congressional representatives, then that's fine - that's part of why ISS exists. But ISS shouldn't act as a means to condemn things "as the Official Voice of the Student Body", especially on issues where they lack the perspective to make a truly informed choice.

**Update:** I was contacted by a source close to the matter shortly after posting. According to this source, the resolution was submitted prior to the Sunday deadline, but was not added to the agenda. After contacting another source close to the agenda setting process, I was informed that the submitted resolution lacked a sponsor, precluding its consideration and thus addition to the agenda. I'm not really sure what to conclude from all this, but that's the update. I've stricken the first paragraph of this post to mark the error, but I think it's still worth reading if you're interested in submitting a resolution to ISS at some future date. [deleted]   This is crap. Disband them immediately. CBoidy, I agree with you! How can the ISS exist if their constituents dont WANT them to exist? To be fair this comment was sarcastic. It would be by and large a waste of time to cover the topic.

That said, I still think they should be disbanded in favor of a more representative system. Though I cannot speak to the mechanism that would be at work in such a system. In order to be more representative, people have to care. How many students even know that ISS exists, let alone what it does?    There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? By that logic, we should be condemning numerous countries because of their human rights issues, including Israel. We can't just pick and choose which countries to publicly condemn, especially if the whole student body does not agree with it.  ISS is a representative government, not a direct democracy.  In a representative government, the leaders decide what is best.   There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue? I don't understand you. You seem to care a lot about the [Civic Leadership Program](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1479pj/the_unfortunate_restructuring_of_the_civic/), but don't say anything positive about the Senate even though they are trying to tackle this issue. Instead you try to convince people that the [Senate is wasting time and money](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/182ely/iss_last_night_300_for_cupcakes_1775_for/) on other things without giving any details. After complaining about the Senate wasting time and money, you then insist that they should go through with a meaningless gesture that could not ever possibly result in meaningful policy change. Your priorities don't make any sense and all you seem to do is hate on the Senate no matter what they are trying to do.

Who do you work for? This post currently has *four* reports.

Someone's mad.

(And no, I'm not going to remove a well reasoned post by an active member of the community that's not violating any rules. Even if you click that report button a million times.) I don't understand you. You seem to care a lot about the [Civic Leadership Program](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1479pj/the_unfortunate_restructuring_of_the_civic/), but don't say anything positive about the Senate even though they are trying to tackle this issue. Instead you try to convince people that the [Senate is wasting time and money](http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/182ely/iss_last_night_300_for_cupcakes_1775_for/) on other things without giving any details. After complaining about the Senate wasting time and money, you then insist that they should go through with a meaningless gesture that could not ever possibly result in meaningful policy change. Your priorities don't make any sense and all you seem to do is hate on the Senate no matter what they are trying to do.

Who do you work for? I'm not surprised that ChairYeoman is defending the Student Senate as the ISS is paying him $1000+ to be the "webmaster" according to his flair.

It is important to understand what the original intent was of the ISS as we discuss its relevance today...10+ years ago the only purpose of the ISS was to lobby the academic/faculty senate on issues relating to the academic/university issues. There USED to be a "Illinois Student Government" which pretended they were government officials. The ISS of today is acting more like the ISG of yesterday, squandering thousands of dollars of senate dollars acquired through mandatory student fees and tuition.

We need to go back to the basics. The civic leadership situation is a prime example on how the ISS can genuinely serve a purpose... Unless of course if you'd rather aspire to keep the ISS around that is spending thousands on cupcakes, toys, and typos... There are Israeli students whose homes and families are affected by a nuclear Iran.  There are Iranian students who are affected by the Iranian regime and its human rights record.  Why shouldn't the ISS tackle this issue?</snippet></document><document><title>Help Support a New All-Ages Venue &amp;amp; Record Shop</title><url>http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/error-records-all-ages-music-venue?c=home</url><snippet>  this town is desperately lacking a steady AA venue since the courtyard cafe stopped having shows. I urge people to contribute to this if they have an interest in fostering young people's interest in music [and ultimately, they start making it on their own] It also looks like it will be a nice practice venue. It'll be nice to have an all ages venue that isn't someone's basement.  Although, when Error was a basement show place, it was also fantastic. the house that was later Aykroyd's / Terror?? the first house shows I ever went to and played at were in that basement. fucking love that place.   I know I probably won't go to the shows, but the Record Shop portion has me very interested.  we got plenty of hipsters on campus im sure you could raise 3 grand if you publicize this more campus hipsters generally don't really give a fuck about stuff like this</snippet></document><document><title>TIL that in 1996 students at UIUC played a pivotal role in bringing South Park to life by sharing the creators' short film "Jesus vs. Santa" with the internet (audio, skip to ~5:30)</title><url>http://www.onthemedia.org/2013/feb/08/viral-videos-patient-zero/</url><snippet>  Bah, beat me by 19 seconds lol.  The whole thing is a great listen! WBEZ listener as well? I am indeed! WBEZ listener as well? What's the station for WBEZ down here?  It used to be at www.killfile.org/soxmas, but looks like Skirv recently updated his site... he mentions it here: http://wiki.killfile.org/projects/soxmas/   It's probably still on the servers there.  Look for "soxmas.mpg"  i myself forwarded that video probably 15 or 20 times.....

edit....looks like I've forgotten the timeline for video formats... it was "soxmas.mov" Hahaha - it is still here!!  

**[Wrong One - see the comment below by never-rong!]**

http://www.ks.uiuc.edu/~tskirvin/soxmas/so-frosty.mov

The account belongs to Tim Skirvin who I believe used to run the local usenet-server after the UIUC shut down the local uiuc.edu newsserver.  :)  It's about 4 minutes long and really bad video quality, unfortunately.  But still funny.

Edit- UH.. it appears that Tim Skirvin was the first to put it online at UIUC!  ha! :)  I think someone should get some sort of compensation... maybe 10% finders fee from comedy central?  ;) You linked the wrong one......the **ORIGINAL**, however is in that directory as well....

http://www.ks.uiuc.edu/~tskirvin/soxmas/soxmas.mov

At the time 50mb was *HUGE* file to move around.  Lots of people outside the dorms had *dialup*, so that took a long time to download and a lot of effort to keep your housemates off the phone long enough. Hahaha - it is still here!!  

**[Wrong One - see the comment below by never-rong!]**

http://www.ks.uiuc.edu/~tskirvin/soxmas/so-frosty.mov

The account belongs to Tim Skirvin who I believe used to run the local usenet-server after the UIUC shut down the local uiuc.edu newsserver.  :)  It's about 4 minutes long and really bad video quality, unfortunately.  But still funny.

Edit- UH.. it appears that Tim Skirvin was the first to put it online at UIUC!  ha! :)  I think someone should get some sort of compensation... maybe 10% finders fee from comedy central?  ;) Yep!  I've got a friend who was in the room when Tim did it.  I was one of the first to download the file, and still have it on an old Mac in my basement. :) </snippet></document><document><title>Isshin-Ryu Karate classes at the Savoy Recreation Center</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18amrk/isshinryu_karate_classes_at_the_savoy_recreation/</url><snippet>A new session of Isshin-Ryu Karate classes are starting at the Savoy Recreation Center. Classes are Tuesdays 6:45 - 8:45pm. Details are at the [Savoy Rec. website](http://savoyrecreationcenter.com) The program says that class takes students 12 - adult, but I will take 10 - adult.

Develop street awareness, practical self-defense, coordination, situational alertness, and also overall strength and fitness. This class will focus on traditional Okinawan karate using both empty hand and weapons applied to practical self defense.

Isshinryu Karate was created by Shimabuku, Tatsuo Sensei and contains elements of Shorin-ryu ,Goju-ryu and Kobudo. Shimabuku included influences from his primary instructors; Chotoku Kyan, Chojun Miyagi, Choki Motobu, and Tiara Shinkin; to create a system which features natural stances and the vertical fist punch.   Who's running this? I practiced Isshin-Ryu for 12 years before college.  I teach the class. My name is Neil Thackeray, and I'm a third generation Isshin-Ryu practitioner. I've been studying for over 25 years now. My sensei is John Kerker Sensei who studied under Sherman Harrill Sensei who studied under Shimabuku Tatsuo Sensei. I'm glad my lineage doesn't go back any further than that I studied under Patrick Doherty, who also studied under Harill. I met Harill once, hell of a guy. </snippet></document><document><title>helicopter tour?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/18a6hk/helicopter_tour/</url><snippet>where i can find a helicopter tour? going to graduate soon, want to have a helicopter tour...  Fake an emergency - Carle will give you a helicopter ride to their trauma center.  Who pays for the ride? Him or his insurance?  The flight school has open-house days where they will give you a tour of campus from the air in one of their planes. It's a lot of fun and not very expensive. It's on a Saturday towards the end of the semester (better weather, senior flight students wanna have some fun), I think around Moms' Weekend. Are you sure they still do this? With the Institute of Aviation [closing](http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2011-07-22/news/ct-met-aviation0722-20110722_1_aviation-program-aviation-students-university-of-illinois-trustees) at the end of the 2013-2014 school year, I'd be a bit surprised if they still have an open house.  Construct your own hot air balloon. 0% chance of disaster.  I've never heard of such a thing around here.

However, if there is, sign me up! :D I don't know...all you'd see are cornfields. I don't know...all you'd see are cornfields. Have you ever rode in a helicopter? It's indescribably fun.   </snippet></document><document><title>Valentines day restaurants</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/1895gq/valentines_day_restaurants/</url><snippet>Does anyone know any nice restaurant around the area?   bacaro, Big Grove Tavern, Destihl...I would say luna but I think they closed...there are more that I'm sure I'm forgetting, though! Luna closed?? Nooooooo It is according to Yelp! Which is disappointing considering I never got to go there... They had such good food, and such a cool atmosphere... sigh. I guess 'tis better to have loved and lost, than never to have loved at all.   [Escobar's](http://www.escobarsrestaurant.com/Welcome.html) is really nice and high quality stuff. I always recommend that place.  [Escobar's](http://www.escobarsrestaurant.com/Welcome.html) is really nice and high quality stuff. I always recommend that place.  [Escobar's](http://www.escobarsrestaurant.com/Welcome.html) is really nice and high quality stuff. I always recommend that place.  The place is ok, definitely nothing to write home about.  I had the roasted duck breast with a fig glaze that was mediocre at best.  I hear this place has better lunch options, but I would honestly recommend somewhere like The Great Impasta if you are looking to take your girl to dinner. What's so special about The Great Impasta? It's just pasta. The place is ok, definitely nothing to write home about.  I had the roasted duck breast with a fig glaze that was mediocre at best.  I hear this place has better lunch options, but I would honestly recommend somewhere like The Great Impasta if you are looking to take your girl to dinner.  Fat sandwich is a very warm and hospitable place (Especially around 1-2 am), and the food is extremely wellmade and healthy. r/uiuc does not like sarcasm. Please go home.

Edit: At the time I posted this, he had a negative score. So this was more directed at the people downvoting him for using humor, and not because I was angry with him or anything. I chuckled at the suggestion of Fat Sandwich on V-Day.  The Bread Company is wonderful restaurant with a nice atmosphere. It's in between Canopy Club and Espresso Royal on Goodwin.  Do they take reservations?  Also: Milo's, the Great Impasta. But mostly Bacaro.   Bacaro is insanely expensive though.       </snippet></document><document><title>Where can I find a good box of chocolates for valentine's day on campus?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/189kxa/where_can_i_find_a_good_box_of_chocolates_for/</url><snippet>  There's a Fannie Mays on neil and green.  Springfield and Neil*
I'm in my car at Neil and green right now.   Best chocolates are off campus. There is two places at Lincoln Square Mall that sell chocolates right now (If you take the Silver or the Gold, they end up at Lincoln Square.) Look for Art Mart. Art Mart has amazing truffles that are made locally (I think). Quite expensive though They used to sell locally made ones. I'm not sure they do anymore. The other place in the mall is now the reseller of the local ones, but I can't remember what it is called... Art Mart has amazing truffles that are made locally (I think). Quite expensive though Yes, I was there this weekend. $54/lb. Best chocolates are off campus. There is two places at Lincoln Square Mall that sell chocolates right now (If you take the Silver or the Gold, they end up at Lincoln Square.) Look for Art Mart.   World Harvest on university and sixth has a really good selection of exotic chocolate bars. You could get a few different favors to try together :)   </snippet></document><document><title>owl city tickets at canopy</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/189gkh/owl_city_tickets_at_canopy/</url><snippet>Hi r/UIUC, I am looking to sell 2 owl city tickets for tonight, had some last minute emergency. Honestly I just don't them to go to waste, tickets were $25 when I bought it, prices negotiable. Please PM me. </snippet></document><document><title>Good places to hold small meetings?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/189b4z/good_places_to_hold_small_meetings/</url><snippet>What are some good places around campus to hold meetings with say 6-7 people? Specifically the southern end of campus or near the Ike. 

How do I go about getting a room with a TV or monitor or projector on reserve or do I need to? 

Thanks!  You can actually reserve rooms in SDRP (ie conference rooms, seminar rooms, etc.). http://space.housing.illinois.edu/virtualems/ You can actually reserve rooms in SDRP (ie conference rooms, seminar rooms, etc.). http://space.housing.illinois.edu/virtualems/     </snippet></document><document><title>Saw this on the front page of nbcnews.com, any more info about what they're talking about</title><url>http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/02/09/16913843-porn-star-teaches-sex-seminar-at-the-university-of-illinois?lite</url><snippet>      I guess this isn't as hardcore as the weather underground dude that was in residence there   Here's part one of two of an interview with [Annie Sprinkle](http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N16fxWQNNKk). She sounds like an interesting woman.    The topics covered in there is mutually exclusive with people on Reddit. If you're reading this, your sexual release tonight is only possible because you aren't an amputee missing hands.    I wonder how much money Allen wasted on that.  Seems like the ISS isn't the only group pissing away our tuition dollars. Allen isn't spending tuition money on this. When you apply to live in Unit One, you pay extra and that money goes into things like this. And I'm pretty sure the Guests-in-Residence aren't paid to come speak, so really what you're paying for is their food, because they live in the dorm. Maybe you end up paying for their travel too.  Allen isn't spending tuition money on this. When you apply to live in Unit One, you pay extra and that money goes into things like this. And I'm pretty sure the Guests-in-Residence aren't paid to come speak, so really what you're paying for is their food, because they live in the dorm. Maybe you end up paying for their travel too.  I wonder how much money Allen wasted on that.  Seems like the ISS isn't the only group pissing away our tuition dollars. It wasn't paid for with general campus tuition money. And even if it was, I would consider it a worth while expenditure. Her talks were interesting and educational and anyone was invited to join. Learning in college doesn't have to be strictly academic.  Promoting sex-positivity is one thing, but inviting her seems to glorify pornography and prostitution.</snippet></document><document><title>The radio call of the win against #1 Indiana!</title><url>https://soundcloud.com/airchecked/illini-win</url><snippet> </snippet></document><document><title>Need something fun to do tomorrow? Check out the local flea market!</title><url>http://www.gordyvilleusa.com/flea-market/</url><snippet>  I went today, it was awesome! Let me know if anyone has questions about what was there, etc.  Baseball cards or memorabilia by any chance? Yeah, definitely saw a few people with some baseball cards, but it was mainly some old packs still wrapped...  Where is it exactly? The link isn't working. What kind of items were they selling? I went today, it was awesome! Let me know if anyone has questions about what was there, etc.  Any watches or clocks? 

 </snippet></document><document><title>What are you all paying for internet &amp;amp; TV?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/187k42/what_are_you_all_paying_for_internet_tv/</url><snippet>Anybody want to compare prices? You can negotiate better with Comcast if you know someone with a better deal. I have Comcast TV (digital preferred package) and "Performance" internet. At first I paid $80/month but now the bill is up to $110 (just called and that's the best they can do). 

My last resort is to cancel and have roommate sign up as a new customer again.

I considered U-Verse but they don't offer TV.   Uc2b Internet for 40/mo for 40mbps up and down. Then directv with dvr for 50/mo My house is already set up for directv (or so they keep telling me with their junk mail) but I hesitate to sign a 2 yr contract...  I've loved it so far. I only lose service in heavy storms and it happens less often than you would think. There's maybe only 3 or 4 times in the past year it has happened. If you sign up, lemme know, I'll send you my account number and we can save 10/mo each for 10 months. My first year was only like 30/mo because of referrals!  Hey, I'd be interested, but my main concern is the heavy load that I'd probably pull.  Do they have any limits on usage that they don't exactly advertise?  Or maybe not very torrent friendly?  I've uploaded over a TB to Bitcasa in the last week and it's still running.  I typically use newsgroups instead of torrents so I have no idea how they are with torrents.    I get ATT U-Verse 18Mbps for $40 a month, split with the neighbors, so $20, split with the roommates, so $6.67.

And unlimited TV and movies b/c piracy. Yup.  $40/month for [limited basic cable](http://customer.comcast.com/help-and-support/cable-tv/difference-between-limited-basic-and-expanded-basic-cable) and [internet](http://www.speedtest.net/result/2497949925.png). We got in on this deal when we moved in to our apartment last year, and Comcast let us transfer it to our new house. It's pretty great, since most of our TV-watching is via torrents &amp;amp; Netflix/Hulu/Crackle. Whoa... I'm on limited basic tv + the "Performance" Internet package (~20mbps) on Comcast and pay $73/mo! It started at $50/mo when I moved here in 2010, but it's steadily increased each year. I called last year to try and lower it, but the most they'd offer was $5 off for 6 months. How did you get such a great deal? Whoa... I'm on limited basic tv + the "Performance" Internet package (~20mbps) on Comcast and pay $73/mo! It started at $50/mo when I moved here in 2010, but it's steadily increased each year. I called last year to try and lower it, but the most they'd offer was $5 off for 6 months. How did you get such a great deal? I have a similar deal;  My bill is something like 34 dollars a month.  Try going into the Comcast office in Urbana.  I went in specifically and told them I wanted to add basic cable to lower my bill, and the woman said she would help me out.  My first bill after was $7, then $15, then up to $34.  Her name is Felicia, I believe.  Felicia is the shit. I have a similar deal;  My bill is something like 34 dollars a month.  Try going into the Comcast office in Urbana.  I went in specifically and told them I wanted to add basic cable to lower my bill, and the woman said she would help me out.  My first bill after was $7, then $15, then up to $34.  Her name is Felicia, I believe.  Felicia is the shit. So you're paying $34 for internet + expanded basic? What did you tell them when you went in to their office? $40/month for [limited basic cable](http://customer.comcast.com/help-and-support/cable-tv/difference-between-limited-basic-and-expanded-basic-cable) and [internet](http://www.speedtest.net/result/2497949925.png). We got in on this deal when we moved in to our apartment last year, and Comcast let us transfer it to our new house. It's pretty great, since most of our TV-watching is via torrents &amp;amp; Netflix/Hulu/Crackle. If I wanted to go as low as basic cable I'd probably just buy an HD antenna and cancel cable altogether. I believe AT&amp;amp;T U-Verse internet is $20/month but not sure about the speed. $40/month for [limited basic cable](http://customer.comcast.com/help-and-support/cable-tv/difference-between-limited-basic-and-expanded-basic-cable) and [internet](http://www.speedtest.net/result/2497949925.png). We got in on this deal when we moved in to our apartment last year, and Comcast let us transfer it to our new house. It's pretty great, since most of our TV-watching is via torrents &amp;amp; Netflix/Hulu/Crackle. May I ask which area you live in? I'm going to try to talk to the sales rep but it's be more convincing in saying "I know someone who lives in this area and got this deal. Gimme!" :)  If you search the internet a bit, you would discover that comcast loves, just loves charging random amounts of money for the same service. The trick is to find the lowest number in the below answers, then go the comcast office physicially (it is located near Urbana high school on race street). Wait in line, talk to the Comcast person [be extremely polite]: "I am a very poor student/unemployed/etc and I really like comcast services because they wonderful, but they cost too much. It turns out I can pay only $&amp;lt;insert amount&amp;gt; for similar services from X. Could you please reduce my bill somehow? Otherwise, I would have to change service provider."

And thats it - they would be happy to give you a better "limited time" deal. I know because I did it recently, and I am neither a student nor poor. You might have to repeat it after a year or so - their deals are always limited. Also, if you connected somebody else for a year, and reconnect to them, they would consider your a new customer, and give you a good deal. 

Also, if you are in the right area, uc2b is probably the future. I am sure going to dance with happiness when they are able to connect to my neighberhood/home. http://uc2b.net/ Thanks, I know Comcast is super random with their pricing. I even gave them a factual example of what my friend is paying, but they were pretty firm saying that's "as low as they can go." 

I had even less luck over the chat service, and so I had to call retentions on the phone.  $93/month for Comcast Digital Starter w/ HBO &amp;amp; Showtime, Performance Internet, HD service fee, and modem rental Nice! Are you a new customer? Or how did you get that deal?    I got on the 69$ internet, TV, free HBO and Showtime for 1 year deal at the beginning of the school year from Comcast. Ive got my own modem, no hd box though. 

I would split internet with my neighbors but I have none.... Did you go to Best Buy or something? Or just walked in to the Comcast office?    As always when the conversation turns to entertainment on reddit, I want to reap downvotes by pointing out that I kind of hope all of the freeloading torrenters get caught and sued. 

I have AT&amp;amp;T U-Verse Internet and TV. I think we pay around $125, but we have higher speed internet and a bigger channel subscription with HBO.  I really dont understand why cable TV is still a thing. Why do you need it if you have the internet? I want to watch my favorite shows the same time as everyone else to avoid spoilers. And live streams online suck... unless you know some secret I don't. &amp;gt; And live streams online suck... unless you know some secret I don't.

it's called torrents But then I can't watch it when it's really "on" :( Typically all the shows i want to watch are online 30mins to an hour after they air. Full HD if I torrent, and decent streams. Also, ive gotten so used to not being bombarded by ads that watching TV just makes me feel really dumb.  I really dont understand why cable TV is still a thing. Why do you need it if you have the internet?  I'm paying fuck you, that's what.  I'm at One South, so [I pay $0.](http://i238.photobucket.com/albums/ff200/stevedinsd/frog.gif) But then again you live at One South. 
http://i.imgur.com/q4jwscn.gif But then again you live at One South. 
http://i.imgur.com/q4jwscn.gif</snippet></document><document><title>Hiking spots?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/187bbl/hiking_spots/</url><snippet>I've been thinking about going hiking in the spring time, and I looked up some hiking spots online but the pics all seem to be blurry/from the 1800's so I was wondering if any of you could recommend a hiking spot for the spring! Thanks!  If you want to drive an hour Turkey Run over the Indiana border is great.  For places closer, Allerton is my favorite.   Any good places to hike/walk nearby  for those without cars? Any good places to hike/walk nearby  for those without cars?  We do live in quite the shitty area for outdoor activities, but all is not lost. Could you give a better idea of what you're looking for? Day hikes (so 3 to 10 miles) or more backpacking (multiple days with camping)? Do you have a car to travel in? How far are you willing to drive? Have a car, willing to travel up to 2 hours, looking for a day hike spot since my camping gear is nonexistent.  Let me throw out a couple locations for you to try out.

The best area close by is [Kickapoo State Park](http://dnr.state.il.us/lands/Landmgt/PARKS/R3/kickapoo.htm), [Kennekuk County Park](http://www.vccd.org/gikennekuk.html), and Middle Fork State Fish and Wildlife Area. They are all part of a river system that was bought up in the 1960s with the intention of flooding it all to turn into a lake. There was a ton of push back from environmental groups, so it just ended up getting split up into these three parks, as no one agency could afford to run the whole thing. 

Kickapoo - This is a cool area that is a reclamed strip mining site from the early 20th century. There are tons of small lakes that you can rent canoes on and paddles through some really clear water. They also can drop you up a few miles with canoes and tubes on a river that runs the length of all the parks. It's a nice park, but the busiest of the three. There are lots of small hiking trails here and it' worth checking out. There is also a frisbee golf course here.

Kennekuk County Park - This one has one big lake that has about a 7 mile loop that goes around it. It's a really nice hike that goes up and down through forests and parries, and with it being that long without many entrances, it's a good opportunity to get away and not have to see many people for a couple hourse. There are a few picnic tables and benches along the way so take a lunch. There are also mile markers so you know exactly how far you have to go.

Middle Fork Fish and Wildlife Area - This place has 35 miles of hiking trails looping through forests and grassland. Tons of day hikes available here, it's the farthest from CU at about 35 minute drive. You can get to Kickapoo in 25 minutes.


There are other things around, Lake Shelbyville is a little over and hour south. Clinton Lake has a nuclear reactor on it, and if you're looking for something really cool to do right now, get there in the early morning when the sun is just coming up. The lake is heated by the reactor, so there are fish flying all over catching insects that can still survive through winter, they dive through the steam rising off the water, it's a beautiful sight. There's also Turkey Run State Park over in Indiana, and Shades State Park in Indiana also, those are about 1.5 hours. Homer lake is alright, and probably the closest, it's 10 miles east of town and has about 20 miles of hiking trails.

Let me know if you have any specific questions. That kind of turned into a general natural area tour of the area. I was feeling a bit confined when I first moved here as I like being outside a lot, and while people bitch that there isn't anything to do around here, you just have to look a little harder. If you get sick of the local stuff, Shawnee National Forest and Hoosier National Forest are each 3 hour drive in different directions. Both are amazing and you should definitely see before leaving the area. Have a car, willing to travel up to 2 hours, looking for a day hike spot since my camping gear is nonexistent.   Hey man i'm really into hiking and backpacking, I just transferred here and I've been looking around for places to hike.

From what I've read, there's not too many hilly areas to hike in - although there are nice trails, some of which are dense, and lakes/rivers that are all connected to go canoeing through.

check out kickapoo state park
http://dnr.state.il.us/lands/Landmgt/PARKS/R3/kickapoo.htm


I'm currently looking for a student organization that hosts events to go hiking/backpacking - but so far, no luck :\.

If you come across one shoot me a PM.


P.S. I think there could be a group at UIUC that is strictly about geocaching too, that could be fun.        You do realize where you live right?  Somewhere in this orange square, roughly. http://dnr.state.il.us/lands/landmgt/programs/hiking/region3.htm Somewhere in this orange square, roughly. http://dnr.state.il.us/lands/landmgt/programs/hiking/region3.htm oh i thought you were looking for spots in the CU area.  [Meadowbrook Park](http://www.urbanaparks.org/facilities/16.html), [Crystal Lake Park](http://www.urbanaparks.org/facilities/11.html), [The Arboretum](http://arboretum.illinois.edu/), and [Carle Park](http://www.urbanaparks.org/facilities/8.html) are all within easy walking distance of campus and served by the bus routes. You're not going to find a mountain to hike in central Illinois, but it's not as boring as people think.

Within a 40 minute drive of campus there are a bunch of state parks and nature reserves with real hiking trails.</snippet></document><document><title>My phone got itself lost last night in Urbana: Reward if found!!!</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/187nkf/my_phone_got_itself_lost_last_night_in_urbana/</url><snippet>Hey r/UIUC, I lost my phone last night and am very upset about it and was hoping someone out there could please, please, please help! I'm sure it's super scared to be so far away from me...

I would have lost it somewhere around W. Elm and Busey in Urbana. 

It's a Samsung Galaxy S3. It's a black phone with a clear case. The lock screen is a picture of an adorable German shepherd sitting in the front seat of my car (it's a darker photograph). That sweet puppy would be so happy if you were able to get my phone back to me...

If found, please contact 815-444-1566. YOU WILL MOST DEFINITELY BE REWARDED FOR YOUR AWESOMENESS AND KINDNESS. And I will love you forever. 
  Do you know how to push apps? You could try pushing Plan B, Prey, or Lookout (free options, get you a rough estimate of where the phone is) or even Cerberus, which is $5, but comes with a pretty high powered set of tools for finding/controlling your phone.

Was it on? Was data turned on? Was the GPS turned on? What carrier are you using? Good point. [Where's My Droid](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.alienmanfc6.wheresmyandroid&amp;amp;hl=en) might work, too. Yep, there are any number of apps you could choose from. OK, I mean, my phone is already lost, and I didn't download those apps to it before it decided to get lost... so, can I still utilize any of those options?

Thanks again for all the responses. My phone may still be lost, but the help is making me feel a bit more hopeful. So, it's important that you answer a couple questions. Was it powered on? Was Mobile Data turned on? Was GPS turned on?

If your phone is on, and data is on, you can *remotely* install tracker apps, such as [this one.](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.androidlost&amp;amp;hl=en) Just log in to the same google account you used for the phone's setup, and click install. From there, follow the app's instructions to locate your phone.

Let me know if you get stuck anywhere. It was on, and I believe it's still on because when I call it, it still rings and doesn't go straight to voicemail. I think Mobile Data was turned on... and I'm not sure about GPS.

I guess I don't know how to push apps. I'm trying but it doesn't seem to be working. 

Tbh, the main problem I'm having is remembering the google account I created for the phone setup. I can't access it because I don't remember the username or password. Which is just dumb of me, I should have written it down somewhere, but didn't :( Here's a way to jolt your memory. Whenever you added a contact, it says the google account you're logged in under at the top. Do you remember what it was?

Also, do you have a gmail? Which email account did you read on your email app?

Here's how pushing works. It's really simple! So, go to this page: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.androidlost&amp;amp;feature=nav_result#?t=W251bGwsMSwyLDNd

and in the upper right corner, log in to your google account (that you definitely remember :) ), then click the little "INSTALL" button on the left next to the little droid guy. A "Checkout" dialog will pop up. Select your device from the dropdown menu (it'll be selected by default, assuming you don't have more than one android phone on this google account) then click "INSTALL" one more time.

The phone takes care of the rest! You'll receive emails about the phone to the email that you logged in with.

Also, for that particular app, here's a great tutorial about it: https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=gcTZbreowJM#! You are very thorough and helpful, thanks so much for trying. 

My parents freaked out about the phone being lost and just deactivated it. My very old phone is now reactivated (not a smart phone). 

So now I'm assuming nothing much can be done about finding it...

U.S. Cellular reported it as missing in their records. 

I will continue trying to remember my gmail account information, just because. That's a good trick to try to trigger it. 

Thank you again for all the help. I'm so sorry! I wish I could be more help, but I can't do much about that. I'm so sorry! I wish I could be more help, but I can't do much about that. Do you know how to push apps? You could try pushing Plan B, Prey, or Lookout (free options, get you a rough estimate of where the phone is) or even Cerberus, which is $5, but comes with a pretty high powered set of tools for finding/controlling your phone.

Was it on? Was data turned on? Was the GPS turned on? What carrier are you using? I've never heard of those options, but I will most definitely look into them.

It was on, and I called it a bunch of times and it rang, so I'm assuming it wasn't dead. I believe data was turned on. A few of the apps I used on it utilized GPS tracking, but I couldn't say for sure if it was permanently turned on. And I use U.S. Cellular.  Samsung has a tracking feature like iphone has find my iphone. granted it would of been helpful if you made a Samsung account but i'm sure if you have your product number you can still track it.  If you're referring to Samsung Dive, it's actually not supported for the S3. For some odd reason that I can't comprehend. I have the s3, idk if its Samsung drive but there is a feature on the s3 which lets you track it thru your samsung account What carrier? Cause mine turned it off (Verizon), which kinda sucks. Why would they turn it off? That's just stupid.  I have t mobile I have the s3, idk if its Samsung drive but there is a feature on the s3 which lets you track it thru your samsung account Samsung has a tracking feature like iphone has find my iphone. granted it would of been helpful if you made a Samsung account but i'm sure if you have your product number you can still track it.  Samsung has a tracking feature like iphone has find my iphone. granted it would of been helpful if you made a Samsung account but i'm sure if you have your product number you can still track it.  English, motherfucker!  Haven't seen it but I live around there so I'll keep an eye out and an ear open in case of anything coming up  I'll definitely keep an eye out. I hope you get your phone back!  So you're the one who put the sign on my apartment building. Sorry you lost it Yeah, I got desperate... I've never had a nice phone, and I've never lost anything expensive. It feels terrible. 

That's the building I was in last night, and if I dropped it or something, it would've been outside near that apartment complex... Thank you for your response! I lost a pair of ray bans once. I was so sad. I only had em for like 8 months too</snippet></document><document><title>"Healthy" restaurant choices in C-U?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/187yc7/healthy_restaurant_choices_in_cu/</url><snippet>I'm looking for some healthier places to go with my friend coming to town. She eats meat but prefers healthy food. I'm more of a burger and beer sort of person myself, so I'm not really sure what is available (on or off campus) with a healthier selection. Any suggestions?   probably not fat sandwhich   Big Grove Tavern (http://www.biggrovetavern.com/) could be considered "fresh" or "healthy" depending on her definition.  Their catch phrase is "Farm-to-table" and are located downtown Champaign.   Big Grove Tavern (http://www.biggrovetavern.com/) could be considered "fresh" or "healthy" depending on her definition.  Their catch phrase is "Farm-to-table" and are located downtown Champaign.     [Black Dog](http://www.facebook.com/BlackDogSmokeAndAleHouse) is a BBQ restaurant in Urbana that uses a lot of locally grown and raised products and prides themselves on that. It's a BBQ place so it's definitely possible to eat really unhealthy there, but you pick your own sides and the sauce comes on the side so it's also easy to eat healthy if you want to. As a bonus their beer menu is usually pretty good. Black Dog is my favorite restaurant in Champaign-Urbana, and is in the running for my favorite anywhere. But I don't see how you can call it healthy. I honestly can't think of one meal that you could put together on their menu that would be "healthy."

I'm going to go ahead and keep on eating there anyway. You can get a beef brisket or pull pork platter at black dog with a sweet potato and veggies as your side. They put the BBQ sauce on the side so you aren't forced to smother your food in sauce. There's nothing that unhealthy about it.

Ordering a pulled pork sandwich smothered in sauce with fries and pit beans on the side would be a way to make it unhealthy. Smoked meat is fairly unhealthy. Beef is fairly unhealthy. Pulled pork (pork shoulder or pork butt) is quite fatty and generally unhealthy. 

As far as BBQ goes, what you're describing is healthy. But BBQ is not healthy. 

I'm going to keep eating there, regardless. There's nothing unhealthy about beef or fatty meat, really. Saturated fat isn't bad for one's health. That's plain inaccurate. The exact nature of the link is somewhat unclear, but saturated fat is generally considered among medical authorities to be unhealthy. 

And, unlike the lack of clarity on saturated fat, there's absolutely no debate about the fact that beef is bad for you. And that smoked meats are bad for you. That's not even in debate. 

But hell, an accountant asserts otherwise. Smoking meats is a great way to add flavor without calories. I'd like to see you come up with a healthier way to cook chicken/turkey.

The sauces don't have to be unhealthy either. A pulled chicken platter with Carolina Vinegar (It's exactly what it sounds like. Apple Vinegar with dried ground peppers in it) would be a great way to go at Black Dog if you're tying to keep your caloric intake down. Pulled Pork and Beef Brisket is pretty awesome if you're concerned about protein though.

On the other hand, Ribs are TERRIBLE for you. 400 calories a piece and not much else. Yes, but the smoking process is also infusing the meat with carcinogens. That's plain inaccurate. The exact nature of the link is somewhat unclear, but saturated fat is generally considered among medical authorities to be unhealthy. 

And, unlike the lack of clarity on saturated fat, there's absolutely no debate about the fact that beef is bad for you. And that smoked meats are bad for you. That's not even in debate. 

But hell, an accountant asserts otherwise.    I watch what I eat, and my go-to places are Subway, Chipotle, and Ruby Tuesday's. There are usually good "healthy" options at most of the chain restaurants on Prospect too. Chipotle can definitely be healthy if you get the right item.

http://chipotless.com/</snippet></document><document><title>Is the top story of Beckman Institute open to undergrad students?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/187p14/is_the_top_story_of_beckman_institute_open_to/</url><snippet>If not, is anywhere else like the top floor in CSL accessible? I'm trying to get a good view of the new ECE building for a construction class.

Edit: thanks for the responses. Most people in this class are probably gonna observe this site too so I'll be taking ~50-60 mpixel panoramas to try to stand out. Will share if it looks decent.   The monitor in the main hallway of Everitt (as you go through the main doors and up the stairs, just outside room 151) has a live webcam feed of the construction of the new building. You can view this webcam from the ece website.    CEE 420? Yup.  </snippet></document><document><title>IU fan wakes up this morning to learn about the crushing defeat Illinois dealt out last night. Reacts accordingly. </title><url>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AFteLOCepZo</url><snippet>  Aw, it's a kid? I was hoping to rejoice at the tears of some hungover IU student.   I am a highschooler in S. Indiana planning to attend Illinois. This morning I put on my Illinois t-shirt without thinking. Bad call. A lot of people weren't very happy about that game...  Poor kid doesn't know how to lose gracefully like an Illini fan... At least in the last couple of years, he doesn't have as much practice as we have... At least in the last couple of years, he doesn't have as much practice as we have... Poor kid doesn't know how to lose gracefully like an Illini fan...  Are people supposed to cry this much, if at all, because of sports? Sports are the ONLY thing worth crying this much over.   I hope this is the only time I upvote a video of a young kid crying on Reddit.  Reminds me a lot of [a story from my own undergrad](http://imgur.com/qpV5hxl)... I love how at texas, no matter who you're playing, you do the "OU sucks" cheer. You mean the "It's $TIME and OU still sucks" one? I don't remember that really being the case, but I made a point of not going to games.         *Crushing*? http://endablog2.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/montoya.jpg Yes, as in it is emotionally crushing for Indiana fans. *Crushing*? http://endablog2.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/montoya.jpg #1 Indiana losing to unranked Illinois is crushing no matter how you look at it. 2 Point miracle or not. #1 teams should not lose to unranked teams. </snippet></document><document><title>Coach Groce celebrating with his son after last night's stomping of Indiana</title><url>https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/72652_10151429023821600_2111823186_n.jpg</url><snippet>  this is a great picture, but stomping might be an overstatement       Dude should still be fired.  This has been a terrible season. It's his first year. Yup, and the only way he is going to go is down.

Hiring a mediocre coach from the mid majors was a massive mistake. I think you're thinking of Beckman. 

Groce has brought a different play style to the team, it'll take time like with any sport to adjust. 

If you're going to base him being fired over a half a season, which doesn't yet include the dance/nit, well, the down votes should be enough to tell you how ridiculous your opinion is.  Yup, and the only way he is going to go is down.

Hiring a mediocre coach from the mid majors was a massive mistake. I don't think you know what you're talking about. Great, explain why.  Groce was an ok at best coach for U Ohio.  At best.

He has already shown he can't hack it with the big dogs.</snippet></document><document><title>Gotta love Ferrell and Watford's expressions</title><url>http://sphotos-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/395645_10151429968501600_1211630297_n.jpg</url><snippet>  Alright I'll say it.  Who am I supposed to be looking at? Watford is #2 on Indiana, on Griffey's left.  Ferrell is #11, standing on the far right of the picture. Alright I'll say it.  Who am I supposed to be looking at?  Who's the guy in the tie?   </snippet></document><document><title>Any laws we should be aware of on Unofficial?</title><url>http://www.reddit.com/r/UIUC/comments/185pax/any_laws_we_should_be_aware_of_on_unofficial/</url><snippet>My roommates and I are looking to have a yard party on unofficial, kegs and all. We went to the CPD today but they weren't very helpful as the guy in charge was out of office.  I'll be emailing him, but I was just wondering if anyone knew of any rules/laws my roommates and I should be aware of before throwing this? We've thrown huge parties for Unofficial before but they've always been indoors.  you will get boned if you have a single under 21 in there      I noticed you said kegS. Not sure how it works for a yard/outdoor party, but I know you're not allowed to have more than 1 keg at any indoor party. Last year CPD caught us getting 2 the day before, took one away, and gave us a $320 ticket. Double check to make sure how many you can have. How did that happen? Why didnt you tell them they were not going to the same location? Or if they showed up at your place, why did you answer and let them in? I guarantee they didn't have a warrant.  I put 1 keg under my name, my roommate put 1 keg under our neighbor's name (they had given us permission but were all at work for the night, and this was the Thursday before Unofficial). Cops saw us put 2 kegs in the car, followed us, then once we started bringing the second keg up they busted us, mainly because we didn't have our neighbor's keys on us so they were being put in the same apartment right away. 

Recommendation: take the time to go to multiple liquor stores and get 1 keg from each. Not only will you not get caught how we did, when the cops get the records of keg purchases there won't be two at the same location from each store.  Wow I can not believe that cops followed you to your house because you had kegs. That just fires me up but I know there's really nothing you could have done. It also really bothers me that cops have records to keg purchases. Is there no privacy or explicit rights on a college campus when it comes to drinking? Yeah it was pretty shitty, especially cuz at that point we knew they would have an eye on our place for any questionable activity all day. I'm not sure if there are normally privacy laws, but I know a lot of laws are 'changed' in a sense on Unofficial because of all of the injuries/alcohol poisoning/death that has happened in recent years. i.e. you can get multiple kegs legally with a permit, but said permit is not available for Unofficial. Also, supplying minors got bumped up from a standard ticket to a criminal misdemeanor last year.  You can have 2 kegs. You just need to get a permit at city hall for $25 bucks. They don't give that permit out for the day of unofficial. At least they didn't last year, because when I was getting the ticket I asked if there was anything we could have done and he told me about that permit but that they don't allow it on unofficial.   yeah id say best bet is to invite your 21 and over friends. Also try renting fences to control the inflow and outflow. Make sure you get your kegs a day or two early.  You're uninvited you are a mean person. http://assets0.ordienetworks.com/images/GifGuide/DealWithIt/tumblr_limthcd5BD1qfyv11o1_500.gif why does this exist    I thought unoffical was started because of all the police attention people would get on St Patricks weekend. From my expereince last year, unofficial seemed much less fun than the average weekend here.  Someone always dies on Unofficial. Don't be that guy. Don't let your friends be that guy. I've been here for eight years and I can remember two deaths on Unofficial weekend. They'll be sure to pound it home that someone got drunk and tried to cross University last year though (Against the wishes of the family). I've been here for eight years and I can remember two deaths on Unofficial weekend. They'll be sure to pound it home that someone got drunk and tried to cross University last year though (Against the wishes of the family). Tried to cross university? Someone always dies on Unofficial. Don't be that guy. Don't let your friends be that guy. Go hard or go home, bitch Go home Freshman.  It's way overrated. Unofficial is as fun as you and your friends make it. If you never drink and you don't have friends who party regularly, frat style Unofficial is gonna suck. Remember, alcohol doesn't improve a party unless you're able to have fun without it.

If your favorite thing to do on a weekend is hosting a LAN party, then you probably should host a gigantic LAN party for Unofficial. A Super Smash Brothers party with 20 friends from back home, two TVs, a keg, and some drinking games going on? Probably a better party than trying to crash a beer pong tournament where you end up puking. Unofficial is as fun as you and your friends make it. If you never drink and you don't have friends who party regularly, frat style Unofficial is gonna suck. Remember, alcohol doesn't improve a party unless you're able to have fun without it.

If your favorite thing to do on a weekend is hosting a LAN party, then you probably should host a gigantic LAN party for Unofficial. A Super Smash Brothers party with 20 friends from back home, two TVs, a keg, and some drinking games going on? Probably a better party than trying to crash a beer pong tournament where you end up puking. Unofficial is as fun as you and your friends make it. If you never drink and you don't have friends who party regularly, frat style Unofficial is gonna suck. Remember, alcohol doesn't improve a party unless you're able to have fun without it.

If your favorite thing to do on a weekend is hosting a LAN party, then you probably should host a gigantic LAN party for Unofficial. A Super Smash Brothers party with 20 friends from back home, two TVs, a keg, and some drinking games going on? Probably a better party than trying to crash a beer pong tournament where you end up puking.</snippet></document></searchresult>